<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CE 200 AND CE 300 BUS BODY COMPONENTS - Paint and Finish</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Paint and Finish</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This procedure is for the touch up and painting for National School Bus Yellow Urethane Paint.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Touch Up and Paint Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Surface cleaning and preparation.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All dirt, grease, oils, sealants or any contaminants must be removed.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Surface should be washed. Solvent wash is recommended.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Surface area must be scuff sanded with fine finishing grade sandpaper until gloss is
                        removed.
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>On final sanding operation, 400 grit or finer sandpaper is recommended.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Surface area must be clean of all sanding dust and other particulates.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>tach cloth wipe of area is recommended.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Metal Preparation and Prime</para>
                <para>All bare metal areas are to be treated/conditioned and then primed. Use a metal
                    treatment/conditioner. Apply a coat of good quality, two-component epoxy primer before applying
                    topcoat. Primer should be an automotive grade.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Topcoat</para>
                <para>KAY0015 / CT0066 needs to be mixed at a ratio of four (4) parts paint (KAY0015) to one (1) part
                    catalyst (CTC00660) by volume.
                </para>
                <para>Products are to be mixed thoroughly.</para>
                <para>Paint can be reduced with a maximum of 2.5 ounces BCA solvent per quart. Add the BCA solvent to
                    the KAY0015 part before mixing with the CTC0066.
                </para>
                <para>This product has a "pot life" of fifteen minutes at 77 degrees F after being mixed together.
                    Product should be used within this time.
                </para>
                <para>Product, when mixed properly, will "cure to tape" in two hours with maximum hardness being
                    achieved in three to five days with no external heat source.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_142.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_144.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
