<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>End Caps</title>
        <figure id="f47005131" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g47005131.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005131.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 131. End Caps (Rear Shown)</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">REAR EMERGENCY EXIT WINDOW</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">RED WARNING LIGHTS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">AMBER WARNING LIGHTS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DESTINATION BOARD</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">REAR CLEARANCE LIGHTS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SIDE RUNNING LIGHTS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The bus body end caps if damaged can be removed and replaced (
            <hotlnk document="s47005_6.xml" xrefid="f4700540">Figure 40</hotlnk>). The front cap and rear cap (End Caps)
            follow the same general procedure in the removal process.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Due to the proximity and nature of the end cap removal, the driver windshield assembly must
                be removed. Follow the procedure as outlined in the windshield removal section of this manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Front cap requires removal of the outside rear view mirror. Depending on the type mirror,
                the drivers side rear view mirror may not require removal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the passenger side rear view mirror support brackets. Remove the rear view
                mirror assembly. If the mirror is equipped with optional heater accessories, disconnect the heater
                harness connection.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the front or end cap warning lights and disconnect all electrical
                connections between the cap and the body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove as many rivets from the front end drip rail as needed to free the front cap for
                removal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all remaining rivets the attach the cap to the body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Follow the same general procedure for the rear end cap removal. The bus rear windows and
                emergency exit door need not be removed to remove the end cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_60.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
