<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Passenger Door Control Panel- Electric</title>
        <para>The electric passenger door opener is standard on all FE 300 buses. Optional air operated and manual
            openers are also available. Prior to doing any work on the electric door mechanism disconnect the power
            supply, and set the manual override switch to emergency position.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Electric Door Opener</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The electric door opener drive mechanism is located in the compartment directly over the
                passenger entry door.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">To access the mechanism, rotate the door latch locking device and lift the door up.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the power to the drive mechanism, locate the harness plug at the forward
                    section of the door mechanism compartment. Disconnect the harness plug.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47003154" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g47003154.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003154.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="232px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 154. Electric Door Opener Harness Disconnect</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC PASSENGER DOOR OPENER HARNESS CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the door hardware from the drive mechanism:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the drive arm mounting lock nut on the main gear drive plate.</para>
                <figure id="f47003155" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g47003155.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003155.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 155. Drive Arm Disconnect</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">DOOR DRIVE MOTOR GEAR PLATE</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVE ARM MOUNTING NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">DOOR DRIVE ARM</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the lock nut from the drive arm assembly and main gear drive plate.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the drive arm assembly end.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the entire electric drive mechanism:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the six mounting bolts on the motor drive assembly.</para>
                <figure id="f47003156" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g47003156.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003156.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 156. Door Opener Electric Drive Motor Remove</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC DOOR OPENER DRIVE PLATE</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC DOOR OPENER DRIVE GEAR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC DOOR OPENER ASSEMBLY MOUNTING BOLT HOLES</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC DOOR MANUAL / AUTOMATIC ACTUATION SWITCH</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVE ARM ATTACHMENT MOUNTING STUD AND NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ELECTRIC DOOR OPENER LIMIT SWITCHES</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting bolts, and lift the drive motor out of the compartment.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove door opener connecting rods:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The main drive arm from the electric door drive mechanism is attached to the door
                    bracket assembly. Main drive arm is a swivel joint attachment connection with lock nut and washer at
                    the door drive mounting bracket. The door drive mounting bracket is located at the top of the
                    forward door panel, and is mounted with two mounting bolts into the door assembly.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The rear door assembly of the passenger entry doors is connected utilizing a drive arm
                    with swivel joints connected to the forward door bracket. The rear door drive arm is connected to a
                    bracket mounted on the upper frame of the rear door panel of the main passenger entry doors. This
                    bracket is mounted to the door frame assembly with two mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The door opener drive rods have swivel joints at each and are secured to the brackets
                    with lock nuts and washers at each end.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The doors are equipped with a mounting bracket with mounting points for the drive arm
                    ends and swivels.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_80.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_82.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
