<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BE 200 BUS FRONT END AND BODY COMPONENTS - INSTALL - Interior Install</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="17">
        <title>Interior Install</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The procedures outlined in this section are the general procedures for the standard items and select
                options that are most commonly specified.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Step Well</title>
            <para>The step well assembly is secured to the floor substructure, body side panel and driver substructure
                frame. Because portions of the step well assembly are spot welded in place, take the proper precautions
                in the disconnecting the battery system.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the step well assembly, check the floor for holes from the previous
                    step well mounting. If pre-existing holes are found, fill the holes and seal the under structure to
                    prevent leaks that could lead to rust and/or other deterioration.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the step well in position with the step well opening. Prior to spot welding the
                    assembly in place, ensure that all surfaces are clean and free of dirt and/or debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the step well assembly is spot welded in place check for open gaps that may allow
                    moisture in the interior.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal any open areas.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the understructure for clean areas to spot weld the step well assembly to the
                    structures as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All undercoating and paint if applicable should have been removed from the area
                    surrounding the step well mounting points.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the step well, mark and cut out the openings for any courtesy lights
                    that may be mounted in the step well.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the step well spot welded and screwed into place, re-install the flooring material
                    and trim pieces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Relocate the step well assist handrail brackets, drill and mount the handrail base
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remount the passenger entry door assembly, check the alignment of the doors and lower
                    mounting blocks on door cross frame structure.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assist Handrails</title>
            <para>The assist handrail located on the left side of the entry step well is the standard location for the
                assist rail. An optional assist rail is located on the forward step well bulkhead.
            </para>
            <para>To install the standard step well assist handrail:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the hex head mounting hole at the crash barrier panel hand rail attachment
                    point.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the hex head mounting screw and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting screws on the lower step well handrail mounting brackets, two on
                    each bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screws. The assist handrail assembly can be mounted in the handrail
                    mounting brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the stainless steel handrail in the mounting brackets, locate the set screw on
                    the handrail assist mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the set screw to secure the handrail.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the bus is equipped with the optional assist handrail, follow the same basic
                    procedure as outlined in steps 3 through 7.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The top mounting bracket for the forward mounted handrail will be attached with a
                    mounting screw attachment to the forward dash vertical support bracket or the step well optional
                    heater side cover plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Defroster Fans (Optional)</title>
            <para>The optional defroster fan or fans are mounted on the bulkhead over the windshield area. The fan
                mounting base is the ground circuit.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the base of the 12 VDC defroster fan, align the fan base
                    mounting holes with the mounting holes in the bulkhead assembly (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_65.xml" xrefid="f47006106">Fig. 106, Item 1</hotlnk>)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the wire leads to the harness connection through the grommet in the bulkhead
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When connecting the fan circuits the black wire lead is for low speed, the red wire lead
                    for high speed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the fan direction by loosening the spring adjustment screw. Tighten the
                    adjustment screws when fan is in desired position.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sun Visor</title>
            <para>The sun visor mounts to the overhead structure above the driver position.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the sun visor assembly bracket on the overhead panel above the driver position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the overhead assembly, align the sun visor mounting bracket
                    holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_66.xml" xrefid="f47006107">Fig. 107, Item 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting screws in the brackets and into the overhead panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hand tighten all other sun visor fasteners.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque all fasteners until tight and still adjustable.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Destination Sign Lights (Optional)</title>
            <para>On busses equipped with lighted destination boards front and rear, the light bulbs and socket
                assemblies are located in the compartment over the windshield in the bulkhead compartment. To replace
                the bulbs:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the latching devices on the panel door and lift panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the light bulb socket assemblies (6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the burned out bulb or bulbs and install new bulbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on the bus lights to activate the destination board lights. Check bulbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close compartment door and secure latches.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Interior Rear View Mirror</title>
            <para>Prior to the installation of replacement glass, the glass should be inspected for small chips. If
                chips are found, do not install.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always use safety equipment and eye protection when removing or working with glass.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the mirror glass section on the backing plate. Install the rubber perimeter
                    strip.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the metal backing plate assembly on the bulkhead mounting bracket. Align with
                    the bulkhead mounting bracket holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_124.xml" xrefid="f47006205">Fig. 205, Item 2</hotlnk>), both right and left
                    side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the fasteners and hand tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust mirror to proper position for driver and tighten lock nut.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dash Board Panels, Cluster and Switch Panels</title>
            <para>Prior to installation of the dash panels, check all harness connections, check the defroster duct
                installation and heater connections.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Side Storage Compartment</title>
            <para>(
                <hotlnk document="s47006_43.xml" xrefid="f4700666">Figure 66</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the driver storage compartment assembly in place, connect the 12 volt power
                    receptacle plug at the bottom of the storage compartment.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the 6 mounting screw holes in the bottom of the driver storage compartment (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_125.xml" xrefid="f47006211">Fig. 211, Item 2</hotlnk>), insert the mounting
                    screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater and Environmental Controls</title>
            <para>(
                <hotlnk document="s47006_43.xml" xrefid="f4700662">Figure 62, Item 2</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the heater, defroster and fan control harness to the system harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and install the heater, defroster and recirculation control panel (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_125.xml" xrefid="f47006209">Fig. 209, Item 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the control knobs for the environmental controls.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Left Side Switch Panel</title>
            <para>(
                <hotlnk document="s47006_43.xml" xrefid="f4700662">Figure 62, Item 3</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and connect the driver left side switch panel and harness plugs. Connect the
                    switch harness plugs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the switch panel and align the panel mounting holes. Install the mounting screws
                    and tighten (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_125.xml" xrefid="f47006210">Fig. 210, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cluster Assembly</title>
            <para>(
                <hotlnk document="s47006_96.xml" xrefid="f47006173">Fig. 173, Item 7</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the instrument cluster in position, locate the harness connections for the
                    instrument cluster and connect.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seat the cluster and locate the cluster mounting holes and mounting screws (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_125.xml" xrefid="f47006208">Fig. 208, Item 1</hotlnk>). Insert the mounting
                    screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cluster Cover Panel</title>
            <para>(
                <hotlnk document="s47006_43.xml" xrefid="f4700662">Fig 62, Item 5</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the instrument cluster cover forward edge mounting holes with the mounting holes
                    along the lower edge of the windshield assembly (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_96.xml" xrefid="f47006173">Fig. 173, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>). Insert the
                    mounting bolts and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clock Spring</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Read and follow directions for the clock spring installation very carefully. This device will
                        break if not properly installed. If the clock spring binds, it must be re-aligned or it will
                        break in use.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the clock spring harness to the dash harness (Figure 222, Item 3).</para>
                <figure id="f47006281" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figG47/G47006281.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                             scalefitheight="288px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 281. Clock Spring Installation Detail</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CLOCK SPRING BODY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. RETAINER CLIP</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. ALIGNMENT ARROW ON TAB</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. ALIGNMENT ARROW ON CLOCK SPRING BODY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the clock using the alignment arrows (Figure 282, Items 3 and 4) on the spring
                    body and on the tab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To assure the spring is centered, do the following:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the spring 3 1/2 turns counterclockwise.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Return the spring clockwise 3 1/2 turns.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the spring 3 1/2
                        <emph type="bold">more</emph>turns clockwise.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Return the spring 3 1/2 turns counterclockwise to the center.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no binding has occurred, the spring is now centered. Insert the clock spring mounting
                    screws in mounting tabs (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_130.xml" xrefid="f47006222">Figure 222, Item 1</hotlnk>) to secure the
                    clock spring. If binding occurs, rotate the clock spring body appropriately and repeat steps a, b,
                    c, and d until no binding occurs through 3 1/2 turns from the center in each direction. (Seven turns
                    lock-to-lock)
                    <emph type="bold">IF THE CLOCK SPRING BINDS, IT MUST BE RE-ALIGNED OR IT WILL BREAK IN USE.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Steering Wheel / Clock Spring</title>
            <figure id="f47006282" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006282.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 282. Clock Spring Installed</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CLOCK SPRING BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CLOCK SPRING HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SPINDLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Line up the marks made earlier to assure the wheel is centered on the spindle (Figure
                    281, Item 3 and 4).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install retaining nut on spindle, tighten the nut to 660 to 720 LBF-IN (75 to 81 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assure that the locking clip (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_128.xml" xrefid="f47006216">Figure 216</hotlnk>) is properly located to
                    prevent it from working loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install steering column covers (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_127.xml" xrefid="f47006215">Figure 215</hotlnk>) and fasten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cover (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_127.xml" xrefid="f47006214">Figure 214</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Steering Column</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the steering column check the assembly for any damage to the splines that connect
                with the steering column yokes.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant, insert the steering column through the opening at the base of the
                    cowl plate panel, align the lower steering column mounting plate holes with the cowl wall holes.
                    Check alignment of universal joints in lower steering shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the upper mounting bolts with the steering column bracket and insert the mounting
                    bolts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006283">Figure 283, Items 2 and 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f478006283" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006283.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 283. Steering Column Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. STEERING COLUMN COVERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. UPPER STEERING COLUMN MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOWER STEERING COLUMN BRACKET MOUNTING BOLTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER STEERING COLUMN MOUNTING PLATE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With upper steering column mounting bolts securing steering column in the proper
                    position, insert the lower mounting bracket bolts through the steering column mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006283">Figure 283, Items 3 and 4</hotlnk>) into the cowl assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting bolts to the required torque value: 34 to 42 LBF-FT (46 to 56
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten steering column mounting bracket bolts to 17 to 23 LBF-FT ( 23 to 31 Nm).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install steering column covers and fasteners.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accelerator Pedal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and align the accelerator pedal assembly mounting holes on the cowl reinforcing
                    mounting plate and insert the mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting bolts to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the accelerator harness connection plug into the accelerator assembly plug
                    receptacle.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pedal</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the brake pedal assembly, ensure that the brake pedal arm is seated and the dust
                cover is in place and not damaged.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47006284" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 284. Break Pedal Assembly Install</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRAKE PEDAL ARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. STEERING COLUMN MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PIVOT BAR MOUNTING NUT AND LOCK WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE ROD RETAINER PIN AND CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. BRAKE ROD DUST BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. BRAKE ROD ATTACHMENT CLEVIS</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PIVOT BAR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert nylon bushings in ends of pivot bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert pivot bar and brake pedal assembly in position on steering column bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the pivot bar mounting holes with mounting holes on steering column bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert mounting bolt through bushings and pivot bar (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006284">Figure 284, Item 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lock nut, and hand tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate, align and install brake rod clevis to brake pedal arm (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006284">Figure 284, Item 6)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install retainer pin and clip (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006284">Figure 284, Item 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten lock nut to torque value.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Right Wing Switch Panel and Cluster Bezel</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and install the right wing switch panel, align the panel mounting holes with the
                    mounting holes in the panel support bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the panel aligned and in place, insert the panel and bezel mounting screws. Tighten
                    the panel screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate any of the optional equipment mounted on the switch panel. Align with the
                    mounting holes, insert the mounting screws (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_125.xml" xrefid="f47006207">Fig. 207, Item 2</hotlnk>), and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Step Well Panel</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Prior to any installation of assemblies that have been attached to the bus interior through
                        the floor assembly, the existing holes must be plugged or filled and or sealed prior to
                        sub-floor installation. All fasteners that protrude the floor assembly must be painted and/or
                        under coated to prevent corrosion.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the step well dash panel in place and align the lower over lap mounting holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align step well forward edge mounting holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_96.xml" xrefid="f47006173">Fig. 173, Items 3 and 4</hotlnk>) with the
                    cluster cover / wing switch panel cover mounting hole and mounting hole at right hand windshield
                    wing panel lower edge of the windshield assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting bolts and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the lower edge of the step well panel mounting holes with the mounting holes in
                    the bus cross beam support bracket. Insert the mounting screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Seat</title>
            <para>Prior to installation of the driver seat assembly, the mounting hardware should be inspected, and the
                adjustment mechanisms should be lubricated. The seat belts should be inspected for smooth operation and
                secure attachment.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the driver position platform prior to installation of the driver seat assembly.
                    Locate and check the driver seat mounting holes in the platform area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the driver seat mounting holes on the driver platform floor holes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolts through the seat pedestal and floor (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_48.xml" xrefid="f4700670">Figure 70, Item 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant located under the driver seat platform beneath the floor assembly,
                    install the washers and lock nuts on each of the driver seat mounting bolts. Hand tighten the
                    mounting nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the seat mounting for alignment, torque seat anchoring hardware to 20-22 Lbf-ft.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Seat Belts (3-Pt Belt Install)</title>
            <para>Check the type of driver seat (for air ride seats) installed and follow the manufacturers recommended
                procedure for seat belt installation. This procedure requires an assistant under the bus to install the
                mounting nut and washer.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the seat belt latch assembly floor mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Figure 231, Item 5</hotlnk>) and mounting bolt
                    and washer (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Figure 231, Items 8 and 9</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the mounting bracket hole with the mounting hole through the floor on the driver
                    platform.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolt and washer through belt assembly attachment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the assistant under the driver platform, install the washer and lock nut (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Figure 231, Items 2 and 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the lock nut to 40-42 Lbf-ft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting bracket mounting hole on the left side of the driver seat platform
                    floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align and install the floor mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Fig. 231, Item 6</hotlnk>) and mounting bolt (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Fig. 231, Item 5</hotlnk>) through the bracket
                    and floor assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the assistant under the driver platform, install the washer and lock nut (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Fig. 231, Items 2 and 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the lock nut to 40-42 Lbf-ft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the seat belt harness and cover assembly floor mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006231">Fig. 231, Item 7 and 6</hotlnk>) on left side
                    of driver position. Install the mounting bolt, washers and lock nut through the belt assembly
                    hardware and floor mounted bracket. Torque to 10-12 Lbf-ft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the upper wall mounting holes directly behind the driver rear sliding glass
                    window pillar (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006230">Fig. 230, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the shoulder harness assembly mounting bracket and insert the mounting bolts
                    through the bracket and into the wall structure mounting holes, both upper and lower bracket
                    assemblies (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_137.xml" xrefid="f47006230">Fig. 230, Items 2 and 3</hotlnk>). Torque the
                    mounting bolts to 40-42 Lbf-ft.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Crash Barrier (Rail Mounted)</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The installation of the floor mounted seat and barrier attachments can be located underneath
                        the bus floor. An assistant is required to install the washers and lock nuts. Installation also
                        requires torquing the fasteners to the specified values from under the bus body.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the barrier to be installed and place the inboard (rail mounting bracket) on the
                    chair rail along the bus side wall.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006285" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006285.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 285. Chair Rail Seat Mounting</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. LOWER SEAT CUSHION</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CHAIR RAIL</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SEAT / CHAIR RAIL MOUNTING BOLTS AND WASHERS</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. CHAIR RAIL SEAT MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the barrier wall bracket mounting holes on the chair rail (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006286">Figure 286</hotlnk>) mounting holes. Insert the mounting bolts through
                    the barrier mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006286">Fig. 286, Item 4</hotlnk>) and chair rail. Install the washers and lock
                    nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the barrier foot assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006286">Fig. 286</hotlnk>) mounting holes and align with mounting holes in floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f47006286" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006286.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 286. Crash Barrier Floor Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BUS CHAIR RAIL ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ROAD WARNING TRIANGLE MOUNTING BRACKET SCREWS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ROAD HAZARD WARNING TRIANGLE CASE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CRASH BARRIER FOOT MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting bolts, washers and lock nuts as required and torque to specified
                    value.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the entry assist handrail as required (if installing passenger side crash
                    barrier).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fire Extinguisher</title>
            <para>The fire extinguisher installation may vary depending on location of the extinguisher. The
                extinguishers are generally mounted in the vertical position.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the area the extinguisher is to be mounted. Mark the bulkhead or area where the
                    extinguisher bracket will be mounted. Use the bracket mounting holes as a guide. Drill the mounting
                    holes or use the existing mounting holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f47006287" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006287.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 287. Extinguisher Mounting Bracket</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FIRE EXTINGUISHER BRACKET MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FIRE EXTINGUISHER RETAINER STRAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXTINGUISHER LOCK CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FIRE EXTINGUISHER MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the bracket mounting holes and bulkhead mounting holes, insert mounting screws and
                    tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert extinguisher in bracket and secure strap band.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>First Aid Kit</title>
            <para>The first aid kit provided for the school bus application is designed for use from the mounted
                position. The kit is furnished with an upper mounting bracket and a lower spring clip retainer.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To mount the first aid kit locate the mounting holes in the overhead panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f47006288" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006288.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 288. First Aid Kit mounting Clip and Screws</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HANDLE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LOCK CLIP BRACKET ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FRONT BULKHEAD LEADING EDGE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the kit in on the lower bracket retainer assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the two mounting screws through the kit upper mounting flange and tighten the
                    screw until the kit is snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Fluid Clean-up Kit (Optional)</title>
            <para>The body fluid clean-up kit provided for the school bus application is designed for use from the
                mounted position. The kit is furnished with an upper mounting bracket and a lower spring clip retainer.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To mount the Body Fluid Clean-up Kit locate the mounting holes in the overhead panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the kit in on the lower bracket retainer assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the two mounting screws through the kit upper mounting flange and tighten the
                    screw until the kit is snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger Door Control Mechanism</title>
            <para>The BE 200 school bus model is equipped with one of two different style or type passenger entry door
                opener mechanisms. The standard door opening type is the electrically operated door opening mechanism.
                The second style is the optional manual type door opener. All types automatically activate the student
                warning lights, the crossing gate and driver side stop arms.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Electric Actuated Door Opener</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Electric Actuated Door Opener Removal</para>
                <para>The electric door opener motor and drive mechanism are located in the compartment directly above
                    the passenger entry door. The door operation is activated by a double switch operation on the left
                    side of the steering wheel. An optional two position switch is located on the left console switch
                    panel. A manual override switch for emergency purposes is located on the door opener access panel.
                    See bus operators manual for operational instructions.
                </para>
                <para>To install the door opener use the following procedures:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate and open the drive motor access door.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the six motor mounting bolts holes that secure the motor mounting bracket to
                        the compartment structure.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the door opener drive motor, and align with mounting holes in compartment.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the six mounting bolts and tighten.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate and connect the harness plug at the upper left hand corner of the
                        compartment.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Move the emergency release lever forward to release the emergency door.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the drive arm on the cam gear plate.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the drive arm and drive arm end bushing mounting hole.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolt through the bushing and gear plate.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the lock nut attaching the drive arm to the gear plate.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tighten to required torque value.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Set emergency door switch to automatic.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Activate door from steering wheel switch. Check operation. If adjustment is required
                        see door adjustment section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Electric Door Adjustments</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The passenger entry door has no speed adjustments. The doors do have a limit switch
                    adjustment that sets the limits of the door opening. To adjust these limits loosen the mounting
                    screws on the switch assembly. Move the switch in or out to set the limit of the door opening
                    operation.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To replace either switch, set the emergency manual door opener to open.</para>
                    <figure id="f47006289" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006289.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                                 scalefitheight="312px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 289. Electric Door Opener Adjustment- Limit Switches</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. LIMIT SWITCH MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. LIMIT SWITCHES</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the 2 Phillips head screws on the top surface of the switch. Loosen and
                        remove screws.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove switch. With switch removed disconnect the wire connectors to switch. Mark
                        switch for placement of wires when re-installing.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the opposite switch if it is to be replaced.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bus Interior Light Bars</title>
            <para>The light bar assemblies along each side of the bus body above the passenger and driver windows
                contain the harness for the rear bus warning, stop-tail, directional and back-up lights. They also
                contain the wire harness for the emergency exit door buzzers, the roof escape hatches, emergency window
                exits, interior bus lighting and speaker assembly wiring (if equipped).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Driver light bar. The driver light bar (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_50.xml" xrefid="f4700674">Fig. 74, Item 1</hotlnk>) contains the harness
                    and connections from the chassis and body electrical compartment.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the light bar assembly in position over the driver window assembly. Align the
                        mounting holes in the driver light bar and the passenger light bar assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check that the light bar cut out for the wire duct (
                        <hotlnk document="s47006_50.xml" xrefid="f4700674">Fig. 74, Item 5</hotlnk>) from the electrical
                        compartment fits properly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the Phillips head screw and tighten.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Light bar panels</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The light bar panels (
                        <hotlnk document="s47006_50.xml" xrefid="f4700675">Fig. 75</hotlnk>) are located along the
                        window line. The top flange of the light bar panel is attached to the ceiling panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the light panel behind the passenger window top flange.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lay the upper light bar flange against the ceiling panel, insert the mounting screw
                        and tighten.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Passenger lights and speakers assemblies (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_50.xml" xrefid="f4700675">Fig. 75, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Passenger light assemblies are located above the window assemblies in the light
                        bar.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If a light assembly is being replaced, locate the harness connection in the light
                        bar for the light connection. Insert the light assembly connectors into the harness connector.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the light fixture and lens over the opening in the light bar.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the mounting holes and insert mounting screws.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mounting the speaker assemblies in the light bar, locate the speaker wire connectors
                        and attach the connectors.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the speaker assembly over the opening and align the four mounting screws.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the screws and tighten.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Light bar joint cover plate (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_142.xml" xrefid="f47006238">Figure 238, Item 2</hotlnk>)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the end sections of the two light bar panels and install the joint cover over
                        the panel joints. Place the lower flange behind the window top flange. Insert mounting screw in
                        top flange of joint cover into ceiling panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for all other joint cover plates.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Corner covers (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_50.xml" xrefid="f4700676">Figure 76, Item 2</hotlnk>)
                </para>
                <para>The corner cover light bar sections conceal the wire harness junction connectors at the rear
                    corners of the bus body.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When replacing the corner covers, ensure all harness connections are secured and out
                        of the way.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the corner cover over the light bar end section and flush to the inside rear
                        cap assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the mounting screws and tighten.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Torque all mounting screws until tight. Do not over tighten.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Seats</title>
            <para>If the seat has been removed for repairs and is being re-installed to the same position use this
                procedure:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Seat Install. An assistant will be required to install the seat mounting bolts.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Two leg / chair rail mount (30" and 45")</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Align seat wall bracket on chair rail, align the mounting holes on the chair rail and leg
                            mounting holes on the floor.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Install the chair rail mounting bolts, washers and lock nuts. Tighten the chair rail
                            fasteners.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Locate the chair leg floor plate mounting holes and insert the mounting bolts through the
                            mounting plate and floor.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>The mounting lock nuts and washers are installed from beneath the bus and torqued to 19-20
                            Lbf-ft by an assistant.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Four leg (30" and 45")</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Locate the seat in position, aligning the mounting holes in the seat leg floor plate
                            mounting holes with the floor mounting holes.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Insert the mounting bolts through the four leg mounting plates and floor.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>The mounting lock nuts and washers are installed from beneath the bus and torqued to 19-20
                            Lbf-ft by an assistant.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Child Safety seat (Optional)</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Follow the same procedure for standard rail mount seat and four leg seat as previously
                            outlined in steps "a" and "b".
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Flip Up Emergency Exit Seat (Optional)</para>
                    <para>The flip up emergency exit seat is a four leg seat assembly.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Follow the same procedure as described in section "b" of this section.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Seat Cushions</title>
            <para>Inspect all seat mounting hardware attachments. This should be performed at 30 to 45 day intervals.
                Inspect the seat back foam around the upper corner and in the knee impact area. If damage is discovered
                such as breakage or separated seals, the seat back material should be replaced without delay.
            </para>
            <para>The following procedure should be used to replace seat upholstery. In most cases the seat will not
                have to be removed from the bus.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the upholstery or foam on the seat board, align the foam, overlay the upholstery
                    material and staple to the seat board.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006290" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006290.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 290. Seat Cushion Replace</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SEAT BACK CUSHION FOAM</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SEAT BACK CUSHION UPHOLSTERY COVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SEAT CUSHION UPHOLSTERY COVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SEAT CUSHION FOAM PAD</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. SEAT CUSHION PLYWOOD BASE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. SEAT CUSHION UPHOLSTERY ATTACHMENT STAPLES</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. LOWER CUSHION TILT LATCH</callout1>
                        <callout1>8. LOWER SEAT TUBULAR FRAME</callout1>
                        <callout1>9. SEAT FLOOR MOUNTING FEET</callout1>
                        <callout1>10. SEAT BACK FRAME ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the seat board mounting hardware if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the seat cushion on the seat frame, insert mounting hardware screws, and
                    tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the hinge mounting screws through the hinge assembly into seat cushion board.
                    Tighten the screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flip the cushion down to the ride position and rotate locking clip to secure seat
                    cushion assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Seat Back</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the seat cushion flipped forward, locate and install the seat back cushion (foam
                    padding) over the seat back frame. Pull the foam panel all the way down over the frame work and
                    ensure a tight fit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the upholstery (seat back cover) section over the cushion and frame assembly and
                    pull down into place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Staple the material in place on the tack strip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the end seams for adequate fit, flip seat cushion back down and lock in place.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006291" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006291.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 291. Seat Back Cushion Replace</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SEAT BACK CUSHION UPHOLSTERY COVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SEAT BACK CUSHION FOAM</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SEAT BACK FRAME ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Seat Tracks (Optional)</title>
            <para>The seat track configuration may vary depending on the type seats and location.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the floor has a plywood sub-floor the plywood will be routed to accommodate the seat
                    track as part of the floor assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the slots in the plywood sub-floor and insert the seat tracks in the floor
                    slot.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the track section and drill through the mounting holes and
                    sub-floor assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the tapered Phillips head torque lock screw in the track and fasten into the
                    floor system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the track is mounted, ensure that a sufficient amount of undercoat has been
                    applied to prevent moisture from penetrating the bus integrity on the underside of the bus floor
                    where the mounting screws have penetrated through.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the seat track in place install the flooring material as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the seat track mounting studs according to the requirements of the state or
                    district specifications.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the seats on the track and mounting studs. Install the lock nuts and torque to
                    required value.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Seat Belt- 2 Point With Seat Track (Optional)</title>
            <para>With the seat track and seats in place insert the seat belt track mounting studs in the appropriate
                position by inserting the head of the track bolt in the track and slide to lock position.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install seat belt ends through cushion and seat back and place end plate mounting hole
                    on the seat track stud.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the stud mounting lock nut over the seat belt mounting plate and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the remaining seat belt mounting plates on the respective
                    mounting studs. Install lock nuts and torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger Window Installation</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the passenger side windows, inspect the window seat and frame for dirt, old
                sealant and/or debris. Clean as necessary.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Check the window gasket material for full adhesion around the window frame prior to
                        installation. Any cracks or breaks in the seal could result in window leaks.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the window assembly in the window opening.</para>
                <figure id="f47006292" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006292.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 292. Passenger Window Replace</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. PASSENGER WINDOW EXTRUDED FRAME AND WINDOW ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. LIGHT BAR JOINT COVER PLATE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. LIGHT BAR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. PASSENGER VERTICAL WINDOW FRAME POST</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the window mounting cover plates each side of the window assembly. Install the
                    mounting screws in the cover plates and tighten.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006293" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006293.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 293. Install Window Cover Plates</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. WINDOW COVER PLATE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. PASSENGER WINDOW ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the window and seal for fit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant as may be required to ensure good seal and stop possibility of leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stationary Glass Install</title>
            <para>All glass installed in this vehicle meets F.M.V.S.S. requirements. The glass should only be replaced
                with the same type glass. The passenger entry door glass is AS-2 tempered safety glass encased by an
                aluminum frame with a center latching device.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the glass for cracks and or chips before installation process.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the "H" seal around the glass panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place glass and seal in window frame area from inside the bus body. With a flat tool
                    seat glass and seal on the window opening lip.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray the window and seal with a soapy solution to help in the installation of the
                    window assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the window flat tool work the seal around the window frame lip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the inside of the window and seal to ensure the window has seated. Using the same
                    flat tool work the seal around the window perimeter to ensure proper seat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the window seal lock lace around the window area seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A rope in method may be used in place of working the window perimeter with the flat
                    tool.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Exit Window Installation</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the emergency kick-out window assemblies, inspect the window seat and frame for
                dirt, old sealant and/or debris. Clean as necessary.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Horizontally Hinged Kick-out Windows</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate and connect the wire lead to the switch assembly below the window frame.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the plunger switch and install the four mounting screws at the bottom of the
                        window frame that secure the switch in place.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the window assembly in the window opening.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the plunger switch and install the four mounting screws on the bottom of the
                        window frame that secure the switch in place.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the window mounting cover plates each side of the window assembly. Install
                        the mounting screws in the cover plates and tighten.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Verify the window buzzer operation.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Vertically Hinged Kick-out Windows</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate and connect the wire lead to the switch assembly on the vertical window
                        frame.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the plunger switch and install the four mounting screws on the side of the
                        window frame that secure the switch in place.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the window assembly in the window opening.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the window mounting cover plates each side of the window assembly. Install
                        the mounting screws in the cover plates and tighten.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Verify the window buzzer operation.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Exit Doors and Latches</title>
            <para>If the emergency door latch has been removed or replaced use the following procedure to install door
                latches:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the interior door latch mechanism and install on door structure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the four mounting screws on the door latch assembly with mounting holes on the
                    interior door panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the exterior door handle mounting plate on the exterior of the door handle panel.
                    Install the two mounting screws to secure the mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the exterior door handle assembly on the mechanism rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and tighten the torque head screws at the top of the handle and the other set
                    screw (torque head) on the side of the handle stem.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the mechanism latch for proper operation and ensure the lock mechanism is
                    lubricated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the ignition in the "ON" position, check the door buzzer for proper alignment and
                    operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Roof Hatch Exit Install</title>
            <para>If the roof hatch has been removed due to external damage and is being replaced, it is recommended
                that only OEM replacement parts be used in the installation procedure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secure scaffold assembly and safety restraints
                        or equivalent equipment when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An
                        assistant should be present during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the replacement roof escape hatch over the roof opening and align the mounting
                    holes in the hatch assembly with the mounting holes in the roof.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply adhesive or sealer under the perimeter of the hatch assembly prior to fastening
                    the hatch to the roof.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use 1/4" diameter replacement rivets of suitable length. Use a rivet gun of industrial
                    quality to properly set rivets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a pliable sealant around the outside perimeter of the hatch to prevent possible
                    leakage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plastic fastener protective caps over the rivets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside the bus, locate the hatch buzzer wire harness and connect to the body
                    harness plug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the inside hatch trim ring into the hatch opening in the ceiling. Align the trim
                    ring mounting holes with the existing ceiling panel mounting holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screws through the hatch trim ring and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the screw cap covers on the interior trim ring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the hatch assembly, turn ignition key to the "ON" position and open hatch to
                    verify the alarm operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheelchair Access Door (Optional)</title>
            <para>The wheelchair access door is mounted to the bus body structure with three 180 degree swing hinges.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An assistant may be required to locate the wheel chair access door in the door opening.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the door assembly in the door opening with the hinges mounted on the door
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the hinge mounting holes with the body mounting holes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolts in the hinge assemblies, tighten and swing door to check
                    alignment.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the door seats properly, torque hinge mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the door and check the door ajar alarm alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the door assembly, turn ignition key to the "ON" position and open the door to
                    verify the alarm operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheelchair Lift</title>
            <para>The wheelchair lift is a specialized accessory and only a trained technician should attempt the
                installation of the wheelchair lift assembly. Refer to the manufacturer service manual for installation
                and servicing procedures.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheelchair Floor Plates</title>
            <para>Locate the wheelchair plates on the floor where desired. Check all dimensions relative to the
                placement of the wheelchair and related components.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the wheelchair mounting plate holes on the floor. Drill the holes to proper size.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the four carriage bolts per plate as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant locate the mounting bolts from underneath the bus body, install the
                    washers and lock nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten lock nuts with torque wrench to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheelchair Seat Belts and Shoulder Harness</title>
            <para>Locate the seat belt harness track mounting holes above the window assemblies.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the track mounting holes with the window header mounting and ceiling panel
                    holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the torque head mounting screws and tighten to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the wall mounted shoulder / seat belt storage bag mounting holes in the lower
                    interior side sheet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the six mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Door Glass Protection Screen (Optional)</title>
            <para>Locate the emergency door protection screen and place over the lower glass panel.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the screen in the lower clips center on the window opening. Rotate the remaining
                    clips around to capture the screen frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting clips.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the clips on the screen and tighten the mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Door and Wheelchair Access Door Glass Install</title>
            <para>This procedure is for all stationary glass panels excluding the windshield assembly. This includes
                passenger entry doors, emergency exit doors, wheelchair access doors and destination board lighted glass
                panel.
            </para>
            <para>Follow the procedure below to install the stationary glass panels.</para>
            <para>The procedure for installation of the stationary glass panels includes passenger entry doors,
                wheelchair lift access door and rear or side emergency exit doors.
            </para>
            <para>To ease installation, the rubber gasket can be heated with a non-flame source (heat gun). At high
                temperatures, the rubber gasket is more pliable. Do not heat above 125 deg. F for longer than 1 1/2
                hours.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For smaller glass applications, install the glass in the window seal and set on the
                    lower flange.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Utilizing the hook end of the glass installation tool work the seal and glass into the
                    opening.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006294" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006294.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 294. Emergency Exit Door and Wheelchair Door Glass Replace</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DOOR WINDOW FRAME EDGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. GLASS INSERT WITH "H" SEAL</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. DOOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. WINDOW INSTALLATION ROPE TOOL</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A foam type glass cleaner or soapy fluid can be used to lubricate the rubber gasket.
                    This will ease the installation of the window and seal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To install the lock lace into the window seal use a lacing tool (# 201-1127) by Sommer
                    Maca. Thread lace rubber through tool into the window seal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push or pull the rubber around the rubber gasket, feeding the lace rubber into the tool
                    using a hitching motion. This will help prevent the lace rubber from stretching.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the installation and clean off the surface of the glass.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal the rubber gasket and glass with a pliable windshield sealant.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Equipment (Required)</title>
            <para>Road reflective triangles and storage box are a safety requirement on all busses. These are generally
                stored in a plastic case mounted directly behind the driver position on the crash barrier bulkhead.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the reflector mounting case bracket on the lower frame of the driver crash
                    barrier bulkhead.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the mounting holes in the mounting bracket with the mounting holes in the barrier
                    lower frame.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006295" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006295.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 295. Road Hazard Triangle Mounting Bracket</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. BRACKET MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ROAD HAZARD TRIANGLE CASE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screws through the bracket into the barrier frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the bracket mounting screw.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exterior Light Monitor (Optional)</title>
            <para>Locate and position the exterior light check module. Connect the harness connections as may be
                required.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the monitor mounting holes with the mounting holes located in the driver
                    bulkhead.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screws and tighten.</para>
                <figure id="f47006296" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006296.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 296. External Light Monitor Mounting</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. EXTERNAL LIGHT CHECK MONITOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. LIGHT MONITOR COVER SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. LIGHT MONITOR MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to the "ON" position, and check the light monitor for full
                    function.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the monitor works properly, torque the mounting screws to required torque values.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the monitor does not function properly, remove and check harness connections.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the monitor assembly and torque mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Sender Access Panel</title>
            <para>To replace center aisle fuel sender access panel, follow procedure below.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the fuel access panel over the opening in the center aisle floor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the holes in the access plate with the holes in the center aisle flooring and
                    insert the mounting screws in the access panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all the screws around the access panel. Ensure that no sharp edges are
                    protruding upward that might cause any kind of obstacle in the aisle way.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006297" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006297.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 297. Fuel Sender Access Panel</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CENTER AISLE TRIM</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ACCESS PANEL MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. CENTER AISLE FLOOR RUNNER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the access panel under a passenger seat, the seat should have already been removed
                    during the access panel removal procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure as in steps 3 and 4.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant locate the seat removed, align the chair rail mounting holes with the
                    mounting holes on the chair bracket. Insert the mounting bolts, nuts and washers through the chair
                    bracket and chair rail. Hand tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant under the bus floor, locate the mounting foot holes in the chair and
                    align with the mounting holes in the bus floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolts and the assistant will install the washers and lock nuts.
                    Tighten the chair mounting bolts and nuts to the proper torque value.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque the chair rail mounting hardware to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flooring</title>
            <para>If an area of the bus floor is to be replaced, measure the area using the removed piece as a
                template.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the flooring adhesive, make sure the floor and or sub- floor is
                    clean and free of any debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the flooring that was removed with the new cut to fit piece.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a floor rolling tool, roll the surface of the flooring in a continuous motion,
                    covering the entire area replaced and including the seams. Let the flooring set up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the floor was replaced under a row of seats, locate the chair rail holes of the seat
                    and mark the floor accordingly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill the flooring at the marks made and install the mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the entire floor area must be replaced all seats must be removed and the sub-floor
                    checked for damage if applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the sub floor requires replacement, remove the sub-floor prior to installation of the
                    new sub-floor. Plug all holes in the floor structure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal the floor structure and place adhesive. Place the new sub-floor plywood and screw
                    into place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure installing the floor covering as was done in the repair
                    procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-drill the floor seat mounting holes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the seats and torque all hardware as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque all fasteners from beneath the bus. All protruding screws and mounting bolts
                    should be coated to prevent corrosion and/or leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_162.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_164.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
