<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Stationary Glass Removal</title>
        <para>Stationary glass removal are those panels that are mounted in an "H" type seal in the emergency exit door,
            the wheel chair lift access door and the passenger side entry doors.
        </para>
        <para>There are many variations of window and glass arrangements installed school bus applications. However, the
            installation and maintenance procedures given in this section can be used as general information that is
            contingent on state specifications (optional equipment).
        </para>
        <para>If the glass is broken it may have already fallen or been removed from the rubber gasket or seal. It is
            often necessary to remove cracked or otherwise imperfect glass that is still intact. In this case, it is a
            good practice to criss-cross the glass with strips of masking tape before removal. This will help hold glass
            together and minimize the risk of injury.
        </para>
        <para>Follow the procedure as listed below for glass removal.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the lace rubber from the rubber gasket by prying out the edge of the lace rubber from
                the groove and continue to pull out the rubber.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For easy removal, insert a putty knife between the rubber gasket and the glass to break the
                sealant seal, making sure the glass is not stuck.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat step two on the opposite side of glass.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position an assistant outside the vehicle at the glass.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">From inside the bus, push the glass from the rubber seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Have the assistant remove the glass and discard.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the gasket from the window flange.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the gasket is cut or damaged, discard and replace with new gasket.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_147.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_149.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
