<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - IC BUS SERVICE MANUAL - WINDOWS - INSTALLATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INSTALLATION</title>
        <para>To ease installation, the rubber gasket can be heated with a non-flame source (heat gun). At high
            temperatures, the rubber gasket is more pliable. Do not heat above 125&#176;F for longer than 1&#189; hours.
        </para>
        <para>Avoid contacting the glass with anything that may chip or crack the edges. Pressure on the glass will tend
            to concentrate at the chipped areas, causing cracks. If the glass is chipped, the edge should be ground
            smooth prior to installation.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For large applications such as the windshield glass, install the rubber gasket onto the
                flange of the glass opening. For smaller glass applications, such as the entrance door, the rubber
                gasket should be located on the glass itself. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f4700165">Figure 59.</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the hook end of the windshield glass installation tool into the gasket and work the
                glass into the opening.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To install the lace rubber into the rubber gasket, use the lacing tool by threading the lace
                rubber into the tool and installing the rubber. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f4700166">Figure 60.</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Pull the lace rubber around the rubber gasket, feeding the lace rubber into the tool using a
                hitching motion. This will help prevent the lace rubber from stretching.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A foam type glass cleaner or a mild soap and some water can be used to lubricate the rubber
                gasket. This will ease installation of the glass and lace rubber.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the installation and clean off the surface of the glass.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Seal the rubber gasket and glass with a pliable windshield sealant.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f4700165" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g4700165.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 58. Install Glass With Gasket</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f4700166" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g4700166.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 59. Install Rubber Lace</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_36.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_38.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
