<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Windshield Removal</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>There are many variations of window and glass arrangements installed in school bus applications.
                    However, the installation and maintenance procedures given in this section can be used as a general
                    information that is contingent on state specifications (optional equipment)
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>All glass in this vehicle meets F.M.V.S.S. requirements. Should the glass require replacing, replace with
            the same type of glass and glass mounting seal. The windshield is a flat four piece assembly. Replacing the
            windshield assembly requires a qualified glass technician and helper. The windshield is an AS-1 laminated
            safety glass, tinted 73% light transmission and sealed with a rubber "H" style gasket and lock lace.
            Installation of the windshield lace requires standard window glass tools readily available at automotive
            glass suppliers.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>An assistant is required in the removal and installation of the windshield assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, always wear safety glasses and gloves when
                    handling glass.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>If the glass is broken, it may already have fallen or been removed from the rubber seal. It is often
            necessary to remove cracked or otherwise imperfect glass that is still intact. In this case, it is a good
            practice to criss-cross the glass with strips of masking tape before removal. This will help hold the glass
            together and minimize the risk of injury.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Beginning at the center of the windshield at the bottom glass seal of the windshield panel
                to be removed, pry out the windshield lock lace from the groove around the entire perimeter of the glass
                panel. If a windshield side panel is to be replaced just remove the lace lock seal from around the side
                panel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f4700399" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g4700399.webp" filename="../figg47/G4700399.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Windshield Lock Lace Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD LOCK LACE REMOVAL AND TOOL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER SIDE REAR VIEW MIRROR</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD SEAL AND LOCK LACE</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">GLASS HANDLING SUCTION CUPS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Removal can begin at either wing panel. For easy removal a putty knife or non metallic flat
                tool can be use to insert between the glass and seal to release the glass from the seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While releasing the glass from the seal an assistant should apply pressure pushing the upper
                portion of the panel in an outward direction.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003100" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003100.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003100.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Lock Lace Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER SIDE CENTER PANEL LOCK LACE REMOVAL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VERTICAL WINDSHIELD / WING PANEL SUPPORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the panel from the seal and place on a padded table to prevent any damage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Beginning in the upper corner where wing panel glass was removed, insert tool to release
                center glass panel from window seal. Continue across top surface of center windshield panel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003101.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="280px" scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 101. Windshield Center Section</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">PERIMETER LOCK LACE</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">FLAT TOOL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD PANEL (DRIVER SIDE)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ASSISTANT'S HAND FROM INSIDE (PUSHING GLASS OUTWARD)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD "H" SEAL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">As the seal is being released, an assistant should be applying pressure along the upper
                windshield surface, pushing the glass outward.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003102.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 102. Windshield Remove From Seal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VERTICAL SEAL (PASSENGER SIDE SHOWN)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD BOTTOM SEAL SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the windshield and seal have been released from the windshield frame assembly at the
                top of the windshield, remove the vertical seal from the outboard edge of the glass. The assistant
                should be steadying glass during the procedure to remove the windshield seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the seal from the upper edge of the center windshield glass.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant slide the glass toward the side of the bus (the side with wing panel
                previously removed), lift glass out of bottom seal, and remove from bus.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003103.webp" filename="../figg47/G47003103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="280px" scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 103. Windshield Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">SUCTION CUPS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WINDSHIELD DRIVER SIDE PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WING PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If windshield glass is going to be re-used (not broken or cracked) store on padded stand
                until ready to install.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check windshield mounting frame for any damage before installing new seal and or glass.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
