<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - IC BUS SERVICE MANUAL - SEATS - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The list below provides a general guideline for seat maintenance. These items should become part of a
                regular inspection program.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect and tighten all seat and barrier mounting hardware attachments. This should be
                    performed at 30 to 45 day intervals. The seat leg bolts require 19 to 20 ft-lbs. of torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the mounting hardware at the seat cushion mount and seat clip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the seat back foam around the upper corner and in the knee impact area. If
                    damage is discovered such as breakage or separated seals, the seat back material should be replaced
                    without delay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the staples that attach the seat tacking strip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the upholstery for cuts, markings and other damage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When replacing seat back foam and upholstery, use OEM parts to ensure they meet
                    manufacturer's requirements and federal standards.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Upholstery Care and Cleaning Recommendations</title>
            <para>The upholstery vendor has supplied a list of solvents that are safe to use when cleaning the
                upholstery. These solvents, if properly used, will not harm the finish of the material. They are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Denatured Ethyl Alcohol</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VM&#38;P Naphtha</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Odorless Mineral Spirits</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Isopropyl Alcohol</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Recommended Cleaning Instructions</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash with mild soap and hot water to remove ordinary dirt, grime, etc.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Stubborn stains should be cleaned with alcohol. Odorless Mineral Spirits or VM&#38;P
                    Naphtha can be used to remove paint, tar, gum, shoe polish, etc. if alcohol does not remove the
                    stain.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Isopropyl Alcohol and Denatured Alcohol are specifically recommended for cleaning
                    stubborn dirt and stains.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Never clean upholstery with polish remover, Graffiti Eater&#174; strong caustic or
                    acidic agents or any cleaners with active solvents like MEK, Tolual, gasoline, etc.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_51.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
