<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Step Well Tread Plates</title>
        <para>The step well assembly and step tread plates are removable. The step well tread plates should be checked
            for excessive wear and/or damage on a regular basis. If wear on the step tread is discovered, the section
            should be replaced immediately.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The step treads are secured utilizing mounting screws and an adhesive to secure the tread to
                the step well assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the six mounting screws in the step tread, loosen and remove the screws, and remove
                step tread panel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47004133" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004133.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 133. Step Well Tread Plates</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. STEP WELL ENTRY COURTESY LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. STEP WELL TREAD COVERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STEP WELL TREAD MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After removing the step tread, remove any adhesive and sealer along the outside surfaces of
                the area where the tread was removed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the tread panel at the entrance to the center isle and adjacent to the driver
                platform, locate the six mounting screws securing the edge trim piece at the joint between the center
                isle flooring and the entrance panel to be removed. Loosen and remove the trim strip mounting screws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the 4 driver seat mounting bolts and nuts securing the driver seat to the floor and
                entrance tread panel. Loosen and remove the mounting bolts with an assistant under the bus to remove the
                lock nuts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and remove the engine cover mounting bolts along the rear edge of the engine cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the remaining 2 mounting screws from edge trim at the engine cover to the step
                well.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the seal along the edge of the tread panel at the top step.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the entrance panel step tread.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove and clean any adhesive on the floor panels used to secure the entrance tread panel.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_97.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_99.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
