<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - IC BUS SERVICE MANUAL - BUS BODY CONSTRUCTION - BODY PANEL
        REMOVAL PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
        <title>BODY PANEL REMOVAL PROCEDURE</title>
        <para>All body panel joints are assembled with mechanical fasteners. Each joint is designed in such a way that
            it is imperative to replace all body panels and fasteners with OEM equipment. All body panels are required
            to meet federal standard FMVSS 221. This standard establishes that all body panels must meet 60% joint
            strength requirements. Because of this standard and International design, it is very difficult to remove
            certain body panels. The procedure below will simplify what is required to replace damaged body panels, in
            most conditions. Only trained technicians should perform the repair work.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all rivets from the damaged panel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f4700129">Figure 27</hotlnk>). The rivets can be removed by using a large chisel and a
                #10 drill bit. Once the head or cap of the rivet has been removed, the drill bit can be used to drill
                the sleeve of the rivet out of the body panel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f4700130">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Before the body panel is totally removed, notice how the panels are overlapped. It is
                    important that the body panel be installed the same way it was removed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">It may be necessary to remove rub rails, depending on the location of the damage (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f4700131">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Use procedure 1 above to perform this task.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f4700129" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g4700129.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 27. Remove Rivet Head</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f4700130" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g4700130.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Drilling Out Rivet Hole</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f4700131" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g4700131.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 29. Remove Rub Rail</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the area to be repaired. Clean and treat any metal if required. If the replacement
                panel has optional equipment, such as a luggage box compartment or a skirt-mounted air conditioner, the
                cut-out modification should be made to the replacement panel prior to the initial installation.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
