<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Roof Mounted Escape Hatch</title>
        <para>All roof hatches installed are designed to provide years of reliable service with a minimum of
            maintenance. All components are corrosion resistant with lifetime finishes, and moving parts are Teflon
            coated to eliminate the need for lubrication. Use of lubricants, paints or other coatings - such as graffiti
            deterring sprays - is not recommended on roof hatches. The alarm switch should be inspected daily for proper
            operation. The audible warning buzzer should activate when the hatch door is open, with the ignition switch
            "on". The instructional decal to open the hatch should be near the release handle at all times.
        </para>
        <para>If the roof hatch is damaged in any manner, removal and replacement must be undertaken.</para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secure scaffold assembly and safety restraints or
                    equivalent equipment when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant
                    should be present during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the roof hatch, locate the roof hatch assembly interior trim collar. Locate the
                trim caps covering the mounting screws around the perimeter of the interior trim ring.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47005117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005117.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 117. Roof Hatch Interior Mounting Ring</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">INTERIOR HATCH MOUNTING SCREW COVER CAPS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EMERGENCY HATCH ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HATCH EXIT ACTIVATION HANDLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the cap covers.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting screws securing the trim ring to the ceiling and roof hatch
                assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and disconnect the electrical harness connection for the hatch open buzzer
                indicator.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the top of the roof section, locate the rivet cap covers around the outside perimeter of
                the roof hatch assembly.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47005118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005118" filename="../figg47/G47005118.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 118. Emergency Roof Hatch Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HATCH EXIT ACTIVATION HANDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HATCH WEATHER SEAL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HATCH ROOF ASSEMBLY MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HATCH HOLD OPEN CYLINDERS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the caps that cover the hatch mounting screws. Loosen and remove the hatch mounting
                screws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the screws removed, lift the escape hatch assembly from the roof section.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check for sealer material on the surface of the bus roof around the hatch assembly
                opening.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove any sealer or gasket material around the opening and clean the surface prior to
                installation of the roof hatch assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_50.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_52.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
