<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Driver Seat Belts</title>
        <para>The standard driver seat belt assembly is a three point lap and shoulder harness assembly, with retractor.
            The shoulder harness and the shoulder harness mounting assembly are attached to the structural pillar at the
            rear of the driver side sliding side window. The lap connection is mounted to the driver's floor riser
            assembly. The lap connector assembly is bolted through the floor utilizing grade eight structural bolts and
            lock nuts and washers.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The seat belt should be considered to have a limited life and must be replaced as needed
                    throughout the life of the vehicle. The belts must be inspected for needed care and maintenance
                    every 20,000 miles or more often if exposed to severe environmental or vocational conditions. All
                    belts should be replaced at least every 5 years. Failure to maintain the seat belts could weaken the
                    system, resulting in personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To replace the shoulder harness assembly, locate the shoulder harness mounting bolts on the
                driver side sliding window pillar. Remove the bolt cap covers.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003151" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003151.webp" filename="../figg47/g47003151.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 151. Driver Shoulder Harness Mounting Bolts</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER WINDOW REAR PILLAR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">SHOULDER HARNESS ATTACHMENT CLIP MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">SHOULDER HARNESS ATTACHMENT CLIP BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HARNESS AND LAP BELT PLASTIC COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">MOUNTING BOLTS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">LOCK WASHERS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">LOWER SHOULDER HARNESS / LAP BELT MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the three mounting bolts and remove the shoulder harness assembly from the pillar at
                the rear of the driver side sliding window.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the lower left hand lap belt connector, and mounting bolts on the left hand side of
                the driver seat cushion base.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the lap clip assembly, locate the mounting bolt on the driver seat riser assembly.
                With an assistant securing the lock nut and washer from under the riser assembly, loosen and remove the
                lap clip assembly mounting bolt. (On suspension seats the right hand latch assembly is mounted to the
                seat.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the lap clip assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the floor mounted attaching point for the driver seat belt assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f47003152" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g47003152.webp" filename="../figg47/g47003152.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                     scalefitheight="408px"/>
            <caption>Figure 152. Driver Seat Belt Floor Attachments</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT ATTACHMENT BRACKET MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT MOUNTING WASHERS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT ASSEMBLY MOUNTING NUTS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT ATTACHMENT BRACKET</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT ASSEMBLY MOUNTING BOLTS</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT ASSEMBLY FLOOR MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT BELT MOUNTING ASSEMBLY PLASTIC COVER</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER SEAT BELT LAP LATCH ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER SEAT BELT LAP LATCH ASSEMBLY FLOOR MOUNTING WASHER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the assistant below the floor, loosen and remove the seat belt floor attachment bolt.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the seat belt attachment assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When replacing the shoulder harness and lap belt assembly, replace both parts at the same
                time. Do not mix and match shoulder harness and lap assemblies as failure could occur if parts are
                mismatched.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_77.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_79.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
