<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FE 300 BUS BODY COMPONENTS - Exterior Body Repair - Install</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Install</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Instructional and warning decals must be re-installed on emergency doors, windows, etc. when
                        repairs are performed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rivet Replacement</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a 1/4" diameter replacement rivets of suitable length.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">An industrial quality rivet gun is recommended to properly set rivets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the rivets as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal all overlapped joint seals with yellow sealer. Allow to dry before painting.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Panel</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Replacement panels are not pre-punched. Drilling may be required for rivet installation and
                        alignment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Install the replacement panel with the overlap in the same direction of the panel that was previously
                removed.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the panel in the same location as the original part.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a heavy duty reversible drill and #10 drill bit to ream out rivet holes in the
                    replacement panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert #12 screws to secure panel in position until all rivet holes are drilled for
                    rivets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install 3/16" HUCK MAGNA LOCK pop rivet.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal all overlapped joint seals with yellow sealer. Allow sealer to dry before
                    painting.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>End Cap Replacement</title>
            <para>The end caps on the front and rear of the bus body are replaceable. Care should be taken in the
                process or removal and installation of the assemblies.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secured scaffold assembly and safety restraint
                        when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant should be present
                        during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing end caps, some interior panels are required to be removed to drill pilot holes
                        through the roof bows, for the end cap attachment process.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When replacing the front cap assembly, the driver bulkhead compartment and any equipment mounted on it
                will have to be removed to access the roof bow assembly.
            </para>
            <para>This includes:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Optional defroster fan assemblies.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>First aid kits and Body fluid clean-up kits.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Driver interior rear view mirror and sun visor (if applicable).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exterior light check system (if applicable).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The forward ceiling panel or rear depending on end cap being replaced.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Any other items that may be an option that would be mounted on the driver overhead bulkhead.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the applicable interior items removed, mount the forward end cap on the roof
                    assembly and header assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert bolts in the lower forward edge and corners of the end cap assembly. Check the
                    fit and alignment with the roof panels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the inside front section of the bus, drill through the roof bow and roof panel
                    holes, through the end cap assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the roof bow holes drilled, prior to installing pilot rivets, install sealer
                    adhesive along the existing roof panel and under the rear edge of the end cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install pilot rivets across roof bow to ensure alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Beginning at the front corner over the windshield install rivets through the new end cap
                    into header assembly and side section over driver window frame and entry door frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the remainder of roof bow rivets as required, check joint seals at end cap and
                    front roof panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If end cap seats properly, re-install interior bulkheads, and equipment that may have
                    been removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the front windshield assembly (see windshield installation).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the end cap marker light and connect marker light harness plugs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal all seams prior to paint.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If bus is equipped with glass destination board, install the glass panel and seal.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_109.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_111.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
