<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RE 200, RE 300 BUS BODY COMPONENTS - Maintenance - Heaters and Accessories</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="10">
        <title>Heaters and Accessories</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>All heating systems used in the vehicles are hot water type. This type system depends on the vehicle's
                engine to generate heat from the engine coolant or antifreeze. The engine coolant is pumped through the
                heater hoses, then to the heaters. The primary heating system is plumbed in a "series water flow"
                system. In this type of system, the heater coolant supply hose is routed to each heater and returns to
                the engine after exiting the last heater in the system.
            </para>
            <para>Heaters are made up of tube and fin type coils. When the coolant flows through the coils, the blowers
                move air across the fins of the coil and pick up the heat from the coolant.
            </para>
            <para>This section is for the repair and maintenance of the bus interior heaters. It is advised that caution
                be taken during any repairs or maintenance to the heater system and that the recommended procedures as
                defined in the manufacturer's instruction manual be followed.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>School Bus Heaters and Controls</title>
            <para>The heater controls are located directly to the right of the driver position, and below the right wing
                switch panel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47005209" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005209.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 209. Bus Main Heater</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">MAIN BUS HEATER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ENTRY STEPS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Step Well Heater (Main Heater)</title>
            <para>The main heater is located in the step well area at the bus entry and is controlled from the driver
                environmental and climate control panel located between the driver right wing lower control panel. The
                auxiliary heaters are controlled from the driver left switch panel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47005210" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005210.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 210. Main Heater Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">STEP WELL HEATER FACE PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">GLOVE BOX STORAGE COMPARTMENT</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">PASSENGER ENTRY STEP WELL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Under Seat Heaters</title>
            <para>The under seat heaters are located along the driver side of the bus in various locations depending on
                the length of the bus body. The heaters are located under a passenger seat and protected by a screened
                cover to protect them from damage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47005211" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005211.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 211. Under Seat Heaters</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">PASSENGER SEAT (TYPICAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">SEAT CHAIR MOUNTING RAIL</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">UNDER SEAT HEATER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Heater and Control</title>
            <figure id="f47005212" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005212.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005212.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 212. Driver Heater</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER SUPPLY LINE TO AUXILIARY HEATERS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">DRIVER HEATER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">AUXILIARY HEATER RETURNS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">WHEEL WELL COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The driver heater is located along the floor line below the driver left wing switch panel. The heater
                controls for the driver heater are located on the driver left wing switch panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>It is recommended that the heating system be inspected annually. However, more critical areas, such as
                around the engine, should be inspected on a regular basis. Filters should be removed and cleaned
                regularly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heaters and Accessories</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Heater Coils</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The heater coils are most efficient when the coils, fins and air flow passages are
                        kept clean and free of dirt and dust. The coils should be cleaned with a soft flow compressed
                        dry air or vacuum and a soft brush. Damaged fins should be straightened to prevent air flow
                        restrictions.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Hoses</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All heater hoses should be inspected for kinks and chafing that will cause failure.
                        Hoses should be replaced when cracks or permanent distortions are found.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Hoses and clamps should be checked regularly. Hoses may appear in good condition on
                        the outside, but the inside may be partially deteriorated. If there are any doubts about the
                        condition of the hoses, replacements should be made. Clamps should be inspected to ensure they
                        are strong enough to hold a tight connection.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Motors/Switches/Blowers and Fans</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Motors are essentially maintenance free and do not require any lubrication or
                        cleaning. However, excessive vibration caused by damaged blowers, wheels, and fans can cause
                        motor damage.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Switches are maintenance free, but can be damaged by water and loose wire
                        connections. Loose wires cause the component to require more amperage than normal. Inspect on a
                        regular basis.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Defroster fans can be mounted on the bulkhead above the driver. The fans should be
                        kept clean of dirt and dust. The metal cage can be removed for blade cleaning. Bend the metal
                        lock clamps to remove the metal cage.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Antifreeze</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The antifreeze mixture of the coolant system is a 50/50 mixture of antifreeze and
                        water. The mixture will protect the unit to -40 degrees F. For added protection in colder
                        climates, refer to the engine coolant section.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <para>Typically when a school bus does not have heat or air flow, several steps should be taken to eliminate
                the problem. Use the steps below as a guide to problem solving.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Use the following procedure to remove the pressure-type cap from the radiator. Always allow
                        the engine to cool first. Wrap a thick, heavy cloth around the cap. Push down, loosen cap slowly
                        to the first notch position; then pause a moment. This will avoid possible scalding by hot steam
                        or water, which can result in injury and/or property damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">No Heat from the Engine</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the heater hose gate valves. Make sure they are open (supply and return).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f47005213" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g47005213.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 213. Heater Hose Gate Valves</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the coolant level. Make sure the coolant system is full and flowing.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Touch the heater hoses and feel for heat at the engine supply hose.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the heater hose routing for kinked hose that could block coolant flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the booster pump is operating correctly if present.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Open the bleeder valve and check for air in the heater hose (air lock).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check engine operating temperature gauge and compare to air flow from heaters.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the butterfly valve and actuating cable for proper operation.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">No Air Flow from Heater Vents or Ducts</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the circuit breaker or fuse.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the switch.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the blower motor.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the resistor.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the harness connections for an open circuit.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repair any items that are not functioning as required.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater / Defroster and Blower Motor Access Procedures</title>
            <para>Each blower assembly has a resistor that controls the speed of the rotor. The defroster / step switch
                is a three-speed switch with a three-post resistor. When checking for speed variation, check all three
                speeds. Use a multi-meter to check the resistor. Refer to the IC Bus Troubleshooting Guide.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Access Main Front Heater / Defroster Blower Motors and Resistors Assembly</title>
            <para>To access the driver / main heater assemblies use the following steps:</para>
            <figure id="f47005214" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47005214.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005214.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 214. Access Main Front Heater</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">MAIN HEATER COIL ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">MAIN HEATER COVER PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">COVER PLATE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HEATED ASSEMBLY BODY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Driver Heater Filter</emph>
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove all surface mounting screws.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove lower return screws.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove driver's foot warm duct.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove mounting screws for driver left switch panel and storage compartment.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lift panel away from heater assembly.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Auxiliary / Midship Heater Motor Access</title>
            <para>To gain access the auxiliary heater motor or resistors, use the following steps.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The auxiliary and/or midship heaters may vary in location. The rear auxiliary heaters
                    when used with the wheel chair access door may be a vertically wall mounted assembly. The under seat
                    heaters will be mounted under the standard passenger seat assembly. Depending on the type service
                    the seat may or may not require removal.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the passenger seat above the heater assembly.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Flip the seat cushion up by adjusting the seat clip.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the heater cover panel mounting screws in the center.</para>
                    <figure id="f47005215" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g47005215.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005215.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 215. Under Seat Heater Access</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">UNDER SEAT HEATER ASSEMBLY TOP COVER PLATE</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">UNDER SEAT HEATER ASSEMBLY BODY</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">UNDER SEAT HEATER LOWER COVER PLATE</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER MOTOR HARNESS CONNECTION</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the screws that secure the heater to the floor.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pull the heater panels apart, exposing the internal parts.</para>
                    <figure id="f47005216" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic id="g47005216" filename="../figg47/G47005216.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="392px" scalefitheight="392px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 216. Under Seat Heater Core Removal</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER CORE</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">CORE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">UNDER SEAT HEATER BODY ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER FAN</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER MOTOR MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER MOTOR</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">RHEOSTATS</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER BOTTOM COVER</callout1>
                            <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER HARNESS CONNECTIONS</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the heater motor and disconnect the wire leads from the resistor.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the motor casing nuts that secure the motor to the shroud.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the fan from the motor shaft by using a small Allen wrench and turning the
                        set screw counter-clockwise.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Step Well Heater Assembly</title>
            <para>To access the step well heater assembly, check for optional components that may be existing and have
                to be removed to gain access to the step well heater.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Filter Remove</emph>
                </para>
                <para>To remove, clean or change step well heater filter use the following procedure:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the 3 filter plate mounting screws.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Loosen and remove mounting screws.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the filter cover plate.</para>
                        <figure id="f47005217" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g47005217.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005217.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 217. Filter Remove</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER FILTER</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER FRONT COVER PLATE</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">FILTER ACCESS COVER MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">FILTER ACCESS COVER</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER BODY ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the filter assembly.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>To install filter, reverse Steps 1 through 3.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Remove Step Well Heater Blower Assembly</emph>
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the optional assist handrail (if applicable).</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the fire extinguisher and mounting bracket (if applicable)</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the mounting screws along the lower edge of passenger entry dash panel.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Loosen and remove the mounting screws on face plate (cover weldment).</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Loosen and remove the defroster hose clamps attaching defroster hose to front face
                            plate.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Disconnect the harness plug connection to dual wheel blower assembly (if blower is to be
                            removed).
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Loosen and remove the five dual wheel blower mounting screws attaching the blower assembly
                            to the case weldment. Remove the dual wheel blower assembly.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f47005218" figsize="pg-wide">
                            <graphic id="g47005218.webp" filename="../figg47/G47005218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 218. Heater Coil and Blower Removal</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">URETHANE INSULATOR</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER CORE</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER ASSEMBLY BODY</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER RHEOSTAT SWITCH</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER FAN ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER MOTOR HARNESS CONNECTIONS</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">BLOWER MOTOR MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER CORE ACCESS PLATE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER CORE ACCESS PLATE</callout1>
                                <callout1 type="arabic">HEATER CORE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Heater Coil Removal</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The supply lines to and from the step well heater coil should be closed, prior to removal
                        procedure.
                    </para>
                    <para>Follow the procedures above to access the heater coil. To remove the heater coil:</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Locate the four mounting screws on the coil assembly bracket. Loosen and remove the
                            mounting screws.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Partially remove the heater coil assembly to gain access to the hose clamp connection to
                            the supply and return lines.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the coil gasket.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the heater coil.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting Chart</title>
            <table id="t4700301" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Heater Troubleshooting</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.92*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.08*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Application</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Troubleshooting Suggestion</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Hose not warm to the touch.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check heater cut-off valves (open) to make sure they are open. Check the butterfly
                                    valve for proper operation.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cold air flow from heaters.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check coolant level and hoses for indications of coolant flow.</para>
                                <para>Check for kinks and air blockage.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No air flow from heater.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check blower and motor switch.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Blower motor has one speed only.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check wiring and switch connection.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Poor water circulation.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check booster pump and hose routing.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Air in the heater hose system.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove the surge tank cap, fill tank, start engine, open valves, bleed heater at
                                    bleeder valve.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fluid Capacity</title>
            <table id="t4700302">
                <title>Fluid Capacity</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.23*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Application</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Volume / Cu .In.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Main Heater</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>84.35</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Driver Heater</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>71.46</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Auxiliary 1 Fan</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>47.31</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Auxiliary 2 Fan</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>91.69</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Heater Hose 1 Ft.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>.17</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Upholstery Care and Cleaning Recommendations</title>
            <para>The upholstery vendor has supplied a list of solvents that are safe to use when cleaning the
                upholstery. These solvents, if properly used, will not harm the finish of the material. These solvents
                include:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Denatured Ethyl Alcohol</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VM&#38;P Naphtha</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Odorless Mineral Spirits</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Isopropyl Alcohol</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Recommended Cleaning Instructions</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash with mild soap and hot water to remove ordinary dirt, grime, etc.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Stubborn stains should be cleaned with alcohol. Odorless Mineral Spirits or VM&#38;P
                    Naphtha can be used to remove paint, tar, gum, shoe polish, etc. if alcohol does not remove the
                    stain.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Isopropyl Alcohol and Denatured Alcohol are especially recommended for cleaning stubborn
                    dirt and stains.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Never clean upholstery with polish remover, Graffiti Eater, strong caustic or acidic
                    agents or any cleaners with active solvents like MEK, Tolual, gasoline, etc.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_110.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_112.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
