<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Driver Seat Bulkhead / Passenger Crash Barrier</title>
        <para>The driver seat bulkhead or passenger crash barriers are located each side, forward of the first row of
            passenger seats. Additional barriers may be specified at the emergency exit doors or wheelchair access door
            (if specified). The barrier at the front curb side passenger seat may equipped with an assist rail. To
            remove the barrier the assist rail would have to be removed first. The barrier structure is a chair rail
            mounted barrier unless otherwise specified. To remove the barrier:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the mounting bolts on the inboard floor attachment. The bolts are secured through the
                floor assembly to the underside of the floor structure. An assistant may be required to loosen and
                remove the lock washer and nuts from the foot of the barrier assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the barrier mounting bracket along the chair rail on the bus wall.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f47006232" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/g47006232.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Figure 232. Crash barrier Mounting Bolts</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>A. CRASH BARRIER FLOOR MOUNTING ASSEMBLY (DRIVER SIDE CRASH BARRIER FLOOR MOUNTING SHOWN)
                    <callout2>1. CRASH BARRIER PANEL ASSEMBLY</callout2>
                    <callout2>6. CRASH BARRIER FLOOR MOUNT PLATE</callout2>
                    <callout2>7. FLOOR MOUNT PLATE MOUNTING NUTS AND LOCK WASHERS</callout2>
                    <callout2>8. FLOOR MOUNTING PLATE MOUNTING BOLTS</callout2>
                </callout1>
                <callout1>B. CHAIR RAIL MOUNTING ASSEMBLY (PASSENGER SIDE CRASH BARRIER CHAIR RAIL MOUNT SHOWN FOR
                    CLARITY)
                    <callout2>1. CRASH BARRIER PANEL ASSEMBLY</callout2>
                    <callout2>2. CRASH BARRIER CHAIR RAIL MOUNTING BRACKET</callout2>
                    <callout2>3. CHAIR RAIL BARRIER BRACKET MOUNTING NUTS AND LOCK WASHERS</callout2>
                    <callout2>4. CHAIR RAIL SECTION</callout2>
                    <callout2>5. CHAIR RAIL SEAT MOUNTING BOLTS</callout2>
                </callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and loosen the three (3) mounting bolts, nuts and lock washers on the barrier
                mounting bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the crash barrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">In some applications road triangles or other optional equipment may be mounted on the
                barrier directly behind the driver position. These items should be removed prior to removing the driver
                side crash barrier.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Inspect and tighten all seat and barrier mounting hardware attachments. This should be performed
                    at 30 to 45 day intervals. The seat leg bolts require 19-20 lbf-ft of torque.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_138.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_140.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
