<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Street Side Stop Signs</title>
        <para>To remove street side stop signs located on the side of the bus body below driver side window, or the
            optional rear driver side body mounted stop arm or sign, follow the procedure as described. Stop sign lights
            may vary according to the requirements as specified by the municipality or school district. The optional
            lights may be either strobe or L.E.D. type.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If only replacement bulbs are needed in the stop arm sign, the lens should be removed and
                bulb replaced. Replace bulbs with the proper style and bulb designation as required by the manufacturer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the entire stop arm assembly, locate the two front mounting screws on the swing
                arm bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f47006189" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006189.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 189. Stop Arm Assembly Front Mounting Screws</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. STOP ARM FORWARD MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. STOP ARM SIGN ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>3. STOP ARM REAR MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the lower screw, then loosen the upper screw.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect cable pull on the sign assembly and remove the cotter pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Swing the sign to the open position. Locate the rear mounting screws on the swing sign
                assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the upper and lower screws, then remove the lower screws.</para>
            <figure id="f47006190" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006190.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="288px"/>
                <caption>Figure 190. Rear Stop Arm Mounting Screws (Optional Sign Assembly)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REAR STOP ARM SIGN ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. STOP ARM SIGN BACKING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STOP ARM MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant holding the assembly, remove the upper mounting screws.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the stop sign / arm assembly harness plug and remove the stop sign / arm
                assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_105.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_107.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
