<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Under Body Compartments</title>
        <para>The luggage boxes or underbody compartments are located along the lower line of the body and attached to
            the floor structure flange sections. The front face of the compartment door frame is on the side sheet and
            attached with mounting screws (
            <hotlnk document="s47003_6.xml" xrefid="f4700331">Figure 31, Item 2</hotlnk>). The luggage compartment has
            luggage box hanger brackets attached to the rear of the compartment upper surface with a "J" clip assembly
            clipped to the frame rail upper flange. The luggage box mounting brackets are welded to the rear wall of the
            luggage compartment. The upper flanges of the luggage compartment are spot welded to the floor structure
            lower flange. The number of lug box mounting brackets may vary depending on the overall length of the
            compartment.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the under body storage / luggage box compartment, place jack stand supports under
                the compartment in preparation for compartment removal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prior to removing the underbody luggage compartment the compartment door may be removed.
                (See Steps 11-14 below.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With a grinder carefully grind the spot welds at the compartment top flanges and floor
                structure lower flange.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With all the welds removed check the floor structure flange for undercoating or other
                debris. Make sure the flange surface is clean and smooth.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the mounting screws along the face frame of the compartment door.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting screws.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the front face plate of the luggage compartment.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f47003127" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g47003127.webp" filename="../figg47/g47003127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 127. "J" Clip Mounting</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">COMPARTMENT FASTENING ATTACHMENT BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">"J" CLIP WITH REINFORCING</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">TOP OF FRAME RAIL (DRIVER SIDE SHOWN)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the luggage box hanger brackets and "J" clip mounting bolts and nuts at the rear of
                the compartment.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the luggage box "J" clip attachment mounting nuts and bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant lower the compartment support jack stands and remove compartment from bus
                body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <title>Under Body Compartment Door Removal</title>
        </para>
        <para>The under body luggage compartment door can be removed without removal of the entire under body
            compartment. The under body compartment door hinge is a single piece extruded rubber hinge that runs the
            full length of the door opening.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the underbody compartment door, unlatch the door lock mechanism and swing door
                upward.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant, slide the door assembly from rubber extruded door hinge. Remove the door
                when the hinge and the door have been disconnected.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The hinge may then also be removed from the compartment frame extrusion by sliding the hinge
                out of the extrusion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47003128" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g47003128.webp" filename="../figg47/g47003128.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="232px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 128. Under Body Compartment Hinge Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">UPPER SIDE HINGE SECTION (BODY)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">LOWER SIDE HINGE SECTION (DOOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">RUBBER HINGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the rubber extruded door hinge for cracks or breaks and replace if necessary.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_56.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003_58.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
