<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Rear Window Emergency Exit</title>
        <para>The RE school bus utilizes a rear window emergency exit assembly. The emergency exit window is located
            behind the davenport seat and above the rear engine compartment. The window is a push out type window
            assembly with a securing latch on the curb side vertical frame. The latch mechanism is connected to the door
            or window ajar warning system at driver location. The window uses two gas shock type window openers located
            at each vertical frame of the exit window. To remove the rear emergency exit window follow the procedure as
            outlined below.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secure scaffold assembly and safety restraints or
                    equivalent equipment when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant
                    should be present during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release the window latch on the curb side vertical frame.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant holding the window in the open position, locate the gas shock cylinder
                mounting bracket screws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the bracket mounting screws.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the opposite side of the emergency exit window.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the gas spring assemblies.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and remove the trim ring mounting screws.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the window trim ring.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the rear emergency exit window.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_96.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005_98.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
