<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - IC BUS SERVICE MANUAL - OPERATION - PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">WORK SAFELY - FOLLOW THESE RULES</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Proper service techniques and repair procedures are necessary for reliable and safe operation of all
            vehicles as well as the safety of the personnel performing the work. This service manual provides normal and
            effective methods for accomplishing repair and service work. With the many variations in procedures and
            techniques and the skill level of the individual doing the work, the service manual cannot anticipate all
            variations and furnish cautions and directions.
        </para>
        <para>The following list contains some general precautions the technician should follow when servicing the
            vehicle to avoid the possibility of personal injury or property damage:
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>1. Always use safety stands in conjunction with hydraulic jacks or hoists. Do not rely on the jack
                    or hoist to carry the load.
                </para>
                <para>2. Always wear safety glasses when using a hammer, chisel or other tools that may cause chips to
                    fly.
                </para>
                <para>3. Keep work area organized and clean. Clean immediately oil or spills of any kind. Keep tools and
                    parts off the floor. Eliminate situations, which could result in slip-and-fall personal injury
                    accidents.
                </para>
                <para>4. Use a safety catch on all hoist hooks to reduce the possibility that a load could slip off the
                    hook.
                </para>
                <para>5. When using an acetylene torch, always wear welding goggles and gloves. Keep a properly charged
                    fire extinguisher within easy reach. Be sure the acetylene and oxygen tanks are separated by a metal
                    shield and are chained to the cart. Do not weld or heat areas near fuel tanks or fuel lines and
                    utilize proper shielding around hydraulic tanks or hydraulic lines.
                </para>
                <para>6. Always use a cab prop bar and/or other means to hold a tilt cab in the raised position. Never
                    rely on the vehicle hydraulic system to hold the cab in a raised position. If the cab were to come
                    down, it could cause serious or fatal injuries.
                </para>
                <para>7. When reassembling subassemblies, parts, hoses, hydraulic lines, fuel lines, wiring, etc. be
                    sure they are positioned properly for alignment and clearance with related parts to their original
                    setting and/or position.
                </para>
                <para>8. Electrical storage batteries give off highly flammable hydrogen gas when charging and continue
                    to do so for some time after receiving a steady charge. Do not under any circumstances allow an
                    electric spark or an open flame near the battery. Do not lay any tools across battery terminals as
                    this may result in a spark or short circuit, which may cause an explosion. Be careful to avoid
                    spilling any electrolyte on hands or clothing. Use protective clothing and goggles when working on
                    or filling batteries with acid.
                </para>
                <para>9. Be sure the ignition switch is always in the "OFF" position, unless otherwise required by the
                    procedure. Disconnect the battery ground cable when servicing the electrical system to avoid
                    electrical burns and damage to the vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>10. Always set the parking brake when working on a vehicle. Leave the transmission gear selector
                    in "NEUTRAL" with the parking brake applied (engine "ON" or "OFF") unless instructed otherwise for a
                    specific operation. Place wood blocks (4"x4" or larger) against the front and rear surfaces of the
                    tires to provide additional restraint from inadvertent vehicle movement.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>11. Hydraulic fluid escaping under pressure can have enough force to penetrate the skin. Hydraulic
                    fluid may also infect a minor cut or opening in the skin. If injured by escaping fluids, see a
                    doctor at once. Serious infection or reaction can result if medical treatment is not given
                    immediately.
                </para>
                <para>12. Do not attempt to repair or tighten hydraulic hoses that are under pressure or when the engine
                    is running. Cycle all hydraulic control valves to relieve all pressure before disconnecting lines or
                    performing other work on hydraulic systems. Make sure all connections are tight and hoses and lines
                    are in good condition before applying pressure to the system. To locate a leak under pressure, use a
                    small piece of cardboard or wood. Never use hands.
                </para>
                <para>13. When refueling, keep the hose and nozzle in contact with the metal of the fuel tanks to avoid
                    the possibility of an electric spark igniting the fuel. Do not overfill the fuel tank - overflow
                    creates fire hazard. Do not smoke when refueling. Never refuel when the engine is running.
                </para>
                <para>14. Always use a protective cage when inflating tires. Do not exceed recommended tire pressures.
                    On tubeless tires, do not inflate over 30 psi to seat the tire bead. Always check tire and rim
                    diameter to be sure they are identical. Never attempt to mount a tire on a rim where the tire and
                    rim are of different sizes.
                </para>
                <para>15. Use pullers to remove bearings, bushings, gears, cylinder sleeves, etc. when applicable. Use
                    hammers, punches and chisels only when absolutely necessary. Then, be sure to wear safety glasses.
                </para>
                <para>16. Never use trouble lights or electric powered tools that have cut and/or damaged cords or
                    plugs. Be sure all electric tools are properly grounded.
                </para>
                <para>17. Be careful when using compressed air to dry parts. Use approved air blow guns, do not exceed
                    30 psi, wear safety glasses or goggles and use proper shielding to protect everyone in the work
                    area.
                </para>
                <para>18. Do not wear rings, wrist watches or loose fitting clothing when working on vehicles. They
                    could catch on moving parts causing serious injury.
                </para>
                <para>19. Excessive or repeated skin contact with sealants or solvents may cause skin irritation. In
                    case of skin contact, remove sealant or solvent promptly by washing with soap and water.
                </para>
                <para>20. Never operate engine in closed areas. Exhaust gases, particularly carbon monoxide, may build
                    up. These gases are harmful and potentially lethal.
                </para>
                <para>21. On vehicles equipped with a locking differential, never run the engine with the transmission
                    in gear and a driven wheel still on the ground. The wheel still on the ground could cause the
                    vehicle to move.
                </para>
                <para>22. Keep hands clear of all moving parts.</para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>The above is only a partial list of safe work rules. Common sense and good judgment are always
                    necessary to avoid personal injury accidents.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
