<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Passenger Entry Door</title>
        <specpara>
            <para>The side exit door should be inspected daily for proper operation, as stated by the instruction decal.
                Inspect the door seal on each door for foreign debris and dirt accumulation from road film and other
                environmental factors. Over a period of time, door seal rubber can lose its elasticity and become
                brittle. A thin coat of lubricant such as Vaseline will restore the natural characteristics of the seal.
            </para>
        </specpara>
        <para>The passenger entry doors are a double door assembly, with mounting points in the upper and lower corners
            of each door. The standard entry doors are electrically operated. Disconnect the harness connection to the
            door operating mechanism prior to removing the doors, or set door control switch in panel over door to
            manual mode.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the drive arm mounting bolts at the top of each door.</para>
            <figure id="f47004106" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47004106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 106. Drive Arm Disconnect</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DOOR OPENER GEAR DRIVE PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DOOR OPENER DRIVE ARM MOUNTING BUSHING AND CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DOOR OPENER DRIVE ARM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting bracket bolts and remove the bushing and bracket from the
                door jam assembly. An assistant should be available to steady door when removing the lower mounting
                bracket and bushing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f47004107" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47004107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 107. Passenger Entry Door Pivot Bracket (Right Hand shown)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FORWARD PASSENGER ENTRY DOOR PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PIVOT BLOCK MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ENTRY STEP LOWER SUPPORT BAR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the door from the upper mounting hole opening.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set door down in secure out of the way area to avoid possible glass damage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the opposite side entry door.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_76.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_78.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
