<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Assist Handrails</title>
        <para>The assist handrails are located in the step well area and are mounted on the front seat crash barrier
            assembly. Handrails are also available as options and are mounted in the step well on the step well heater
            assembly (if equipped), or on the front plate assembly mounted to the right hand dash panel cover and
            attached to the bus cross beam assembly.
        </para>
        <para>To remove the standard entry assist rail:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the hex head mounting screw at the crash barrier panel hand rail attachment.</para>
            <figure id="f47004134" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004134.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 134. Assist Handrail Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ASSIST HANDRAIL CRASH BARRIER MOUNTING SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. STEP WELL ASSIST HANDRAIL MOUNTING BRACKETS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STEP WELL ASSIST HANDRAIL ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the hex head mounting screw.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the mounting screws on the lower step well handrail mounting brackets, two on each
                bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting screws, remove the assist handrail assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the stainless steel handrail from the lower mounting brackets, locate the set
                screw on the handrail assist mounting bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the set screw and remove the handrail.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the bus is equipped with the optional assist handrail, follow the same basic procedure as
                outlined in steps 3 through 7.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The top mounting bracket for the forward mounted handrail will be at attached with a
                mounting screw attachment to the forward dash vertical support bracket or the step well optional heater
                side cover plate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting screw and remove the forward assist handrail (if
                applicable).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_99.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_101.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
