<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CE 200 AND CE 300 BUS BODY COMPONENTS - Exterior Body Repair - Remove</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Remove</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fasteners</title>
            <para>The fasteners utilized in the manufacture and assembly of the bus body are mechanical type fasteners.
                Each joint is designed in a manner that it is imperative to replace all body panels and fasteners with
                OEM equipment. All body panels are required to meet federal standard F.M.V.S.S. 221. This standard
                establishes that all body panels must meet 60% joint strength requirements. Because of this standard and
                International design, it is very difficult to remove certain body panels. The following procedure will
                describe what is required to replace damaged body panels, in most conditions. Only trained technicians
                should perform the repair work.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all rivets from the damaged panels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Center punch all rivets in preparation for removal. This is important in order to
                    prevent damage to panels that over- or underlap damaged panels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Utilizing a heavy duty reversible drill and 17/64" diameter drill bit, drill through the
                    rivet head until rivet sleeve separates from the rivet head.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Panel Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all rivets from the damaged body panel. The rivets may be removed by using a
                    large chisel and a #10 drill bit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the head or cap of rivet removed, use drill to remove sleeve of the rivet out of
                    the body panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With rivets and sleeves removed from body panel, check panel overlap. New body panels
                    must be installed with same panel overlap as that of removed panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of some panels may require removal of body rub rails, depending on the location
                    of the damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If rub rails are to be removed, follow procedure for removing rivets.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>End Cap Remove</title>
            <para>When removing the front end cap, the exterior rear view mirrors and any electrical connections for
                mirrors must be removed.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">See mirror removal section of this manual for removal of exterior rear view mirrors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The windshield and side panels must also be removed prior to removing end cap rivets.
                    (Refer to windshield removal.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Following rivet removal procedure, remove as many rivets from end cap drip rail as
                    needed to free front end cap for removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_138.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_140.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
