<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Dash Board Panels, Cluster and Switch Panels</title>
        <para>The dash panel, switch panels and drivers storage panels are all constructed of injection molded composite
            material. All panels assemble together to make a clean fully functional assembly, enhancing visibility and
            ease of operation, with the ergonomically designed panels. All panels are removable for access to the
            components and assemblies in the driver control area (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f47006206">Figure 206</hotlnk>). To remove the dash panels follow the procedures as listed.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dash Panels</para>
            <figure id="f47006206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 206. Passenger Side Entry- Dash Panel Section</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PASSENGER SIDE ENTRY DASH COVER PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DEFROSTER DUCT OPENINGS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WINDSHIELD VERTICAL PANEL SEAL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PASSENGER ENTRY PANEL COVER TOP PANEL MOUNTING SCREW</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Beginning at the passenger entry door and step well, locate the dash panel mounting
                    bolts along the leading edge of the step well panel at the lower section of the windshield glass and
                    seal.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the panel mounting bolts.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the panel lower edge mounting screws the secure the panel to the entry panel or
                    step well heater panel (if equipped). Loosen and remove the mounting screws.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With the mounting screws and bolts removed, lift the step well panel cover upward and
                    out.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dash Panel / Cluster And Right Switch Panel</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate and remove the forward edge mounting bolts along the lower windshield seal.
                    Loosen and remove the mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Slide the driver side window forward section open to access the mounting screw at the
                    left hand corner of the dash panel assembly. Loosen and remove the mounting screw.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the right wing switch panel, locate and remove any optional equipment mountings
                    that may be mounted to the right wing switch panel; e.g., communication radio microphone (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006207">Figure 207</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006207" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006207.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 207. Right Wing Switch Panel Remove</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRIVER RIGHT WING PANEL BEZEL TRIM RING</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. RIGHT WING PANEL BEZEL AND COVER MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">To remove right wing switch panel trim bezel, locate the four mounting screws (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47006207">Fig. 207 Item 2</hotlnk>) attaching the switch panel and bezel assembly.
                    Loosen and remove.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the switch panel assembly and disconnect harness connections if necessary.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Prior to removing the instrument cluster, the steering column cover must be removed.
                    Locate the upper and lower column cover mounting screws.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the mounting screws and remove the steering column covers.</para>
                <figure id="f47006208" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006208.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 208. Cluster Attachment Mounting Screws</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CLUSTER BEZEL MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the cluster bezel assembly and remove the bezel.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the cluster mounting screws, loosen and remove.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Lift the instrument cluster out to access the harness connections. Disconnect the
                    instrument cluster harness and remove cluster.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Left Hand Driver Switch Panel And Storage Bin</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The left hand switch panel contains the operating controls for many of the bus interior
                    functions (
                    <hotlnk document="s47006_43.xml" xrefid="f4700662">Figure 62, Item 3</hotlnk>). The switch panel
                    assembly must be removed first.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006209" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 209. Heater Controls</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. LEFT WING SWITCH PANEL</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. TEMPERATURE CONTROL KNOB</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. ENVIRONMENTAL CONTROL PANEL MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. HEAT DIRECTIONAL CONTROL KNOB</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. FRESH AIR / RECIRCULATION CONTROL KNOB</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the heater, defroster, and recirculation control switches to the rear of the left
                    hand switch panel. Remove the control knobs for the heater controls.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the six left hand switch panel mounting screws.</para>
                <figure id="f47006210" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 210. Heat Control and Left Switch Panel Assembly</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRIVER LEFT WING SWITCH PANEL MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DRIVER LEFT WING SWITCH PANEL</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the panel screws.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Lift the switch panel out and disconnect necessary harnesses for removal of the switch
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Open the driver side storage compartment bin cover. Locate the mounting screws in the
                    bottom of the storage bin. Loosen and remove the mounting screws.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47006211" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47006211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 211. Driver Storage Bin</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRIVER LEFT PANEL STORAGE BIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. LEFT WING PANEL STORAGE BIN MOUNTING SCREWS (THREE OF SIX SHOWN IN BOTTOM OF
                            STORAGE BIN)
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the lower edge mounting screws mounting the panel to the driver's heater
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Locate the heater / defroster control harness and disconnect.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Lift and remove the left hand panel dash assembly and storage bin.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 12 volt power receptacle harness from the storage bin receptacle (if
                    applicable).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_124.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006_126.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
