<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CE 200 AND CE 300 BUS BODY COMPONENTS - INSTALL - Exterior Body Components</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="13">
        <title>Exterior Body Components</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This section describes the procedures required to install the exterior body components that may have
                already been removed. All necessary warnings and safety precautions remain in effect during these
                installation procedures.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Windshield Wiper Install</title>
            <para>Prior to installation of the windshield wiper assembly, check blades and washer fluid hoses for
                replacement.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the windshield wiper drive stud and mark previously located to help set alignment
                    of wiper arms.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47004170" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004170.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 170. Windshield Wiper Drive Stud</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. WINDSHIELD WIPER DRIVE STUD MOUNTING JAM NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. WINDSHIELD WIPER DRIVE STUD</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place windshield wiper arm on drive stud aligning the previously marked parts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting nut and hand tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the opposite side if both wiper arms have been removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the drivers position, turn the ignition key, and turn on the wiper switch on. Allow
                    at least one full cycle of wiper operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the wiper switch to the off position and allow the wipers to go to the park
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition key off. Go outside the bus and check the location of the wipers in
                    the parked position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check dimensions as specified in Figure 171.</para>
                <figure id="f47004171" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004171.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="408px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 171. Windshield Wipe Alignment Dimensions</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the location is correct, tighten the wiper arm retaining nut to the proper torque
                    value (See Torque chart).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the wiper arm is not in correct position, remove retaining nut, reposition wiper arm,
                    and check dimension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wiper arm retaining nut and torque to correct value.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace plastic cap on wiper arm assembly covering retainer nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect windshield washer fluid supply hoses at cowl and windshield wiper arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate the windshield wipers and washer to verify correct operation. If wipers contact
                    each other or the window frames during operation, or if they look close and might contact each other
                    or the windshield frame, adjust the wiper arm orientation as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Windshield Install</title>
            <para>Prior to windshield installation, the windshield glass should be inspected for cracks and or chips.
                The windshield fence structure and locator tabs should be inspected for any type of bends or damage that
                might create problems in seal mounting and/or possible leaks. The windshield seal should also be checked
                for breaks, cracks or any other deformity that might cause windshield leaks or improper fit.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always wear safety glasses and gloves to prevent accidents from occurring. Extreme care should
                        always be taken when handling glass and repair tools.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">An assistant is required during the installation of the three piece
                            windshield.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the 3 piece windshield:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the windshield mounting frame (fence) and mounting tabs for any bends or
                        distortion in the assembly. Straighten if necessary.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f47004172" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004172.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="248px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 172. Windshield "S" Seal Cross Section</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. WINDSHIELD GLASS SECTION</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. GLASS SEAT OPENING</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. LOCK LACE</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. WINDSHIELD "S" SEAL ASSEMBLY CROSS SECTION</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. WINDSHIELD FENCE MOUNTING ORIFICE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the windshield "S" seal for any cracks, breaks or deterioration. If found
                        replace "S" seal. Check the windshield glass for cracks or chips in the glass or the edges. If
                        the glass edge is chipped it should be ground smooth prior to installation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When handling glass avoid contacting the glass with anything that might chip or
                        crack the edges of the glass. Pressure on the glass will tend to concentrate at the chipped
                        areas, causing cracks. If the glass is cracked, do not install. Replace with a new section.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <title>Installation</title>
                </para>
                <para>For large applications such as the windshield center section, install the mounting seal on the
                    windshield frame around the opening.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the seal on the insert tabs and lower windshield mounting frame.</para>
                    <figure id="f47004173" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004173.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="248px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 173. Install Windshield Seal</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. WINDSHIELD "S" SEAL INSTALLATION- WING PANEL</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Spray a foam type window cleaner or soapy water solution on the windshield seal.
                        This will lubricate the seal and help in the installation of the windshield glass.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With an assistant, locate the windshield glass panel section from the padded work
                        stand and place in approximate position on the cowl assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With the technician and an assistant on the opposite side of the bus windshield
                        area, place the glass in the lower section of the windshield seal. Using a flat stock windshield
                        tool work the glass into the lower seal section.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align one side of the glass into the vertical seal section at the tee seal
                        connector. Recheck the for alignment on the tab assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using the flat stock tool, ensure the glass is in the position in the vertical
                        section. Use the same tool on the inside of the windshield to properly seat the glass in the
                        vertical section.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f47004174" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004174.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="248px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 174. Seating Glass In Seal</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. WINDSHIELD CENTER PANEL</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. WINDSHIELD LOWER SEAL SECTION</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With the assistant on the outside of the windshield glass, steady the assembly,
                        insert a 1/8" rope section in the glass seal around the upper section of the main glass panel.
                        Spray the glass again with a soapy solution to help insert the glass into the upper seal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The assistant from the outside should apply a steady pressure against the upper
                        portion of the center glass toward the windshield frame.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The technician using the glass tool should encapsulate the top corner of the
                        windshield glass on the fence (or frame), then with a constant, steady pulling motion on the
                        rope work his way across the top of the interior of the windshield glass, checking the glass is
                        seating in the seal as he pulls the rope. If the step is done properly the windshield should be
                        mounted in the seal on the windshield frame around the top and bottom and both ends of the
                        center panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With the windshield glass properly seated in the top and bottom frame, use the flat
                        stock tool and/or other appropriate glass tool as may be available to work the seal around the
                        opposite end of the vertical windshield seal.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f47004175" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004175.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                                 scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 175. Windshield Installation</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. ALIGNING SEAL AND GLASS ON UPPER MOUNTING FENCE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check both the interior and exterior of the windshield panel for any irregularities
                        in the seal that could cause a leaking condition.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <title>Side Panels / Wing Panels</title>
                </para>
                <para>Prior to installing side panel or wing glass, check the glass for cracks or chips.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align seal with windshield frame at wing panel area.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the wing or side panel glass at the top corner of the seal and align the
                        inboard edge in the vertical seal adjacent to the center windshield panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Spray the seal and glass with soapy solution to aid in installation of glass.</para>
                    <figure id="f47004176" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004176.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                                 scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 176. Inserting Wing Panel</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. WINDSHIELD FLAT TOOL WORKING SEAL PERIMETER</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. DRIVER WING PANEL GLASS</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using flat stock glass tool or other appropriate glass tool, work seal around the
                        outside edge of the wing panel glass. Pressure should be applied against glass to fit glass into
                        seal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Continue around the exterior perimeter of panel or wing glass until entire panel is
                        seated on window frame section.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Follow the same procedure on the inside of the wing panel ensuring the glass in
                        inserted in the seal assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for the opposite side wing panel (if necessary).</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <title>Windshield Lace / Lock Seal</title>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">The recommended windshield lace insertion tool : Lock Strip Straight Tool, Part
                        number 201-1127 from Sommer Maca.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <figure id="f47004177" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004177.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 177. Windshield Lock Lace Tool</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>A sufficient length of windshield lace should be on hand for installation. A single piece length
                    is required to fit the entire perimeter of the windshield opening. Two additional sections for the
                    vertical panels between the windshield and wing panels are required. Prior to installation find the
                    center of the lace perimeter section and place at the approximate center of the windshield seal at
                    the top of the windshield.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To install the lace rubber into the seal, use the lacing tool by threading the lace
                        rubber into the tool. Depending on the method used and the direction in which the lace is
                        installed will determine whether the tool is pushed or pulled while inserting the windshield
                        lace.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f47004178" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004178.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                                 scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 178. Windshield Lace Installation</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. WING PANEL GLASS</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. VERTICAL WINDSHIELD AND WING PANEL SEAL</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. LOCK LACE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">After installation of the surround lace, install the two remaining vertical pieces
                        between the panel glass sections and the center windshield panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A foam type glass cleaner or mild soapy solution and some water can be used to
                        lubricate the rubber seal. This will ease installation of the lace rubber.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the installation and clean off the surface of the glass, both inside and
                        outside the bus.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A pliable windshield seal may be used to seal the rubber and glass.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Side Rear View Mirror</title>
            <para>Check mirrors for cracks or any type of damage prior to installation. If the mirrors have a heater
                element option, check the wires and plug for breaks in the harness wire or cracks.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Beginning on the drivers side of the bus body, locate and align the mounting holes in
                    the mirror and bus body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the four mounting bolts (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_8.xml" xrefid="f4700410">Fig. 10, Item 3</hotlnk>) and hand tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the mirror has the optional mirror heater, locate the harness wire (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_8.xml" xrefid="f4700410">Fig. 10, Item 2</hotlnk>) and insert through the
                    grommet in the body section. Connect the mirror harness plugs in the appropriate harness connections
                    in the upper corner of the electrical compartment located under the drivers window on the exterior
                    of the bus.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mirror mounting bolts to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Enter the bus, open the drivers sliding window and adjust the mirror to the proper
                    settings.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger Side Rear View Mirror</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the passenger side rear view mirror (
                <hotlnk document="s47004_8.xml" xrefid="f4700411">Fig. 11</hotlnk>), check the mirrors for cracked
                mirror glass or any harness damage.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a step ladder at the passenger side of the bus body by the passenger entry
                    doors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes for the mirror support brackets (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_8.xml" xrefid="f4700411">Fig. 11, Item 1</hotlnk>) and hand tighten along
                    the header above the top of the windshield assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the mirror support bracket mounting holes with the header mounting holes, insert
                    the bracket mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mirror base mounting holes on the "A" pillar forward of the side entry door.
                    Align the mirror base with the mounting holes and insert the four mounting bolts. Hand tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the passenger side mirror support clip bracket to the mirror arm. Insert the
                    attachment bolt, washer and lock nuts as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the mirror position and tighten all mounting bolts to the required torque.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the mirror is equipped with optional heater element locate the mirror harness and
                    insert into body harness hole. Install grommet on mirror harness, and insert grommet in opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mirror heater element harness and plug in the mirror connectors. Replace the
                    "A" pillar cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the passenger side "A" pillar cover on the inside of the bus body. insert
                    mounting screws in pillar cover, tighten. Install "A" pillar plastic cap covers over mounting
                    screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check mirror for adjustment, adjust as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Warning Lights</title>
            <para>Replacement of the upper front warning lights on the face of the front end cap.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the hood forward. Using a step ladder to allow access to the end cap light
                    locations, insert the warning light wire harness through the grommet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the warning light plug into the harness plug and insert in body opening.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the grommet into bus end cap. Feed excess wire through grommet into the end
                    cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place warning light on end cap and align mounting holes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the warning light lens on the light assembly, insert the lens mounting screws and
                    tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for replacement of all other warning light assemblies on end
                    caps.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Destination Sign</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always wear eye protection and other safety equipment when handling glass to minimize the risk
                        of injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The back lit destination board if previously removed because of damage to the glass area should be
                replaced only with IC Corporation authorized replacement parts to ensure the proper fit and operation.
            </para>
            <para>To ease installation, the rubber gasket can be heated with a non-flame source (heat gun). At high
                temperatures, the rubber gasket is more pliable. Do not heat above 125 degrees Fahrenheit for longer
                than one and a half hours.
            </para>
            <para>Avoid contacting the glass with anything that may chip or crack the edges. Pressure on the glass will
                tend to concentrate at the chipped areas, causing cracks. If the glass is chipped, the edge should be
                ground smooth prior to installation.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the hood to forward position, cover engine components to protect from any dirt or
                    debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The glass destination sign is installed utilizing an "H" type glass seal. Locate the
                    seal to be installed and check the seal for breaks or cracks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For large installations such as the windshield glass, install the rubber gasket or seal
                    onto the flange of the glass opening. For smaller applications, such as the entrance door, the
                    rubber gasket should be located on the glass itself.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the hook end of the windshield installation tool into the seal and work the glass
                    into the opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the glass seated in the seal check the fit around the perimeter of the glass for
                    distortion or cracks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To install the lace rubber into the rubber gasket or seal, use the lacing tool by
                    threading the lace rubber into the tool and installing the rubber.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull the lace rubber around the gasket, feeding the lace rubber into the tool using a
                    hitching motion. This will help prevent the lace rubber form stretching.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A foam type class cleaner or a mild soap and some water can be used to lubricate the
                    rubber gasket. This will ease installation of the glass lace rubber.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the installation and clean off the surface of the glass.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal the rubber gasket and glass with a pliable windshield type sealant.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>D.O.T. Lights and Reflectors</title>
            <para>The D.O.T. reflectors mounted on the exterior of the body as required by F.M.V.S.S. must be replaced
                if cracked or broken.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To replace a damaged reflector, locate the mounting hole of the removed reflector (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_74.xml" xrefid="f47004102">Fig. 102, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screw through the center hole of the reflector and mounting hole in
                    the bus body. Tighten the mounting screw till snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Broken D.O.T. marker lights or lens must be replaced if broken or damaged.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the lens mounting hole, insert the lens mounting screw, and align with the
                    mounting hole on the marker light assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the marker light lens mounting screw.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the light assembly was broken and removed, locate the marker light mounting hole on
                    the bus body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the harness and plug in the new marker light connector. Insert the marker light
                    wire through the body grommet and insert the grommet in the body panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the marker light mounting hole with body mounting holes. Insert the mounting
                    screws and tighten. Replace the lens cover (see step 4).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vandal Lock</title>
            <para>The Vandal lock assembly is located at the front panel above the passenger side transition panel
                forward of the passenger entry door (if equipped).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the vandal lock assembly through the bus body panel, install the jam
                    nut and washer on the assembly stem. Allow extra length for mounting the exterior mounting nut and
                    washers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the vandal lock assembly from inside the bus body by sliding the assembly stem
                    through the opening in the body panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the exterior lock washer and threaded collar.</para>
                <figure id="f47004179" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004179.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 179. Vandal Lock Install</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. EXTERIOR JAM NUT LOCK WASHER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. EXTERIOR JAM NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SWITCH HANDLE MOUNTING SCREW</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside the bus slide the interior lock washer against the body panel. Tighten the
                    jam nut against the washer and body panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the vandal lock wiring leads to the harness connection (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_75.xml" xrefid="f47004104">Figure 104</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the assembly from outside the bus to ensure a snug tight fit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the dash panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes at the lower joint of the passenger entry dash panel and the
                    lower edge of the right wing switch panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the 2 dash panel mounting holes at the leading edge of the dash panel by the
                    bottom edge of the windshield assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the 2 dash panel mounting holes and insert the two mounting screws. Tighten the
                    mounting screws to the torque value required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting screws along the lower edge of the dash panel, insert the mounting
                    screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assist Steps</title>
            <para>The assist steps (
                <hotlnk document="s47004_13.xml" xrefid="f4700416">Fig. 16, Item 2</hotlnk>) are mounted each side of
                the bus body directly behind the front fender extension and below the transition panel.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the assist step body mounting holes and align the assist step assembly bracket
                    holes on the body holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the two mounting bolts through the bus body panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the lock nuts and washers behind the panel and tighten to the required torque
                    value.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger Entry Door</title>
            <para>Installation of the passenger entry doors may require the help of an assistant when aligning the pivot
                pins and blocks.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant, place the forward door in the upright position at the door opening.
                    Insert the upper pivot pin in the overhead header opening (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_112.xml" xrefid="f47004153">Figure 153</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the lower pivot block and slide on lower pivot pin, align pivot block mounting
                    holes with mounting holes in lower step door opening cross bar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolts in the pivot block and support bar (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_112.xml" xrefid="f47004153">Fig. 153, Item 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check door in position and pivot points, and ensure door swings freely.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the door mounting bracket attached to the door opener drive arm. Align the
                    bracket mounting holes with the mounting holes in the upper portion of door frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert two mounting bolts and tighten to required torque.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure on opposite door if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Fill Door</title>
            <para>Depending on the location of the fuel tank assembly the fuel door may vary in location. All fuel doors
                have a positive closure spring, and may be equipped with a latching device or keyed lock. Locate the
                opening where the fuel fill door assembly is to be installed.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the fuel fill door assembly over the opening in the bus body side panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the mounting holes in the fuel fill door assembly with those in the bus body side
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the six mounting screws in the fuel fill door assembly and tighten (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_78.xml" xrefid="f47004108">Fig. 108, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger Windows</title>
            <para>Passenger windows and related hardware are installed from the inside of the bus body. Reference Body
                Interior installation section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Exit Windows</title>
            <para>Emergency exit windows and related hardware are installed from the inside of the bus body. Reference
                Body Interior installation section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Emergency Exit Doors and Latches</title>
            <para>The rear emergency exit door is a flush mounted door assembly with interior recessed hinges.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the door assembly, check the door seal for cracks and or breaks in
                    the material. Replace if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant locate the emergency exit door in the bus body door opening.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the hinge assemblies on the inside of the door assembly. Rotate the door hinge
                    assemblies out and align with the hinge mounting plates on the inside of the door frame assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting bolts in the hinge assembly (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_80.xml" xrefid="f47004111">Fig. 111, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>) and hand
                    tighten. Open the door and close to check for door fit in the opening. Adjust the door assembly as
                    may be required. Tighten the hinge bolts, install the remaining hinge bolts, and torque to the
                    required value.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the alignment with the door latch assembly and the buzzer plunger switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the door is aligned and functional, install the plastic hinge covers on the interior
                    hinge assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the plastic covers, and align with mounting holes in bus
                    body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Roof Mounted Escape Hatch</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secured scaffold assembly and safety restraints
                        when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant should be present
                        during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Check the roof surface around the opening of the emergency roof hatch assembly. Make sure no sharp
                edges or foreign materials are present when installing sealer or the hatch assembly.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the roof area around the hatch opening prior to any installation procedure.</para>
                <figure id="f47004180" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004180.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 180. Emergency Roof Escape Hatch Opening</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. ROOF HATCH CUT OUT SECTION</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ROOF HATCH MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. ROOF PANEL OVERLAP SECTION</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the roof hatch assembly on the opening and align the hatch mounting holes with
                    the mounting holes in the roof section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply any sealer required to the roof or hatch assembly prior to fastening the hatch
                    assembly in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the emergency escape hatch in the opening.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the mounting holes in the hatch perimeter frame and the mounting holes in the roof
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using an industrial type rivet gun, insert the rivet in the mounting holes and secure
                    the hatch assembly to the roof structure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install plastic fastener covers over fasteners on the hatch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant around the outside perimeter of the hatch assembly at the roof line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect hatch open alarm switch harness to bus harness connectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the interior trim ring in the ceiling, insert mounting screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place plastic insert caps over the mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Chair Access Door</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the wheel chair access door, check the door seals for cracks or breaks in the door
                seal. Replace if necessary.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant place the access door in the door opening. Check the alignment of the
                    hinge mounting holes with the mounting holes in the bus body. Adjust the door as may be required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the door hinge mounting bolts and hand tighten. Recheck the door alignment and
                    seal for proper fit.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47004181" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004181.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="328px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 181. Wheel Chair Lift Access Door Hinges</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. ACCESS DOOR HINGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DOOR HINGE ATTACHMENT SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. ACCESS DOOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. DOOR FRAME HINGE MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. DOOR FRAME ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the door fits securely, tighten and torque door hinge mounting bolts to required
                    torque values.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the door latch alignment, ensure proper latching and locking.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the alarm buzzer assembly plunger for proper alignment and operation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Bumper Assembly</title>
            <para>An assistant is required for rear bumper installation.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant locate the bumper to the rear of the bus body and align the rear
                    mounting holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_83.xml" xrefid="f47004115">Fig. 115, Item 2</hotlnk>) on the bumper with
                    those on the rear frame bumper mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the upper mounting bolts through the bumper into the bumper mounting bracket.
                    Install the bumper mounting bolt nuts and washers on the mounting bolts and hand tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and install the lower rear bumper mounting bolts through the bumper and mounting
                    bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting nuts and washers on the bumper mounting bolts and hand tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and install (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_83.xml" xrefid="f47004115">Fig. 115, Item 1</hotlnk>) the remaining side
                    bumper mounting bolts (2 each side) with nuts and washers. Hand tighten side bumper mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the alignment of the bumper assembly with the body. Locate and align the bumper
                    transition panels at each end of the bumper assembly and side body panels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all bumper mounting bolts and lock nuts to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bumper transition panel mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Body Exterior Lights and Warning Lights</title>
            <para>The rear body warning lights and standard stop / tail, directional and back-up lights all follow the
                same removal and install procedure.
            </para>
            <para>A step ladder is required to access the warning light mounted on the end cap assembly.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the end cap light mounting locations. Insert the warning harness wire and
                    connector through the grommet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the warning light plug into the harness plug and insert in body opening.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the grommet into bus end cap. Feed excess wire through grommet into the end
                    cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place warning light on end cap and align mounting holes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert mounting screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the warning light lens on the light assembly (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_84.xml" xrefid="f47004118">Fig. 118, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>), insert the
                    lens mounting screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure for replacement of the stop / tail lights, back-up lights and
                    directional lights.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Street Side Body Stop Signs</title>
            <para>Prior to mounting optional street side body stop signs, check the wiring harness connectors and the
                wiring access hole for proper grommet fit.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the wire harness connection and plug into the body harness. Feed the excess wire
                    through the grommet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the stop sign mounting holes in the body side sheet. Align the stop sign assembly
                    mounting holes with the body holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_85.xml" xrefid="f47004119">Fig. 119, items 1 and 2</hotlnk>) and insert the
                    mounting screws as required (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_85.xml" xrefid="f47004120">Fig. 120, Item 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rubber Fenderettes</title>
            <para>With an assistant, locate the rubber fenderette at the rear wheel well opening.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the fenderette, and align with the mounting holes in the
                    wheel well opening trim ring (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_86.xml" xrefid="f47004121">Fig. 121, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin inserting the mounting bolts approximately every fourth bolt with washer and lock
                    nut and hand tighten. There are 21 per side. With the pilot mounting bolts in place, install the
                    remaining mounting bolts, washers and lock nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all remaining nuts and recheck the fenderette alignment around the wheel well
                    opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque all the lock nuts to the required torque value.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Under Body Compartments</title>
            <para>The under body compartments can be installed without the door assemblies in place.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant, locate the body compartment in the area of the compartment opening.
                    Using a hydraulic lift or other mechanical means, raise the compartment assembly in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the door frame assembly on the body side panel and align the mounting holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting screws through the door frame face plate assembly holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_87.xml" xrefid="f47004122">Fig. 122, Item 2</hotlnk>) and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the luggage box hanger bracket on the rear of the compartment assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the "J" clip around the upper flange of the chassis frame rail. Locate the
                    bracket mounting hole and the rear bracket hanger mounting hole.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the mounting bolt through the frame bracket and compartment hanger bracket.
                    Install the washer and lock nuts as required. Tighten the underbody "J" clip mounting bolts at the
                    compartment mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to vehicle electronic components, disconnect both battery positive (+) and (-)
                        negative cables prior to any welding operations. Attach the welding ground cable as close as
                        possible to the part being welded. If necessary to weld close to an electronic component, it is
                        recommended that the component be temporarily removed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the surfaces on the flange edges of the compartment and the surface area of the
                    floor structure where the compartment flange surface and the floor structure surface meet. Ensure
                    that both surfaces are clean and free of dirt, undercoating or debris, prior to spot welding the
                    compartment flanges in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the compartment assembly has been welded in place, torque the "J" clip mounting
                    bolts to the required torque value.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all surfaces and undercoat or paint as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal all overlap joint seams with yellow sealer. Allow to dry before painting.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electrical Compartment Door</title>
            <para>Prior to installing the electrical compartment door assembly, check the door seal for breaks and or
                cracks that might cause a leak problem into the chassis electrical compartment.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the door assembly hinge mounting holes and align them with the hinge mounting
                    holes. The hinge assemblies are slotted for door adjustment.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47004182" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/g47004182.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 182. Electrical Compartment Door Installation</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. ELECTRICAL COMPARTMENT DOOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL COMPARTMENT DOOR / HINGE MOUNTING NUTS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the hinge mounting bolts and nuts and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the electrical compartment door and check the seal and fit. If necessary loosen
                    and adjust the mounting bolts and nuts in the hinge slots.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Compartment</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Excessive voltage or current applied to electronic components may damage or destroy them,
                        resulting in expensive repairs.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to vehicle electronic components, disconnect both battery positive (+) and (-)
                        negative cables prior to any welding operations. Attach the welding ground cable as close as
                        possible to the part being welded. If necessary to weld close to an electronic component, it is
                        recommended that the component be temporarily removed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The battery compartment face plate is mounted to the outside skin of the bus body panel and is mounted
                utilizing with Phillip head mounting screws along the front face perimeter.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the battery compartment assembly, check the floor structure flanges
                    for undercoating, paint, dirt and or debris. Clean surfaces where attachment points are to be welded
                    in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the battery compartment in the opening and support in place by jacks or other
                    mechanical means.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and align the mounting holes on the front face of the compartment assembly with
                    the holes in the body side panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the floor structure flanges clean and free of dirt and debris, spot weld the
                    battery compartment mounting flanges to the floor structure flange assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the battery tray and related hardware.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Radio Antenna</title>
            <para>The entertainment radio antenna connection mounting is directly behind the drivers side widow (if
                equipped) (
                <hotlnk document="s47004_25.xml" xrefid="f4700431">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Feed the antenna wire through the body opening with grommet on antenna wire. Insert
                    grommet in body opening as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the antenna mounting holes on the body, align the antenna mounting base and
                    insert the mounting screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting screws, and plug antenna end into radio.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Side Sliding Window</title>
            <para>The driver sliding window assembly is an aluminum extruded framed horizontal sliding dual panel
                window. The window individually slides forward and aft in the window frame. The window is secured with a
                positive latching device.
            </para>
            <para>To install the driver sliding window:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installation check the window frame and opening for old sealant, dirt and or
                    debris. Clean as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the driver storm window assembly into the window frame opening.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the (4) frame mounting screws located in the bottom extrusion, (2) screws on the
                    forward vertical frame and (3) screws across the top lip flange.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the (4) mounting screws on the bottom of the window assembly extrusion. Tighten
                    the mounting screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting holes in the forward vertical extrusion, insert the two mounting
                    screws and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the mounting screws along the top extrusion of the window frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Double check the window for fit and apply seal around window frame area as may be
                    needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Side Storm Window (Optional)</title>
            <para>The driver side storm window procedure follows the same procedure as listed above.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transition Panels</title>
            <para>The transition panels are comprised of two assemblies, driver side and passenger side panels. Prior to
                installation check the surface areas for any caulking or seal that may remain from the removed panels.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the transition panel mounting holes with mounting holes in the cowl and body
                    panels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the top mounting screws in the cowl panel and hand tighten (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_91.xml" xrefid="f47004126">Fig. 126, Item 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the alignment of the rear edge of the transition panel with the body mounting
                    holes. Beginning at the top of the transition panel align and insert mount screws in the transition
                    panel rear cover reinforcing strip (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_91.xml" xrefid="f47004126">Fig. 126, Item 2 and 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the bottom recessed mounting screw in the lower center recessed mounting hole and
                    tighten (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_91.xml" xrefid="f47004126">Figure 126, Item 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the perimeter of the transition panel for any gaps and re-adjust if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant along the rear edge of the rear transition panel reinforcing strip as
                    needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>End Caps</title>
            <para>The end caps on the front and rear of the bus body are replaceable. Care should be taken in the
                process or removal and installation of the assemblies.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secured scaffold assembly and safety restraint
                        when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant should be present
                        during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing end caps, some interior panels are required to be removed to drill pilot holes
                        through the roof bows, for the end cap attachment process.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When replacing the front cap assembly, the driver bulkhead compartment and any equipment mounted on it
                will have to be removed to access the roof bow assembly.
            </para>
            <para>This includes:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Optional defroster fan assemblies.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>First aid kits and Body fluid clean-up kits.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Driver interior rear view mirror and sun visor (if applicable).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exterior light check system (if applicable).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The forward ceiling panel or rear depending on end cap being replaced.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Any other items that may be options that would be mounted on the driver overhead bulkhead.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the applicable interior items removed, mount the forward end cap on the roof
                    assembly and header assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert bolts in the lower forward edge and corners of the end cap assembly. Check the
                    fit and alignment with the roof panels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the inside front section of the bus, drill through the roof bow and roof panel
                    holes, through the end cap assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the roof bow holes drilled, prior to installing pilot rivets, install sealer
                    adhesive along the existing roof panel and under the rear edge of the end cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install pilot rivets across roof bow to ensure alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Beginning at the front corner over the windshield install rivets through the new end cap
                    mounting holes (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_29.xml" xrefid="f4700436">Fig. 36, Item 5</hotlnk>) into header assembly
                    and side section over driver window frame and entry door frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the remainder of roof bow rivets as required and check joint seals at end cap and
                    front roof panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If end cap seats properly, re-install interior bulkheads, and equipment that may have
                    been removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the front windshield assembly (see windshield installation).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the end cap marker light and connect marker light harness plugs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal all seams prior to paint.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If bus is equipped with glass destination board, install the glass panel and seal as
                    described in section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Follow the same basic procedure for rear end cap. Rear emergency door and windows need not be
                removed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Static Roof Vents</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death always use a secured scaffold assembly and safety restraint
                        when servicing the bus roof panels or roof component accessories. An assistant should be present
                        during any roof or roof accessory repair procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the static roof vent opening in the bus roof . Check the edges of the opening for
                    old seal gasket material or sharp edges.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the static roof vent and gasket assembly on the roof aligning the mounting holes
                    in the roof vent and the roof (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_95.xml" xrefid="f47004132">Fig. 132, Item 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using an industrial type rivet gun, insert the rivets through the static roof vent
                    flange into the roof panel assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Seal as necessary and allow seal to dry before painting.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Optional Roof Mounted Warning Lights</title>
            <para>Roof mounted clear strobe light assembly (
                <hotlnk document="s47004_27.xml" xrefid="f4700434">Figure 34</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the roof mounted strobe light, ensure the surface is clear and clean
                    of any dirt or debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the strobe light harness connection plug, and the body harness connection.
                    Connect the plug assemblies, install the body grommet on the harness wire and insert in the body
                    opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting gasket and place on body section. Align the mounting holes on the
                    light base and insert fasteners.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten fasteners and check gasket for proper seal.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Attachments or Tie Downs</title>
            <para>The body attachment tie downs are mechanical fasteners that secure the body floor panels to the
                chassis frame rail. This application consists of a combination of body tie down clips.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Failure to properly torque tie down bolts can result in body damage.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>"J"-Clip</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for anti-squeak pad. If it is missing, install. Locate the 1/2"-13 x 13 in
                    "J"-clip and bolt around the chassis frame rail and insert in floor frame structure (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_94.xml" xrefid="f47004127">Fig. 127, Items 1, 3 and 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the washers and lock nuts.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Torque the "J"-clip bolt to 30-40 Lbf-ft. (see Torque Chart).</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Shear Bolt Tie Downs</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the shear bolt mounting angle at the upper section of the bumper mounting bracket
                    assembly and chassis frame rail (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_94.xml" xrefid="f47004128">Fig. 128, Item 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the mounting holes in the shear angle assembly with the holes in the floor
                        structure flange.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert the 1/2"- 13 x 13" mounting bolts, washers and lock nuts.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Torque the mounting bolts to 30-40 Lbf-ft.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Formed Tie Down</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the formed tie down end in the notch in the floor flange structure. Locate the
                    opposite end under the frame rail flange (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_94.xml" xrefid="f47004129">Fig. 129, Items 4 and 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate the 1/2"-13 x 2 1/2" bolt through the formed tie down and floor structure
                        flange.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the washer and lock nut and tighten to 30-40 Lbf-ft.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Front Tie Down (Outrigger Tie Down)</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the mounting hole in the drivers platform frame assembly. Insert the 1/2"-13 x 4"
                    mounting bolt through the compression spring and through the driver platform frame mounting hole (
                    <hotlnk document="s47004_94.xml" xrefid="f47004130">Fig. 130, Item 4 and 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the flat washer and mounting nut. Torque to 50-60 Lbf-ft.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_133.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004_135.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
