<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - IC BUS SERVICE MANUAL - DOORS AND ACCESSORIES - OUTWARD
        OPENING AND FORWARD FOLDING DOOR CONTROL LUBRICATION/ MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="11">
        <title>OUTWARD OPENING AND FORWARD FOLDING DOOR CONTROL LUBRICATION/ MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Open and close the side emergency and/or rear emergency door. This will ensure penetration of
                lubricant in the required area. As part of general inspection, always open and close doors to inspect
                their operation. Always activate and de-activate the locking mechanism.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Instructional and warning decals must be re-installed on emergency doors, windows, etc. when
                        repairs are performed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection</title>
            <para>There are several points on the manual door operator and door itself that should be inspected,
                adjusted and lubricated for free and normal operation during routine maintenance (Every 30 days
                Recommended). The outward opening door hinge pins and nylon bearings should be inspected for wear. Nylon
                bushings and retainers at hinge pins should be replaced if they are worn or door is difficult to operate
                when disconnected from door control. The forward folding door hinge pin bushings and retainers at the
                top and bottom of the door should be inspected and replaced if door does not operate smoothly or is
                difficult when disconnected from manual door control. The roller bearing at the top of the door should
                be replaced if it is worn or will not turn easily.
            </para>
            <para>Inspection of the manual door control requires removal of the right hand dash cover. First, remove the
                four screws that retain the black plastic door rod cover. Then, remove the buttons that cover screws on
                the right hand dash cover. Remove the screws that retain the right hand dash cover. Lift the dash cover
                and feed the door control rod past the clearance hole.
            </para>
            <para>The manual door control has been tested to last the life of the vehicle. It requires regular
                lubrication with a graphite-based lubricant (Part# 407408R2) or equivalent and some adjustment may be
                required if it gets difficult to operate. If it is difficult to operate or stuck, first
                <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a4">inspect the upper</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a5">lower nosing rubber</hotlnk>; it should not drag or bind. If the nosing rubber
                is dragging or binding, it should be trimmed to allow the door to operate freely. Next, check the door
                control for any trash or loose components that may have fallen in the mechanism or slide. Take an air
                hose and blow this area clean.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Compressed air can damage some sensitive components and turn loose debris into projectiles, so
                        take the necessary safety precautions when using compressed air.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Lubricate and adjust as described later in the manual.</para>
            <figure id="f47001a4" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f47001a5" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjustment</title>
            <para>
                <title>Outward Opening</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjustment of Top Door Bar on Door Panels</para>
                <para>If the door control becomes difficult to operate, first check for obstructions or loose components
                    as described in the inspection process. Next, check the adjustment of the door control. There are
                    three adjustments that can be made that affect the operation of the door control. They are: 1.) Nut
                    adjustment of the pivot points on the operator itself, 2.) Adjustment of the door control rod that
                    attaches to the door, and 3.) Adjustment of the bar that attaches the two door panels together at
                    the top of the door. The first item that should be checked for out of adjustment operation is the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a6">bar at the top</hotlnk>
                    of the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a7">forward</hotlnk>
                    and rear door panels.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47001a6" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f47001a7" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>If this bar is out of adjustment, then the door control will be difficult to operate. Before
                    adjusting this bar, remove the door control rod from the forward door panel. Remove the keeper ring
                    from the pin that attaches the rod clevis to the door bracket.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a8">Pull rod away from door</hotlnk>. Door panels should open and close easily
                    by hand. If they do not, then rod at the top of the door requires adjustment. On doors with four
                    piece glass,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001a9">loosen bolts</hotlnk>
                    at top of door that attach
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001b0">bar brackets</hotlnk>
                    to door.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Caution should be taken when manually operating the doors with the rod detached; a
                            detached rod can damage windows.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f47001a8" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f47001a9" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001a9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f47001b0" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001b0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>To adjust bar, pull doors completely closed and allow bar to slide into proper position. With
                    doors closed, tighten one fastener on each bracket, making sure the brackets are straight and level.
                    Open and close doors a couple of times to ensure that doors operate smoothly without binding. If
                    doors bind or resist, repeat procedure and re-adjust brackets. If doors operate smoothly, tighten
                    remaining fasteners. Spray a high quality graphite-based lubricant (Part# 407408R2) or equivalent
                    onto bar pin connections at top of doors. Open and close doors several times to work in lubricant.
                    Re-attach door control rod, pin and keeper to door bracket. Operate door control several times and
                    determine if operation efforts are reduced. If door control is still difficult to operate, then door
                    control rod may need adjustment.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjustment of Door Control Rod</para>
                <para>If door does not fully open or close, is difficult to open or close, or if door is difficult to
                    latch, then door control rod yoke may need adjustment. Use the following logic to determine how to
                    adjust rod yoke.
                </para>
                <table id="t4700109">
                    <title>Rod Yoke Adjustment</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.72in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.54in"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Door control is hard to latch</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be extended on control rod or turned counter-clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Door is difficult to close</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be extended on control rod or turned counter-clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Doors do not close all the way</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be brought into rod or turned clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Doors do not open all the way</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be extended or turned counter-clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Door control lock open position is difficult</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be brought into rod or turned clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Door control lock open position is too weak</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>Yoke needs to be extended or turned counter-clockwise</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <para>The door control and door operation is sensitive to adjustment of the door rod yoke. Make small
                    adjustments and try door control for proper operation. Correct adjustment of the door control will
                    allow the door to operate properly and easily.
                </para>
                <para>Prior to removal of the rod yoke from the door bracket, loosen the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001b1">5/8" hex nut next to the door rod yoke</hotlnk>. To adjust the door
                    control rod yoke, remove the retainer on the bottom of the pin that attaches the rod yoke to the
                    door bracket. Remove the pin from the yoke and door control bracket. Rotate the yoke either
                    extending it or decreasing the length according to need. Make adjustments one turn at a time, then
                    re-attach rod yoke to door bracket. Do not install retainer yet.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Caution should be taken when manually operating the doors with the rod detached; a
                            detached rod can damage windows.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f47001b1" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001b1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>Operate the door control and check operation. Once final adjustment has been made, install pin
                    retainer. Tighten 5/8" diameter yoke retaining nut. Do not over-tighten.
                    <emph type="bold">Ensure that when tightening yoke nut that the yoke is parallel to the door control
                        end to prevent binding.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjustment of Door Control Mechanism</para>
                <para>To make adjustments to the door control mechanism the dash cover will have to be removed. Remove
                    four screws retaining black
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001b2">door rod cover</hotlnk>
                    from right hand dash cover.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47001b2" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001b2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>Remove retaining ring on pin that attaches end of door control rod to door control bracket. Remove
                    pin and disconnect rod from door control bracket. Remove buttons on front of right hand dash and
                    remove screws retaining dash. Feed door control rod past dash and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001b3">lift dash off</hotlnk>
                    of bus.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47001b3" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001b3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>Door control should operate easily without door control rod attached to door. If door control
                    mechanism feels stiff or hard to operate, then the pivot bolts and nuts on door control may need to
                    be adjusted.
                </para>
                <para>There are
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f47001b4">three fasteners</hotlnk>
                    on the pivot triangle which require periodic adjustment. First, identify the fastener that fits into
                    the slot in the triangle. This fastener attaches the control arm to the triangle. Initially, tighten
                    the bolt to 15 ft-lbs., then back off the nut half turn.
                </para>
                <figure id="f47001b4" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg47/G47001b4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <para>The second fastener is the pivot stud for the door control rod. Loosen and torque the nut to 15
                    ft-lbs., then back off the nut &#188; turn. The door control rod should pivot easily on the stud
                    without resistance. If some resistance is felt, back off the nut slightly until the door control rod
                    pivots easily.
                </para>
                <para>The third fastener is the pivot bolt for the triangle. This fastener is retained with a &#188;"
                    diameter lock screw. Loosen the lock screw with a cross-head screwdriver. Loosen the &#189;"
                    diameter bolt, then torque to 25 ft-lbs. Back off this nut &#188; turn. Tighten &#188;" diameter
                    lock screw.
                </para>
                <para>Operate the door control a couple of times while holding the door control rod. It should operate
                    smoothly and easily at about 3-1/2 lbs. of effort. If it does not, slightly loosen the pivot bolt
                    and slide nut until the door control operates easily.
                    <emph type="bold">Remember that the lock screw on the triangle pivot bolt will have to be loosened
                        and re-tightened every time you adjust the pivot bolt.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>Install the door control rod yoke on the door bracket with pin and retainer. Install the right
                    hand dash cover back onto the dash console with the screws and buttons that were removed. Install
                    the black plastic door control rod cover onto the dash. Adjustment and installation is complete. If
                    the door control has been in service for one year, then it should be lubricated. (See lubrication
                    and maintenance section.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Forward Folding</title>
            </para>
            <para>1. Adjustment of Door Control Rod</para>
            <para>If the forward folding door does not open or close all the way or the door control is difficult to
                latch, then the door control rod may need adjustment. Use the following logic to determine how to adjust
                the door control rod on the forward folding door.
            </para>
            <table id="t4700110">
                <title>Door Control Rod Adjustment</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.49in"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Door control is difficult to latch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Decrease rod length by turning door control rod yoke inward</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Door is difficult to close against rubber seals</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Decrease length of door control rod by turning yoke inward</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Door does not open all the way or does not seal adequately against rubber seals
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Increase door control rod length by extending yoke</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>To adjust the door control rod, loosen the 5/8" diameter hex nut securing the yoke that is attached to
                the door control bracket. Remove the retaining ring at the bottom of the pin. Remove the pin that
                attaches the rod yoke to the door control bracket. Rotating the yoke either clockwise or
                counter-clockwise changes the rod length and adjustment. Rotating the yoke clockwise decreases the
                length of the rod. Rotating counter-clockwise extends the length of the rod.
            </para>
            <para>Make adjustments in one turn intervals, re-install the pin into the yoke and door bracket and check
                the operation of the door control. Once satisfactory adjustments have been made, re-install retainer
                ring onto pin and tighten yoke retaining nut. When tightening yoke retaining nut, ensure that rod end
                that is attached to door control is not being rotated against pivot stud and binding. Yoke retaining nut
                should not be over-tightened. Yoke should be parallel with door control bracket.
            </para>
            <para>2. Adjustment of Door Control Mechanism</para>
            <para>To adjust the door control mechanism for a forward folding door follow the same procedure as outline
                for the outward opening door.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Warning Light Switch Adjustment</title>
            </para>
            <para>A switch attached to the door control activates the warning lights. If the warning lights do not
                operate properly when the door control is operated, the warning light switch may need to be replaced or
                adjusted. To adjust the warning light switch, the right hand dash cover must be removed. Remove the four
                screws retaining the black plastic cover around the door control rod. Remove the buttons and the
                cross-head screws retaining the right hand dash cover. Remove the right hand dash cover and feed the
                dash past the door control rod. The switch is located at the opposite end of the door control as the
                handle. With the door control in the full closed position, the button of the switch should be exposed
                1/16".
            </para>
            <para>Once the switch is adjusted, open and close the door control to ensure proper operation of the warning
                lights. If the warning lights still do not operate properly or the switch will not remain adjusted,
                replace warning light switch. Replace dash cover and door control rod cover plate in reverse order it
                was removed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lubrication and Maintenance</title>
            <para>
                <title>Outward Opening and Forward Folding Doors</title>
            </para>
            <para>Manual door control and doors should be lubricated to ensure proper operation. If doors or door
                controls are being adjusted, they should be lubricated during this process. Door controls and doors
                should be lubricated during regular maintenance intervals (Every 30 days Recommended) of the bus.
            </para>
            <para>The door hinge pins may be lubricated by spraying a high quality graphite-based lubricant (Part#
                407408R2) or equivalent on these areas. This may also be done on the door control rod hinge-pin. Wipe
                off any excess lubricant. Open and close door several times to work in lubricant.
            </para>
            <para>Forward folding doors should also be lubricated regularly with a high quality graphite-based lubricant
                to ensure proper operation. Forward folding doors are more susceptible to wear than outward opening
                doors. Spray lubricant on top and bottom hinge points of forward leaf of door. Spray lubricant on piano
                type hinge between forward and rear door leafs. Also, spray lubricant on roller bearing in track at top
                of door. Wipe off any excess lubricant. Open and close doors several times to work in the lubricant.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Door Control</title>
            </para>
            <para>Door control should be lubricated during the regular maintenance schedule (Every 30 days Recommended)
                or if door control becomes difficult to operate. To lubricate door control, the right hand dash cover
                must be removed. First, remove four screws retaining black plastic door rod cover. Next, remove buttons
                and cross-head screws retaining dash cover on bus. Then, lift off dash cover and feed over door control
                rod.
            </para>
            <para>There are six areas that require lubrication on the linear stroke door control.</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Slide mounted on door control base.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Nylon wear pad between control arm and base-plate.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Nylon wear pad between pivot triangle and control arm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Door control rod attachment stud.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Sliding point at slot in pivot triangle.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pivot stud at triangle base-plate attachment.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Apply a high quality graphite-based lubricant (Part# 407408R2) or equivalent to the nylon wear pad
                between control arm and base-plate, the nylon wear pad between pivot triangle and control arm, and to
                the slot in pivot triangle. Spray high quality graphite-based lubricant on triangle pivot bolt, rod
                pivot stud, and operator slide. Open and close doors several times to work in the lubricant. If
                adjustments are necessary, see previous sections on adjustment of door control and doors. Re-install
                dash cover door rod cover in reverse order of removal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <table id="t4700111">
                <title>Troubleshooting</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.80in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Problem</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Remedy</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>1. Door control is hard to operate.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1A. Determine if door bar on top of door panels is adjusted properly.</para>
                                <para>1B. Determine if door rod is adjusted properly. See section on door rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                                <para>1C. Door control and doors need lubrication. See section on door and door control
                                    lubrication.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>2. Door control is difficult to latch.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>2A. Door control rod requires adjustment. See section on door control rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3. Doors do not close all the way.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>3A. Door control rod requires adjustment. See section on door control rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>4. Doors do not open all the way.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4A. Door control rod requires adjustment. See section on door control rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>5. Door control break- over to hold door in open position is too hard.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>5A. Door control rod requires adjustment. See section on door control rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>6. Door control break-over is too weak. No detent in door control when opening to
                                    full open position.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>6A. Door control rod requires adjustment. See section on door control rod
                                    adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>7. Door control is stuck. Won't operate.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>7A. Remove dash cover from dash. Disconnect door control rod from door as
                                    described in instructions. Determine if door control is stuck or door is stuck. If
                                    door is stuck, investigate door pins and center hinge for proper operation. Replace
                                    parts if necessary.
                                </para>
                                <para>7B. If door is OK. Investigate door slide, triangle and control arm. Determine if
                                    there are any loose parts or components in mechanism preventing it from working.
                                </para>
                                <para>7C. Investigate door control for any worn or damaged parts. Replace damaged or
                                    worn parts.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>8. Warning lights don't operate properly.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>8A. Warning light switch on door control requires adjustment. If switch cannot be
                                    adjusted or will not stay adjusted, replace switch. See section on door control
                                    switch adjustment.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s47001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
