<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00302 - VIN Number Error</stitle>
    <recall id="rec00302">
        <recallnumber>00302</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 2000</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>GENERAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>VIN Number Error</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/17/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/13/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/15/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. In accordance with
                the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, American Transportation
                Corporation has determined that the Vehicle Identification Number (VIN) on certain International&#174;
                IC, AmTran RE&#8482; and AmTran FE&#8482; buses fails to conform to federal regulation requirements for
                VINs (49 C.F.R. (Code of Federal Regulations) 565 Vehicle Identification Number Requirements).
            </para>
            <para>On some of the above International IC, AmTran RE and AmTran FE school buses, the digits located in the
                9th and 10th positions of the VIN are in error. The 10th position code reflects the model year, and was
                published as a "Y" (for 2000 model year) on the recalled units. It should have been a "1" for 2001 model
                year. Changing the model year code also changes the 9th position code since it is derived from a
                calculation using the model year code.
            </para>
            <para>The VIN is located on the certification label on every vehicle and must reflect the correct number.
                The invoice and Manufacturer's Certificate of Origin (MCO) may also have the incorrect VIN applied.
                These errors will affect the registration of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected International IC model buses were built from March 17, 2000 through June 13, 2000. The
                affected AmTran RE and AmTran FE model buses were built from June 1, 2000 through July 15, 2000.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer has been sent the official recall letter with the required materials to repair the
                vehicle.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>ACTIONS REQUIRED</title>
            <para>If you are making the repairs for the customer, please obtain the materials that were included with
                the recall letter.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the current certification label in the bus with the label enclosed with the
                    recall letter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine the MCO.</para>
                <para>If the VIN on the MCO agrees with the corrected certification label, the MCO is correct and the
                    AFFIDAVIT OF CORRECTION should be destroyed. If the VIN on the MCO does not agree with the corrected
                    certification label, the MCO is in error and the AFFIDAVIT OF CORRECTION along with the MCO to
                    register the bus. If the vehicle has already been registered it will have to be re-registered with
                    the correct VIN. If the vehicle does not require registration, retain the AFFIDAVIT of CORRECTION
                    with the MCO.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the certification label has been replaced, please check box #2 on the
                    "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card. Sign and return the card to American Transportation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Some states require a label reflecting the VIN to be placed on the dash at the bottom of
                    the windshield. If the vehicle was built with this option, we have enclosed a small replacement tag
                    with the correct VIN. Please follow the procedure below to install.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On International IC models only, a mylar manufacturer's label that is located under the
                    hood on the driver side of the dash next to the wiring connector (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0030201">Figure</hotlnk>) is not a federal or state requirement. American
                    Transportation is not required to change this label. It may be removed or ignored.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0030201" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0030201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Mylar Label Under Hood</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>LABEL REPLACEMENT</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Certification Label Replacement</title>
                <para>The certification label is located on the forward overhead panel above the driver (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0030202">Figure</hotlnk>
                    below).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0030202" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0030202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Certification Label Located Above Driver</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Paper Certification Labels:</title>
                <para>If the vehicle identified has a paper label, the kit supplied with recall letter should have a new
                    paper label enclosed. Remove the backing off the label and apply it directly over the existing
                    certification label.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Metal Certification Labels:</title>
                <para>If the vehicle identified has a metal certification label, the kit supplied with the recall letter
                    should have a new metal label enclosed. Remove the rivets using a #27 bit, drill through the center
                    of all four rivets that retain the metal tag to the bulkhead panel. Remove and destroy the old metal
                    tag. Install the new enclosed metal tag in the same location using four rivets (part #400050000)
                    enclosed.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Metal Lower Windshield VIN Tags:</title>
                <para>If your vehicle has a metal VIN
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0030203">tag located on the dash in front of the driver</hotlnk>, we have enclosed
                    a new VIN tag. Remove the rivets using a #27 bit, drill through the center of the two rivets that
                    retain the metal tag to the panel. Remove and destroy the old metal tag. Install the new enclosed
                    metal tag in the same location using two rivets (part #400050000) enclosed.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0030203" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0030203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Metal Tag Located on Dash in Front of Driver</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0030201">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.98in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.58in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install new Paper Certification</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove and install new Metal Certification (when required)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install small windshield VIN tag (when required)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Locate vehicle and complete recall information</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Re-Registration Cost</emph>- The charges from the Motor Vehicle Department to change
                the title will be reimbursed. A copy of the receipt along with the invoice for the above labor is
                required.
            </para>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">recall claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-00302.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
