<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00305 - Driver Seat Mounting</stitle>
    <recall id="rec00305">
        <recallnumber>00305</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>December, 2000</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Driver Seat Mounting</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/17/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/08/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>On some International&#174; IC school buses, the driver's
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0030501">seat mounting hardware</hotlnk>
                may loosen, allowing the driver's seat to separate from the mounting platform.
                <emph type="bold">Separation of the driver's seat from the mounting platform could result in
                    displacement of the driver which could cause the driver to lose control of the vehicle, possibly
                    resulting in an accident that could cause injury and/or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0030501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0030501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Pedestal Type Seat Shown</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SEAT MOUNTING USES FOUR BOLTS TO SECURE THE SEAT TO THE PLATFORM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The vehicles involved were built from March 17, 2000 through October 8, 2000.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer notification letter notified the owner to inform all drivers to be aware of this
                potential problem. American Transportation suggests that, until their bus has been repaired, they
                inspect the seat mounting hardware prior to each operation to make sure that the seat fasteners are
                secure. They were also told if the fasteners are not secure, do not operate the bus until the repair for
                this defect is completed
                <emph type="bold">and even if their seat fasteners are secure at this time, this recall must be
                    performed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The notification letter gave the customer the choice to make the repairs themselves or contact their
                dealer to make the repairs.
            </para>
            <para>The customer was told that American Transportation estimates that its dealers will have instructions
                to remedy this defect by January 2, 2001.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00305 - Driver Seat Mounting</stitle>
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Six additional special self-tapping machine screws will be added to secure the seat to the mounting
                platform. The repair procedure will involve removing the driver seat from the platform and drilling six
                additional clearance holes in the seat base plus pilot holes in the mounting platform. Instructions,
                templates and parts will be included with the repair kits. Repair kits will be available by December 27,
                2000.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0030501">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.03in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.36in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.22in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>To order parts, call 1-800-843-5615</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Kit IC Driver Seat Mounting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0030502">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.98in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.58in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Repair time</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.8 hour without air suspension seat</para>
                                <para>1.0 hour with air suspension seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Documentation time</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>None of the units involved were exported.</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
