<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00503 - Power Steering Pumps Installed on T 444E V-8 Engines in Vehicles Built 2/1/2000 Through
        3/24/2000
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec00503">
        <recallnumber>00503</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2000</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>Power Steering Pumps Installed on T 444E V-8 Engines in Vehicles Built 2/1/2000 Through 3/24/2000
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/24/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/24/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/24/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>A power steering pump defect was found that can cause a loss of fluid flow. The power steering pump is
                designed to provide power assist to both the steering system and the hydraulic braking system. A
                defective pump may reduce the fluid flow to less than the minimum required flow rate to provide full
                power assist to the brake system with low engine speed.
                <emph type="bold">This defect may cause an increase in both stopping distance and steering wheel efforts
                    during steering and braking maneuvers at slow engine speeds; therefore, increasing the possibility
                    of an accident, which may result in property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This campaign covers 3400, 3800, 1652 SC, RE Bus, RE CMRCL, 4700 4 X 2, 4700 LPX and 4700 LP models
                built 2/01/2000 through 3/24/2000.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <stitle>Recall 00503 - Power Steering Pumps Installed on T 444E V-8 Engines in Vehicles Built 2/1/2000
                Through 3/24/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, ALWAYS wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Please read the following steps carefully before proceeding.</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">INSPECTION:</emph>Read both A. and B. below before replacing the pump.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">DEFECTIVE PUMPS:</emph>
                        The casting numbers should be cleaned and read before the pump is removed. Defective casting
                        numbers end with a dot nine (.9) or a dot ten (.10) (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0050301">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>). Both the dot and the number 9 or 10 are easily
                        readable.
                        <emph type="bold">SPECIAL NOTE:</emph>
                        The casting numbers ending in a 9 or 10 must have a dot ( . ) in front of the 9 or the 10 and
                        not a backslash ( / ). Read B. and continue to Step 2. (PUMP REPLACEMENT PROCEDURE) if
                        necessary.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">GOOD PUMPS:</emph>
                        All pumps ending in a number other than a 9 or a 10 should be considered good pumps, and pumps
                        that have casting numbers ending in a backslash nine ( /9 ) or a backslash ten ( /10 ) are good.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0050301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - DEFECTIVE PUMP SAMPLE: This defective pump has a casting number ending with a dot
                    ten (.10).
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00503 - Power Steering Pumps Installed on T 444E V-8 Engines in Vehicles Built 2/1/2000
                Through 3/24/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>2. PUMP REPLACEMENT PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Shut off engine and block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove CAC pipes if necessary.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Prepare for fluid loss and remove both hoses at the pump.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Moving the steering wheel after the hoses are disconnected will allow more air into
                                the hydraulic system; therefore, do not move the steering wheel after removing hoses
                                from pump.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the two pump mounting nuts and remove the pump from the studs. Return all
                        defective pumps to Fort Wayne, Indiana per the instructions on the R-5185 (PDA)
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Note the orientation of the fittings on the pump and remove the fittings from the
                        pump.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean the hose fittings, remove both old o-rings from the fittings, pre-lube new
                        o-rings with clean PS fluid, carefully install the o-rings on the fittings, make sure o-rings
                        are seated, and re-install the fittings in the new pump in the original orientation.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Carefully avoid pinching or twisting the new o-rings when re-installing.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Discard the old pump o-ring and install new o-ring on pump casting, pre-lube with
                        grease to hold in place, and re-install pump on mounting studs. Tighten the mounting nuts to
                        46-56 FT-LBS.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-install hoses to pump.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-install all removed CAC pipes.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Bleeding the System</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Top-off reservoir with International PS fluid and replace cap.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start engine and let idle, turn the wheels fully left and hold hard for up to 5
                        seconds, then turn the wheels fully right and hold hard for up to 5 seconds. Repeat these full
                        cycle turns three times and stop with the wheels straight ahead. Shut off engine and top-off
                        reservoir.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Continue operation in Step 2 until correct level is attained.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Run engine at fast RPM and continue to turn wheels back and forth slowly for
                        approximately 5 minutes. Again top-off reservoir to the correct level, replace cap, and check
                        for leaks in hoses.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Return all defective pumps to Fort Wayne, Indiana per the instructions on the R-5185
                        (PDA).
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>An estimated 9% of the vehicles in this campaign will require a new power steering pump. Please keep
                these details in mind when ordering parts. To replace a pump you will need one of each part number
                except the nut part number. The nut part number is provided in case you would need an extra part.
            </para>
            <table id="t0050301">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="3.44in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.98in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>LuK Power Steering Pump</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>2010412C92</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Pump o-ring</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>1822747C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Pressure hose o-ring at pump end, hose on side of pump</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>876106C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Return hose o-ring at pump end, hose on top of pump</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>876108C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>10mm Flange Headed Nut, reusable nuts, part number for information only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>31083R1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>ALL DEFECTIVE PUMPS MUST BE RETURNED TO FORT WAYNE, INDIANA PER THE INSTRUCTIONS ON THE R-5185
                        (PDA).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0050302">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00503-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect PS pump</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00503-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect and replace PS pump</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.2 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">Campaign Identification Label</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="490px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be notified from your distributor
                location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-00503.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
