<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00508 - Replacement of the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on AmTran
        FE, RE, and IC buses built from 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec00508">
        <recallnumber>00508</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 2000</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Replacement of the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on AmTran FE, RE,
            and IC buses built from 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/13/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec00508.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>This defect involves the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) which controls the Antilock
                Braking System (ABS). The ECU can misinterpret erratic signals that can be generated by one of two
                conditions: 1. A chafed wheel speed sensor wire on a rotating part, or 2. An incorrect gap between a
                tone ring and a wheel speed sensor. Either of these conditions can cause the air ABS ECU to exhaust the
                air at the air brake modulators for one or more of the wheels. During the above described conditions,
                the ABS warning indicator light may not come on to warn the driver of an ABS event or a malfunction and
                the driver can experience an extended stopping distance without warning when the vehicle is decelerating
                from 8 to 4 miles per hour. If an extended stopping distance occurs,
                <emph type="bold">the vehicle could be involved in an accident which could result in property damage,
                    personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This Safety Recall includes AmTran FE, RE, and IC buses built from 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000 with
                Bendix Air ABS brakes.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation
                <emph type="bold">has already notified owners</emph>
                of these vehicles about this campaign. During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses
                will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00508 - Replacement of the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on
                AmTran FE, RE, and IC buses built from 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTERIM ACTIONS DEALERS CAN PERFORM UNTIL THE ECU IS AVAILABLE (ESTIMATED ECU
                    AVAILABILITY DATE OF 9/15/2000):
                </emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Perform safety recall 00505 on all buses built 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the ABS-lamp comes on, service the ABS system, even if the lamp goes off.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00508 - Replacement of the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on
                AmTran FE, RE, and IC buses built from 3/01/1998 through 7/13/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>REPLACEMENT PROCEDURE FOR THE EC-17</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Introduction:</emph>
                    The following instructions for Replacing the original ECU, with the new revised ECU, on all of these
                    vehicles are simple instructions for physical removal, installation and testing of the ECU and will
                    not require reconfiguring time. None of these vehicles have Automatic Traction Control and all are
                    4-sensor systems. If there are problems with the ABS system after the new ECU is correctly
                    installed, refer to the CTS 5000 Master Service Manual section CTS-5292 for further information.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, ALWAYS wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Please read the following steps carefully before proceeding.</emph>
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal of the Valve-Mounted EC-17:</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Locate the EC-17 on the inside of the left frame rail behind the rear axle.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove as much contamination as possible from the assembly's exterior. Keep the
                        contamination away from the electrical connections.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">On vehicles built in July of 2000, check to see if the revised ECU was installed at
                        the assembly plant. There are two ways to determine this. First, if there is a green dot sticker
                        on top of the ECU it is a revised ECU and does not need to be changed. Second, if the bar code
                        sticker on the side of the ECU has the number 5008311 (LED models only) it is a revised ECU and
                        does not have to be changed.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Note and mark the mounting position of the EC-17 on the valve.
                        <emph type="bold">Do not use an impact wrench to remove the ECU mounting bolts</emph>. Before
                        removing the ECU mounting bolts, tap on the heads of the ECU mounting bolts to help eliminate
                        the risk of the bolts breaking off in the valve. Loosen, remove and save the mounting hardware
                        that attaches the controller to the valve. On some vehicles it may be necessary to remove the
                        frame-mounted bracket, the valve and the ECU as an assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installing the New EC-17</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remount the ECU in the proper orientation with the original mounting hardware and
                        torque the bolts to 98 in-lbs or 11 Nm.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect the electrical connections to the EC-17 and torque the connector retaining
                        bolts to 15-20 in-lbs or 1.7-2.3 Nm.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the vehicle and bring the air system pressure up to governor cut-out and turn
                        the ignition switch to the off position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal and turn the ignition switch to the on position. The ABS
                        system should cycle through a series of short bursts of air from the modulators. You should hear
                        the air released in the following sequence: Right Front, Left Front, Right Rear and Left Rear.
                        The air burst sequence will automatically be repeated one more time.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">While the ECU is releasing the air bursts in step 4 above, the lamp should come on
                        and stay on during the test, flash twice, and go out.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">No lights should stay on if the system is functioning properly but if they do, refer
                        to the CTS 5000 Master Service Manual section, "Initial Start-up Procedure" in section CTS-5292.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check to make sure the brakes are functioning properly.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Retain the removed ECU as they all must be returned. They will be requested as usual by
                            the R-5185 Parts Disposition Authorization.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>There is one ECU part number used on all of the buses in this recall:
                <emph type="bold">PN: 8900072R91</emph>. The estimated part availability date is September 15, 2000. All
                of these replacement parts will be easily identified with a white adhesive stripe on them.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Returning the old parts:</emph>
                Return all parts. All shipments of parts in the U. S. less than 150 lbs are to be shipped collect via
                UPS (account A7T 571). Shipments over 150 lbs are to be shipped collect via Yellow Freight. Ship to:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Bendix ABS Recall</line>
                <line>901 Cleveland Street</line>
                <line>Elyria, OH 44036</line>
            </verbatim>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0050801">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.48in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.32in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00508-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace ABS ECU</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.8 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be notified from your distributor
                location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-00508.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>Distribution: All Dealers</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
