<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00504 - Eaton AutoShift II Transmissions in Vehicles Built 06/01/1999 Through 4/20/2000</stitle>
    <recall id="rec00504">
        <recallnumber>00504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 2000</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subject>Eaton AutoShift II Transmissions in Vehicles Built 06/01/1999 Through 4/20/2000</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Eaton</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/20/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This is a software defect that can cause the transmission to be in the forward second gear rather than
                the reverse gear when reverse is selected by the operator. In other words, this would be an incorrect
                gear engagement causing the vehicle to move in an unintended direction.
                <emph type="bold">If the vehicle is in the forward second gear when the reverse gear was selected by the
                    operator the vehicle may be involved in an accident which may result in property damage, personal
                    injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This campaign covers 2574 6X4, 8100 4X2, 8100 6X4, 9100i 4X2, 9100i 6X4, 9200i 4X2, 9200i 6X4, 9400i
                6X4, and 9900i 6X4 models.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>REVISION SUMMARY</title>
            </para>
            <para>A new start date for the build date window resulted in an increase in the number of vehicles in this
                campaign. Please perform the following steps to clearly document this change.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Change the start date of the build date range on your copy of the original G-00504 letter
                        dated June, 2000 from 1/10/2000 to
                        <emph type="bold">6/1/1999</emph>. This date change is required in only two places in the
                        original G-00504 dealer mailing. The first location is on the first page in the
                        <emph type="bold">SUBJECT</emph>. The second place the date should be changed is in the first
                        page of the customer letter.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Refer to the original G-00504 letter (below) for Parts, Labor, Warranty and Service
                        information.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Attach this letter to the original G-00504 letter dated June, 2000.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If you do not have the original G-00504 letter, a copy can be ordered by calling 616-968-4856
                        or printing one from the International web site.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00504 - Eaton AutoShift II Transmissions in Vehicles Built 06/01/1999 Through 4/20/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>EZ-Tech ServiceRanger Setup</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>To perform this programming you must have the Eaton ServiceRanger software installed on your
                    EZ-tech service tool. The ServiceRanger software and instructions have been mailed to all dealers in
                    the US and Canada. If you have not received your software package by mail call the Eaton
                    ServiceRanger support toll free at 1-888-880-0970.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>Using ServiceRanger With Your EZ-Tech</title>
                </para>
                <para>The processes below outline the procedure for updating AutoShift Generation II transmission
                    software. More details on using this software can be found in the ServiceRanger Users Guide.
                </para>
                <para>A NavPPP connection will be required to get product programming software from Eaton. The NavPPP
                    connection is only required for the "Getting Product Software" phase.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>A) Obtaining an Eaton USER ID</title>
                <para>An Eaton USER ID is required for downloading product software and ServiceRanger updates.</para>
                <para>There are two ways to obtain an Eaton USER ID. The first way is to call Eaton ServiceRanger
                    support toll free at 1-888-880-0970 and select option 5.
                </para>
                <para>The second way is to use the Eaton web-site. To access this web site perform the following
                    steps.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Double click on the Vehicle Diagnostics folder.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Double click on the NavPPP icon and dial-up International as you usually would. For
                        details on using NavPPP see the section titled "How to Use NavPPP" after this procedure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Double click on the ServiceRanger icon. This is located in the Vehicle Diagnostics
                        folder.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the Internet Download button from the main menu.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the ServiceRanger Main Menu button to open the ServiceRanger Internet home
                        page. Please note that Internet Explorer 4.0 or 5.0 is required. If you have Internet Explorer
                        3.0 then the page will come up in error.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the REGISTRATION Button at the top the ServiceRanger web-site and fill out
                        the form that appears. Once the form is complete, click on the Submit Button at the bottom of
                        the form. Note that it is recommended that you use your DYYxxxx id for the user name and
                        Password of ServiceRanger.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">When the form is submitted, the ServiceRanger administrator will send an e-mail
                        confirming your user name and password within 2 days.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once complete, you may exit the ServiceRanger Web Page.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>B) Authorizing Your EZ-Tech</title>
                <para>Please note that you cannot authorize your PC until you have received an Eaton USER ID and
                    password from the steps above.
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Double click on the Vehicle Diagnostics folder.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Double click on the NavPPP icon and dialup International as you usually would. For details
                            on using NavPPP see the section titled "How to Use NavPPP" after this procedure.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Double click on the ServiceRanger icon. This is located in the Vehicle Diagnostics
                            folder.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Click on the Internet Downloads button.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Click the ServiceRanger Main Menu button to open the ServiceRanger Internet home page.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Click on the Authorize PC button at the top of the page. You will be asked for the
                            ServiceRanger USER ID and password that was created above.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Once complete, you may exit the ServiceRanger Web Page.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>Recall 00504 - Eaton AutoShift II Transmissions in Vehicles Built 06/01/1999 Through 4/20/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>AutoShift Application Product Downloads</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>There are three phases in creating an AutoShift Product Download. The three phases are 1) Getting
                    AutoShift Product Information, 2) Getting AutoShift Product Software, and 3) Downloading AutoShift
                    Product Software. Only downloading application software will be discussed here. For configuration
                    download information please refer to the ServiceRanger Users Guide.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Get AutoShift Product Information</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the EZ-Tech PC to the vehicle using Navistar communications interface cable
                        (part number ZTSE4444A).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Double click on the Vehicle Diagnostics folder. Double click on the ServiceRanger
                        icon.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the Product Download button. When a vehicle is equipped with multiple Eaton
                        products a Product Selection screen will appear. Select the AutoShift AS2 product and click the
                        OK button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If vehicle information is not available, you will be asked to enter it, the
                        information that must be entered is VIN, Transmission Serial Number, and Mileage. Once the
                        information is typed in, click on the OK button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The Product Download Screen will then appear showing the vehicle information and
                        software available.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the Application software is available for the AutoShift you are working on, it
                        will automatically appear on the available applications download section of the screen. You may
                        proceed to download software if the application software numbers are greater than: Shift
                        Control: 742; Transmission Control: 066. These numbers will be in the application download name.
                        If no software is available you will need to exit the Product Download screen and go to the next
                        step Getting AutoShift Product Software below.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once the screen is shown, if no application is shown, close the product download
                        screen and go to Getting AutoShift Product Software.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Getting AutoShift Product Software</title>
                <para>The Internet download button allows for retrieval of AutoShift Product Software from the NavPPP
                    connection. Once you have opened the Internet download screen, the information at the top of the
                    screen is where product groups are selected for software retrieval. Product groups are vehicles that
                    are programmed the same at the factory. Select the group containing the vehicle being programmed,
                    and the ServiceRanger server will provide a list of available software for that product. Select the
                    application software and then download it onto your EZ-Tech.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Double click on the Vehicle Diagnostics folder. Double click on the NavPPP icon and
                        dialup International.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the Internet download button from the ServiceRanger Main Menu.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the product group by double clicking on the desired product group. The
                        Product Group will contain the vehicle information, which was input in the Retrieve Product
                        Information process. This will connect to the ServiceRanger web-site and provide the software
                        that is currently available for this product group.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">A screen will open, asking for the user name and password. This is the USER ID and
                        password obtained in the registration process above.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The ServiceRanger web page will open showing available software. The application
                        software is shown in blue on the top of the screen. Select the Software that has a name similar
                        to "RTO-xx710x-AS2 070 and 043" by clicking on the radio button to the right of the name. DO NOT
                        USE THE "LEVER" SOFTWARE (for example RTO-XX710X-A52 shift lever 070).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the SELECT CONFIGURATION button. This will take you to the select quantity
                        screen.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">To select the number of downloads that will be available for downloading to a
                        product, click in the drop down box after the software name. When the desired number of
                        downloads have been selected, click on the Purchase Configuration button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The next screen provides a summary of the product software requested in the previous
                        screens. If correct, click on the Confirm Purchase button. If the configuration is not correct,
                        then close WebRanger window and start Getting AutoShift Product Software from the beginning.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">To download the selected software to the EZ-Tech's hard drive, click on CLICK HERE
                        TO DOWNLOAD. A status window will appear, showing progress of the download. A window will be
                        displayed when the download has finished. Click the OK button to return to the Internet main
                        menu, then close the Internet download screen.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Downloading AutoShift Product Software</title>
                <para>This procedure will actually download the product software into the AutoShift transmission.</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the EZ-Tech PC to the vehicle using International communications interface
                        cable (part number ZTSE4444A).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the Product Download button. When a vehicle is equipped with multiple Eaton
                        products a PRODUCT SELECTION screen will appear. Select the AutoShift AS2 product and click the
                        OK button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If vehicle information is not available, you will be asked to enter it. The
                        information that must be entered is VIN, Transmission Serial Number, and Mileage. Once the
                        information is typed in, click on the OK button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The Product Download Screen will then appear showing vehicle information and
                        software available.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The Application software appears on the available applications download section of
                        the screen. You may proceed to download software if the application software numbers are greater
                        than: Shift Control: 742; Transmission Control: 066.
                        <emph type="bold">Note: these numbers will be in the application download name. If an
                            application is not provided for one of the controllers, it already has the latest software.
                            You may confirm this by double clicking on the view configuration button. The software
                            numbers should be greater than the numbers above.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start download by double clicking on the software part number. Both the transmission
                        and shift control will require downloading using the same step. Start by clicking on the
                        software which contains the word "Shift Control" in the name.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">ServiceRanger will prepare the transmission for downloading and prompt you to turn
                        the ignition key to the off position. When the key is in the off position click on the OK
                        button. ServiceRanger will start to download and will indicate the download progress with the
                        status bar at the bottom of the screen. It should be noted that once a download is begun it
                        cannot be canceled. The user must wait for the download to be completed.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once download is complete, ServiceRanger will request the ignition key be turned
                        back on and update the product information. Once information is updated, start transmission
                        download by clicking on the software with the words "Trans Controller" in the name. Once the
                        download is complete. Turn the ignition back on to update vehicle information.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The download is now complete. To confirm download click on View Current
                        configuration button and confirm the Shift Control software is greater than 742 and the
                        transmission controller is greater than 066.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The ServiceRanger program can be closed or you may close the product download screen
                        and move to another vehicle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="11">
            <stitle>Recall 00504 - Eaton AutoShift II Transmissions in Vehicles Built 06/01/1999 Through 4/20/2000
            </stitle>
            <title>How to Use NavPPP</title>
            <para>To manually start Dial-Up Networking open the Vehicle Diagnostics folder on the Desktop, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050401">click on the NavPPP icon</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050401" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Click on NavPPP Icon</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When the NavPPP icon is launched, the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050402">following screen will come up</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050402" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>First Screen When NavPPP is Launched</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Make sure that the phone number is correct (does the current location require a 9 to be dialed
                first?).
            </para>
            <para>Next, click the Connect button to start the connection process. If the connection is made properly,
                the following screen will come up. It may take a minute or so to make the connection and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050403">you will see a screen like this</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050403" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Screen Shown When Connection is Made</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Key in your ID, hit the enter key, and you will be prompted for your password. Type in your password
                and hit the enter key.
            </para>
            <para>You will then see a
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050404">menu like this</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050404" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Menu Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Your options here are:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Connect to the Navistar Network</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Change your Password</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Enter 1, 2 or q(uit)</para>
            <para>Entering PPP Mode.</para>
            <para>IP address is "dynamic - it may be different the next time you log in"</para>
            <para>MTU is 1524</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">You must make a choice!</emph>
                If you type 1, hit enter and hit F7 or click on the Continue (F7) button you will connect to the
                Navistar Network.
                <emph type="bold">If you type 1, hit enter and don't hit F7 or click Continue (F7) you will see a
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0050405">screen like Figure 14</hotlnk>, the Gateway will time out in about two
                    minutes, disconnect and return you to the Connect To
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0050406">screen as in Figure 15</hotlnk>. Start over.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050405" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050405.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 14</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0050406" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050406.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 15</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If you hit F7 without making a choice from the menu the Gateway will be unable to negotiate what you
                are trying to do and an
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050407">error box will be displayed as in Figure 16</hotlnk>. Once you have clicked on
                OK you will be returned to the Connect To dialog box. Start over.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050407" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050407.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 16</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If you type 2 and hit enter you will be prompted to type in your old password, your new password and
                to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050408">re-enter your new password as in Figure 17</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050408" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050408.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 17</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The menu will again be displayed. Make a choice and hit F7 or click on the Continue (F7) button.
            </para>
            <para>If, when you key in your password you see that your password has expired you will be prompted to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050409">enter a new password as in Figure 18</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050409" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050409.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 18</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Be very careful to note if your "Caps Lock" is 'ON' when you type in your new
                    password.
                </emph>
                You will then be prompted to re-enter your new password. After it verifies your new password you will be
                prompted to login again.
                <emph type="bold">Make sure you use your new password when prompted.</emph>
                Make your choice from the menu.
                <emph type="bold">Again, be sure you hit F7 or click on Continue.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When you key in your password, you see that your password has expired, you enter a new password ,
                re-type it, and if they don't match you will see a
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050410">screen like Figure 19</hotlnk>. Type it in again and then re-enter it.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050410" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050410.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 19</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If you accidentally type in the wrong ID and/or password you will see the message - ** Bad Password -
                and Login: will again be
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0050411">displayed as in Figure 20</hotlnk>. Re-type your ID and password and follow
                the menu.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0050411" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0050411.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Figure 20</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">It is STRONGLY advised not to use a script or a batch file to connect to NavNet for
                    several reasons. You will never see the menu, you will never see when your password expires, and you
                    won't be able to change your password when you want to if you use a script. Please use this guide
                    when connecting to NavNet. If your screens don't look like they do in this guide chances are you are
                    using a script to connect to NavNet. If you call the Dealer Support Hotline you can receive
                    instructions on how to correctly connect to NavNet.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">System 21 or EZ Tech Technical support is available through Fieldworks by calling
                    International toll free at 1-800-527-7879.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>No parts are required for this recall. However, if you did not receive your programming software
                package by mail please call Eaton ServiceRanger support toll free at 1-888-880-0970.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0050401">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00504-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Reprogram Transmission ECU</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.7 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">Campaign Identification Label</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be notified from your distributor
                location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-00504.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
