<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00510A - Replacing the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on 2000, 4000,
        5000, 8000 and 9000 model STRAIGHT TRUCKS with code 04091
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec00510">
        <recallnumber>00510A</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Replacing the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) for air brakes on 2000, 4000, 5000, 8000
            and 9000 model STRAIGHT TRUCKS with code 04091
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/11/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/11/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/11/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/11/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/11/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec00510.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus00510.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SPECIAL NOTE: ACTION REQUIRED!</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This letter was written to replace the original recall letter G-00510 Dated January 2001. Please scrap
                all copies of G-00510 in your facility and replace with copies of this letter. Revisions were made to
                the "SERVICE PROCEDURE" section and the "PARTS INFORMATION" section. The revisions are due to part
                application changes and special issues that have arisen since the initial release of this campaign. No
                changes were made in any other sections of this letter. Please read these sections and familiarize
                yourself with the changes.
            </para>
            <para>This defect involves the Bendix EC-17 1030R electronic control unit (ECU) which controls the Antilock
                Braking System (ABS). The ECU can misinterpret erratic signals that can be generated by one of two
                conditions: 1. A chafed wheel speed sensor wire on a rotating part, or 2. An incorrect gap between a
                tone ring and a wheel speed sensor. Either of these conditions can cause the air ABS ECU to exhaust the
                air at the air brake modulators for one or more of the wheels. During the above described conditions,
                the ABS warning indicator light may not come on to warn the driver of an ABS malfunction and the driver
                can experience an extended stopping distance without warning when the vehicle is decelerating from 8 to
                4 miles per hour. If an extended stopping distance occurs,
                <emph type="bold">the vehicle could be involved in an accident which could result in property damage,
                    personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This Safety Recall includes 2000, 4000, 5000, 8000 and 9000 model
                <emph type="bold">STRAIGHT TRUCKS ONLY</emph>
                (04091) built within the following build date ranges:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Springfield Plant: vehicles built from 3/1/98 to 6/16/00</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chatham Plant: vehicles built from 3/1/98 to 6/27/00</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Escobedo Plant: vehicles built from 3/1/98 to 6/20/00</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Garland Plant: vehicles built from 3/1/98 to 7/11/00</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>In September of 2000 International notified customers and dealers of this Safety Recall and projected
                part availability for January 2001. Parts are now available and the official customer notification
                letters were mailed in late January 2001. During the recall process a listing of owner names and
                addresses will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPLACEMENT PROCEDURE FOR THE BENDIX AIR BRAKE ECU</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <para>The following instructions are for replacing the original ECU with a revised EC-17 or an EC-30.
                    All vehicles in this campaign have 4-sensor systems. There are special instructions for vehicles
                    with Automatic Traction Control or split shaft PTO. If there are problems with the ABS system after
                    the new ECU is correctly installed, refer to the Master Service Manual section CTS-5292 for further
                    information.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">DOES THE VEHICLE HAVE A SPLIT SHAFT PTO?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">FOR SPLIT SHAFT PTO APPLICATIONS:</emph>
                    If you install ECU part number 8900072R91, 8900073R91, or 8900075R91 and the vehicle has a split
                    shaft PTO or a transfer case that drives something for the body equipment while the truck is
                    stationary, there will be a problem with the ABS light latching ON. To correct this problem a wiring
                    change is necessary; therefore, please call the TECH SERVICE HELP LINE AT
                    <emph type="bold">1-800-336-4500</emph>
                    to get instructions for the modification.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, ALWAYS wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="boldundersc">Please read the following steps carefully before proceeding.</emph>
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removing the EC-17:</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the "WPID" screen in DDEW or check ISIS to see if the vehicle is marked for
                        the ABS sensor wire inspection Safety Recall 00505. If the VIN is marked for 00505 but 00505 has
                        not been completed, perform the procedure for 00505. If the VIN is not marked for 00505, do not
                        do the inspection for 00505.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Locate the EC-17 on the inside of the left or right frame rail, near the rear axle
                        or under the cab.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove as much contamination as possible from the assembly&#x2019;s exterior. Keep
                        the contamination away from the electrical connections.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Vehicles built in the last couple weeks of the build date ranges above may have had
                        a revised ECU installed at the plant. Only replace ECU&#x2019;s that have one of the following
                        two Bendix numbers on the bar code sticker: 5002767 (with LED) or 5002927 (without LED),
                        <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                        one of the following five International part numbers on the ECU: 3518871C1, 3520190C91,
                        3521228C91, 3527451C91 or 3533409C1.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Do not replace the ECU if it has:</emph>
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">A green dot sticker on top of the ECU housing,</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">A white or green adhesive stripe across the top of the ECU housing,</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The number 5008311 on the bar code sticker (for ECU's with LED's), or</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The number 5008313 on the bar code sticker (for ECU's without LED's).</para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Note and mark the mounting position of the EC-17 on the valve or the bracket.
                        <emph type="bold">Do not use an impact wrench to remove the ECU mounting bolts on valve mounted
                            models.
                        </emph>
                        For valve mounted ECU&#x2019;s, it is very important to tap on the heads of the ECU mounting
                        bolts before removing the bolts, to help eliminate the risk of the bolts breaking off in the
                        valve. Loosen, remove and save the mounting hardware that attaches the controller to the valve
                        or bracket. On some vehicles it may be necessary to remove the frame-mounted bracket, the valve
                        and the ECU as an assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installing the new ECU (instructions for both the EC-17 and the EC-30)</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reference the "
                        <emph type="bold">PART INFORMATION</emph>" section in this letter to determine which ECU should
                        be installed.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remount the ECU in the proper orientation with the original mounting hardware and
                        torque the bolts to 98 in-lbs or 11 Nm.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect the electrical connections to the ECU and torque the connector retaining
                        bolts to 15-20 in-lbs or 1.7-2.3 Nm.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">BEFORE TURNING THE IGNITION SWITCH ON IN STEP 5, PICK THE CORRECT INDICATOR
                            LAMP FLASH SEQUENCE BELOW IN EITHER A OR B FOR YOUR APPLICATION. IF THE VEHICLE HAS
                            AUTOMATIC TRACTION CONTROL, MAKE SURE THE AUTOMATIC TRACTION CONTROL (ATC) SWITCH IS IN THE
                            ENABLED POSITION
                        </emph>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">BEFORE TURNING THE IGNITION ON IN STEP 5</emph>. All straight trucks
                        with ATC were configured from the factory for both torque limiting and differential braking.
                        Upon power-up, one of the following two dash indicator-lamp flash sequences will occur.
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">
                            <emph type="bold">For EC-17's with or without traction control:</emph>
                            The ABS lamp and the Traction Control lamp (if equipped with ATC) will
                            <emph type="bold">come on initially and then flash on and off twice</emph>. This means the
                            ECU is configured correctly. If the lamp flash sequence does not flash as described, go to
                            step 5.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">
                            <emph type="bold">For EC-30's with or without traction control:</emph>
                            The ABS lamp and the Traction Control lamp (if equipped with ATC) will
                            <emph type="bold">come on for 2.5 seconds and then go out</emph>. This means the ECU is
                            self-configured correctly. If the Traction Control lamp flashes once or twice instead of
                            staying on for 2.5 seconds, the ECU is not configured correctly and must be reconfigured (go
                            to step 5).
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch on and watch for the correct indicator lamp sequence from
                        step 4, bring the air system pressure up to governor cut-out, and then turn the ignition switch
                        to the off position. If the indicator lamp sequence was not correct as described in step 4,
                        proceed to step 6 for reconfiguration.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the indicator lamp sequence was not correct as described in step 4, one of the
                        following methods may be used to reconfigure the ECU. With the ignition in the on position,
                        perform one of the following.
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Press the DCI reset switch for about 20 seconds (until the LED's begin to flash
                            rapidly), then release the switch. Turn OFF ignition switch and repeat step 5 and then go to
                            step 7.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Hold a magnet on the reset location of the diagnostic display for about 20
                            seconds (if ECU has LED's, they will begin to flash rapidly), then remove the magnet. Turn
                            OFF ignition switch and repeat step 5 and then go to step 7.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After the ECU is properly configured, depress the brake pedal and turn the ignition
                        switch to the on position. The ABS system should cycle through a series of short bursts of air
                        from the modulators. You should hear the air released in the following sequence: Right Front,
                        Left Front, Right Rear and Left Rear. The air burst sequence will automatically be repeated one
                        more time.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">No lights should stay on if the system is functioning properly, but if they do,
                        refer to the Master Service Manual section, "Initial Start-up Procedure" in section CTS-5292.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check to make sure the brakes are functioning properly.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Return the removed ECU as instructed in the "PARTS INFORMATION" section of this
                        letter. The ECU's will be requested as usual by the R-5185 Parts Disposition Authorization.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">THIS SECTION INCLUDES:</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>WHICH ECU SHOULD YOU ORDER?</para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>If you are the selling dealer.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If you are not the selling dealer.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>PART NUMBER HISTORY AND USAGE</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IDENTIFYING NEW ECU&#x2019;S</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>RETURNING THE OLD PARTS AND IDENTIFYING DEFECTIVE ECU&#x2019;S</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <table id="t0051002">
                <title>Eaton Automated Manual Transmission Codes</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.67*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.53*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>AutoShift</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>AutoShift 2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>AutoSelect</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>13GJU, 13GJV, 13GJW</para>
                                <para>13GKP, 13GKR</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>13GKU, 13GKV, 13GKW, 13GKX, 13GKY</para>
                                <para>13GMG, 13GMH, 13GMT, 13GMU, 13GMV, 13GMW</para>
                                <para>13GNR, 13GNS, 13GNT, 13GNU, 13GNV, 13GNW</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>13GJE, 13GJG, 13GJH, 13GJJ, 13GJK, 13GJL, 13GJM, 13GJN</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">WHICH ECU SHOULD YOU ORDER? (Please read section 1 completely.)</emph>
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">If you are the selling dealer,</emph>
                                order the ECU part number provided in the green bar report with this revision. Due to
                                the complexity of determining which ECU is required for each vehicle, International has
                                provided, in this dealer revision mailing, a special green bar report that gives the ECU
                                part numbers, to selling dealers, for vehicles that were not completed as of June 2001.
                                <emph type="bold">Note:</emph>
                                the part numbers in this special green bar report are recommended for vehicles "
                                <emph type="bold">as they were built</emph>". Body companies may have added a split
                                shaft PTO that would require a wiring change (see
                                <emph type="bold">SPECIAL NOTE FOR SPLIT SHAFT PTO APPLICATIONS</emph>
                                in B. below). Reference the green bar report supplied with this letter to order the
                                correct part for a VIN. To allow the Parts Distribution Centers to manage inventory,
                                please limit your order quantities to the number of ECU&#x2019;s that can be installed
                                in a short period of time. If you are not the selling dealer for the vehicle you are
                                servicing, you can either call the selling dealer and ask them to reference their green
                                bar report or you must follow the rules, in B below, to determine which ECU to install.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">If you are not the selling dealer</emph>, you can call the selling
                                dealer and ask them to reference the green bar report
                                <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                                follow the guidelines below and use the "
                                <emph type="bold">WPIE</emph>" screen in DDEW to search for the build codes below.
                            </para>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">To determine which part to order, refer to the following questions.
                                </emph>
                            </para>
                            <seqlist style="arabic">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Was the vehicle built with an Eaton Automated Manual Transmission listed in
                                        <hotlnk xrefid="t0051002">Table 1</hotlnk>
                                        above? If yes, then stop and you
                                        <emph type="bold">MUST USE THE EC-30</emph>
                                        (8900075R91). If no, then continue to question 2 below.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Was the vehicle built with Traction Control brake code 04AZD or 04AZJ? If yes,
                                        then stop and you
                                        <emph type="bold">MUST ORDER THE EC-30</emph>
                                        (8900075R91). An EC-17 with LED&#x2019;s (8900072R91) cannot be ordered anymore
                                        but will work if you have one at your location. If no, then continue to question
                                        3 below.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Was the vehicle built with brake codes 04AZM or 804AZA (804AZA would be found
                                        towards the bottom of the code list, not with the 04 codes)? If yes, then stop
                                        and order the EC-30 (8900075R91). An EC-17 with LED&#x2019;s (8900072R91) cannot
                                        be ordered anymore but will work if you have one at your location. If no,
                                        proceed to step 4 below.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Was the vehicle built with brake code 04AZN? If yes, then stop and you MUST
                                        order the EC-30 (8900075R91). If no, then use 8900073R91. Note: There were only
                                        50 VINS built with code 04AZN and all for the same customer. If you have not
                                        determined that the EC-30 is required from answering questions 1 through 4, then
                                        you should use the 8900073R91.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">PART NUMBER HISTORY AND USAGE:</emph>
                        Parts Distribution Centers (PDC&#x2019;s) have supplied three ECU part numbers for this
                        campaign, two "revised EC-17 part numbers", and one EC-30 part number. However, production of
                        the revised EC-17 with LED&#x2019;s (8900072R91) has stopped and this part has been replaced by
                        the EC-30 (all EC-30&#x2019;s have LED&#x2019;s).
                        <emph type="bold">ONLY 10%</emph>
                        of the vehicles in this campaign should need the EC-30. Do not order all EC-30&#x2019;s just
                        because they work for all applications. Stock of the EC-30 is limited. No more EC-17&#x2019;s
                        will be manufactured by Bendix; however, PDC&#x2019;s have a large quantity of the EC-17 without
                        LED&#x2019;s, which must be used. Reference the special green bar report for the correct part
                        number or follow the part selection guidelines provided in number 1. WHICH ECU SHOULD YOU ORDER?
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">8900072R91: NO LONGER AVAILABLE</emph>. Bendix quit making this part
                                number. This ECU is the revised EC-17 with LED&#x2019;s. The EC-30 (8900075R91) will
                                automatically be substituted when 8900072R91 is ordered. The 8900072R91 is still a good
                                part and should be used, if you have any in stock at your location.
                                <emph type="bold">Do Not</emph>
                                use with the specific EATON AUTOMATED SHIFT TRANSMISSIONS listed in Table 1 because the
                                shift points can be affected.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">8900073R91:</emph>
                                This is the EC-17 without LED&#x2019;s. Most or 90% of the vehicles in this campaign
                                should use this ECU. Use for vehicles that originally had no LED&#x2019;s or traction
                                control.
                                <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                                use for vehicles with 04AZJ, 04AZM, or 804AZA.
                                <emph type="bold">Do Not</emph>
                                use with the specific EATON AUTOMATED SHIFT TRANSMISSIONS listed in Table 1 because the
                                shift points can be affected.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">8900075R91:</emph>
                                This is the EC-30. All EC-30&#x2019;s have LED&#x2019;s. The EC-30 will be substituted
                                for all orders for the discontinued 8900072R91.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">IDENTIFYING NEW ECU&#x2019;S:</emph>
                        All replacement ECU&#x2019;s can be easily identified with a white or green adhesive stripe
                        across the top of the ECU housing and/or a green sticker on the top of the housing.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">RETURNING THE OLD PARTS AND IDENTIFYING DEFECTIVE ECU&#x2019;S:</emph>
                        Return all removed (defective) parts. Defective parts can be identified by one of the following
                        bar code sticker numbers: 5002767 (with LED) or 5002927 (without LED)
                        <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                        by International part numbers 3518871C1, 3520190C91, 3521228C91, 3527451C91 or 3533409C1.
                        Defective parts will not have the white or green adhesive stripe or the green dot sticker on the
                        ECU housing. If you have further questions on how to identify an ECU, please call Bendix at
                        1-800-AIR-BRAK. All shipments of parts in the U. S. less than 150 lbs. are to be shipped collect
                        via UPS (account A7T 571). Shipments over 150 lbs. are to be shipped collect via Yellow Freight.
                        Ship to:
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <verbatim>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Bendix ABS Recall</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">901 Cleveland Street</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Elyria, OH 44036</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0051001">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.48in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.32in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00510-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace ABS ECU</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.8 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be notified from your distributor
                location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-00510.
            </para>
            <para>Distribution: All Dealers</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
