<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 00512R - TRW Tie Rod Ends On Certain 2000, 4000, 8000, 9000 and 9000i model series built from
        7/5/1999 through 11/30/1999
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec00512">
        <recallnumber>00512R</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>TRW Tie Rod Ends On Certain 2000, 4000, 8000, 9000 and 9000i model series built from 7/5/1999 through
            11/30/1999
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>TRW</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/05/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/30/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/05/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/30/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/05/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/30/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/05/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/30/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/05/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/30/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec00512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SPECIAL NOTES: THIS SAFETY RECALL HAS BEEN REPLACED!</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Campaign 00512 has been canceled and replaced by 01510.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Campaign 01510 includes all the vehicles in campaign 00512.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Customers that had the tie rod ends replaced in 00512 were not notified for 01510.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All original copies of 00512 at your DEALERSHIP
                        <emph type="bold">MUST HAVE THE FOLLOWING NOTE WRITTEN ON THE FIRST PAGE:</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">THIS CAMPAIGN HAS BEEN REPLACED BY 01510. WARRANTY CLAIMS WILL NOT BE APPROVED
                            FOR 00512 AFTER OCTOBER 1, 2001.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>This letter will also replace letter G-00512 on ISIS.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Refer to G-01510 to make repairs for this Safety Recall.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>G-01510 instructs dealers to replace all tie rod ends in pairs for involved vehicles.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Certain TRW tie rod ends were produced with less than specified material hardness, which can result in
                separation of the ball stud from the ball socket. In the original G-00512 letter, dated October of 2000,
                there was an inspection for certain date codes; however, International is now replacing all tie rod
                ends. There is no inspection option. All tie rod ends must be replaced in pairs under the new Safety
                Recall 01510. If a tie rod end separates, the driver could experience a loss of steering control and
                <emph type="bold">cause a vehicular accident, which could result in property damage, personal injury, or
                    death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Safety Recall 00512 involved certain 2000, 4000, 8000 and 9000 model series built from 7/5/1999
                through 11/31/1999. The new 01510 Safety Recall covers all these models in addition to 5000 models and
                the build date range was expanded to cover from 6/15/1999 through 8/15/2000.
            </para>
        </defect>
    </recall>
</isis>
