<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01306 - Wiring Diagram Decal Error</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01306">
        <recallnumber>01306</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Wiring Diagram Decal Error</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/05/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01306.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This
                notice is sent to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act. American Transportation Corporation has determined that a defect which relates to motor
                vehicle safety exist in certain AmTran&#174; FE&#8482; and International&#174; FE buses. The wiring
                diagram decal located on the electrical access panel door incorrectly displays that the circuit
                protection size for circuits #7 and #8 is 30 ampere. The correct circuit size should be 20 ampere. The
                possible change to a higher amperage protection reduces the protection to the electrical components of
                the heater system. This defect is being considered a safety issue. The units were built with the proper
                size protection in the fuse panel.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected International/AmTran FE model buses were built from January 1, 1999 through November 5,
                2001.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer was supplied with his notice a strip that must be placed over the incorrect information
                on the current decal. See repair procedure.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The owner was told that they might make this repair or contact their dealer to perform this repair.
                The repair procedure requires taking the decal strip supplied with the notice and placing it over the
                current data on the existing decal. Make sure that the surface is clean and dry. The new strip has a
                protective back and when removed will stick to the current decal. The new strip shall be aligned to
                cover the same detail that is on the original decal. See picture below for more detail.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0130601" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130601.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Portion of Label on Electrical Panel Door</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. STRIP PLACEMENT AREA</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Complete and return the enclosed self-addressed and stamped "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card
                with box # 2 checked with an invoice to collect for the labor (see Recall Claims below).
            </para>
            <para>If you prefer to have your dealer make this repair, please arrange with your dealer for repair on a
                mutually agreed upon date.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Strip supplied with letter.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0130601">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Place the strip and complete documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Customer or Dealers Other Than
                    International
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to American Transportation Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance
                Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01306</emph>.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
