<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01305 - Heater/Defroster Harness Connection Wiring</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01305">
        <recallnumber>01305</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Heater/Defroster Harness Connection Wiring</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/29/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/24/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01305.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent
                to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act.
                American Transportation Corporation has determined that a defect which relates to motor vehicle safety
                exist in certain AmTran&#174; FE&#8482; and International&#174; FE buses. This defect resulted in the
                heater connection bypassing the relay for the high-speed defroster blower and a hot loose white wire
                hanging in the access compartment. The hot loose wire is protected with a 20-ampere circuit protection,
                but in a rare case could cause a fire. The defect is being considered a
                <emph type="bold">safety issue</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected International/AmTran FE model buses were built from April 29, 2001 through September 24,
                2001.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer was requested to advise the operators of the subject buses of this defect. We also
                requested the customer to have the wiring at the connector repaired. See the following repair procedure.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="7">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The owner was told that they might make this repair or contact their dealer to perform this repair.
                The repair procedure should not require any new parts. Follow the instructions below to rewire the
                connector and connect the relay into the system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If this unit does not have the loose hot wire from the power supply in the switch harness,
                        contact our Compliance Department at 1-800-843-5615.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Remove the circuit protection for circuit's number 7 and 8 on the fuse panel located just
                        under the driver's window on the outside of the unit. This protects against accidental shorting
                        while making the repair.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0130501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Fuse Panel Below Driver's Window</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CIRCUITS 7 AND 8</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>To access the connector wiring, open the right front panel (entrance door side of unit) that has the
                wiper motor system mounted. Inside this compartment you will find the connector for the heater harness.
                The heater switch harness with the gray connector has a white, brown, gray and orange wire. Also you
                will find a relay with a connector mounted to the heater box.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0130502" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Harness Connection Properly Wired</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEATER SWITCH HARNESS AND GRAY HEATER SWITCH CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WHITE HEATER HARNESS CONNECTION AND HARNESS TO HEATER BOX</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. REFERENCE: POWER STEERING RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the relay connector from the relay located on the heater housing behind this
                    connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0130503" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Correct Wiring at Relay Connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RELAY MOUNTED ON HEATER BOX</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the ring lug on the ground wire from the relay connector (the black wire in slot
                    85) to either ground stud on the bus.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0130504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Ground Screw</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. GROUND SCREWS RIGHT SIDE OF DOOR OPENING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug the switch harness connector (gray connector) from the heater harness connector
                    (white connector).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the orange wire from the switch harness connector. Plug it into slot 86 on the
                    relay connector. See detailed relay picture below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the white wire (the hot wire from the power supply in the switch harness) into slot
                    87 on the relay connector. See detailed relay picture below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the orange wire (high output) from the relay connector (location 30) into the top
                    location of the gray switch connector on the heater switch harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0130505" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130505.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Back Side of Gray Switch Harness Connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BACK SIDE OF GRAY SWITCH HARNESS CONNECTOR SHOWING POSITION TO INSERT ORANGE WIRE THAT
                        COMES FROM SLOT 30 OF RELAY CONNECTION
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0130506" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130506.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Relay Connector: Do not remove any wires plugged into relay connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SLOT 86. INSERT HIGH ORANGE OUTPUT WIRE FROM HEATER SWITCH HARNESS THAT WAS IN GRAY
                        SWITCH HARNESS CONNECTOR.
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SLOT 30 HIGH ORANGE OUTPUT WIRE. THIS WIRE WILL PLUG INTO GRAY SWITCH HARNESS
                        CONNECTOR.
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SLOT 85 BLACK GROUND WIRE. CONNECT TO GROUND STUD ON BUS.</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SLOT 87. INSERT WHITE (HOT) POWER SUPPLY WIRE FROM HEATER SWITCH HARNESS.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0130507" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130507.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Correct Assembly of Wires When Repaired</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ORANGE WIRE FROM RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BROWN WIRE IN SWITCH HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. GRAY WIRE IN SWITCH HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ORANGE WIRE IN SWITCH HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WHITE WIRE IN SWITCH HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. BLACK WIRE TO GROUND</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Finally, connect the two harness connectors and plug the relay connector into the
                    relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace circuit protection that was removed and check to make sure that the blower fan
                    operates on all three speeds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>After completing the repair, complete and return the enclosed self-addressed and stamped
                "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card with box # 2 checked with an invoice to collect for the labor
                (see Recall Claims below).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>No parts required.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0130501">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Rewire the heater connection and complete documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.5 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Customer or Dealers Other Than
                    International
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to American Transportation Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance
                Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01305</emph>.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
