<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01300 - Mirror System Non Compliance</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01300">
        <recallnumber>01300</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>May, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Mirror System Non Compliance</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/28/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/23/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent
                to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act.
                American Transportation Corporation has determined that the
                <emph type="bold">mirror system</emph>
                in certain AmTran&#174; RE and AmTran&#174; FE school buses fails to conform to federal regulation
                requirements (49 CFR 571.111 9.3(a), also known as FMVSS No.111, Section 9.3(a)).
            </para>
            <para>On some of the subject AmTran RE and AmTran FE buses, the lower support arm of the driver's left side
                rear view mirror obscures the line of sight from the left crossview mirror to the top surface of two
                FMVSS 111 test cylinders located at the centerline of the rear axle. The mirror system involved is with
                the Rosco non-breakaway left driver's mirror only. The same two cylinders that are obscured through the
                cross view mirror are very visible through the left driver's mirror.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected AmTran FE and AmTran RE model school buses were built from August 28, 2000 through March
                23, 2001.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer has been sent a recall letter asking them to complete and return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card that was enclosed with their notice.
                When the card is returned to us with box number 8 checked, we will forward to their attention a kit and
                instructions to move the left driver's mirror to eliminate the obscured line of sight.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The owner was told that they may make this repair or contact their dealer to perform this repair. The
                repair procedure involves the driver's left rear view mirror only.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RE Models:</emph>
                Remove the driver's mirror from the bus. Apply new sealer to the mirror mounting angles and remount the
                mirror to the bus by locating the lowest mounting angle to the second hole from the bottom of the
                original four hole mounting pattern. This will raise the mirror 3 1/8 inches from its original location.
                The third mounting angle from the bottom will align with the top hole of the original four-hole pattern.
                Using a 7/64 drill bit, drill two new holes to mount the second and forth mounting angle from the
                bottom, using the angles as a template. Use the same screws to remount the mirror. Use the same type of
                screws to plug the unused holes.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0130001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Relocated Mirror Mounting on RE Model</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TWO HOLES NEED TO BE ADDED</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXISTING HOLES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FE Models:</emph>
                Remove the driver's mirror from the bus. Disassemble the hardware to turn the upper arm upper mounting
                angle upside down and reassemble the hardware. Apply new sealer to the mirror mounting angles and
                remount the mirror to the bus by locating the lowest mounting angle to the second hole from the bottom
                of the original four hole mounting pattern. This will raise the mirror 3 1/8 inches from its original
                location. The third mounting angle from the bottom will align with the top hole of the original
                four-hole pattern. Using a 7/64 drill bit, drill one new hole to mount the second mounting angle from
                the bottom, using the angle as a template. Use the same screws to remount the mirror. Use the same type
                of screws to plug the unused holes.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0130002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Mounting Holes</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. NEW HOLE REQUIRED</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ORIGINAL 4 MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0130003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130003.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>FE Showing New Location of the 3-Point Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FE MODEL UPPER ARM UPPER MOUNTING ANGLE MOUNTED UPSIDE DOWN PER INSTRUCTIONS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0130001">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.51in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.60in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443569001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Screw, Self Drilling &#188; x 1 &#188;" SST</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>FE-1; RE-2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443271001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Sealing Tape</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>5 inch piece</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0130002">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.98in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.58in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove, rework and install mirror assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Complete recall information</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Safety Recall
                01300.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
