<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01301 - IC (Bus Boy) Cross View Mirror System</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01301">
        <recallnumber>01301</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>IC (Bus Boy) Cross View Mirror System</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/06/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/23/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01301.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent
                to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act.
                American Transportation Corporation has determined that the cross view
                <emph type="bold">mirror system</emph>
                in certain International&#174; IC school buses fails to conform to federal regulation requirements (49
                CFR 571.111 9.3(a), also known as FMVSS No.111, Section 9.3(a)).
            </para>
            <para>On the subject International IC school buses, the lower support arm of the left and right side cross
                view mirrors were mounted too low. The line of sight from the driver to the cross view mirrors may be
                obscured by the dash panel. The mirror system involved is with the Bus Boy cross view mirrors only.
                <emph type="bold">Obstruction of the line of sight to the cross view mirrors could prevent the bus
                    driver from seeing passengers in the area that is normally viewed with the aid of the cross view
                    mirrors, which might result in an accident that could cause injury and/or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected International IC model school buses were built from April 6, 2000 through April 23,
                2001.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer was requested to advise the operators of the subject buses of this defect. Make sure that
                the drivers adjust all mirrors for proper visibility before operating the school bus. Complete and
                return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card. When the card is returned to us with
                box number 8 checked, we will forward to their attention a kit and instructions to move the cross view
                mirrors up to eliminate the potential obscured line of sight.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The owner was told that they may make this repair or contact their dealer to perform this repair. The
                repair procedure involves replacing both cross view mirror support systems using the existing mirror
                heads and mounting holes. Complete instructions to make the repair are included with the kit and no
                special tools are required.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0130101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.15in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.41in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Replacement parts for black mirror option</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>452384005</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Base &#38; Arm Assy L/H Black</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>452384006</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Base &#38; Arm Assy R/H Black</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Replacement parts for stainless steel mirror option</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>452384007</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Base &#38; Arm Assy L/H SST</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>452384008</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Base &#38; Arm Assy R/H SST</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0130102">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.68in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.18in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove, and install new mirror support assemblies</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.9 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Complete recall information</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Safety Recall
                01301.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
