<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01303 - Flip Seat Support Binding</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01303">
        <recallnumber>01303</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Flip Seat Support Binding</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/18/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/25/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/18/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/25/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01303.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01303.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent
                to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act.
                American Transportation Corporation has determined that a defect which relates to motor vehicle safety
                exist in certain AmTran&#174; and International&#174; RE, AmTran&#174; and International&#174; FE,
                AmTran&#174; and International&#174; Conventional Bus Body, and International&#174; IC school buses.
                These buses have one or two 39-inch wide flip seats that may bind in the occupied position and not
                automatically return to the stored upright position when not occupied. This condition is considered a
                safety issue since it could block the aisle to the emergency exit during an emergency, which could
                result in injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>The cushion frame support bar slides off the seat support pad. When this occurs, the tabs can wedge
                against the support bar, which may retain the seat in the occupied position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0130301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Picture Showing Cushion Frame Support Bar Ready to Slip Off Seat Support Tab</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CUSHION FRAME SUPPORT BAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SEAT SUPPORT TAB</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected AmTran and International buses with 39-inch wide flip seats were built from August 18,
                1999 through July 25, 2001.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer was requested to inspect his bus for this defect and informed of the following. If the
                seat catches on the seat support pads when in the occupied position, lift up on the seat to return it to
                the upright position. If the bus must be used prior to repairing this defect, actions must be taken to
                prevent passengers from occupying this seat. Advise the operators of the subject buses of this defect.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">All units built in the above time frame with 39-inch flip seats must have this recall
                    repair performed.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The owner was told that they might make this repair or contact their dealer to perform this repair.
            </para>
            <para>The repair procedure involves adding a "Z" shaped bracket to the underside of the seat. The following
                steps must be followed to repair the defect.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Proper eye protection must be worn while operating power tools.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the existing seat retaining clip.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The "Z" shaped bracket must be attached to the "Cushion Frame Support Bar" and the bottom side
                        of the seat. The short leg of the bracket must face the rear of the seat. The bracket must be
                        centered width wise on the "Cushion Frame Support Bar". The front edge of the bracket should
                        align with the front face of the "Cushion Frame Support Bar". Make sure that the bracket will
                        contact both "Seat Support Tabs".
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Using the holes provided in the bracket as a location guide, use a # 16 (0.1770) drill bit to
                        drill three holes in the "Cushion Frame Support Bar" and three holes in the seat cushion plywood
                        base.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">CAUTION: Do not drill completely through the plywood.</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the supplied screws in all six holes.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Complete and return the self addressed "
                        <emph type="bold">RECALL REPAIR REPLY CARD</emph>" included with the kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f0130302" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0130302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="200"/>
                <caption>Repaired Seat with "Z" Bracket</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CUSHION FRAME SUPPORT BAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. "Z" BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SEAT SUPPORT TAB</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0130301">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.85*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.34*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>452875001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Kit, Recall 01303</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1 required per 39-inch flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0130302">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.1 hr per bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Complete recall information</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.2 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Customer or Dealers Other Than
                    International
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to American Transportation Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance
                Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01303</emph>.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
