<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01503 - Limiting the forward travel on the driver's seat by installing a stop-bracket on the adjuster
        track for 4700 models built from 9/5/98 through 3/2/01
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec01503">
        <recallnumber>01503</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subject>Limiting the forward travel on the driver's seat by installing a stop-bracket on the adjuster track for
            4700 models built from 9/5/98 through 3/2/01
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/02/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01503.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01503.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>If someone outside the cab adjusts/slides the driver's seat to its most forward position, with the
                parking brake set, the seat will contact and release the parking brake lever. If the parking brake is
                accidentally released the vehicle could move unexpectedly and
                <emph type="boldundersc">the vehicle could be involved in an accident resulting in property damage,
                    personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>Only 4700 models built from 9/5/98 through 3/2/01 with Bostrom driver's
                seat models (910, 910SC, or 914) and with parking brake code 04036.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign. A
                copy of the owner letter is attached. During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses
                will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION</emph>: This procedure is for the installation of a seat stop-bracket on
                the driver's seat track to limit the forward travel of the seat so that the seat can not push the
                parking brake lever forward and release it. The seat may still touch the parking brake lever when the
                lever is in the brake-set-position and the seat is all the way forward; however, the seat will not
                travel forward enough to release the lever.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INSTALLING THE SEAT STOP BRACKET:</title>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0150301">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on level ground, put the transmission in neutral, set the parking brake
                    and shut off the engine.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions. If the vehicle
                            rolls unexpectedly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide/adjust the driver's seat as far back as it will go (most rearward position).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the seat to the highest position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert stop-bracket "B", in the orientation as shown in Figure 1, through the opening in
                    the top of the seat suspension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align hole "1" in the stop-bracket with hole "2" in the upper plate of the seat
                    suspension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert screw "A" into hole "2" but do not tighten (use a &#189;" socket).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat step 6 and 7 for the other side of the stop-bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten both screws to 20 Lbf-Ft or 27 NM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the parking brake set, stand outside the vehicle, slide the driver's seat all the
                    way forward and verify that the seat will stop before releasing the parking brake lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0150301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0150301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption></caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1 - One hole in each side/end of stop-bracket</callout1>
                    <callout1>2 - One existing hole in each side of upper plate of seat suspension</callout1>
                    <callout1>A - Two screws to hold stop-bracket to upper plate of seat suspension</callout1>
                    <callout1>B - Stop-bracket proper orientation</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>There is one recall kit part number that is used for this campaign (
                <emph type="bold">8900077R91</emph>). Each vehicle in this campaign will require only one kit.
            </para>
            <table id="t0150301">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.72in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.18in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>CONTENTS for Service Kit 8900077R91</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Stop-Bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>3566980C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Screw, 5/16" X &#189;" washer head</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>3566984C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Instructions (same as instructions in this letter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>2507042R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note: Only one labor operation should be used for vehicles in this campaign.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0150302">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.90in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.16in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" align="left" charoff="50" char="" colwidth="2.00in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01503-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install seat-stop bracket</para>
                                <para>Kit #8900077R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>0.4 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">Campaign Identification Label</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable
                allowance for depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each
                owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall letter
                G-01503.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter.</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
