<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01502 - Automatic Brake Adjuster Anchor Brackets On Air Brake Vehicles With Long Stroke Brake
        Chambers, Eaton / Spicer Brakes, And Built From 10/7/96 Through 11/14/00
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec01502">
        <recallnumber>01502</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>February, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Automatic Brake Adjuster Anchor Brackets On Air Brake Vehicles With Long Stroke Brake Chambers, Eaton /
            Spicer Brakes, And Built From 10/7/96 Through 11/14/00
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>8100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/14/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Eaton</vendor>
                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01502.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01502.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The automatic brake adjuster anchor brackets may fail and completely separate, causing the automatic
                brake adjusters to function as manual brake adjusters. If the anchor bracket for an automatic brake
                adjuster fails, the brakes at that wheel end will not automatically adjust. As the brake linings wear on
                a wheel end without automatic adjustment,
                <emph type="bold">the vehicle could have reduced braking capacity and the vehicle could be involved in
                    an accident resulting in property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>All 8100, 9100, 9100i, 9200, 9200i, 9300, 9400, 9400i, and 9900i models built from 10/7/96 through
                11/14/00 with EATON / SPICER (Haldex) automatic brake adjusters, long stroke brake chambers, and EATON /
                SPICER brakes.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>INSPECTING AND REPLACING THE BRAKE ADJUSTER ANCHOR BRACKETS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                These brackets are used on rear axles only. All vehicles in this campaign will either have two or four
                brake adjuster anchor brackets that will have to be inspected prior to replacement. Single rear axle (4
                X 2) vehicles have two brackets and tandem axle vehicles (6 X 4) have four brackets. Most, but not all
                brackets will have to be replaced. Replace brackets according to the inspection in step 6 below.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on level ground, put the transmission in neutral, set the parking brake
                    and shut off the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions. If the vehicle
                            rolls unexpectedly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over and cause
                            injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary to raise the vehicle in order to remove the brake adjuster anchor brackets,
                    support the vehicle with safety stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply air to release the spring brake, assure the pushrod is fully retracted. If air is
                    not available, the spring brake must be caged back.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">INSPECTION: REQUIRED</emph>: Before replacing the anchor brackets, follow the
                    replacement rules below and reference
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>. Some tandem axle vehicles were manufactured with the
                    correct bracket and brake adjuster combination on one axle but not the other.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Putting the anchor bracket for this campaign on the wrong slack adjuster can cause tight
                            or dragging brakes.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="boldundersc">GOOD ANCHOR BRACKETS (FACTORY INSTALLED):</emph>
                    Good brackets have a double bend as shown in the left figure of
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">may have</emph>
                    a "500" stamped on the longest part of the bracket.
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT REPLACE THESE BRACKETS OR TIGHT OR DRAGGING BRAKES MAY OCCUR.</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="boldundersc">DEFECTIVE ANCHOR BRACKETS:</emph>
                    Defective brackets DO NOT have a double bend. Compare the left figure and the middle figure of
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>. All defective brackets will look like the one in the
                    middle figure and
                    <emph type="bold">may have</emph>
                    a "430" stamped on the longest part of the bracket.
                    <emph type="bold">Change all brackets that match this description.</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="boldundersc">REPLACEMENT BRACKET SUPPLIED FOR THIS CAMPAIGN:</emph>
                    The replacement bracket supplied for this campaign does not have a double bend like the originally
                    installed good bracket but it is physically different than the defective bracket. When this part is
                    installed correctly there will not be a bend or bow near the control arm stud (see the right figure
                    of
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>
                    below).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0150201" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0150201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption></caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>LEFT FIGURE: Do Not Replace brackets that have a double bend as shown above.
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>MIDDLE FIGURE: Replace brackets that look like the above bracket with no double bend.
                            The bracket will be bowed or bent at the control arm slot.
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>RIGHT FIGURE: View with recall part 2506341C1 installed correctly should have no
                            bending at the control arm slot.
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a &#189;" wrench, remove the nut holding the anchor bracket to the control arm.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a six-point 7/16" wrench rotate the adjusting hex counter-clockwise. A racheting
                    sound will occur. This will back off the brake and allow the travel necessary to remove the air
                    chamber mounting nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 15/16" wrench, remove the air chamber mounting nut and flat washer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the anchor bracket and scrape away any debris or material on the area where the
                    anchor bracket mounts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the new bracket over the air chamber stud and the control arm stud. Install the
                    air chamber flat washer and nut. Snug the nut and verify that the bracket is flat against the
                    mounting surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten and torque the air chamber stud nut to 105 - 125 ft-lbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assure that the system air pressure is above 85 psi and the brake chamber pushrod is
                    fully retracted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the adjusting hex clockwise until the brake shoes hit the brake drum.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the adjusting hex counter-clockwise &#189; turn.
                    <emph type="bold">The control arm is now out of position.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To position the control arm. Rotate the control arm counter-clockwise as viewed in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>
                    or away from the adjusting hex and towards the air chamber until it comes to a definite internal
                    stop. If the control arm is mis-positioned, TIGHT BRAKES WILL OCCUR.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and tighten the control arm nut to 10 - 15 ft-lbs. Assure that the control arm
                    does not move out of position while tightening. Verify that the anchor bracket it not bent or bowed
                    at the control arm slot and that it is correctly installed as shown in the right figure of
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0150201">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Uncage the brake chamber if caged in step 5.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not return or reuse the defective brackets, destroy and recycle the defective
                    brackets locally.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>There is one bracket part number that is used for this campaign (
                <emph type="bold">2506341C1</emph>). Vehicles in this campaign will require either two or four brackets
                (see inspection step 6 of Service Procedure).
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note:</emph>Only one labor operation should be used per vehicle for this campaign,
                either operation 1 or 2 below.
            </para>
            <table id="t0150201">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.48in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.32in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-01502-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R two anchor brackets</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-01502-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R four anchor brackets</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.9 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                G-01502.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>Distribution: All Dealers</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
