<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01501 - Changing the brake pedals on all 1652 stripped chassis built from 6/12/00 through 11/17/00
        and all IC buses built from 3/2/00 through 12/4/00. All of these vehicles have hydraulic brakes and automatic
        transmissions.
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec01501">
        <recallnumber>01501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>February, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Changing the brake pedals on all 1652 stripped chassis built from 6/12/00 through 11/17/00 and all IC
            buses built from 3/2/00 through 12/4/00. All of these vehicles have hydraulic brakes and automatic
            transmissions.
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1652
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/12/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/17/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>IC BUS
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/02/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/04/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>This defect involves the alignment of the brake pedal with the pressure activated brake switch. The
                original brake pedal may not activate the brake lights during light-pedal-pressure braking. To correct
                this defect, a new pedal has been designed and must be installed on all vehicles in this campaign.
                <emph type="boldundersc">If the brake lights do not activate properly, the vehicle could be involved in
                    an accident resulting in property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>This Safety Recall involves all 1652 stripped chassis built from 6/12/00
                through 11/17/00 and all IC buses built from 3/2/00 through 12/4/00. These vehicles also have hydraulic
                brakes and automatic transmissions.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign. A
                copy of the owner letter is attached. During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses
                will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <title>REMOVING THE BRAKE PEDAL</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on level ground, put the transmission in neutral, set the parking brake and
                        shut off the engine.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">WARNING: BLOCK THE WHEELS TO PREVENT THE VEHICLE FROM MOVING IN BOTH
                            DIRECTIONS. IF THE VEHICLE ROLLS UNEXPECTEDLY, THE RESULT COULD BE SERIOUS PERSONAL INJURY
                            OR DEATH.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Disconnect the brake switch wiring and note that the connector points down.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Note the position of the brake switch before removing. The brake switch is mounted on the left
                        (driver's side) of the brake pedal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the cotter pin, clevis pin, and brake switch.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the nut from the brake pedal pivot bolt. There is a bushing on each end of the pedal
                        tube, be careful not to drop the bushings as you remove the brake pedal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the bolt, pedal with two bushings, and the spacer.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Do not return the defective pedal, destroy and recycle the defective pedal locally.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <title>INSTALLING THE NEW BRAKE PEDAL</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Transfer the brake pedal pad and both bushings to the new pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the new pedal, bolt, spacer, and nut. Torque the nut to 75 - 85 foot pounds.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the brake switch, clevis pin, and cotter pin. Make sure the brake switch is mounted on
                        the left side (driver's side) of the pedal with the connector pointing down.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Reconnect the brake switch wiring.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the vehicle running and in forward gear, apply the brakes just enough to keep the vehicle
                        from moving forward and make sure the brake lights are on.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Ordering parts:</emph>
                Order one brake pedal for each vehicle in this campaign. There are two different pedal numbers, one for
                each model in this campaign.
            </para>
            <table id="t0150101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>1652 Stripped Chassis use:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>3542173C2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>IC Buses use:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>3542136C2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Returning parts:</emph>
                Do not return the defective pedal, destroy and recycle the defective pedal locally.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Only one labor operation is required for this campaign.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0150102">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.90in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.16in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" align="left" charoff="50" char="" colwidth="2.00in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R brake pedal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>0.6 hrs</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">Campaign Identification Label</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable
                allowance for depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each
                owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="520px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be notified from your distributor
                location.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter.</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
