<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01512-R1 - Lower Steering Shafts On 9000i and 5000i Models built in July and August of 2001</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01512">
        <recallnumber>01512-R1</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 2007</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>Lower Steering Shafts On 9000i and 5000i Models built in July and August of 2001</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/27/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/23/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/27/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/23/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">REVISION DESCRIPTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">SERVICE PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Removed Item 14. Parts are no longer required to be returned.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">INSPECTING AND REPLACING THE LOWER STEERING SHAFT -</emph>
                        Section revised.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">PARTS INFORMATION</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Fax form REMOVED.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>New part number tables added.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Parts are no longer required to be returned.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">LABOR INFORMATION</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Handling charge note removed. Dealer handling charge will be as any other part purchased from
                        the PDC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The steering could fail at any time without warning under normal driving conditions. The potential for
                failure is due to a mis-located weld on the lower steering shaft. If the vehicle has a defective
                steering shaft, there could be a complete loss of steering control.
                <emph type="bold">This could cause an accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury,
                    or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>All 9000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                and 5000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                models built at the following assembly plants with the following build date ranges.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Chatham: 7/27/01 through 8/17/01</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Garland: 7/27/01 through 8/20/01</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Escobedo: 7/27/01 through 8/23/01</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTING AND REPLACING THE LOWER STEERING SHAFT</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">All vehicles in this recall must have the steering shaft replaced. There is no
                            inspection option for this campaign.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If further instructions are needed at any point in this repair procedure refer to
                        International's Master Service Manual. Follow all standard safety precautions and procedures
                        recommended by International's Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position steering wheel to provide access to steering yoke pinch bolt at bottom of
                    steering column.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the brakes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plastic tie strap at the cowl boot bushing, outside the cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>On some models, the outside bushing hole is vertically offset. Please note its position
                            and re-install it in the same position. Pull both plastic bushings out of the boot and
                            remove it from the shaft by separating the two pieces of the bushing. Be careful not to
                            damage the bushings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the yoke pinch bolt at the lower end of the shaft (at steering gear).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the yoke pinch bolt at the upper end of the shaft (at bottom of steering column,
                    in cab).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip both end yokes off the splined shafts and compress the steering shaft. Carefully
                    slide the shaft through the cowl boot from the inside out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip the new shaft back through the boot from outside the cab. Be careful not to damage
                    the boot during installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the yoke on the steering gear shaft and tighten the pinch bolt to 60 Lbf-Ft (81
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the yoke on the steering column shaft and torque pinch bolt to 60 Lbf-Ft (81
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the upper and lower plastic bushings and then slip into position inside the
                    boot.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new plastic tie strap around the boot at the oval bushing, outside the
                    cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The following parts are required to complete this recall service procedure:</para>
            <table id="t0151201" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.50*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3530957C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>I-SHAFT, for the following VINs ONLY: 2C032490, 2C033093, 2C033817, 2C033818,
                                    2C033819, 2C033820, 2C035124, 2C035125, 2J032260, 2J032112
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3530955C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>I-SHAFT, all other VINs</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Review the REMARKS in the Parts Catalog Online system to determine the proper I-Shaft part number for
                your vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Please order parts from the PDC.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">All removed parts are to be destroyed locally.</emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0151202" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01512-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R Lower Steering Shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.6 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01512-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R Lower Steering Shaft With butterfly hood, 09ASA</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.8 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance
                for depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to
                repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Notes:</emph>
                No inspection option is offered for this campaign; therefore, the disposition for this campaign cannot
                be a 1.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01512</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
