<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01513 - Secondary Air Lines On 5000i Models built from 7/17/01 through 8/29/01</stitle>
    <recall id="rec01513">
        <recallnumber>01513</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Secondary Air Lines On 5000i Models built from 7/17/01 through 8/29/01</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/17/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/29/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01513.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01513.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The secondary air brake line that connects the foot valve with the spring brake valve (or inversion
                valve) may not have been installed. If there is a failure in the primary system and the secondary brake
                line has not been installed, only the front brakes would actuate, without rear spring brake actuation.
            </para>
            <para>Upon failure of the primary air system, a warning light and buzzer will turn on, and only the front
                brakes will actuate, without rear spring brake actuation. This would result in an extended stopping
                distance,
                <emph type="bold">which could cause a vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage,
                    personal injury or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>All 5000i models built at Garland from 7/17/01 through 8/29/01.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                There is a 3/8-inch orange secondary air line that must be inspected to determine if it was installed
                properly at the vehicle assembly plant. Some foot valves were incorrectly assembled with a plug in the
                port where the 3/8-inch orange secondary air line should have been installed (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0151302">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The following procedure is necessary to inspect and repair
                the suspect air line. Parts that may be needed to complete the installation of the brake line are listed
                in the "PART INFORMATION" section of this letter.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following procedure and
                    instructions completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If further instructions are needed at any point in this repair procedure refer to
                        International&#x2019;s Master Service Manual. Follow all standard safety precautions and
                        procedures recommended by International&#x2019;s Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the foot valve (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0151301">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the foot valve: The 3/8-inch orange air line should be connected to the port
                    shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0151302">Figure 2</hotlnk>; however, on some vehicles, you may find a plug in the
                    foot valve port where the 3/8-inch orange line should be connected. Make note and continue to step
                    5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the 3/8-inch orange air line: The air line should be connected at the coupling
                    (item 4) shown in Figure 1 and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0151303">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                    and it should also be connected to the inversion valve (Item 7) as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0151304">Figure 4</hotlnk>. If the air line is properly connected as inspected in
                    step 4 and 5, then stop and submit a claim for inspection only. If the air line is not installed
                    properly, continue to step 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the air line is present, make sure it is disconnected at the foot valve and at the
                    inversion valve and blow the dirt out of the line with pressurized air. If the air line has been cut
                    or is not present, install a new air line and follow the routing shown in Figures 1, 3 and 4. The
                    air line is part of the harness for trucks, but is separate from the harness for tractors. The
                    inversion valve is standard with air brakes on straight trucks but is optional on tractors. For
                    tractors use a 63-inch piece of air line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the plug is present, remove the plug from the foot valve port where the air line
                    should be connected and connect the air line (see Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the air line at the inversion valve (see Figure 4).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the air line at the coupling (see Item 4 in Figure 1 and Figure 3) if it was not
                    connected at the assembly plant. The air line should now be properly installed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the air brake system. Bring the air brake system pressure up to operating pressure
                    and then drain the air from the primary system. With the parking brake disconnected, have someone
                    watch the parking brake chamber slack adjusters as the brakes are applied. The slack adjuster motion
                    indicates a properly operating system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0151301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0151301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Bottom View of Cab Showing Foot Valve Location</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FOOT VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE IN QUESTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. UNDER CAB AIR HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. COUPLING: ON 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. AIR HARNESS P-CLAMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0151302" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0151302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Foot Valve Viewed in the Direction of Arrow A in Figure 1 (Viewed from the rear)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FOOT VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0151303" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0151303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>3/8-Inch Orange Air Line Routing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>2. 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE IN QUESTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. UNDER CAB AIR HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. COUPLING: ON 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE TO INVERSION VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0151304" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0151304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>3/8-Inch Orange Air Line Routing To The Inversion Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>6. 3/8-INCH ORANGE AIR LINE TO INVERSION VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ELBOW AT INVERSION VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INVERSION VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parts Ordering:</emph>
                In this campaign we expect 30% of the vehicles to require some sort of repair to the secondary air line
                while 70% will only require a visual inspection. To repair a vehicle for this campaign, a combination of
                the following parts may be required from Table 1 below.
            </para>
            <table id="t0151301">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.49*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.51*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Description/ Application</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3/8" Orange nylon tubing,used from the foot valve to the connector on all vehicles
                                    and from the connector to the inversion valve on vehicles not with 04675.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>2643441R1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3/8" Quick connect connector, used for nylon to nylon connections not with 04675
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>2017507C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: The next two parts serve the same purpose as 2017507C1
                                        above; however, they are used to connect nylon tubing to hose provided with
                                        optional code 04675. Both parts below are required to make one connection of
                                        this type.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3/8" Hose to &#188;" female pipe thread</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>121323</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3/8" Quick connect to &#188;" male pipe thread</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>2017484C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>&#8226;
                <emph type="bold">There is an inspection option for this campaign because 70% of the secondary air lines
                    on these vehicles are expected to be properly installed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>&#8226;
                <emph type="bold">Claims will not be approved if they have more than one of the labor operations shown
                    below, because labor operation 2 includes inspection.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>&#8226;
                <emph type="bold">Do not submit both labor operations 1 and 2 on a claim.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0151301">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01513-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect air line only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01513-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect, perform air line installation and test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.8 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance
                for depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to
                repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01513</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter.</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
