<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 01514 Revision A - Reprogramming the ESC to Prevent Software Fusing of the Headlights on 4300 and4400
        Models Built from 10/24/00 through 11/07/01
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec01514">
        <recallnumber>01514 Revision A</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Reprogramming the ESC to Prevent Software Fusing of the Headlights on 4300 and4400 Models Built from
            10/24/00 through 11/07/01
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/07/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/07/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec01514.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus01514.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DETAILS OF THIS REVISION</title>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Replace all copies of the original letter with this Revision A letter throughout your
                        location.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>We have revised the service procedure section with the latest software versions and eliminated
                        METHOD #3.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Additional vehicles have been included in this campaign, which also changed the END of the
                        build date range from 9/19/01 to
                        <emph type="bold">11/07/01</emph>.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Separate software fuses within the Electrical System Controller (ESC) control the low and high beam
                headlights. A software problem within the ESC can cause the circuit for the low beam or the circuit for
                the high beam headlights to fuse or open, resulting in loss of either the low or high beam headlights or
                possibly even both. Repeated switching from low to high or from high to low beam headlights can induce
                this condition. If the low/high beam headlight circuit fuses, the software will turn off the low/high
                beam headlights for a half second and then try to turn on the lights again. If the software determines
                that the fault is still present, it will turn the low/high beam headlights off for a second. As long as
                the fault is still present, the off-time will increase in doubling increments to a maximum off-time of
                512 seconds. If the fault is still present at this point, the low/high beam headlights will be turned
                off and the software will not try to turn on the lights again until the ignition key is cycled once.
            </para>
            <para>A headlight fusing condition could occur without warning to the driver and potentially leave the
                driver in a blackout situation while operating the vehicle in the dark. A headlight blackout condition
                could cause a vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>All 4300 and 4400 models built from 10/24/00 through
                <emph type="bold">11/07/01</emph>.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT CAMPAIGN INFORMATION PLEASE READ!</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>All the vehicles that were originally marked for AFC 01911 must have Safety Recall 01514
                            performed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The software used for this Safety Recall, 01514, includes the changes required for AFC
                            01911; therefore, AFC 01911 has been canceled.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Safety Recall 01514 and AFC 01911 will be completed with software version 13 or higher for
                            Infineon based ESC's or software version 105 or higher for Hitachi based ESC's.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Please discard all CD's received for 01911. They are outdated due to the release of new
                            software for Safety Recall 01514 (9/20/01).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Upon the release of this campaign, Safety Recall 01514 replaced 01911 on the VIN records
                            of vehicles that were not completed in AFC 01911.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>There are two methods by which the ESC reprogramming can be executed using International
                            Configuration, Authorized Field Change and Programming Tool (ICAP):
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Method 1:</emph>
                            Use ICAP to perform a reconfigure ESC operation
                            <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Method 2:</emph>
                            Use ICAP to perform a replace ESC operation.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following procedure
                        and instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>METHOD 1: Use ICAP to Perform a Reconfigure ESC Operation</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1"></para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the parking brake.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Launch ICAP.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure that you have ICAP version 1.7 loaded on your EZ-Tech.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select item 1,
                        <emph type="bold">Get Data</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter the last 8 digits of the VIN number for the vehicle to be programmed, select
                        the radio button for Re-Configure, and select the radio button for Get from International.
                        Select
                        <emph type="bold">Add Chassis</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Next</emph>
                        button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the chassis to reconfigure then select the
                        <emph type="bold">Next</emph>button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select connection type, DCN 2 or DCN 2 dial-up.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter appropriate username(s) and password(s).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Submit</emph>
                        button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">A message window will appear that states "There are no added or deleted features to
                        submit. Do you wish to submit." Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Yes</emph>
                        button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">A message window will appear that states "Submit Successful." Select the
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                        button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Complete</emph>
                        button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If you select to automatically receive the program back, you will be prompted to
                        please wait, after which the file will download file 1 of 1.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If you select to manually receive the file later, click on item 4,
                        <emph type="bold">Manual Receive</emph>, from the ICAP main screen. Enter the chassis number and
                        receive the program.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">After programming make sure you reconnect to International ICAP and send the
                            programming confirmations by clicking "Manual History Update" from the ICAP main screen. You
                            may want to do this periodically; however, the time between uploading this information
                            should be kept to a minimum because warranty claims won't be approved for payment until the
                            Data Base verifies the reprogramming has been completed and a "Y" is marked on the VIN
                            record. As soon as the claim is processed the "Y" will be replaced by a "2" to show
                            completion.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>METHOD 2: Use ICAP to Perform a Replace ESC Operation (Note, you can only process 2 vehicles at a
                    time using the replace operation)
                </title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1"></para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the parking brake.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Launch ICAP.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure that you have ICAP version 1.7 loaded on your EZ-Tech.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select item 1,
                        <emph type="bold">Get Data</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter the last 8 digits of the VIN number for the vehicle to be reprogrammed, select
                        the radio button for Replace ESC, and enter the serial number of the ESC that you want to
                        program. Select
                        <emph type="bold">Add Chassis</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the chassis to reprogram and then select
                        <emph type="bold">Next</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select how you will receive the program file back,
                        <emph type="bold">Automatically</emph>
                        or
                        <emph type="bold">Manually receive later</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select connection type, DCN 2 or DCN 2 dial-up.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter appropriate username(s) and password(s).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If you selected to automatically receive the program back, you will be prompted to
                        please wait, after which the file will download file 1 of 1.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If you selected to manually receive the file later, click on item 4,
                        <emph type="bold">Manual Receive</emph>, from the ICAP main screen. Enter the chassis number and
                        receive the program.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">After programming make sure you reconnect to International ICAP and send the
                            programming confirmations by clicking "Manual History Update" from the ICAP main screen. You
                            may want to do this periodically; however, the time between uploading this information
                            should be kept to a minimum because warranty claims won't be approved for payment until the
                            Data Base verifies that the reprogramming has been completed and a "Y" is marked on the VIN
                            record. As soon as the claim is processed the "Y" will be replaced by a "2" to show
                            completion.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">No warranty claims for 01514 should have parts involved because, this campaign is for
                    software reprogramming only.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>&#8226; There is one labor operation for this campaign.</para>
            <para>&#8226; Warranty claims will not be approved for more than 0.5 hrs.</para>
            <table id="t0151401">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-01514-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Reprogram ESC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.5 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance
                for depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to
                repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-01514</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter.</para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
