<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02302 - Stepwell Joint</stitle>
    <recall id="rec02302">
        <recallnumber>02302</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Stepwell Joint</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/12/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02302.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02302.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice: "This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has determined that the vertical stepwell joint in the RE school bus entrance door may fail to conform
                to federal regulation requirements (49 CFR 571.221 S5, also known as FMVSS No.221, Section S5)".
            </para>
            <para>On some of the subject RE buses, if the vertical joints on the forward and rear side of the stepwell
                are assembled with rivets only, at a spacing of about two inches, the stepwell is incorrectly assembled
                and will not meet joint strength requirements per the above regulation. See pictures below that show the
                location and types of the joints.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0230201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0230201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - (NON-COMPLIANT) Picture of riveted vertical joint on the forward side of the
                    entrance door stepwell that reaches from the second step to the floor trim. This same joint is
                    duplicated on the rear side of the stepwell. This picture shows the vertical joint assembled with
                    rivets at a spacing of about two inches and does not meet the requirements of the regulation.
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0230202" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0230202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2 - (COMPLIANT) Picture of welded vertical joint on the rear side of the entrance door
                    stepwell that reaches from the second step to the floor trim. This same joint is duplicated on the
                    forward side of the stepwell. This picture shows welded joint with a trim part covering the seam.
                    This joint is compliant and is not involved in the recall.
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected RE model school buses were built from January 1, 2001 through June 12, 2002.</para>
            <para>
                <title>ACTIONS REQUIRED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The customer was told, if the joint is assembled with rivets spaced at approximately two inch
                increments (no additional screws or rivets) the joint must be repaired (reference Picture # 1). Follow
                the repair procedures stated below.
            </para>
            <para>If the joint is not assembled with rivets and has a trim panel with a few screws (reference Picture #
                2), it does not require repair. Please complete and return the enclosed "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card with box # 1 checked (Inspected - No
                corrections necessary).
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <stitle>Recall 02302 - Stepwell Joint</stitle>
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The customer was told that their dealer would make this correction for them at no cost and to contact
                their dealer to make the arrangements to repair the unit.
            </para>
            <para>They were also told, if they desired to make this repair themselves, they could purchase the screws
                from their dealer or their local hardware center. When they invoice us for the cost of labor they may
                add the cost for miscellaneous materials that will include the cost of the screws. If the miscellaneous
                materials exceed $3.00 per unit, a receipt must be attached to the invoice. If for some reason they were
                unable to obtain the screws from their local dealer or hardware center, they may return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card with box # 8 checked and we would ship
                the screws directly to them at no charge.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers, you may purchase the parts directly from the Parts Depot. If you purchase the screws, you
                will receive two boxes of 100 screws each. Keep this in mind when ordering these parts. You also have
                the same option as the customer for charging the cost of material. When filing your labor charges you
                may add up to $3.00 per unit for miscellaneous materials including the cost of the screws.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform this repair.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>This repair procedure involves adding approximately 26 screws, (13 per side) to the vertical joints.
                No special tools are required. Pilot holes must be drilled prior to installing the screws using a
                3/16-inch (#10) bit. Screws are to be located as follows. Insert one screw approximately 1 inch above
                the top rivet but no closer than about &#189; inch from the top edge of the metal piece on the forward
                joint and not to interfere with the floor trim piece on the rear side of the stepwell. Then insert two
                screws evenly spaced between the existing rivets.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0230203" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0230203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3 - Example Showing Repair to the Forward Joint By Adding Screws</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0230201">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.47*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.64*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>91301600*</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Screw #12 x &#190; inch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>26</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>*The same screw that is only 5/8 long is an approved substitute.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0230202">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.08in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>To install fasteners and complete paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.5 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspection only (includes) paper work when no repair is required</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.2 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Dealers Other Than Authorized Dealers
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to IC Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parts Cost</emph>
                (if materials exceed $3.00 per unit, you must include copy of receipt)
            </para>
            <para>All correspondence must be returned to IC Corporation, PO Box 6000, Conway, Arkansas, 72033, Attn:
                Compliance Department.
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-02302</emph>.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
