<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02301 - Between the Rail Fuel Tank System Crossmember</stitle>
    <recall id="rec02301">
        <recallnumber>02301</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FRAME</subjectfile>
        <subject>Between the Rail Fuel Tank System Crossmember</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/10/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/12/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02301.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has determined that the
                <emph type="bold">between the rail fuel tank system</emph>
                in certain IC school buses may fail to conform to federal regulation requirements (49 CFR 571.301 6.5,
                also known as FMVSS No.301, Section 6.5).
            </para>
            <para>On some of the subject IC buses, the crossmember located just in front of the fuel tank may be
                incorrect. The correct crossmember is of heavy-duty design and the certification of the system was based
                on the heavy-duty crossmember.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected IC model school buses were built from August 10, 2001 through May 12, 2002.</para>
            <para>
                <title>ACTIONS REQUIRED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The customer was asked to inspect the unit identified by the notice to determine if the correct
                crossmember was installed.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <stitle>Recall 02301 - Between the Rail Fuel Tank System Crossmember</stitle>
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The owner or dealer may perform this repair. The repair procedure involves replacing the crossmember
                located just in front of the fuel tank. Complete instructions are included with the kit. No special
                tools are required.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid possible property damage, personal injury or both, park the vehicle on a flat level
                        surface, set the parking brakes, chock the wheels and set the ignition to the OFF position
                        before performing this inspection.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform this
                        inspection.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0230101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0230101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Correct Crossmember is the Top One</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The upper crossmember in the picture shows the correct crossmember with a center height of
                        approximately 4.6 inches.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The lower crossmember in the picture is the wrong one with the center height of approximately
                        3 inches.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The customer was told, if the correct crossmember was installed, complete and return the enclosed
                "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card with box # 1 checked.
            </para>
            <para>The customer was told, if during the inspection it was determined that the wrong crossmember was
                installed, steps to replace the crossmember must be taken.
            </para>
            <para>We told the customer that their dealer will make this correction at no cost and to contact their
                dealer to make the arrangements to repair the affected unit.
            </para>
            <para>We also told the customer, if they desired to make the repair, they may purchase the parts from the
                dealer and invoice the parts and labor cost to us, or you may return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card with box # 8 checked and we will ship
                the parts directly to them at no charge. We asked them to verify their shipping address. P.O. Box
                numbers for shipping are not acceptable. We need a street or road address.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0230101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.47*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.64*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1660090C2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Crossmember</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8000835R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Kit Contains:</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>143406H</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Connector</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2007991C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Sleeve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>414511C2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Nut Compression</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>414506C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Insert</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2509574C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Instructions Repair</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0230102">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.08in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove, and install new crossmember and complete paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>1.2 hrs. w/o air suspension</para>
                                <para>1.7 hrs. w/air suspension</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspection only (see "ACTIONS REQUIRED" above)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.2 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Dealers Other Than Authorized Dealers
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to IC Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-02301</emph>.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
