<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02502 - Hydraulic Brake Master Cylinders on FC, FE, and RE Buses Built From 05/21/91 through
        11/08/96
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02502">
        <recallnumber>02502</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>March, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Hydraulic Brake Master Cylinders on FC, FE, and RE Buses Built From 05/21/91 through 11/08/96</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/21/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/08/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02502.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02502.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>These master cylinders have remote mounted reservoirs and a die cast aluminum adapter plate mounted on
                top of the cast iron master cylinder body. Galvanic corrosion on the die cast adapter plate can cause
                distortion of the wagon wheel seals that are mounted on the adapter plate. This condition exists between
                the aluminum adapter plate and the cast iron master cylinder body. If the seals become distorted, the
                tipper valves cannot properly seat against the wagon wheel seals. The function of the tipper valves is
                to seat against the seals and hold fluid pressure during brake applications. If the tipper valves cannot
                seat completely, the fluid can back flow past the tipper valves towards the reservoir and create a
                pressure loss for the front brakes, the rear brakes or both.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>The decrease in braking potential is not predictable because it is dependent on the volume of back
                flow past the tipper valves. This problem can result in an extended stopping distance without warning to
                the driver and the driver may feel the pedal fade or go completely to the floor. An unpredictable
                extended stopping condition could cause a vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage,
                personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The bus models involved are the FC, FE, and RE&#x2019;s built from 05/21/91 through 11/08/96 with
                hydraulic brakes.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                    This procedure begins with a visual inspection to identify the type of aluminum adapter plate on the
                    master cylinder (there are two types of adapter plates, both aluminum). If the master cylinder has a
                    die cast adapter plate as defined in the following procedure, the master cylinder must be replaced.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1"></para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly
                                or suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1"></para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                                Jacks can slip or fall over potentially resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the parking brake.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the master cylinder assembly and identify the type of adapter plate (clean
                        if necessary).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0250201" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Die Cast Adapter</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. Adapter has indentation with no date markings</callout1>
                        <callout1>REPLACE MASTER CYLINDERS WITH INDENTATION</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0250202" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Permanent Mold Adapter</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. No indentation, adapter has a flat bottom with date markings</callout1>
                        <callout1>DO NOT REPLACE IF THERE IS NO INDENTATION</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the adapter plate has an indentation on the bottom as shown in FIGURE 1, proceed
                        to Master Cylinder Replacement Instructions; however, if the adapter plate has a flat bottom
                        like in FIGURE 2 (with no indentation) then DO NOT replace the master cylinder.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Master Cylinder Replacement Instructions</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect pressure differential switch plug.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place a drain pan under the master cylinder and spray lubricant on all four brake
                        line fittings at the master cylinder.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen all four brake line fittings, remove the two pressure brake lines,
                        immediately install bleeder kit hoses, loosen reservoir cap and allow all brake fluid in the
                        reservoir to drain through the master cylinder and into the drain pan. Do not reuse the fluid.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the four master cylinder mounting nuts.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the two brake lines on top of the master cylinder and cover the open ends
                        of the lines to prevent contaminants from entering the brake lines and remove the master
                        cylinder.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the new master cylinder, which has a new pressure differential switch
                        installed, from the box and save the box to return the old part.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the new master cylinder. Torque the four mounting nuts to 25-30 Lbf-Ft
                        (34-41 NM).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the top two brake lines and torque to 16-17 Lbf-Ft (22-23 NM).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect the wire connector to the pressure differential switch.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-fill the reservoir with new DOT3 brake fluid.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With the bleeder kit, bleed the master cylinder on the vehicle.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect the two pressure lines to the master cylinder and torque to 16-17 Lbf-Ft
                        (22-23 NM).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Bleed the complete system, top-off reservoir and tighten reservoir cap.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Immediately return the removed master cylinder with the R-5185 PARTS DISPOSITION
                        AUTHORIZATION form.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Less than 25% of the buses are expected to need a new master cylinder. When ordering parts, please
                consider that most vehicles will only be inspected. The part number for the new master cylinder is
                1691024C94. Do not use any part numbers that precede this number.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: All master cylinders must be returned.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Return the parts per the instructions on the R-5185 PARTS DISPOSITION AUTHORIZATION form and attach
                the return authorization form to the part.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: Use either labor operation 1 or labor operation 2 but not both.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0250201">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02502-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect master cylinder</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-02502-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect, Remove and Replace master cylinder</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.5 hrs</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                Most claims should be for inspection only (cause number of 1 below).
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
