<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02501 - Under-Torqued Mounting Bolts on International Ride Optimized Air Suspensions (IROS) on 4300
        and 4400 Models Built from 10/24/00 through 10/30/01
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02501">
        <recallnumber>02501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>March, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subject>Under-Torqued Mounting Bolts on International Ride Optimized Air Suspensions (IROS) on 4300 and 4400
            Models Built from 10/24/00 through 10/30/01
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/30/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/30/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>14TBG</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBH</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBJ</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBL</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBM</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBN</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>There is a right and left main support member on the IROS rear suspension that mounts between the air
                spring, main support member frame hanger bracket, and the axle (see Figure 1). The function of the main
                support members is to provide support and location for the axle. Two bolts and nuts hold the ends of the
                bar pin, found in each main support member end bushing, to the frame mounted main support member hanger.
                During assembly, those bolts and nuts were not tightened to the required torque specification of 500 to
                625 NM.
            </para>
            <para>With less than the specified clamp load, the nuts can become loose and un-thread completely, or the
                bolts could fracture from fatigue. Either of these conditions could cause the connection to fail during
                the life of the vehicle which could result in a sudden loss of control of the vehicle and possibly a
                vehicular accident, property damage, or personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Only 4300 and 4400 models built at the Springfield Assembly Plant from 10/24/00 through 10/30/01 with
                suspension codes 14TBJ, 14TBL, 14TBM or 14TBN.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                Replace all four bolts and nuts on all vehicles in this campaign. There is no inspection option for this
                Safety Recall. Use one kit (8900081R91) per vehicle, which contains four locking nuts and four bolts.
                See Figure 1 below.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0250101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Driver's Side View of IROS Suspension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Bolts go through the bushing bar pin in the direction of the arrow with the bolt head
                        against the bar pin and the nut against the hanger. There are two bolts and two nuts required
                        per side.
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks
                            can slip or fall over resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the brakes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove one bolt and nut at a time then install a new bolt and nut and tighten the new
                    bolt almost to full torque so that the clamp load will hold the bushing pin aligned while the other
                    bolt is replaced. Repeat this step until all four bolts and nuts have been replaced. The new bolts
                    and nuts must be installed with the nuts facing the rear.
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT REUSE ANY OF THE ORIGINAL BOLTS OR NUTS</emph>
                    because they may not hold torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the new bolts and nuts to 370-460 Lbf-Ft (500-625 NM) with a torque wrench.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Immediately scrap the original equipment nuts and bolts that were just removed.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>All vehicles in this recall will require one repair kit. All the parts required for this recall are
                included in kit number
                <emph type="bold">8900081R91</emph>. All vehicles marked for this campaign must have this kit installed;
                therefore, no inspection labor operation has been set up.
            </para>
            <table id="t0250101">
                <title>Kit Contents for 8900081R91</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.62*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.83*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.54*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Bolt Metric, M20X100 phosphate coated</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>31090R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Hex Nut Metric, M20 prevailing torque, Lock nut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>40204R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All vehicles must have the four bolts and nuts replaced.</para>
            <table id="t0250102">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>R &#38; R Four Main Support Member Mounting Bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.6 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                No inspection option is offered for this campaign; therefore, the disposition for this campaign cannot
                be a 1.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
