<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02508 - Inspecting and Replacing the Fuel Injector Control Module on 3200 and 4200 Models Built From
        09/21/01 through 06/26/02 With VT 365 Engines
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02508">
        <recallnumber>02508</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Inspecting and Replacing the Fuel Injector Control Module on 3200 and 4200 Models Built From 09/21/01
            through 06/26/02 With VT 365 Engines
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/21/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/26/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/21/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/26/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 365</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02508.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02508.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The fuel injector control module also known as the injector driver module (IDM) on these VT 365
                engines could be missing a vibration damping shell, which could allow electronic components to vibrate
                and break loose from the component board inside the module.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>This defect could result in a rough running engine, loss of engine power, a no start condition, or
                immediate engine shut down without warning. If immediate engine shut down occurs, the result could be a
                vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>3200 and 4200 models built from 09/21/01 through 06/26/02 with the VT 365 engine.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="6">
            <title>Removing the IDM / ECM Assembly</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DESCRIPTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must have the injector driver module (IDM) replaced. The IDM is mounted on
                top of the engine and is bolted to the engine control module (ECM). The IDM and ECM will be removed from
                the engine as an assembly so the IDM can be replaced. The ECM will not be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine, apply the parking brake and put the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main negative battery
                            terminal before removing or installing any electrical components.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four mounting bolts (shown in Figure 1) that secure the IDM / ECM assembly to
                    the support bracket and remove the IDM / ECM assembly without removing the support bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250801" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>IDM/ECM Mounting Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the IDM / ECM assembly and remove the four ECM harness connectors (Item 3) from the
                    ports shown in Figure 2, Items 1 and 2. Pull the connectors straight out being careful not to bend
                    the pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250802" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250802.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>ECM Harness Connectors</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ECM ENGINE HARNESS CONNECTOR PORTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ECM CHASSIS HARNESS CONNECTOR PORTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HARNESS CONNECTOR, ONE OF FOUR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all three IDM harness connectors from the ports shown in Figure 3, Item 1.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250803" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250803.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>IDM Harness Connectors</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. IDM HARNESS CONNECTOR PORTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. IDM HARNESS CONNECTOR PLUG, ONE OF THREE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the ECM (Item 1) from the IDM (Item 2) as shown in Figure 4, by removing the
                    four bolts and spacers. All nuts, washers, bolts, spacers, and pilots must be saved for the
                    reassembly steps. DO NOT remove the grommets and bushings from the ECM. Keep both the IDM and the
                    ECM handy for step 9.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250804" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250804.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Separating the ECM and the IDM</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ECM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. IDM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT SKIP THIS STEP.</emph>
                    International requires the tracking numbers for the IDM / ECM assembly and for the old and new
                    IDM's. The time to complete the INFORMATION SHEET is part of the 1.5-hour labor operation. Using the
                    "INFORMATION SHEET" (below), fill in the required serial numbers for items 6 through 10. The
                    "INFORMATION SHEET" is the next figure in this letter and is also supplied with each new recall kit.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Item 6</emph>
                            requires the IDM serial number from the old IDM label.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Item 7</emph>
                            requires the ECM serial number from the bottom of the ECM, as shown in Figure 5.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Item 8</emph>
                            requires the IDM/ECM assembly serial number from the old IDM / ECM assembly label, as shown
                            in Figure 5. Determine the part number from the old IDM / ECM assembly label and enter the
                            serial number from the old IDM / ECM label in the spaces provided behind the correct part
                            number on the INFORMATION SHEET.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Item 9</emph>
                            requires the IDM serial number from the new label on the new IDM.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Item 10</emph>
                            requires the IDM / ECM assembly serial number from the new IDM / ECM assembly label that
                            came in the recall kit.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250805" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250805.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Shows the Bottom of the ECM, the IDM / ECM Assembly and ECM Labels are Circled</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250806" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250806.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="562px"/>
                <caption>Information Sheet</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSTALLING THE IDM / ECM ASSEMBLY</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check both modules (IDM and ECM) for damage to the rubber seals (1) or to the pins in
                    any of the connector cavities (2) as shown in Figure 7. If there is seal or pin damage, replace the
                    control module. Do not attempt to straighten bent pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250807" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250807.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Inspecting the Rubber Seals and the Connecting Pins</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When assembling the IDM and the ECM, orient items 1 through 4 as shown in Figure 8.
                            Continue to step 3 for assembly.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250808" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250808.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Orientation of the IDM / ECM Spacers and Bolts</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. M8 X 70 BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PILOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. IDM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SPACER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the ECM and the IDM: Reference Figures 8 and 9.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Orient the ECM and IDM as shown in Figure 9.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install and finger tighten all four bolts and hardware as shown in Figures 8 and 9,
                        with all four nuts on top.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using a wrench, gently snug all four nuts.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Holding the bolt heads with a wrench, torque the nuts to 19 - 22 Lbf-Ft (25-29
                        NM).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250809" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250809.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Assembly of the ECM to the IDM</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before removing the old IDM / ECM Assembly Serial number label, make sure the serial
                    numbers were recorded, on the "INFORMATION SHEET", as instructed in step 9 of the Removal Procedure.
                    Using a box cutter or a scraper, remove the old IDM / ECM assembly label.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the area where the old IDM / ECM Assembly Label was attached is clean and dry.
                    The new label will not properly adhere if the area is dirty or greasy. Install the new IDM / ECM
                    Assembly Label (from recall kit, as shown in Figure 10), on the ECM and in the same location and
                    orientation as the old label. Apply the Mylar (transparent label) over the New IDM / ECM assembly
                    Label.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250810" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250810.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Sample of a New Assembly Label from a Recall Kit</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill out the remainder of the "INFORMATION SHEET". Put the completed "INFORMATION SHEET"
                    and the old IDM in the recall kit box and return the box as instructed in the "PARTS INFORMATION"
                    section of this letter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully install the three IDM harness connectors (keyed for port matching), making
                    sure not to damage the pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the four ECM harness connectors, making sure not to damage the pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the IDM / ECM assembly onto the support bracket. Tighten the mounting bolts to
                    18 Lbf-Ft (24 NM).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the main negative battery terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Program the modules using the NETS system.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: ALL IDM's MUST BE RETURNED WITH THE COMPLETED INFORMATION SHEET.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Return the parts per the instructions on the R-5185 PARTS DISPOSITION AUTHORIZATION form and attach
                the return authorization form to the part.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>There is no inspection option. All vehicles must have the IDM replaced and all claims must be
                submitted with the labor operation below for 1.5 Hours.
            </para>
            <table id="t0250801">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02508-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace injector driver module (IDM)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>1.5 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                <emph type="bold">ALL CLAIMS MUST BE CAUSE NUMBER 2 BELOW</emph>, which is for "inspected and repaired".
                There is no inspection only option for this Safety Recall. All vehicles must have the IDM replaced, no
                exceptions.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
