<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02507 - Lower/Horizontal Clutch Rod Replacement on 4300 and 4400 Models Built from 10/24/2000 Through
        5/30/2002 with Manual Transmissions
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02507">
        <recallnumber>02507</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CLUTCH</subjectfile>
        <subject>Lower/Horizontal Clutch Rod Replacement on 4300 and 4400 Models Built from 10/24/2000 Through 5/30/2002
            with Manual Transmissions
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/30/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/30/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>11LDL</ucode>
                <ucode>11LEA</ucode>
                <ucode>11LED</ucode>
                <ucode>11LEG</ucode>
                <ucode>11LEH</ucode>
                <ucode>11LEK</ucode>
                <ucode>11LEL</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02507.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02507.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Lower/horizontal clutch rods with turnbuckles may fail from fatigue near the turnbuckle due to bending
                forces experienced during clutch pedal applications.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>The lower/horizontal clutch rod can break without warning and make it difficult to shift the
                transmission. If the clutch rod breaks while the vehicle is stopped with the engine running or during
                deceleration, the vehicle may lunge unexpectedly in the direction of the selected gear. Either of these
                conditions could cause a vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury or
                death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Only 4300 and 4400 models built with manual transmissions from 10/26/2000 through 5/30/2002.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DESCRIPTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must have the original lower/horizontal clutch rod replaced. The original
                rod has a turnbuckle and the new rod does not have a turnbuckle (see Figures 1 and 2 below).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0250701" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Replace Original Clutch Rod PN: 3544400C91 with Turnbuckle</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250702" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Install New Clutch Rod PN: 3532869C91 without Turnbuckle</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks
                            can slip or fall over, potentially resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine, apply the parking brake and put the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removing the complete lower/horizontal clutch rod as an assembly:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Do not loosen the turnbuckle or jam nuts.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the nut and washer connecting the forward end to the relay or bell crank.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Hold the rod and remove the bolt that connects the rearward end to the clutch
                        release lever, then remove the rod assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjusting the new rod to length:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">On the old rod, measure the straight distance from rod end to rod end.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure the new rod in the exact same way and adjust it to match the old rod length
                        by turning the rod ends.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the new rod is the same length as the old rod.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the rod so that the bend of the rod is in the same plane as the flat face of
                        the rod ends by turning the rod ends as required. When the stud is pointed horizontally, the
                        bend should be in the up or vertical direction.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the jam nuts on the rod ends to 7-11 Lbf-Ft (10 - 15 NM).</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Installing the adjusted rod:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the rod with the studded end towards the front and with the stud pointing
                        inboard and through the bell crank.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the nut and lock washer on the stud and torque to 14 - 18 Lbf-Ft (19 - 24
                        NM).
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE: The bend in the rod should be in the up position.</emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the other end, the end without the stud, to the outboard side of the clutch
                        release lever using the M10 bolt. Tighten the bolt to 35 - 43 Lbf-Ft (47 - 58 NM).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to International's Master Service Manual group 11 for clutch final adjustment.
                    First check the clutch internal adjustment and adjust if necessary. Then check the clutch free
                    travel and adjust if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Scrap the old clutch rod locally to assure it will not be used again.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>All vehicles need to have the original style lower/horizontal clutch rod (with turnbuckle) replaced. A
                few of the vehicles may have had the newly designed clutch rod (3532869C91, without turnbuckle)
                installed before this recall was released. Purge all 3544400C91 parts from your inventory.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: Scrap the removed defective clutch rods locally. Do not return these
                    parts.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: There is only one labor operation required for this recall. All vehicles must
                    have the original lower/horizontal clutch rod replaced.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0250701">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02507-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace the lower/ horizontal clutch rod assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.5 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                Most claims should use cause number 2 below.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
