<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02509 - Fuel Line Harness Inspections and Retrofits on Certain 7300, 7400 and 7500 Models Built from
        7/19/01 through 7/16/2002 with Right Side Frame Rail Mounted Fuel Filter and with a Left Side Mounted Fuel Tank
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02509">
        <recallnumber>02509</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FUEL TANKS</subjectfile>
        <subject>Fuel Line Harness Inspections and Retrofits on Certain 7300, 7400 and 7500 Models Built from 7/19/01
            through 7/16/2002 with Right Side Frame Rail Mounted Fuel Filter and with a Left Side Mounted Fuel Tank
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/19/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/16/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/19/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/16/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/19/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/16/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>This is a routing and clipping issue for the fuel line harnesses that run from the left side fuel tank
                to the engine. This campaign requires an inspection to determine if action is required to correct the
                routing and clipping on the fuel line harnesses on these vehicles. If the fuel line harness is not
                routed and clipped properly, a fuel leak may develop due to the fuel harness being too close to the
                engine exhaust pipe.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>A fuel leak could develop without warning if the fuel line harness is too close to the engine exhaust
                pipe. If the fuel line is melted to the point of rupturing, while the vehicle is running, the engine may
                shut down immediately. If the engine shuts down, the result could be a vehicular accident, possibly
                resulting in property damage, personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>7300, 7400 and 7500 models built from 7/19/01 through 7/16/02 with right side frame rail mounted fuel
                filter in conjunction with left side mounted fuel tank. Verify vehicles involved using ISIS.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="7">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must have the routing and clipping of the fuel line harness visually
                inspected. If the routing fails the inspection, a new fuel line harness must be installed using a
                special recall fuel line routing kit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear appropriate eye protection when performing vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine, apply the parking brake and put the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the hood assembly and remove the right engine splash shield.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Inspect the fuel line routing.</emph>
                    From the right side wheel well, locate the fuel line harness as shown in Figure 1. The fuel line
                    harness must be routed behind the engine breather tube or between the engine breather tube and the
                    engine as shown in Figures 1 and 2. If the fuel line on your vehicle is routed as shown in Figure 1
                    and 2, it passes the inspection and you should go directly to steps 22 and 23. If the fuel line is
                    routed for the two different exhaust systems, as shown in Figures 3 or 4, a new fuel line harness
                    must be installed and you must continue to step 5 to complete this recall procedure. Reference the
                    <emph type="bold">PART INFORMATION</emph>
                    section and obtain the correct fuel line harness and routing kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250901" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250901.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - GOOD ROUTING. NO ACTION REQUIRED. The harness is between the engine breather tube
                    and the engine.
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250902" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250902.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2 - GOOD ROUTING. NO ACTION REQUIRED. View looking forward from transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250903" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250903.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3 - BAD ROUTING . The harness is too close to the smooth turbo pipe. The Fuel Harness
                    Must Be Replaced and Re-Routed. Continue to step 5. View looking forward from transmission.
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250904" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250904.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4 - BAD ROUTING. The harness is too close to the flex exhaust pipe. The Fuel Harness
                    Must Be Replaced and Re-Routed. Continue to step 5. View looking forward from transmission.
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both right and left hood fender extensions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the right seat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cup holder assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the shifter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the right sill plate and kick panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the cab floor mat out of your way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the engine cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard all clipping from the fuel line harness except for item 1 in Figure
                    7. This clip must be reused during the installation. The rest of the clips will be replaced with new
                    ones from the recall kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make note of the fuel line connection locations, disconnect all fuel lines and use a
                    drain pan to catch the fuel that will drain from the lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the fuel line harness as one assembly and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lay the fuel line harness in place. Use Figures 5 and 7 for vehicles with the exhaust
                    system that has the smooth exhaust pipe shown in Figure 3. Use Figures 6 and 7 for vehicles with the
                    exhaust system that has the flex exhaust pipe shown in Figure 4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0250905" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5 - Routing From Bell Housing Forward, Routing Kit 8900088R91 for Vehicles With A Smooth
                    Exhaust Pipe
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>2. Two Z-style extension clips, p-clamps, M8 nuts/bolts</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. One L-shaped extension clip, p-clamp, M8 nut/bolt, mounted to upper/ forward engine
                        mount
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>5. One clamp, M6 bolt/nut on cab mount</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. Fuel harness</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250906" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6 - Routing From Bell Housing Forward, Routing Kit 8900087R91 For Vehicles With A Flex
                    Exhaust Pipe
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>2. Two Z-style extension clips, p-clamps, M8 nuts/bolts</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Straight extension clip, clamp, at filter base</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. Fuel line harness</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. The harness MUST be behind the breather tube</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0250907" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0250907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7 - Routing From Tank to Bell Housing &#38; Pump, Applies To All</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Save original clamping hardware and reuse during installation</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Two Z-style extension clips, p-clamps, M8 nuts/bolts</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Beginning at the fuel tank, install the new harness clips up to the bell housing (see
                    Figure 7). Clips are to be installed at the black tape locations on the harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the bell housing forward, the instructions are different depending on which harness
                    is being installed. Using the appropriate Figure, 5 or 6, install the clipping from the bell housing
                    forward.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all the fuel lines and bleed the fuel lines as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the engine cover and reposition the floor mat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the kick panel, sill plate, shifter assembly, cup holder and the seat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install both hood fender extensions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the engine splash shield.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the hood assembly and remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>We expect that half of the vehicles will fail the inspection and need replacement parts. There are two
                routing kits available for this recall and three different harnesses. However there are 19 VINs,
                provided in row 1 and 2 of Table 1 below, that have 11-inch fuel tanks. For these 19 VINs you must
                verify which style of 11-inch fuel tank is on the vehicle, see rows 1 and 2 of Table 1. All other
                vehicle applications are provided in rows 3 and 4 of Table 1.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: Scrap the removed parts locally. Do not return these parts.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0250901">
                <title>Harness and Routing Kit Application Table</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.98*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.16*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.84*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Application</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Fuel Line Harness</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Routing Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8 vehicles built with flex exhaust pipe &#38; 11" left side fuel tank should use
                                    these parts.
                                </para>
                                <para>2J030129, 2J032252, 2J036245, 2J036246, 3J044858, 3J044859, 2J051780, 3J050597
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3572007C92</para>
                                <para>Reference the NOTE following this table to verify this is the correct part for the
                                    vehicle.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900087R91</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>11 vehicles built with flex exhaust pipe &#38; an 11" left side fuel tank should
                                    use these parts.
                                </para>
                                <para>3J044505, 3J046352, 3J046353, 3J048894, 3J048895, 3J048918, 3J049813, 3J051411,
                                    3J057782, 3J057867, 3J062898
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3576765C92</para>
                                <para>Reference the NOTE at the end of this table to verify this is the correct part for
                                    the vehicle.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900087R91</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vehicles with smooth exhaust pipe &#38; NOT with 11" left side fuel tank</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3577849C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900088R91</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vehicles with the flex exhaust pipe and NOT with 11" left side fuel tank</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3572007C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900087R91</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">NOTE</emph>: The fuel sender location on the tank moved during
                                    this time frame. To determine which harness is required, a measurement must be taken
                                    on the top of the fuel tank from the front-end weld to the center of the sender. If
                                    you measure approximately 16 inches (400mm), use harness 3572007C92. If you measure
                                    approximately 20 inches (500mm), use harness 3576765C92.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="t0250902">
                <title>KIT CONTENTS FOR 8900087R91</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.46*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Extension clip, Z-style</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3572001C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Clamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>352356C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Bolt hex head M8x20</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3547776C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Nut M8 10Phc flange</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>31082R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Extension clip, straight, for filter base</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3545562C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Clamp/ filter base</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>365215C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Bolt hex flange M6x20, filter base</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3552155C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>M6 nut, filter base</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40233R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="t0250903">
                <title>KIT CONTENTS FOR 8900088R91</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.46*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Extension clip, Z-style</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3572001C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Clamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>352356C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Bolt hex head M8x20</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3547776C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Nut M8 10Phc flange</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>31082R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Clip extension, L-style</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2509984C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>M6 bolt/cab mount</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3552155C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>M6 nut/cab mount</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40233R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All vehicles must be inspected. Use only one labor operation per claim.</para>
            <table id="t0250904">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02509-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect, no repair required</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-02509-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect &#38; Replace fuel harness</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.8 hrs</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Use only one labor operation per claim.</para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
