<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02504 - Missing Cotter Pin at the Connection of the Drag Link to the Pitman Arm on 4200, 4300 and
        4400 Models Built From 1/24/2002 through 1/31/2002
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02504">
        <recallnumber>02504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>Missing Cotter Pin at the Connection of the Drag Link to the Pitman Arm on 4200, 4300 and 4400 Models
            Built From 1/24/2002 through 1/31/2002
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/31/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/31/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/31/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02504.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02504.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The cotter pin that goes through the drag link ball stud at the connection to the pitman arm may not
                have been installed. This cotter pin prevents the castle nut from loosening.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the castle nut loosens and comes completely off the drag link ball stud, the drag link could detach
                from the pitman arm resulting in a complete loss of steering control which could cause a vehicular
                accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Only some 4200, 4300 and 4400 models built from 1/25/2002 through 1/31/2002 at the Springfield
                Assembly Plant are in this campaign.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DESCRIPTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must be inspected to determine if the cotter pin was installed at the
                assembly plant. If no cotter pin is present, torque the castle nut and install a cotter pin.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks
                            can slip or fall over potentially resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and apply the parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the drag link ball stud that goes through the pitman arm; does it have a cotter
                    pin? If there is a cotter pin, then the inspection is complete. If no cotter pin is present,
                    continue to step 5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check to make sure the castle nut has not loosened by tightening it to 110-125 Lbf-Ft
                    (149-170 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the cotter pin. If the cotter pin cannot be installed, tighten the castle nut to
                    the next position and install the cotter pin. Never loosen the castle nut to install the cotter pin.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Only some vehicles are expected to be missing the cotter pin. The International part number for the
                cotter pin is an old style part number and must be entered as follows: "1-8X2 P", with five spaces in
                front of the P. The description for the steel cotter pin is a 1/8-inch by 2 inches, but a 1/8 by 1
                &#190; will work.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: Not Applicable.</emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: There is only one labor operation required for this recall. All vehicles must be
                    inspected to see if the cotter pin was installed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0250401">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02504-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect for cotter pin, torque nut and install cotter pin</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                Most claims should be for inspection only (cause number of 1 below).
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
