<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02514 - INTERMEDIATE STEERING SHAFT PINCH BOLTS COULD BE MISSING OR LOOSE on 9200i, 9400i, and 9900i
        models built at Escobedo from 6/4/02 through 9/12/02
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02514">
        <recallnumber>02514</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>INTERMEDIATE STEERING SHAFT PINCH BOLTS COULD BE MISSING OR LOOSE on 9200i, 9400i, and 9900i models
            built at Escobedo from 6/4/02 through 9/12/02
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/04/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/12/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/04/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/12/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/04/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/12/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02514.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02514.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The intermediate steering shaft connects the steering column to the steering gear box and is held in
                place by two pinch bolts. One pinch bolt is at the upper end of the intermediate shaft, inside the cab,
                and the second pinch bolt is at the lower end of the intermediate shaft, outside the cab, at the
                steering gear box. Both pinch bolts could be missing or loose. See Figure 1.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>If a pinch bolt is missing or loose, the operator can experience loss of steering control. Loss of
                steering control can cause a vehicular accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury
                or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Only 9200i, 9400i, and 9900i models built at Escobedo from 6/4/02 through 9/12/02 are involved.
                Escobedo-built models can be identified by the 3N designation in the 10th and 11th digits of the VIN.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DESCRIPTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must have the intermediate steering shaft inspected to make sure the pinch
                bolts AT BOTH ENDS are installed and have the proper torque applied to the bolts. The upper end of the
                intermediate shaft is inside the cab and the lower end is outside the cab and connects to the steering
                gear. See Figure 1.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0251401" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0251401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Assembly View of Intermediate Steering Shaft</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. UPPER PINCH BOLT AT STEERING COLUMN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. UPPER END OF INTERMEDIATE SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COWL OR CAB FRONT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER PINCH BOLT AT STEERING GEAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LOWER END OF INTERMEDIATE SHAFT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks
                            can slip or fall over, potentially resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine, apply the parking brake and put the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Some interior trim levels require removal of the lower cover, under the steering column,
                    for access to the upper intermediate steering shaft u-joint pinch bolt. If necessary, remove this
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the head of the pinch bolt and see if the 3/8" 12-point head (reference Figure 2,
                    Item 4) has been properly twisted off, leaving an unpainted spot in the center of the bolt head. If
                    the twist-off head is gone, no action is required for this pinch bolt. Proceed to step 8.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0251402" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0251402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Special Pinch Bolt</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEX HEAD OF PINCH BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLANGED NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FLAT WASHER FOR UNDER HEAD OF BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TWIST-OFF 12-POINT HEAD ON PINCH BOLT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0251403" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0251403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Under-torqued Bolt</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Twist-off head has not been properly tightened.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0251404" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0251404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Tightened Bolt</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Pinch bolt has been properly tightened when twist-off head breaks off.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the bolt is missing, install the new bolt, hardened flat washer and nut as described
                    in the following "PART INFORMATION" section. The washer must be positioned under the bolt head.
                    Holding the nut, tighten the 12-point head on the bolt until the 3/8" head snaps off as shown in
                    Figure 4. No further torque is required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the 3/8" 12-point twist-off bolt head is still attached to the bolt as shown in
                    Figure 3, this indicates the bolt is not at the proper torque. Hold the nut and tighten the 3/8"
                    12-point bolt head until it snaps off of the hex head of the pinch bolt as shown in Figure 4. When
                    the 12-point hex head snaps off, the bolt is properly torqued.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Under the hood, inspect the pinch bolt at the intermediate steering shaft coupler to the
                    steering gear. Repeat steps 5, 6 and 7 for this bolt also.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                Very few vehicles are expected to need bolts installed for this recall. Parts stock is limited. Please
                do not order parts until you have verified that they are needed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If A BOLT is missing you will need:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">One bolt part number 3535854C1 and</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">One nut &#38; washer kit number 8900079R91.</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <table id="t0251401">
                <title>The nut and washer kit contents for 8900079R91 are as follows.</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.53*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7/16 - 20 Hex Locknut, Prevailing Torque, Grade 8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>273896</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7/16 Hardened Flat Washer (0.469 I.D. X 0.922 O.D.)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>26272R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Contents and Torque Specification Sheet</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2508386R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: Use labor operation one or two, but not both. Maximum total labor paid for this
                    campaign should be 0.4 Hrs.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0251402">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02514-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect and/ or torque both pinch bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-02514-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect, install and torque pinch bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.4 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                Most claims should use cause number 1 below for inspection only.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
