<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 02512 - TC-7 Hand Operated Trailer Brake Control Valve With Push-to-Connect Fittings May Have Slow
        Air Delivery and Exhaust on Certain 2000, 4000, 5000, 7000, 8000 and 9000 Models Built Between 4/24/02 and
        6/21/02
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec02512">
        <recallnumber>02512</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 2002</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>TC-7 Hand Operated Trailer Brake Control Valve With Push-to-Connect Fittings May Have Slow Air Delivery
            and Exhaust on Certain 2000, 4000, 5000, 7000, 8000 and 9000 Models Built Between 4/24/02 and 6/21/02
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/24/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/21/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec02512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus02512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The delivery port in the Bendix TC-7 hand operated trailer brake control valve body may be partially
                blocked due to a problem during the molding process at the supplier. Blockage could slow the air
                delivery and exhaust to and from the trailer brakes when the brakes are operated from this valve.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the hand control valve is used while the vehicle is in motion, a slow trailer brake application or
                a slow trailer brake release could contribute to a loss of vehicle control, which in turn could cause an
                accident, possibly resulting in property damage, personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Certain 2000, 4000, 5000, 7000, 8000 and 9000 models with push-to-connect air line fittings at the
                trailer brake control valve and built between 4/24/02 and 6/21/02 are involved in this recall. Verify
                which vehicles are in the campaign by using ISIS.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION</emph>: The hand operated trailer brake control valve must be tested
                before replacing it. If the air does not exhaust from the valve in less than one second, it must be
                replaced. Before replacing the valve you must choose one of the two different repair kits. All of these
                valves use quick connect fittings.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear appropriate eye protection when performing vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Obtain two glad-hands, with the ports plugged, for this test procedure (See Figure 1).
                    Block off both service and emergency glad-hands on the vehicle by connecting them to the plugged
                    glad-hands shown in Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0251201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0251201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - Plugged Glad-Hands</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and keep it running until the governor reaches cutout pressure (125 psi
                    minimum).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push in both the Red and Yellow MV-3 dash buttons (trailer supply and tractor parking
                    buttons).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and release the service brakes if applied.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the hand control valve to full apply, making a full trailer brake application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wait 5 seconds to allow the pressure to stabilize.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Quickly move the hand control valve back to zero, making a full exhaust.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the time it takes to exhaust the control line until no audible exhaust sounds
                    are heard. If the exhaust time is less than a second, the time it takes to quickly say "one thousand
                    one", the valve does not need to be replaced and you can go directly to step 21. If the exhaust time
                    is one second or longer, proceed to steps 10 through 21 and replace the hand control valve.
                    Disconnect and remove the plugged glad-hands from the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain air from all tanks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the steering column cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the trailer hand control valve handle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the trailer hand control valve from the mounting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect push-to-connect air lines from valve and mark air lines as needed. Remove
                    valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air lines to the new trailer hand control valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the control valve to the mounting bracket and tighten fasteners to 30-60 IN-Lbs
                    (3.4 to 6.8 NM).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the handle to the control valve and torque to 30-60 IN-Lbs (3.4 to 6.8 NM).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and build the air pressure to 125 psi minimum. Check valve for proper
                    operation and for air leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the steering column cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Return the parts per the instructions in the "PART INFORMATION" section of this
                    letter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>We expect less than 30% of the vehicles will need the trailer brake control valve replaced. Kit
                8900093R91 will mainly be used for this recall. However, there are 9 VINs provided in Table 1 that will
                require the other kit number 8900094R91. Each vehicle that fails the test will require one new valve
                kit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: Return defective parts per the instructions on the R-5185 PARTS
                    DISPOSITION AUTHORIZATION form and attach the return authorization form to the part.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0251201">
                <title>Kit Part Numbers and Applications</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.92*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.20*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.87*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>International Kit Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Vehicle Applications</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Kit Contents, Bendix Part Numbers</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">8900093R91</emph>
                                    Bendix Kit # 801405
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Most vehicles use this kit, Except those VINs shown below</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>109389 Valve</para>
                                <para>112741 Plastite screw</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">8900094R91</emph>
                                    Bendix Kit # 801406
                                    <emph type="bold">Note: Verify VIN before ordering.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>There are only 9 vehicles that may need this kit. They were built with code 834465
                                    or with code 12920. All nine VINs are shown here.
                                </para>
                                <para>2R704168, 2R704413, 2R704414, 3C051456, 3C052592, 3C053423, 3C053525, 3J043393,
                                    3J043394
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>109409 Valve with self-return hand control</para>
                                <para>112741 Plastite screw</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All vehicles must be inspected in this recall. Only one labor operation below will be used. Claims
                must have labor operation number 1 or 2 but not both.
            </para>
            <table id="t0251402">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-02512-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Test Valve Operation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-02512-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test and Replace Valve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.6 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
