<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03301 - Missing Seat Mounting Reinforcement</stitle>
    <recall id="rec03301">
        <recallnumber>03301</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April 2003</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Missing Seat Mounting Reinforcement</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/05/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/31/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03301.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus03301.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice: "This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has decided that a defect, which relates to motor vehicle safety, exists in certain CE buses. The flip
                and four (4) legged seats were improperly installed. During a crash, this defect may allow the seat to
                become loose which could cause personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>The reinforcement located under the floor for the rear mounting hardware of the seat legs to floor was
                not included during the assembly process. This applies only to the flip and four legged seats. Seats
                mounted with legs on the aisle side and to the seat rail on the wall are not involved in this recall.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected CE model buses were built from June 5, 2001 through July 31, 2002 with flip seats and
                seat belts or flip seats and anchor seats. The vehicle identified on the enclosed card fits this
                description and our records show you as the owner of this vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ACTIONS REQUIRED</title>
            </para>
            <para>On buses meeting the above description with seat belts: Advise the operators of the subject vehicles
                of this defect and ask them not to place passengers on these seats until the repair is completed.
            </para>
            <para>On buses meeting the above description without seat belts: Do not install seat belts until the repair
                is completed.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>All buses involved in this recall must have the reinforcements added.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The customer was told that their dealer would make this correction for them at no cost and to contact
                their dealer to make the arrangements to repair the unit.
            </para>
            <para>They were also told, "If you desire to make this repair yourself, you may purchase the parts from the
                dealer. When you invoice us for the cost of labor, you may add the cost for the parts purchased from
                your dealer. If for some reason you are unable to obtain the replacement parts from your local dealer,
                you may return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card with box # 8 checked and we will ship
                the parts directly to you at no charge. Please verify that your shipping address is correct. A Post
                Office Box (P.O. Box) number for shipping is not acceptable. We must have a street or road address.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                        suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If the vehicle must be raised, do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can
                        slip or fall over potentially resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>This repair procedure involves adding reinforcements under the floor to the rear mounting hardware of
                both the flip and four legged seats. This operation requires two people, one inside the bus and one
                under the bus.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the nuts and washers from the mounting bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean excess undercoating from the area where the reinforcement will seat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the reinforcement using the bolts as a guide. For proper placement of the
                    reinforcement use Figures #3 and #4 as a guide.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the washers and nuts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque to 13 - 16 lbf-ft.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0330101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Aisle Side View Of 4-Leg Rear Mounting Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0330102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Aisle Side View Of Flip Seat Rear Mounting Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0330103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Reinforcement Position When Bolts Are Positioned Through The Floor Joints Or Cross Sill
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0330104" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330104.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Reinforcement Position When Bolts Are Positioned Through The Floor Only</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0330101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.60*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.11*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="1.30*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>429639001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Reinforcement, Seat Mounting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4</para>
                                <para>If your bus is equipped with two (2) flip seats the quantity should be 8.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All vehicles in this campaign will require addition of the reinforcements. Only one of the labor
                operations below should be used for this defect repair.
            </para>
            <table id="t0330102">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.28in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Labor Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03301-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Add reinforcements to both seat RR legs on buses w/1 flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>.7 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03301-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Add reinforcements to both seat RR legs on buses w/2 flip seats</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.2 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RECALL CLAIMS - Repairs Performed By Authorized Dealers</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For Repairs and/or Inspections Performed By Dealers Other Than Authorized Dealers
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information to IC Corporation, P.O. Box 6000, Conway, AR, 72033, Attn: Compliance Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vin #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Recall Campaign #:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Facilities Repair Labor Rate:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parts Cost:</emph>
            </para>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-03301</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">LESSOR RESPONSIBILITY:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Federal Regulations require that any vehicle lessor receiving this recall notice must forward a copy
                of this notice to the lessee within ten days.
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation asks for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you
                have any questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your
                regional office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
