<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03305-R1 - Roof Topping Sheet Joints</stitle>
    <recall id="rec03305">
        <recallnumber>03305-R1</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Roof Topping Sheet Joints</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/01/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/28/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>FE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/01/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/28/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/07/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/28/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03305.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">THIS IS AN ISIS ONLY REVISION. THERE WILL BE NO PAPER MAILING.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">REVISION DESCRIPTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INSPECTION PROCEDURE CLARIFICATION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>There has been some confusion with regard to the inspection procedure for the top joint. The
                <emph type="bold">INSPECTION PROCEDURE</emph>
                instructions stated: "Measure up approximately 20 inches from the drip rail. The inspection measurement
                can be taken on either the right or left side of the bus. Only one side is required."
            </para>
            <para>The instructions that were developed were intended to take into account the possible variation due to
                manufacturing from side to side. Therefore, it is
                <emph type="bold">NOT</emph>
                necessary to perform the inspection measurement on both sides of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>However, regardless of which side of the bus the inspection is performed on, if it is found that the
                measurement does not fall within the 1 1/8 inch criteria, then that joint must be repaired per the
                instructions outlined in the letter. In this situation the screws only have to be added across the panel
                until the measurement does comply with the 1 1/8 inch acceptance criteria.
            </para>
            <para>If only a few (3 or less) rivets at/or above the measurement location of 20 inches exceed the 1 1/8
                inch criteria,
                <emph type="bold">NO</emph>
                repair is required.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">ORIGINAL RECALL NOTICE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation had mailed to the affected customers the following notice: This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has decided that certain IC and American Transportation CE, RE and FE school buses may fail to conform
                to Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard (FMVSS) No. 221, "School Bus Emergency Body Joint Strength."
            </para>
            <para>One or more joints that connect the roof top sheets may not meet the requirement of FMVSS 221. In the
                event of an accident involving the roof of the bus, the joint may separate. Separation of the joint may
                cause injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected CE and FE model buses were built from September 1, 1993 through August 28, 2003 and the
                affected RE model buses were built from March 7, 1995 through August 28, 2003.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ACTIONS YOU SHOULD TAKE</title>
            </para>
            <para>The customer was told to inspect the identified buses following the inspection procedure outlined
                below. Any joint that exceeds the 1 1/8-inch measurement when using the inspection procedure must have
                the next joint forward repaired using the repair procedure below.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSPECTION PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The customer was told if they would prefer their dealer to make this inspection at no cost, to contact
                their dealer and make the arrangements. They were also told if they preferred to make this simple
                inspection to follow these instructions. The inspection requires measuring the rear end of the top sheet
                to the first row of rivets.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0330501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0330502" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Measure the distance from the back edge of the top sheet to the centerline of the first row of rivets.
                Note the most rear top sheet is attached to the rear cap with only one row of rivets and the measurement
                is taken to that row of rivets. If this distance exceeds 1 1/8 (1.12) inches the next joint, which
                contains the covered end of the same sheet involved in the measurement, may be noncompliant and must be
                repaired. Make sure that the measurement is from the edge of the metal and not the sealer that may have
                oozed from the joint. If it is equal to or less than 1 1/8 (1.12) inches, the joint is compliant and
                does not need to be repaired.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0330503" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="184px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>The 1 1/8-inch measurement at the rivet line at the rear end of the top sheet being measured
                determines if the joint at the forward end of the same sheet is compliant.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0330504" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="184px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Continue this inspection procedure for the remaining top sheets except the top sheet above the right
                entrance door. This top sheet above the right entrance door, which attaches to the front cap does not
                require inspection. Therefore do not measure the row of rivets above the entrance door rear doorpost; it
                is not part of the inspection procedure.
            </para>
            <para>If all of the joints are found to be compliant during the inspection process, IC needs to be informed.
                Authorized dealers should use the warranty system using code "1" for this notification. Others should
                check box # 1 of the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card, sign and date and place it in the mail.
                In lieu of returning the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card, IC will accept a signed list of units
                that were inspected and found to be compliant. This list must contain at least the last eight characters
                of the VIN and must be mailed or faxed to our Compliance Department. If a joint is determined to be
                noncompliant when measured by the preceding process, please follow the repair procedure.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a flat
                        level surface, set the parking brake, turn the engine off and chock the wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Fall Hazard. Fall protection equipment must be worn to prevent property damage, personal
                        injury, or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>In-line with the rear most row of rivets in the non-compliant joint; screws must be added between
                every other rivet. See sketch below for an example. Drill a .1590 diameter hole (drill size 21) for each
                screw required. Insert the screw and use matching touch up paint if required. The screws that should be
                used for this repair are pre-painted either in white or yellow and have been dipped to provide sealing
                of the hole.
            </para>
            <para>Authorized dealers should purchase these screws from their parts depot. Others may return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card with box # 8 checked and circling yellow
                or white screws to match your vehicle roof color and we will ship the parts directly to you at no
                charge. If you prefer, instead of returning the above card you may call, fax, mail to our Compliance
                Department or email to kathy.anders@ic-corp.com, and we will ship the parts directly to you at no
                charge. Provide at least the last eight characters of the VIN for the units requiring repair, how many
                joints need to be repaired and the color screws needed. Please verify that your shipping address is
                correct. A Post Office Box (P.O. Box) number for shipping is not acceptable. We must have a street or
                road address.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0330505" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0330505.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="184px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>The customer was told If they preferred their dealer to make this correction at no cost, contact their
                dealer to make the arrangements.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CAUTION SHOULD BE USED WHEN PREORDERING PARTS FOR THIS CAMPAIGN. THE REPAIR RATE FOR
                    THIS CAMPAIGN IS EXPECTED TO BE VERY LOW BASED ON PRELIMINARY INVESTIGATION.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t0330501" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.73*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.49*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900143R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Recall Service Kit - White Screw Head</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>8900142R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Recall Service Kit - Yellow Screw Head</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Each service kit above has a quantity of 50 screws, enough to repair two joints. These screws
                        are AB #10-16 X &#190;" Cross Recessed Pan Head, have a sealer applied and have the heads
                        painted white or yellow to blend with the color of the roof.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All units will require labor operation number A40-03305-1</para>
            <table id="t0330502" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.28in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Labor Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect all joints and complete paper work only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair one (1) joint</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.6 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair two (2) joints</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.9 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair three (3) joints</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.2 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair four (4) joints</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.5 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair five (5) joints</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.8 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03305-7</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect all joints, complete paper work and repair six (6) joints</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2.1 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your dealer location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RECALL CLAIMS - Repairs Performed By Non Authorized Dealers</emph>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information:
                <emph type="bold">Body Serial #:, Vin #:, Recall Campaign #:, Facilities Repair Labor Rate:, Repair
                    Code:, Cost of Screws if Purchased (If purchased must have receipt and cannot exceed $2.00 per
                    repaired joint. Sales tax is not refundable.)
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>All correspondence must be returned to IC Corporation, PO Box 6000, Conway, Arkansas, 72033, Attn:
                Compliance Department.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RECALL CLAIMS - Repairs Performed By Authorized Dealers</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Recall
                <emph type="bold">G-03305</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">LESSOR RESPONSIBILITY:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Federal Regulations require that any vehicle lessor receiving this recall notice must forward a copy
                of this notice to the lessee within ten days.
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation asks for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you
                have any questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your
                regional office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
