<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03501 - NON-COMPLIANCE RECALL - Installing the Hydraulic Brake Monitor Module on 3200, 4200, 4300,
        and 4400 Models Built with Brake Code 4GAS from 7/16/02 through 1/14/03
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec03501">
        <recallnumber>03501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>February, 2003</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>NON-COMPLIANCE RECALL - Installing the Hydraulic Brake Monitor Module on 3200, 4200, 4300, and 4400
            Models Built with Brake Code 4GAS from 7/16/02 through 1/14/03
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/16/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/14/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/16/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/14/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/16/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/14/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/16/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/14/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04GAS</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus03501.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>These vehicles are noncompliant with Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard (FMVSS) 105 section 5.3.1
                if they were built without the hydraulic brake monitor module. Without this brake monitor module, the
                brake warning light will not come on to warn the operator if there is a loss of hydraulic pressure in
                the brake system, a loss of power steering flow or if the emergency brake booster motor is not
                functioning.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>These vehicles were built with brake code 04GAS from 7/16/02 through 1/14/03 and include the following
                models: 3200, 4200, 4300, and 4400.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">INTRODUCTION:</emph>
                All vehicles in this recall must have the hydraulic brake monitor module installed if it was not
                installed at the assembly plant. Some vehicles built at the end of the build date range may have had the
                module installed at the assembly plant.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine, apply the parking brake and put the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition to the on position and watch the dash indicator lights go through an
                    illumination test sequence. This will take about 10 seconds. If the hydraulic brake warning light
                    does not come on and stay illuminated after this initial test cycle, then continue to step 3 and
                    perform the recall. If the hydraulic brake warning light illuminates during the light test cycle and
                    stays on after the test cycle then stop at this step because the module is already installed (some
                    of the vehicles that were built at the end of the build date range may have had the module installed
                    at the assembly plant).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the hood assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the battery ground cable and the ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the fuse panel cover located inside the cab on the right side of the dash in
                    front of the passenger seat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the steering column cover for access to the instrument panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the instrument cover then the instrument panel (4 screws).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the Electronic System Control Module (ESC) cover (left kick panel).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the dash trim panel from the center section. Remove the storage bin or the switch
                    panel or the blank from the upper right double din location of the dash center section to allow for
                    wire access and routing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the pass through connector at the cowl. Connect the A90N gray wire to cavity
                    20 on the pass through connector and connect the A90M gray wire to cavity 19 on the pass through
                    connector (Reference Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 1600 connector from the ESC module and connect the A90P gray wire to
                    cavity 9 in the 1600 connector (reference Figure 1 below).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0350101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - ESC Module</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove one of the nuts from a ground stud in the cab next to the pass through connector,
                    install the ring terminal of the 90-GA white wire over the ground stud and tighten the nut
                    (Reference Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the connector of the A13FF pink wire into the F11 fuse position, install the new 5
                    Amp fuse into the F11 fuse position, plug the A13FG pink wire connector into cavity E of the brake
                    monitor module plug attached to the gray and white wire harness installed above, push this plug into
                    the brake monitor module and lay the pink harness over the main harness (Reference Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the pass through connector at the cowl.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the ESC module connector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the instrument panel wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery ground cable and the ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the brake warning light operation. The brake warning light should come on and stay
                    on after the key is left in the on position for more than 10 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the module and both overlay harnesses to the main harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the ESC module cover (kick panel).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the instrument panel and cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the steering column cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the dash panel center section components and install the center section trim
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the fuse panel cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the hood assembly and remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0350102" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2 - Installation Schematic For The Hydraulic Brake Monitor Module</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>One of each of the following parts will be needed for each vehicle in this recall.</para>
            <table id="t0350101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.62*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.83*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.54*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity per VIN</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Hydraulic Brake Monitor Module: black plastic box</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>1658510C3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Harness: gray and white wires with plug for brake monitor module and terminated
                                    wire ends
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>3567209C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Harness: pink wires with a diode and terminated wire ends</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3581303C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuse, 5 Amp mini fuse</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>MIN5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RETURNING PARTS: There are no parts to be returned.</emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>All vehicles in this recall are expected to need the hydraulic brake monitor module installed, but
                there could be a few built at the end of the build date range that had the module installed at the
                assembly plant. If a dealer finds a vehicle that had the module installed at the assembly plant, the
                claim should be for inspection only (for 0.3 hrs).
            </para>
            <table id="t0350102">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-03501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install the Hydraulic Brake Monitor Module</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>1.0 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Special Note:</emph>
                Most claims should use cause number 2 below. A few may use cause number 1 if they had the monitor module
                installed at the assembly plant.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
