<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03509 - Steering Arm Tapered Bore Oversize</stitle>
    <recall id="rec03509">
        <recallnumber>03509</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2003</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>Steering Arm Tapered Bore Oversize</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/21/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/05/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus03509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The tapered bore in the steering arm/steering knuckle assembly was machined too large on some steering
                knuckles where it connects to the drag link. The clearance between a correctly sized drag link ball stud
                and the oversized tapered bore is great enough to allow the drag link ball stud to fatigue and break.
                This condition may also allow the castle nut to back off and shear the cotter pin allowing the drag link
                to fall off, possibly resulting in
                <emph type="bold">property damage, personal injury, or death.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This campaign covers 8600 models built 6/21/2002 through 5/5/2003 with the following front axle
                feature codes: 02AGG, 02AGE, and 02AGB.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This Recall has two procedures: an INSPECTION PROCEDURE and a REPAIR PROCEDURE. Please
                            perform Inspection Procedure first to determine if Repair Procedure is required.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection Procedure</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the inspection, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Set parking brake and block rear wheels to prevent vehicle from moving.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Raise the front axle and position vehicle on floor stand(s).</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn steering wheel to the right, to gain access to steering arm for inspection.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>
                    <title>VISUAL INSPECTION</title>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Please use the following method of visual inspection. If, by this method, it
                        cannot be determined if the Repair Procedure is required, continue on to use the DIAL INDICATOR
                        INSPECTION procedure.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the position of the castle nut relative to the cotter pin hole in the drag
                        link ball stud. If the cotter pin hole in the drag link ball stud is above the top of the castle
                        nut (as shown in figure 1) the
                        <emph type="bold">steering knuckle needs to be replaced</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350901" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350901.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">While applying an upward force to the drag link, determine if there is a gap between
                        the castle nut and the top of the steer arm machined surface (as shown in Figure 2). If a gap
                        exists the
                        <emph type="bold">steering knuckle needs to be replaced</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350902" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350902.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If
                        <emph type="bold">none</emph>
                        of the above conditions exist, continue on to the
                        <emph type="bold">DIAL INDICATOR INSPECTION</emph>
                        procedure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If
                        <emph type="bold">any</emph>
                        of the above conditions exist, skip the
                        <emph type="bold">DIAL INDICATOR INSPECTION</emph>
                        procedure and go directly to the
                        <emph type="bold">REPAIR PROCEDURE</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>
                    <title>DIAL INDICATOR INSPECTION</title>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Mount a magnetic based dial indicator on the steer arm, with the indicator tip
                        contacting the center of the drag link ball stud (as shown in Figure 3).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350903" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350903.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Push and pull the drag link in an up and down motion (as shown in Figure 4). If the
                        dial indicator detects any movement, the steering knuckle will
                        <emph type="bold">need to be replaced</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350904" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350904.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="19">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Steering Knuckle Removal Procedure</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The procedure below begins with the wheel, hub, and brake assembly already removed and
                            starts with steps to remove the steering knuckle. If instructions are needed at any point in
                            this repair procedure, refer to the Master Service Manual. Follow all standard safety
                            precautions and procedures recommended by the Master Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove cotter pin and slotted nut on tie rod end.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350905" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. TIE ROD ARM</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SLOTTED NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. COTTER PIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. POSITION CLAMP FASTENER AWAY FROM BEAM</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect tie rod end from tie rod arm using a suitable tool such as a pickle
                        fork.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350906" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. TIE ROD ARM</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. PICKLE FORK</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Be careful not to damage the tie rod end boot during this removal procedure.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not use heat on any axle parts or fasteners.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect drag link from steering arm and Pitman arm by removing cotter pins and
                        slotted nuts.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350906" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove top and bottom knuckle caps.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Dual draw keys.</emph>
                        Remove both draw key nuts. Then drive keys out using a brass hammer and drift.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350908" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350908.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRAW KEY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. BRASS DRIFT</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Drive kingpin out with a brass hammer and drift.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not damage kingpin, it will be re-used during installation of new knuckle.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0350909" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350909.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. BRASS HAMMER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DRIFT</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove steering knuckle from axle beam.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove steering stop adjustment Screw, lock-nut, and adapter fitting from old
                        knuckle. They will be cleaned and re-installed on new knuckle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Measure and record distance the old Steering Stop Screw protrudes out of the knuckle
                            before removing it.
                        </para>
                        <para>When installing the screw into the new knuckle make the initial setting (protrusion)
                            approximately 1/8 inch longer. This will prevent over-traveling of the steering linkage and
                            steering gear in full left turn, minimizing the possibility of adjusting steering gear
                            poppets.
                        </para>
                        <para>Complete stop screw adjustment while on turntable as described in STEERING KNUCKLE STOP
                            ADJUSTMENT section.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent personal injury, never strike hardened metal parts with a steel hammer or
                            tool.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Cleaning</title>
                <para>After disassembly, clean axle end as follows:</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Steel parts with ground or polished surfaces.</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Wash in a suitable cleaning solvent.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Rinse thoroughly to remove any cleaning solution.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Dry parts with clean rags.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean castings, forgings and other rough-surface parts.</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Wire brush or steam-clean areas that are susceptible to accumulation of mud, road
                                dirt, salt.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Gasoline is not an acceptable cleaning solvent because of its extreme combustibility. It
                            is unsafe in the workshop environment.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Steering Knuckle Installation Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the old steering stop adjustment screw, lock nut and adapter fitting. Torque
                        adapter fitting to
                        <emph type="bold">120-160 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (160-217 Nm). Be sure screw is cleaned as per the above procedure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Before installing the kingpins, lubricate inside of bushing and outside of kingpins
                        with Fleetrite EP2 Moly Grease or equivalent NLGI No. 2 multipurpose lithium grease to provide
                        initial lubrication.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Make certain that kingpin hole in axle center is clean and dry.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the steering knuckle yoke holes with axle and thrust bearing holes.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Pre-adjust knuckle vertical play by wedging the steering knuckle up and filling the
                        gap at the top side of the knuckle with shim(s).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350910" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350910.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. INSTALL SHIM(S) AS NEEDED</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SHIM ONLY TOP OF KNUCKLE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Floor jack can be used to wedge up steering knuckle.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install kingpin from the top with notch and draw key hole aligned. Hand start in
                        bushing.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350911" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350911.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. KINGPIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. STEERING KNUCKLE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Never shim on the bottom side of the beam.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install kingpin in knuckle and axle beam. If necessary, lightly tap kingpin in place
                        using hammer and brass drift.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350912" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350912.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. KINGPIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. PROTECT WITH SHIM STOCK</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Protect kingpins with a suitable material such as shim stock.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>At this point in reassembly, check knuckle vertical play and adjust if necessary.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Center steering components.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Mount dial indicator to steer beam and reference top of the knuckle. Zero dial
                        indicator.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350913" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350913.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. REFERENCE ON TOP OF KNUCKLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DIAL INDICATOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. PRY BAR</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. PRY KNUCKLE DOWNWARD</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Simulate axle loading with a jack and note dial indicator reading.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350914" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350914.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. STEERING KNUCKLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. JACK</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Floor jack can be used to wedge up steering knuckle.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Knuckle vertical play should be .002" -.012" (.051 -.305 mm). Add or remove shims as
                        necessary to obtain correct endplay. Center shims to prevent damage during assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">When vertical play adjustment is correct, align draw key opening and pin flat
                        alignment.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350915" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350915.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. KINGPIN NOTCH</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. KINGPIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. STEER KNUCKLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SINGLE DRAW KEY</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. DUAL DRAW KEYS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new draw keys.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Seat draw keys with a hammer and punch.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350916" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350916.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRAW KEY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. BRASS HAMMER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install draw key nuts and tighten to
                        <emph type="bold">30-45 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (41-61 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350917" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350917.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DRAW KEY NUT</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure draw key is fully seated by repeating step 13 and 14. Recheck draw key nut
                        torque.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install kingpin caps. Tighten caps to
                        <emph type="bold">50-75 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (68-102 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Tighten nut to range minimum in steps 14 and 17, then tighten just enough to align cotter
                            pin hole.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Attach new drag link to steering arm and Pitman arm. Install and torque nuts to
                        <emph type="bold">165-230 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (224-312 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350918" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new cotter pins into the drag link nuts.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Attach tie rod end to tie rod arm on knuckle. Install nut and tighten to
                        <emph type="bold">120-160 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (163-217 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350919" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350919.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new cotter pin.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Grease all kingpin and tie rod assemblies as required.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Steering Knuckle Stop Adjustment</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Old Steering Stop Adjustment Screw, lock-nut, and adapter must be re-installed onto
                        new knuckle. Torque adapter to
                        <emph type="bold">110-120 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (150-163 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350920" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350920.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. FRONT OF VEHICLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. STEERING KNUCKLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. AXLE BEAM</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. STEERING STOP ADJUSTMENT (BOTH ENDS OF AXLE)</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. DEGREE OF STEERING ANGLE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check steering angle with alignment turntable set. Refer to the following tables to
                        determine the correct steering angle for the truck:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <table id="t0350901">
                    <title>With Front Tire Size: 11R24.5 Use the following table:</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Front Axle Lineset Code</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Steering Gear Lineset Code</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Turn Angle</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGG</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>42&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGG</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>46&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGE</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>42&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGE</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>46&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGB</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>32&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGB</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>39&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <table id="t0350902">
                    <title>With ALL OTHER Front Tire Sizes Use the following table:</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Front Axle Lineset Code</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Steering Gear Lineset Code</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Turn Angle</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGG</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>46&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGG</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>50&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGE</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>46&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGE</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>50&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGB</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PRJ</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>40&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>02AGB</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>05PSA</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>43&#176;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If adjustment is required, loosen jam nut and turn stop screw as necessary.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350921" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350921.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. JAM NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. STOP SCREW</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After adjustment, tighten stop screw jam nut to
                        <emph type="bold">90-120 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                        (122-163 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Adjust power steering unit so that power assist stops approximately 3&#176; or 1/8" (3.175
                            mm) before touching the stop screws. Please refer to the Master Service Manual for
                            instructions on making this adjustment.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Steering gear must be functioning properly or steering linkage damage may occur. Poppet
                            relief must be checked after adjusting stop screw setting.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please refer to the Master Service Manual for instructions on checking and setting the
                            poppet relief valve properly for each steering gear set.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Wheel Alignment Check</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The procedure below begins with the wheels, hubs, and brake assemblies already
                            re-installed and with the front axle raised off the ground. If instructions are needed at
                            any point in this repair procedure, refer to the Master Service Manual. Follow all standard
                            safety precautions and procedures recommended by the Master Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please replace wheel hub seals during re-installation of wheel hub.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If electronic alignment equipment is used to set the toe-in, it is very important that the
                            equipment be in calibration to insure an accurate toe reading.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following procedure may be used to set the toe-in when electronic alignment equipment is not
                    available. To obtain an accurate toe reading, two mechanics are required to insure that the pointers
                    are always placed or adjusted to be exactly in front of the line scribed on both front tires.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the front wheels to the exact straight-ahead position.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Wipe off excess dirt and moisture from the center of both front tire treads (360&#176;).
                        Use a piece of chalk to mark the center area of both front tires around the complete
                        circumference.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Put a scribe or pointed instrument against the center of the whitened part of each
                        tire and rotate the tires 360&#176;. The scribe must be held in place so that a single straight
                        line is marked all the way around the tires.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Put a full floating radius gauge plate under each wheel. Lower the vehicle and
                        remove the lock pins from the radius gauge plates to allow the front wheels to return to the
                        normal operating position. If full floating radius gauge plates are not available, lower the
                        vehicle to the floor and roll it forward 12 to 15 feet (3.65 to 4.57 m) to neutralize the front
                        suspension. Neutralizing the front suspension is extremely important especially if the vehicle
                        has been jacked up to scribe the tires; otherwise, the front wheels will not return to the
                        normal operating position due to the tires gripping the floor surface when the vehicle is
                        lowered.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Set the sliding scale end of a trammel bar to zero (0) and lock the scale in
                        place.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350922" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350922.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SCRIBED LINE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Put the trammel bar at the rear of the front tires so that the sliding scale that
                        was set to zero in step 6 is centered against the scribed line on one of the tires.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Adjust the pointer on the end of the trammel bar opposite the sliding scale so it
                        lines up with the scribed line on the rear of the opposite front tire. Lock the pointer in place
                        on the trammel bar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Put the trammel bar against the front of the tires so the pointer end is against the
                        scribed line on the front tire. Loosen and move the sliding scale pointer on the opposite end of
                        the trammel bar so it is against the scribed line on the opposite tire. Lock the scale in place.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0350923" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0350923.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. POINTER END</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SLIDING SCALE END ADJUSTED TO SCRIBED LINE TO INDICATE ACTUAL TOE SETTING
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Read the toe-in or toe-out on the sliding scale. If toe-in is correct, it will read
                        <emph type="bold">1/16</emph>
                        inch &#177;
                        <emph type="bold">1/16</emph>
                        inch (1.59mm &#177; 1.59mm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If toe-in adjustment is necessary, use the following procedure:</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Loosen the tie rod clamps that secure the tie rod ends in position in the tie rod.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set the sliding scale on the trammel bar to read 1/16 inch (1.59mm) toe-in.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn the tie rod to set the toe-in. After the toe-in is set, the sliding scale and the
                            pointer should both be on the scribed line of the tire each is in front of.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn the steering wheel in each direction to center the steering linkage (if the vehicle
                            has power steering, start the engine before turning the wheel). Make sure the front wheels
                            are in a straight ahead position (stop engine), and re-check the toe-in setting. Make any
                            necessary adjustments.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Repeat step 4 until the toe-in reading is
                            <emph type="bold">1/16</emph>
                            inch &#177;
                            <emph type="bold">1/16</emph>
                            inch (1.59mm &#177; 1.59mm).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Position and tighten the tie rod clamp bolts to
                            <emph type="bold">45-65 Lbf-Ft</emph>
                            (61-88 Nm).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The part required for this recall is:</para>
            <table id="t0350903">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.19*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>8900101R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>03509 Recall Service Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Wheel Seals</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>As per Lineset 29XXX Code</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>As Req'd</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>This Service Kit 8900101R91 contains the following parts:</para>
            <table id="t0350904">
                <title>Service Kit 8900101R91</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.19*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>329825</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Dana Recall Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Recall Kit Contains:</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>971683 Steer Knuckle Assy</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>160HP104-1 Draw Key</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>160HP104-2 Draw Key</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>220HN103 Draw Key Nuts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>817493 .005" Shim</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>817494 .010" Shim</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>971370 Knuckle Caps</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>HP102 Pitman Arm Cotter Pin</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3571919C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Link, Steering Drag, RH-HDD</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>137214</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Drag Link Cotter Pin</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This Recall service kit DOES NOT contain wheel seals. Please replace with wheel seals as per
                        Lineset code 29XXX for each truck.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">Only approximately 50 trucks are expected to need the recall kit. Please order a
                    Recall Kit only when the Inspection Procedure determines it is required.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">All removed parts should be destroyed locally.</emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0350905">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03509-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Inspect</emph>
                                    Steering Arm and Drag Link Clearance Only
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.7 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-03509-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Replace</emph>
                                    Steering Knuckle and Drag Link Only
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>3.8 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
