<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03505 - NONCOMPLIANCE RECALL - Windshield Washer Wiper Switch Defective on Certain 5000i and 9000i
        Models
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec03505">
        <recallnumber>03505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>March, 2003</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subject>NONCOMPLIANCE RECALL - Windshield Washer Wiper Switch Defective on Certain 5000i and 9000i Models
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/06/2003</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/15/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/06/2003</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/15/2003</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus03505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Certain 5000i and 9000i vehicles are noncompliant with Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard (FMVSS)
                104; section S.4.2.2 because the windshield washer may not function properly when the washer switch is
                activated. When the engine is running with all accessories off, including the windshield wipers, and the
                wash function is activated, fluid may squirt briefly or not at all onto the windshield. The wipers cycle
                normally, but in the absence of washer fluid, the windshield will not be adequately cleaned.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Certain 5000i and 9000i models built between 1/6/03 and 1/15/03 are involved in this recall.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this campaign.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign, because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. If a vehicle moves unexpectedly or
                            suddenly, the result could be serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Operational Test</title>
                <para>The following Operational Test
                    <emph type="bold">must</emph>
                    be performed before replacing any windshield washer wiper switch to determine whether the switch is
                    defective.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify there is sufficient fluid in the windshield washer reservoir.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With the engine running and all accessories including the wiper switch off, activate
                        the wash function of the switch by holding the wash button
                        <emph type="bold">longer than 1/2 of a second</emph>. The wipers should start cycling and wipe
                        the windshield clean within 5 cycles of the wiper blades. Washer fluid should squirt onto the
                        windshield and continue to squirt as long as the button is held. When the button is released,
                        the washer should continue to squirt for 2 seconds and stop.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If after activating the wash cycle, the washer does not start squirting fluid or
                        shuts off prematurely before the wipers can clear the windshield, the switch must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Replacement of Switch</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect negative battery cable at the battery.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove screws retaining dash switch panel. Pull panel forward and disconnect
                        electrical wire at windshield washer wiper switch and remove the windshield washer wiper switch
                        from the dash switch panel.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new windshield washer wiper switch in the dash switch panel and reconnect
                        the electrical wire to the new switch. Reinstall dash switch panel.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect negative battery cable.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify washer wiper switch performs as stated in item 2 of the above operational
                        test.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0350501">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.62*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.82*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.57*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity Required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Windshield Washer Wiper Switch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>3534329C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">All removed switches are to be scrapped locally.</emph>
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0350502">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-03505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Perform Operational Test Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03505-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform Operational Test and Remove and Replace Windshield Washer Wiper Switch
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
