<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 03516 Interim Notice - FRONT DRIVE SHAFT on 4800 4x4's with FABCO TC-200 TRANSFER CASES built
        6/30/1999 thru 5/8/2002
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec03516">
        <recallnumber>03516 Interim Notice</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subject>FRONT DRIVE SHAFT on 4800 4x4's with FABCO TC-200 TRANSFER CASES built 6/30/1999 thru 5/8/2002
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/30/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/08/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>13TJZ</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec03516.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus03516.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>An excessive front driveshaft angle may cause accelerated wear and failure of the driveshaft and
                related components. The front driveshaft can possibly become separated from the vehicle without warning
                and get into the path of other vehicles on the highway, possibly resulting in property damage, personal
                injury, or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This Safety Recall involves 4800 4x4 models with a Fabco TC-200 transfer case (feature code 13TJZ
                ONLY) built 6/30/1999 through 5/8/2002.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of these vehicles about this Interim
                Action.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">If owners operate their vehicles at highway speeds for extended periods of time,
                    they are given the option of removing the front driveshaft or limiting their road speed (please see
                    the attached owner notification letter). In cases where owners desire to have the shaft removed (or
                    installed) but do not wish to perform the service themselves, the instructions below are being
                    provided.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">The final remedy is not expected to be available until the end of 2004.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent unexpected movement of the vehicle and possible serious personal injury or death,
                        block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FRONT DRIVESHAFT REMOVAL</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove
                    <emph type="bold">front</emph>
                    driveshaft only.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure no parts remain loose.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FRONT DRIVESHAFT INSTALLATION</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install existing driveshaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use new bolts and straps as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The part required for this interim action is:</para>
            <table id="t0351601">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.45*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.56*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1658834C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>KIT U-JT STRAP &#38; BOLT 1610</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0351602">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-03516-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>REMOVE FRONT DRIVESHAFT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-03516-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>INSTALL FRONT DRIVESHAFT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">There is NO campaign ID label required for this interim action.</emph>
            </para>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for
                depreciation, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
