<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 04305 - 30-Inch Child Restraint Seat Cushion Retention</stitle>
    <recall id="rec04305">
        <recallnumber>04305</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>30-Inch Child Restraint Seat Cushion Retention</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/25/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/24/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000 FE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/25/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/24/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000 RE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/25/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/24/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec04305.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus04305.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice: This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has decided that a defect which relates to motor vehicle safety exists in certain CE, FE and RE model
                school buses.
            </para>
            <para>The 30-inch child restraint seat cushion retention may not retain the seat in all circumstances. In
                the event of a sudden stop, the seat cushion may tip forward and may become unattached causing the
                passenger to slide off the seat and/or be trapped by the seat cushion. This action could possibly result
                in personal injury or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected buses were built from March 25, 1998 through August 24, 2004. This recall does not affect
                the use of the fold down child safety seat.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INTERIM PRECAUTIONS UNTIL REPAIR COMPLETED:</title>
            </para>
            <para>The customer was told not to use the seats for seating passengers until the recall has been remedied.
                Seats that have the turn buckle on the underside of the seat at the wall side properly applied can be
                used for seating the proper passenger size in the child safety seats.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The customer was told that their dealer would make this correction for them at no cost or contact us
                for parts to make their own repair.
            </para>
            <para>Since each unit may require different quantity of parts IC is prepared to ship parts directly to the
                dealer matching the needs of the units being repaired at no charge. Therefore the last eight characters
                of the VIN of each unit to be repaired must be forwarded to our Compliance Department when calling our
                number 1-800-843-5615, faxing to 1-501-505-2433 or emailing to kathy.anders@ic-corp.com. Make sure to
                include the name of the person responsible and street or road address. A Post Office Box (P.O. Box)
                number for shipping is not acceptable. PDC's will not have these materials for this recall.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Follow the steps below to make this repair.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure that the cushion is in place and snug against the sidewall of the bus.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the metal Z-shaped clip, hold in place against the rectangular rear longitudinal
                    bar and the board on the bottom side of the seat cushion. Leave about 1 inch between edge of clip
                    and seat frame reinforcement plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the locations of the fastener holes in the Z-shaped clip on the seat cushion
                    board.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the turnbuckle located on the wall side of the seat cushion.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the seat cushion to drill holes and add clinch nuts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill two 5/16 diameter holes at the locations marked in the prior step. You may want to
                    use the Z-shaped clip as a guide for checking the location of the holes. When drilling these holes
                    use caution not to penetrate beyond the thickness of the board, which is about 1/2 - inch, to
                    prevent damage to the seat cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the staples that hold the seat cover to the board in the area where the holes
                    were added to allow placing of the T-nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place one T-nut in each drilled hole from the cushion side of the board. They do not
                    have to be pressed into the board. When the z-shaped clip is installed, the T-nuts will set
                    themselves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the seat cover material and staple back in place.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The turnbuckle on the aisle side of the cushion must be turned with the handle side
                    pointing to the aisle. This will provide clearance at the retaining end of the turnbuckle with the
                    seat frame tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Return seat to the proper position, which requires the seat cushion to be tight against
                    the wall of the bus.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using two (2) &#188;-inch bolts with &#188;-inch lock washers, secure the z-shaped clip
                    to the board using the T-nuts just installed. These bolts must be inserted into the nut insert that
                    was just installed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The seat cushion is now secure to the seat frame.</para>
            <figure id="f0430501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0430501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0430501" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.83*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.33*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.85*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>180020</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#188;-20 x &#190;-inch bolt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 required per seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>120380</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#188; lock washer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 required per seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>90902200</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>T-nut &#188; -20</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 required per seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2211130C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Z-shaped clip</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 required per seat</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0430502" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.05*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.67*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Labor Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair one (1) seat in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair two (2) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.7 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair three (3) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.9 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair four (4) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.1 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair five (5) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.3 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair six (6) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.5 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-7</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair seven (7) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.7 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair eight (8) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.9 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04305-9</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Time to repair nine (9) seats in one unit and file paper work</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2.1 hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary corrections to the units in your inventory. All inventory
                vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If
                vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and/or
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle which is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately repaired within a reasonable time after the
                owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair within 60 days after a tender of a
                vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If the condition is not
                adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with an identical or
                reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a reasonable
                allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made
                to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - REPAIRS PERFORMED BY AUTHORIZED DEALERS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary correction to the units in your inventory. All inventory
                vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If
                vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Safety Recall
                04305.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">LESSOR RESPONSIBILITY:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Federal Regulations require that any vehicle lessor receiving this recall notice must forward a copy
                of this notice to the lessee within ten days.
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation asks for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you
                have any questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your
                regional office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
