<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 04304 - Driver Seat Pedestal on certain FE Bus models built between 03-12-1992 and 03-03-2004
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec04304">
        <recallnumber>04304</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Driver Seat Pedestal on certain FE Bus models built between 03-12-1992 and 03-03-2004</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>FE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/12/1992</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/03/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec04304.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus04304.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The seats involved in this recall are manufactured by CE White and are mounted on a pedestal type base
                only. The plate of the upper pedestal mounting of the driver seat pedestal, which provides the mounting
                surface for the seat, may develop cracks. These cracks could progress to the extent that the seat
                becomes unstable and distracts the driver, or in some cases the seat could separate from the base. This
                could possibly result in personal injury or death in the event of an accident.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0430401" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0430401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This recall involves certain FE Bus models built between 03-12-1992 and 03-03-2004.</para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to Figure 1 shown previously in the document.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four nuts that mount the seat adjusters to the plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift off the seat making sure that you clear any seat belt parts that may be guided by
                    the seat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unscrew the "T" handle and guide bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While holding the positioning lever in the most upright position, remove the upper
                    pedestal mounting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the new upper pedestal, making sure the guide slot (long vertical slot in the
                    tube) is inline with the guide bolt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Screw the guide bolt back into place.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the seat assembly removed in Step 2, using the nuts removed in Step 1.
                    <emph type="bold">Make sure</emph>
                    that the seat belt is placed back in the guide if available. The nuts should be
                    <emph type="bold">torqued</emph>
                    to 16 to 18 LbF-Ft (21.7 Nm to 24.4 Nm) if dry and 12 to 14 LbF-Ft (16.3 to 18.9 Nm) if oiled.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the seat to desired height and tighten the "T" handle to secure the seat
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Destroy the removed upper pedestal.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0430401" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.92*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.49*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.60*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2589628C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Upper Pedestal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0430402" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.05*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.67*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Labor Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04304-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace upper pedestal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary corrections to the units in your inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer, or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and/or
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date. To avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the
                purchase price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair
                his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>POSSIBLE CUSTOMER REIMBURSEMENT</title>
            </para>
            <para>There may be an occasion when a customer was charged for repairs related to this Recall prior to the
                Recall being released. The customer letter contains a statement for the customer to contact the Dealer
                if they believe they are entitled to reimbursement costs. The Dealer should follow the Customer
                Reimbursement guidelines in Warranty Policy Letter 03-001G. The Warranty Procedures and Administrative
                Policies manual (CTS1100) includes the information in Policy Letter 03-001G.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary correction to the units in your inventory. All inventory
                vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If
                vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
