<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 04302 - Emergency Exit Window Instructions</stitle>
    <recall id="rec04302">
        <recallnumber>04302</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Emergency Exit Window Instructions</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000 RE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/31/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/14/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec04302.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus04302.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice: This notice is sent to you
                in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act. IC Corporation
                has decided that certain American Transportation and IC RE&#8482; model school buses fail to conform to
                Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard (FMVSS) No. 217, "Bus Emergency Exits and Window Retention and
                Release."
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>REASONS FOR THIS RECALL</title>
            </para>
            <para>The rear emergency exit window interior opening procedure instruction label on the frame of the window
                located inside the bus is not one centimeter in height as required by FMVSS 217. In the event of an
                emergency, understanding the proper operation of the emergency exit window may be impaired preventing
                rapid egress from the bus.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected RE model school buses were built from July 31, 2000 through April 14, 2004. The vehicle
                identified on the enclosed card fits this description and our records show you as the owner of this
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ACTIONS REQUIRED</title>
            </para>
            <para>IC requested the owner to place the label enclosed with the notice on the units identified to them as
                displayed on the green cards.
            </para>
            <para>IC requests the dealer to add the new label to any of these windows in the dealer inventory. The part
                numbers of the windows are 448288001 through 448288020.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Repair Procedure</title>
            <para>The customer was told that IC had included with the notice a sufficient number of labels to repair the
                units in their inventory. The label has a peel off back that must be removed prior to placing it on the
                glass, as shown on the picture below. The customer was asked to make sure the glass is clean and dry
                before the application is made. To comply with federal regulations, it is important to place the label
                in the location shown in the picture below.
            </para>
            <para>We also told the customer that if they would like their dealer to make this correction for them at no
                cost, they should contact their dealer to make the arrangements to repair the unit. You will need to
                give your dealer the new label.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0430201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0430201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0430201">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.05*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.67*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900138R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Label Instructions Interior</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>To add label to the glass and complete the paper work.</para>
            <table id="t0430202">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.05*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.67*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Labor Operation Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04302-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install label on glass</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.2 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary corrections to the units in your inventory. All inventory
                vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If
                vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and/or
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle which is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately repaired within a reasonable time after the
                owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair within 60 days after a tender of a
                vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If the condition is not
                adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with an identical or
                reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a reasonable
                allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made
                to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the affected vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make the necessary correction to the units in your inventory. All inventory
                vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If
                vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, the transfer location or the customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Safety Recall
                04302.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">LESSOR RESPONSIBILITY:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Federal Regulations require that any vehicle lessor receiving this recall notice must forward a copy
                of this notice to the lessee within ten days.
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation asks for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you
                have any questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your
                regional office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
