<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 04508 - Kelsey-Hayes (Lucas Varity or TRW) Anti-Lock Brake (ABS) Electronic Control Unit on 1552,
        1652, 4700, and 4900 models built 2/28/1999 thru 3/25/2004
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec04508">
        <recallnumber>04508</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Kelsey-Hayes (Lucas Varity or TRW) Anti-Lock Brake (ABS) Electronic Control Unit on 1552, 1652, 4700,
            and 4900 models built 2/28/1999 thru 3/25/2004
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1552
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/28/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/25/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>1652
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/28/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/25/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/28/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/25/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/28/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/25/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">This recall is the final remedy and supercedes Safety Recall G-02510.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">This recall is for truck models only.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec04508.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus04508.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The anti-lock brake system (ABS) electronic control unit may misinterpret a corrupt wheel speed
                signal. The corrupt wheel speed signals may improperly activate the ABS, instead of deactivating the
                ABS. This may result in the driver experiencing a hard pedal feel and a decrease in deceleration at the
                end of the stop, resulting in extended stopping distances which could cause a vehicle crash, possibly
                resulting in
                <emph type="bold">property damage, personal injury, or death</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This Safety Recall involves 1552, 1652, 4700, and 4900 models with hydraulic brakes and a Kelsey-Hayes
                (Lucas Varity or TRW) ABS electronic control unit built 2/28/1999 thru 3/25/2004.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">Many vehicles involved in this recall are also involved in Safety Recall G-04501.
                    The owners of vehicles who are involved in BOTH recalls were sent a special notification letter that
                    informed them of both recalls. The Authorization for Recall Service cards were also printed with
                    both recall numbers on them.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">The owners involved in this recall that are NOT part of Safety Recall G-04501,
                    received a standard owner notification.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent unexpected movement of the vehicle and possible serious personal injury or death,
                        block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the negative battery terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the EHCU assembly on the driver's side frame rail.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0450801" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0450801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove dirt from the EHCU assembly with a dry soft brush or cloth. Blow loose particles
                    and dust away with low-pressure shop air.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not use water or chemical cleaners.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 2-way and 24-way connectors from the ECU.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Avoid touching the pins of the electrical connectors on the ECU. Damage could occur, due to
                        electrostatic discharge.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0450802" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0450802.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 2-way connector from the electrical interconnect between the ECU and HCU
                    (it is located on the side of the EHCU that was next to the frame rail).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a small hammer, lightly tap the four T-25 Torx&#174; bolts which fasten the ECU to
                    the HCU. Remove the bolts cautiously, so as to ensure they are not broken during removal.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If bolts cannot be removed due to corrosion, or stripped heads, or if they become
                        broken off, replace entire EHCU assembly. This is the only condition in which EHCU assembly
                        replacement will be necessary.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Refer to Master Service Manual for proper EHCU removal and re-installation
                                instructions.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not pry on the ECU or HCU with a mechanical aid. Excessive force will cause damage to the
                        units.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0450803" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0450803.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove the ECU from the HCU. A light amount of force may be required. Ensure
                    no dirt falls into the HCU.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove EHCU gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Always insure hydraulic connections and components are kept clean to prevent contamination.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not reuse the ECU gasket or mounting bolts. Always install new gasket and mounting bolts
                        with the replacement ECU.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new ECU gasket onto the HCU.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not use RTV or any other type of sealant on the ECU gasket or mating surfaces.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mate the ECU with the HCU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install four new Torx&#174; T-25 ECU bolts and tighten them to 5 Nm (39 LbF-in.) in an X
                    pattern.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the 2-way connector from the interconnect on the HCU to the ECU (it is located
                    on the side of the EHCU that will face the frame rail).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the 2-way and 24-way electrical connectors to the ECU .</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-connect the negative battery terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Once installed, the new ECU may activate the ABS warning lamp even though the lamp was not
                        activated prior to the ECU replacement. Should this occur, the MASTER SERVICE MANUAL should be
                        consulted to troubleshoot the cause of the ABS fault.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The new ECU contains software algorithms that can identify marginal system components, such as
                        worn sensors, connectors, wiring, and tone rings. If a marginally performing system component
                        exists, the ECU may set a fault and turn the ABS lamp on. This situation requires proper
                        troubleshooting to identify and repair the marginal component according to the Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Any labor or parts associated with troubleshooting are not part of this recall and are the
                        responsibility of the vehicle owner.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The part required for this recall is:</para>
            <table id="t0450701">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.64*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.65*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>8900100R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Recall Service Kit, ECU Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>There may be a reason to replace the entire electronic control unit (ECU)
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                hydraulic control unit (HCU) assembly (EHCU). Please refer to the SERVICE PROCEDURE to determine under
                which conditions the EHCU assembly is to be replaced. The EHCU part information is as follows:
            </para>
            <table id="t0450702">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.62*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.08*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="0.87*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>8900134R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col2">
                                <para>Recall Service Kit, EHCU Assembly (HCU and ECU)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center" colname="col3">
                                <para>1 -- only as required per service procedure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0450803">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04508-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove and Replace ECU</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.6 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04508-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove and Replace EHCU Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.5 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>POSSIBLE CUSTOMER REIMBURSEMENT</title>
            </para>
            <para>There may be an occasion when a customer was charged for repairs related to this recall prior to the
                recall being released. The customer letter contains a statement for the customer to contact the Dealer
                if they believe they are entitled to reimbursement costs. The Dealer should follow the Customer
                Reimbursement guidelines in Warranty Policy Letter 03-001G. The Warranty Procedures and Administrative
                Policies manual (CTS1100) is in the process of being updated to include the information in Policy Letter
                03-001G.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
