<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 04513 - NONCOMPLIANCE RECALL: COMPLETE VEHICLE LABELS on 4300 and 4400 tractor models built 5/24/2004
        thru 7/26/2004
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec04513">
        <recallnumber>04513</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 2004</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>GENERAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>NONCOMPLIANCE RECALL: COMPLETE VEHICLE LABELS on 4300 and 4400 tractor models built 5/24/2004 thru
            7/26/2004
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/24/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/26/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/24/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/26/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec04513.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus04513.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The "Complete Vehicle" label with the gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR), gross axle weight rating
                (GAWR), recommended tire size and tire pressure was not installed on the vehicle. A misunderstanding of
                the vehicle's weight rating, tire type, or tire pressure may cause a vehicle to be operated outside its
                designed parameters.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This recall involves 4300 and 4400 tractor models built at International's Springfield, Ohio Assembly
                Plant from 5/24/2004 thru 7/26/2004 with 5th wheels.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent unexpected movement of the vehicle and possible serious personal injury or
                            death, block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>The 'Complete Vehicle,' labels are VIN specific and were shipped directly to owners, or
                            selling dealers (for dealer stock units).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicle owners are instructed to install the label. If they do not wish to install the
                            label, they are asked to contact their nearest International dealer for them to install it.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicle owners are also instructed to check the VIN on the label with the VIN on their
                            Authorization for Recall Service Card and the VIN on their vehicle. If the VIN on the label
                            does not match, the owners are instructed to contact their nearest International dealer to
                            obtain a new, correct label.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>To obtain a correct label, the dealer must fill out the fax form below and fax to (260)
                            461-1911. Please do not forget to list the VIN of the vehicle requiring the new label.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>The new label will then be printed and shipped to the dealer (or owner) for
                                    installation.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Label installation is as follows:</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <figure id="f0451301" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0451301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="580px"/>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Label Installation Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Label is to be installed on the DRIVER's side door frame area as shown in Figure 1,
                        Item 'A'.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure area is clean below door hasp, as indicated, with a clean, dry cloth before
                        installing included label.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0451302" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0451302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="520px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>See SERVICE PROCEDURE for part information.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0451301" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-04513-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Label Installation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
