<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05505 - Engine Cover Lid on certain FE School Bus and FE Commercial Bus models built between
        09-04-2003 and 02-05-2005
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05505">
        <recallnumber>05505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Engine Cover Lid on certain FE School Bus and FE Commercial Bus models built between 09-04-2003 and
            02-05-2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>FE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/04/2003</startdate>
                        <enddate>02/05/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus05505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>During pre-trip inspection or engine service, the engine cover lid can be opened until it leans
                against the instrument panel. There is no latching device to keep the lid open. When it is in the open
                position, the lid is slightly over center and can close if bumped or if the bus is on a slight incline.
                Without a retention device, when the engine cover lid is in the open position, it can close without
                warning resulting in possible
                <emph type="bold">personal injury</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This safety recall involves certain FE School and FE Commercial Busses built between 09-04-2003 and
                02-05-2005 at the Conway, Arkansas Bus Assembly Plant.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">All instructions assume that the installer is inside the bus and facing the front. Use
                    a #21 drill bit (.1590 inch) for the screw pilot holes.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the location of the first hole for the first latch bracket 4-inches to the right of
                    the windshield center bar. Using the bracket as a template, align the bracket with the flange of the
                    bulkhead to mark the location of the second hole.
                    <emph type="bold">Slip one end of the cable onto the bracket before attaching the bracket to the bus
                        body</emph>. Attach the bracket using the screws included in the kit. Figure 1 shows the result.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Before marking the holes and attaching the second bracket, make sure that the
                        cable will reach and the snap bolt will hook onto the second bracket where you are planning to
                        attach it.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the location of the left hole of the second bracket 16-inches to the right of the
                    left hole of the first bracket. Again, using the bracket as a template, align the bracket with the
                    flange of the bulkhead to mark the location of the second hole. See Figure 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550502" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For units with optional windshield defogger code 048PKD, the first latch bracket can be
                    installed on the flange of the bulkhead in order to clear the grille. See Figure 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550503" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To retain the engine access cover in the open position, remove the cable latch from the
                    right latch bracket and snap it on to the eye of the engine access cover latch bracket. See Figure
                    4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0550501" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.75*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.53*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2589248C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">FE Engine Cover Kit</emph>
                                    - includes: bracket P/N 421756001 (2), cable assy P/N 2211534C91 (1), self tapping
                                    screws P/N 24396R1 (4)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0550502" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Installation and Documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
