<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05509 - WEBASTO HEATER on certain CE School Bus, FE School Bus, RE School Bus, and RE Commercial Bus
        models built between 12/02/2002 and 03/01/2005
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05509">
        <recallnumber>05509</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subject>WEBASTO HEATER on certain CE School Bus, FE School Bus, RE School Bus, and RE Commercial Bus models
            built between 12/02/2002 and 03/01/2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/02/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/01/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>FE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/02/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/01/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/02/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/01/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus05509.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>An incorrectly manufactured burner tube in the Webasto heater installed in the bus can fail
                prematurely. Premature failure of the burner tube may cause combustible materials in or around the
                vehicle to ignite. This may result in
                <emph type="bold">property damage, personal injury or death</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This safety recall involves certain CE, FE and RE School Bus, and RE Commercial Bus models built
                between 12/02/2002 and 03/01/2005 with Webasto heaters (property codes 49GWX, 0049GDM).
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="7">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a flat
                        level surface, set the parking brake, turn the engine off and chock the wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious injury or death, always disconnect the heater power cable from the vehicle
                        battery before you perform vehicle maintenance or service. Use a voltmeter to make sure the
                        heater is not powered.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A 10mm socket, extension and 1/4 drive ratchet or a long 10mm Tee-handle and socket
                    combination is required.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Before starting work</emph>, check to see if the heater is already marked. This
                    means the burner tube has been replaced already. Corrected heaters are marked with a yellow dot on
                    the control unit or on the front side of the burner head cover (black plastic) or in both places
                    (see Figures 6 and 7).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If the heater is not marked, then inspect the heater for the following serial
                        numbers.
                    </emph>
                    Only these serial numbers must have the burner tubes changed.
                    <emph type="bold">If the Webasto heater serial number is not on this list, DO NOT change the burner
                        tube.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0550902">
                <tgroup cols="1" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>100265 through 100959</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>194702</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>200040 through 200775</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>219442 through 219545</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>228868 through 229116</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>229716</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>300290</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>300905 through 302449</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>400212 through 402002</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>700000 through 704500</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>705501 through 706056</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>707001 through 707498</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>800000 through 801300</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>802002 through 802066</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If the heater serial number was on the list above</emph>, then remove the heater
                    power cable from the vehicle battery or disconnect the heater from other electrical source. Removing
                    the heater from the vehicle is not generally necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For opening of heaters, both eyebolts of the housing are to be loosened (see Figures 1
                    and 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550901" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550901.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0550902" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550902.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the burner head has been unlatched, swing it open to the side (see Figure 3). If
                    there is no clearance to do so, or there is a risk of damaging the wiring harness or fuel lines, the
                    split pin can be either removed or inserted in the other side of the housing
                    <emph type="bold">before</emph>
                    loosening the eyebolts. If there is not sufficient clearance, the burner head can be disconnected
                    and completely removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not damage the ignition electrodes (1) during the work. DO NOT change the screw position of
                        the air intake bellows. This only happens if the adjusting screw is not properly tightened.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0550903" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550903.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The burner tube can now be carefully pulled out (see Figure 4). If burner tube fit is
                    very tight, use two screwdrivers to gently pry it evenly away from the heat exchanger.
                    <emph type="boldundersc">Destroy the burner tube NOW</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">so that it cannot be accidentally re-used (hit aluminum section of tube with a
                        hammer- - once it is damaged, the tube is no longer useable).
                    </emph>
                    Do a visual check of the heat exchanger for damages. If necessary, remove carbon deposits with a
                    steel brush. Insert the new burner tube into the heat exchanger until it is fully seated. No further
                    adjustment is necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550904" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550904.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When reassembling the burner head to the heat exchanger the eyebolts and ears must be in
                    the correct position during tightening (see Figure 1).
                    <emph type="bold">Tighten the eyebolts to a maximum of 4.0 Nm (35.5 lb-in.). Over-tightening could
                        damage the casting. If the split pin was removed, it must now be refitted.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the burner head has been re-installed, make sure that all four grommets (2 right
                    and 2 left) are in place. To minimize combustion air leakage, ensure grommets are fitted tightly
                    around wire cables and fuel pipes (see Figure 5).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550905" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">In the case of the Scholastic Series heater with a
                    <emph type="bold">single line fuel system</emph>, make sure the blank fuel pipe slot in the casting
                    has a
                    <emph type="bold">solid (no hole) grommet</emph>
                    in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a water insoluble (permanent ink or paint) yellow dot, minimum 10mm (0.5 in.), on
                    the control unit and on the front side of the burner head (see Figures 6 and 7) to identify
                    corrected heaters.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550906" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0550907" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">After completing the correction, a visual inspection and a test run of the heater
                        must be performed according to the service instructions.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If you are a bus customer</emph>
                    and are completing this work, please include the Webasto heater serial number when you return the
                    enclosed card.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If you are a dealer</emph>
                    and are completing this work, please include the heater serial number in the warranty claim that you
                    file.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Technical questions can be answered at the Webasto hotline: (800) 555-4518</emph>
                A Service and Repair manual is available online at www.techwebasto.com or by entering "
                <emph type="bold">http://www.techwebasto.com/heater_main/907502.pdf</emph>
                " into the address line of your web browser.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0550901" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.75*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.53*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2585244C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>CHAMBER,HEATER COMBUSTION (Replacement Burner Tube for Webasto Heater)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 As Required by Service Procedure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0550903" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05509-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspection only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05509-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect and Repair if serial number is on list</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
