<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05504 - Brake Pedal Pivot Bolt Locknut on certain CE school bus models built between 4/27/2004 and
        10/13/2004
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05504">
        <recallnumber>05504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Brake Pedal Pivot Bolt Locknut on certain CE school bus models built between 4/27/2004 and 10/13/2004
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/27/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/13/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05504.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/ICCus05504.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>An incorrectly torqued locknut on the brake pedal pivot bracket can allow the pivot bolt to back out
                of the bracket. This may result in the brake pedal falling off.
            </para>
            <para>This could cause a
                <emph type="bold">vehicle crash without warning</emph>
                that may result in
                <emph type="bold">property damage, personal injury or death</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This safety recall involves certain CE school buses built 4/27/2004 thru 10/13/2004 at the Tulsa,
                Oklahoma Bus Assembly Plant.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles.
                During the recall process a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a flat
                        level surface, set the parking brake, turn the engine off and chock the wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Follow the steps below to make this repair.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>See Figure 1 for location of locknut in a bus.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>See Figure 2 for a view of the assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>See Figure 3 for a drawing of the complete assembly.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the locknut. The locknut is located on the right hand side of the pivot bracket,
                    above the brake pedal.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not confuse this locknut with the nut on the brake booster push rod below it.
                    </emph>
                    See Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the locknut appears to be tight, check the torque. Proper torque for this locknut is
                    75 to 85 ft-lb.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the locknut is torqued above or below this range, proceed to step #4. If the torque
                    is within this range, no further action is necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the locknut. Care must be taken to not allow the pivot bolt to back out or the
                    bushings to fall out of the assembly. See Figure 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the locknut for damage. If the locknut is not damaged, continue. If the locknut
                    is damaged, Replace the locknut and continue.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the locknut onto the pivot bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten locknut to 75 to 85 ft-lb of torque with a torque spec tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0550401" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="296px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOCKNUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE BOOSTER PUSH ROD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0550402" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0550403" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0550403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PIVOT BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PIVOT BOLT LOCKNUT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>A part may be required for this recall: NUT, HEX LOCK, 1/2-13 UNC</para>
            <para>Additionally, if a bolt is required: BOLT, HEX HD 1/2-13UNC X 8.0, PHC GRADE 8</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0550401" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05504-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect, check torque; OR check torque and replace locknut; complete paperwork.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
