<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05524 - Bus Control Arm Bracket on Certain CE and BE Bus Models Built Between 02/10/2004 and
        12/15/2005
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05524">
        <recallnumber>05524</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>March, 2006</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>Bus Body</subjectfile>
        <subject>Bus Control Arm Bracket on Certain CE and BE Bus Models Built Between 02/10/2004 and 12/15/2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/10/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>BE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/10/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>47DAC</ucode>
                <ucode>47DAD</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05524.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus05524.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The door control bracket for the manual door control arm does not meet the guidelines in the NHTSA
                handbook for door entrance and handrail design. Failure to meet the guidelines can result in certain
                small objects, including, but not limited to, coat tie strings with draw string clips or other objects
                attached thereto, getting caught as the passenger exits the bus, which could result in death or personal
                injury.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>PB105 (CESB): 2005, 2006, 2007 Model Years</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>PC105 (CECB): 2005, 2006, 2007 Model Years</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>PB405 (BESB): 2007 Model Year</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>This recall includes only the manual door control feature codes: 0047DAC and 0047DAD.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a
                            flat level surface, set the parking brake, shut the engine off and chock the wheels.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Remove Old Bracket</title>
                <figure id="f0552401" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0552401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="502px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1 - Old Bracket and Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Refer to Figure 1.</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the door control yoke from the old bracket.</para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Remove the snap retainer at the bottom of the assembly.</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Pull the clevis pin.</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Be sure to note the order in which the parts are removed so they can be replaced
                            or re-installed in reverse order.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the 4 screws that hold the bracket to the door. These screws are screwed into
                        tapped holes. Be careful not to damage the threads of the tapped hole.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once the 4 screws are removed, the old bracket can be removed.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Install New Bracket</title>
                <figure id="f0552402" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0552402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2 - New Bracket</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Refer to new bracket in Figure 2. (Reverse the order of steps in the removal procedure.)</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the new bracket in the same position against the door.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace the screws into the tapped holes on the door.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Torque screws to 15-20 LbF-Ft (20.4-27.1 Nm). Be very careful not to strip the
                        threads in the door!
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-attach the door control yoke to the new bracket by reinserting the clevis pin and
                        snap ring. Ensure that spacers are positioned correctly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0552401" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.24in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2208857C2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>BAR, ASSY CE ENTRANCE DOOR</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0552402" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05524-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="304px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with
                an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a
                reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date. To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase
                price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or
                her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
