<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05520 - Rear Drive Axle Spindles on certain 5600i, 7300 and 7600 Models built 6/13/2005 thru
        6/16/2005
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05520">
        <recallnumber>05520</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>REAR AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Rear Drive Axle Spindles on certain 5600i, 7300 and 7600 Models built 6/13/2005 thru 6/16/2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>ArvinMeritor</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5600i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/13/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/16/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/13/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/16/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/13/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/16/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05520.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus05520.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The suspect rear drive axle spindles may have been incorrectly heat treated. Such a condition lessens
                the overall structural integrity of the spindles and could result in their fracture. If the spindle
                fractures while the vehicle is in motion it may cause wheel separation, which could, without warning,
                result in a
                <emph type="bold">vehicle crash</emph>
                possibly resulting in
                <emph type="bold">property damage, personal injury or death.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This Safety Recall involves 5600i, 7300 and 7600 models built between 6/13/2005 and 6/16/2005 with
                ArvinMeritor&#174; Series 145 and 160 rear drive axles.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Axle Housing Date Code Inspection Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent unexpected movement of the vehicle and possible serious personal injury or death,
                        block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both rear axle shafts (both sides).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If suspect vehicle has a tandem rear axle, only remove the axle shafts (both sides) from the
                        FORWARD-REAR axle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect each spindle end for date code.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0552001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0552001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - Above example, "B5130"</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the date code on either spindle is: B5129, B5130, or B5131 axle replacement is
                    required.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To make arrangements for axle replacement parts, please contact:</para>
                    <verbatim>
                        <line>Mark Balding, Customer Service</line>
                        <line>Arvin Meritor</line>
                        <line>(828) 687-2060</line>
                    </verbatim>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">ArvinMeritor will arrange payment for any parts, delivery or labor charges for
                            axle replacement separately from International's warranty system.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the date codes on either spindle DO NOT match those in step 3, then NO replacement is
                    necessary.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using NEW axle flange gaskets, re-install axle shafts and top off oil.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The part required for this recall is:</para>
            <table id="t0552001" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.24in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>As per Lineset Ticket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Rear Axle Flange Gasket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0552002" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05520-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Axle Date Code Inspection</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.8 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="304px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with
                an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a
                reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must be made to
                promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
