<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 05522 - SAFETY RECALL on Certain RE School and Commercial Bus Models with Between-the-Frame-Rail Air
        Tanks Located Over the Front Axle built between 7/20/2005 and 10/17/2005
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec05522">
        <recallnumber>05522</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>November, 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>SAFETY RECALL on Certain RE School and Commercial Bus Models with Between-the-Frame-Rail Air Tanks
            Located Over the Front Axle built between 7/20/2005 and 10/17/2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>RE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/20/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/17/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec05522.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus05522.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The air line connections at the primary and secondary air tanks may be reversed. The green line may be
                connected to the secondary air tank instead of the primary and the orange line may be connected to the
                primary instead of the secondary air tank.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>This recall involves certain RE School and Commercial Bus models built with between-the-frame-rail air
                tanks located over the front axle (feature code 04VBX) built between 7/20/2005 and 10/17/2005.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a
                            flat level surface, set the parking brake, shut the engine off and chock the wheels.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Labor Operations</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">This service procedure is split into two (2) sections: 1) an inspection section
                        and 2) a plumbing change section. Perform the inspection on the vehicle first to determine if a
                        plumbing change is required.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <figure id="f0552201" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0552201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="408px"/>
                    <caption>Correct Connection at Air Tank</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. INTERMEDIATE CONNECTION AT FRONT CROSSMEMBER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ORANGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SECONDARY AIR TANK</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. TO REAR OF BUS</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. PRIMARY AIR TANK</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. GREEN</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. TO FRONT OF BUS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The air tanks and air lines can be viewed by looking under the front of the bus. If
                        the air line color is not visible because of dirt or paint, you will have to perform the
                        inspection by sliding under the bus and wiping the dirt off or scraping the paint from the air
                        lines.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the green and orange lines are plumbed as indicated in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure 1</emph>. The green air line should connect to the primary tank, which
                        is located on the driver side of the bus. The orange air line should connect to the secondary
                        air tank, which is located on the entrance door side of the bus.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the tanks are plumbed according to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure 1</emph>, then the brake system is plumbed properly. NO plumbing change
                        is required and the recall is complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the tanks are not plumbed according to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure 1</emph>, and are reversed (orange to primary and green to secondary),
                        then continue on to
                        <emph type="boldital">Plumbing Change Procedure</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Plumbing Change Procedure</title>
                <para>Quality Connect Fitting Instructions:</para>
                <para>The Quality Connect fittings used on the air lines are threadless. A collet in the fitting bites
                    into the line to hold it firmly in place. The fitting O-ring seals the line to the valve, manifold
                    or tee body to prevent leakage. Please refer to TSI 94-04-03, Dated August 1994, Subject File:
                    Brakes, for detailed instructions and warnings on removing and replacing these fittings.
                </para>
                <para>The link on ISIS is:
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/940403.htm" bookname="TSI">http://service.navistar.com/tsis/940403.htm
                    </exhotlnk>
                </para>
                <para>If you do not have access to ISIS, you may request a copy of this TSI by calling 501-505-2193 or
                    emailing a request to Kathy.anders@ic-corp.com
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure 1</emph>
                        for all instructions.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Completely bleed off both primary and secondary air systems to 0 psi (0 KPa).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the 5/8" green line from the secondary air tank. Trim the green line
                        length to provide the same routing to the primary tank that is provided by the orange line.
                        Ensure the line is cut straight and is clean at the new sealing area. Do not remove the
                        intermediate connection at the front crossmember for the green line.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the 5/8" orange line from primary air tank.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the green line to the primary tank making sure there are no kinks.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen or remove all clipping on the 5/8" orange line between the air tanks and the
                        intermediate connection at the front crossmember.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the 5/8" orange line from the intermediate connection at the front
                        crossmember.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Measure and cut 80 inches (203.3cm) of 5/8" black bulk tubing to replace the 5/8"
                        orange air line. Ensure the cut is clean and even.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the new black line to the same port at the intermediate connection from
                        which the orange line was removed. Route and clip new black air line along the same path as the
                        original orange line. Trim line as necessary. Tighten or replace clipping if required. Ensure
                        there are no kinks in the line at any point in its routing. Make sure that any other lines or
                        cables are included in the clipping as originally built.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the black line to the secondary air tank.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the vehicle to pressurize the system and check for leaks at the intermediate
                        connection on the crossmember and the tank connections. Repair as required.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Test Brake System:</emph>
                        Drain the primary air tank. Ensure that the secondary air tank retains pressure. Apply the
                        service brake and ensure that the brakes actuate. Reinstate primary air tank pressure to normal.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0552201" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.13in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.08in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3544557C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>STRAP,CABLE LOCK*382MM BUTTON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>306132C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>STRAP,CABLE LOCK</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>417201C3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>TUBE,NYLON BULK 5/8 OD BLACK</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>80 Inches (203.3 cm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0552202" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05522-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-05522-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect and Repair</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Each vehicle corrected in accordance with this campaign
                <emph type="bold">must be</emph>
                marked with a S00109 Campaign Identification Label.
            </para>
            <para>Complete the label and attach on a clean surface next to the vehicle identification number (VIN)
                plate.
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/IClabel.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with
                an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a
                reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date. To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase
                price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or
                her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
