<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 06505 - NON-COMPLIANCE RECALL: Davenport / Floor Joint on certain RE Buses built between 07/01/2005
        and 05/09/2006.
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec06505">
        <recallnumber>06505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 2006</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>NON-COMPLIANCE RECALL: Davenport / Floor Joint on certain RE Buses built between 07/01/2005 and
            05/09/2006.
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>RE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/01/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/09/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec06505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus06505.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The davenport / floor joint at the rear of certain RE buses built between July 1, 2005 and May 9,
                2006, may not meet the required joint strength requirements of FMVSS No.221 "School Bus Body Joint
                Strength".
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>&#8226;&#9;PB305 (RESB) : 2006 and 2007 Model Years</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a
                            flat level surface, set the parking brake, shut the engine off and chock the wheels.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Required Tools</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Cordless impact &#38; #2 Phillips bit</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drill with 11/64" bit</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Strap cutter or Bolt cutter</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Broom or vacuum</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Magnetic strip or Drill guard</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Hacksaw with metal cutting blade</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>This repair involves securing three flat retaining bars along the front of the davenport joint.
                    The retaining bars are secured with 1 1/2" screws spaced at 1 1/8" installed through the floor
                    covering, plywood (if applicable), the davenport closeout's lower flange, and into the floor's
                    substructure. The davenport closeout's lower flange is typically not visible beneath the floor mat
                    and plywood (if applicable). There is only one part number for one length of retaining bar. The two
                    shorter retaining bars are made by cutting the longer bar to the appropriate length.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Please note the following requirements prior to completing the repair:</emph>
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Right hand side retaining bar must be placed so that it is against the side wall of the
                            bus and as close to the vertical face of the davenport cover as possible.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>All retaining bars must be as close to the vertical face of the davenport closeout as
                            possible.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Left hand side retaining bar must be positioned so that the outboard end is in line with
                            the heater hose notch.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The retaining bars should not overlap.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>All screws must be fully seated and secured through the structural channel under the
                            floor.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Rubber trim must be reinstalled so that the area has a good appearance.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Any nicks or scratches in the painted surface of the davenport closeout must be
                            repaired.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>All drill shavings must be cleaned up and removed.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Repair</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the rubber trim covering the joint between the bottom of the davenport
                        closeout and the floor by removing the retention screws. Typically a cordless impact and #2
                        Phillips bit will be used.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the trim and screws in a secure place so they can be reinstalled later in the
                        process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the last screw in each piece of aisle trim (screw mounted type) so that the
                        trim can be lifted. With screw-less trim, lift trim from retaining strip using a thin flat tool
                        such as a large screw driver or heavy duty putty knife. The screws will need to be replaced in
                        the screw mounted type trim at the end of the process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place a full length retaining bar (P/N 2592739C1) on the floor along the right hand
                        side of the davenport. The bar must be placed against the outer wall and as close to the
                        vertical face of the davenport closeout as possible. This is to ensure that the screws pass
                        through the retaining bar and davenport closeout flange as well as the substructure under the
                        floor. See Figure 1.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0650501" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0650501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Before drilling any of the screw holes, place a magnetic strip or other drill guard
                        along the vertical face of the davenport closeout to protect the painted surface from damage.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using the pilot holes in the retaining bar as guides, drill through the floor
                        material into the metal support bar under the floor with an 11/64" bit. It is recommended that a
                        screw is installed in every 5th hole to prevent the bar from shifting or "pie crusting" (wavy
                        affect) as the holes are drilled and screws installed.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install a screw in each pilot hole location. See Figure 2.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0650502" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0650502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">At the aisle trim location, the retaining bar should be run under the aisle trim
                        except for the screw-less trim. The screw-less trim must be modified so that it doesn't
                        interfere with the bar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the bar is too long, it is acceptable to trim the end of the retaining bar at the
                        corner of the center davenport closeout. This may be necessary for a V-8 bus. Typically a strap
                        cutter or bolt cutter can be used.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the remaining retaining bar adjacent to the diagonal edge of the davenport
                        closeout. Using the length of the diagonal face of the closeout as a guide, cut a section of
                        retaining bar to fit along the diagonal face.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Position the short section retaining bar as close to the vertical face of the
                        davenport closeout as possible.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0650503" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0650503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Drill and install screws in the pilot hole locations following the guidelines for
                        the right hand side retaining bar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the remaining retaining bar along the left hand side of the davenport
                        closeout. The retaining bar on the left hand side must not be placed all the way to the side
                        wall due to the heater hose cutout in the davenport cover. The outside end of the retaining bar
                        must be lined up with the cutout in the davenport closeout for the heater hose. The end of the
                        heater hose cover must be lifted to locate and mount the end of the bar. To lift heater hose
                        cover remove screws as needed. See Figure 4.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0650504" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0650504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Trim the length of the left hand side retaining bar if required.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Drill and install screws in the pilot hole locations following the guidelines for
                        the right hand side retaining bar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the screws removed in step 3. If required, drill a clearance hole in the
                        retaining bar. If the unit has aisle trim that is screw mounted vinyl or screwless trim, modify
                        the underside of the trim by removing the center rib to allow the trim to set flush on top of
                        the retaining bars. Press the screw-less trim back into the retainers.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-install the heater hose cover with the same screws removed in step 13.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean any drill shavings from around the retaining bars.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace the rubber davenport trim. The trim should cover the retaining bars.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0650501" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.06in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.62in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Kit Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Contains</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="2">
                                <para>8900185R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry morerows="2">
                                <para>KIT, FIELD FIX DAVENPORT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2592739C1 - Retaining, Bar Davenport</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2592738C1 - Manual, Field Fix Davenport</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>91305500 - Screw, #12 x 1.5" CRPNH</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>86</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="2">
                                <para>8900188R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry morerows="2">
                                <para>KIT, FIELD FIX DAVENPORT, SS (
                                    <emph type="bold">Florida</emph>
                                    only)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2592739C1 - Retaining, Bar Davenport</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2592738C1 - Manual, Field Fix Davenport</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>91302002 - SST Screw, #12 x 1.5" CRFLH BSD</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>86</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0650502" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.84in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.2 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with
                an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a
                reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date. To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase
                price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or
                her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
