<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 06512-R1 - National Seat ABTS (All Belts To Seat) Driver's Seat on certain BE, CE, FE, and RE school
        and commercial buses built between October 11, 2005 and October 31, 2006 with property codes 0048VUK, 0048VUJ,
        0048VUP, and 0048VUR
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec06512">
        <recallnumber>06512-R1</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>May 2007</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>National Seat ABTS (All Belts To Seat) Driver's Seat on certain BE, CE, FE, and RE school and
            commercial buses built between October 11, 2005 and October 31, 2006 with property codes 0048VUK, 0048VUJ,
            0048VUP, and 0048VUR
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>BE 200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/11/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/11/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>FE 300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/11/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/11/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>48VUK</ucode>
                <ucode>48VUJ</ucode>
                <ucode>48VUP</ucode>
                <ucode>48VUR</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">REVISION DESCRIPTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SERVICE PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Step 12 and Figure 12, in Repair Procedure 1 - Seatbelt Retractor - All Seats, were removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Figure 28, in Repair Procedure 4 - National Bus Seat Service Letter - Installation of New Seat
                        Travel Tether, was revised to remove the washers. There are no washers provided in the Recall
                        Service Kits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Item 6, in Repair Procedure 4 - National Bus Seat Service Letter - Installation of New Seat
                        Travel Tether, the word, "washer," was removed. There are no washers provided in the Recall
                        Service Kits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Contact information changed for obtaining a
                        <emph type="italic">Seat Adjustment Warning Label</emph>
                        (indicated just above the End of Repair Procedures heading).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec06512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Cus06512.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the
                    customer letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>There are four issues that may exist for the National Seat ABTS (All Belts To Seat) driver's seat that
                this recall will remedy.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>For Air and Manually Adjustable ABTS Seats:</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>The driver's seatbelt retractor may not work properly if the seat back is pushed
                                against a barrier or other objects behind the driver's seat.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>For Manually Adjustable ABTS Seats:</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>The driver's seat may be pulled upward past the last seat adjustment position.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The seat and adjustment handle may pinch the driver's hand when the seat is adjusted
                                while the driver is sitting on it.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The driver's seat may be difficult to raise to a higher position due to its weight.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>BE, CE, FE, RE School and Commercial Buses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manufactured October 11, 2005 through October 31, 2006</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Property Codes 0048VUK, 0048VUJ, 0048VUP, and 0048VUR</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>During the recall process, a listing of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved
                dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners and have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the
                use of this listing to this campaign because the list may contain information obtained from state motor
                vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than
                this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="28">
            <title>Repair Procedures</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, park on a
                            flat level surface, set the parking brake, shut the engine off and chock the wheels.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death when servicing the vehicle, the
                            following procedure must be performed with the lower seat base mounted firmly to the vehicle
                            floor. Due to the spring forces present, these procedures MUST NOT be performed with the
                            lower seat base removed from the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PLEASE</emph>
                    read all warnings, inspection, and repair instructions prior to starting the repair process. There
                    are 4 separate repair and 1 inspection procedure. The setup and reassembly instructions for some
                    procedures are the same. Some of these steps may be eliminated when moving from 1 repair to the
                    next. Comments have been added when steps are affected by duplication in multiple procedures.
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Repair 1 - Seatbelt Retractor</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Repair 2 - Height Adjustment Lever</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Repair 3 - Supplemental Spring</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspection 1 - Inspect prior to Repair 4</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Repair 4 - Non-adjustable Tether</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>During the manufacturing process on manual seats without an up-stop mechanism, a plastic
                            tie-strap is used to keep the seat height springs compressed (See FIGURE 1). Once the seat
                            is assembled, this tie-strap must be removed to allow adjustment of the seat height. Before
                            performing the following procedures, inspect the seat being modified and verify that the
                            tie-strap has been removed. If necessary, remove the tie-strap.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0651201" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Repair Procedure 1 - Seatbelt Retractor - All Seats</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Arrange the steering wheel and seat to allow access to rear of upper seat back, on
                        driver's seat (seat should be in forward and upright position).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove any items stored behind the driver's seat.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove inside seat arm.</para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Access the armrest tube underneath the foam and seat cover, as shown in FIGURE
                            2.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0651202" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Locate the button on the armrest by inserting the screwdriver under the seat
                            cover and foam, and into the middle of the armrest tube. See FIGURE 3. (Arm rest is shown
                            already removed in FIGURE 3.)
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0651203" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Twist the screwdriver to depress the retaining button located in the arm rest
                            tube. See FIGURE 4.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0651204" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651204.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 4</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Partially remove cover from upper seat back.</para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Front flap of cover is clipped to back flap of cover at bottom of seat back. The
                            clip piece attached to the front flap must be pulled forward (rotated) to disconnect it from
                            the clip piece attached to the back flap. See FIGURE 5.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Starting at the bottom, roll the cover up one or two rolls; then, grasping the
                            rolled material, slip the cover upward until the upper left corner of the seat back is
                            exposed. See FIGURES 6 and 7.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651205" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651205.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5 - Two Piece Clip for Seat Back Cover (Rotate to Disengage)</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0651206" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0651207" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651207.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Starting at the upper back of the seat back,
                        <emph type="boldital">carefully</emph>
                        pull the grey foam away from the left side of the seat back just enough to expose the top of the
                        seat belt channel on the rear of the seat. The grey foam is attached with adhesive. See FIGURE
                        8.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651208" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651208.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8 - Seat Belt Channel and Guide (Grey Foam Removed for Clarity)</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following steps, the new seat belt guard is used as a template to mark and drill
                            two holes. Do not mark the holes until the guard is correctly positioned. Mark the holes
                            with a center punch before drilling, to prevent the drill bit from 'walking'.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Position the belt guard so that its top flange is over the top of the black plastic
                        belt guide and the guard is not touching the seat belt. This should position the right side hole
                        approximately &#188; inch below the edge of the bracket being drilled. Mark the location with a
                        center punch and drill an 11/64 inch diameter hole. Install the right side screw (provided in
                        kit), but leave the screw loose enough to allow some movement of the guard. See FIGURES 9 and
                        10.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651209" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0651210" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using the guard as a guide, drill an 11/64 inch diameter hole for the left side
                        screw. Install the provided screw.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten both screws. See FIGURE 11.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651211" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following step duct tape may be used, if necessary, to secure the grey foam and
                            prevent it from shifting while installing the seat cover.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Return the grey foam to its original position, then slide the seat cover down the
                        seat back.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Stretch the cover to reconnect the clips attached to the front and back cover flaps
                        at the bottom of the seat back. Insert the front flap clip into the groove of the back flap clip
                        until the clip barb is engaged. See FIGURE 5.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace arm.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Repair Procedure 2 - Seat Height Lever Replacement - Manual Seats</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect any seat-to-floor tethers by unbolting them from the seat. DO NOT unbolt
                        the tethers from the vehicle floor. Step 1 is also required to prepare for Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the seat is equipped with an up-stop mechanism, remove the limiting bolt and nut.
                        See FIGURE 13. Retain this hardware for use during assembly. Step 2 is also required to prepare
                        for Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the seat height adjustment lock knob enough to allow seat height adjustment.
                        Step 3 is also required to prepare for Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651213" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. UP-STOP MECHANISM BOLT AND NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ROLL PIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SEAT HEIGHT ADJUSTMENT LOCK KNOB</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SPRING CAGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. SEAT HEIGHT PIN/LEVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. TENSION SPRING</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With seat height lever raised to disengage, lift upper seat assembly off of lower
                        base. Set the upper seat assembly aside. This step is also required for Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the roll pin from the shaft of the seat height lever using one of the
                        following methods.
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">If the base has an access hole aligned with the roll pin (on the opposite side
                            from the slot) remove the pin with a hammer and punch. See FIGURE 14.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">If no access hole is present, attempt to grasp the roll pin using locking pliers
                            and remove it by tapping the pliers with a hammer.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">If neither of the previous two methods works, drill a 3/8 inch diameter access
                            hole in the spring cage, aligned with the roll pin; then remove the pin with a hammer and
                            punch. See FIGURE 14 for location of access hole. IMPORTANT: Before drilling, mark the hole
                            location using a center punch to prevent the drill bit from 'walking'. After drilling hole,
                            remove all metal shavings to prevent them from damaging the seat mechanism.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Discard the old roll pin. A new longer pin is supplied in the kit.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651214" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651214.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="328px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14 - Roll Pin Access Hole</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the tension spring and the lever assembly from the seat base. See FIGURE 13.
                        Retain the tension spring and discard the old lever assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">While holding the tension spring in place, insert the new seat height lever into
                        position in the seat base, capturing the tension spring.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>In the following step the new roll pin MUST BE installed with the groove on top.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using locking pliers, compress the tension spring; then, use a hammer to install the
                        new roll pin. See FIGURES 15 and 16. The roll pin is correctly installed when the following
                        conditions are met:
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The groove in the roll pin is facing up.</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The pin must be driven far enough through the shaft so that the tension spring
                            rests against the pin on both sides of the shaft.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The leading end of the pin must not contact the wall of the spring cage when the
                            seat height lever is moved through its range.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The pin must protrude at least 7/16 inch outside of the slotted surface when the
                            seat height lever is in the down (engaged) position.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply grease to the roll pin and slot prior to operating seat height lever.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651215" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651215.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0651216" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651216.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The following step is a two person operation. While one person lowers the seat assembly,
                            the other person must guide the seat assembly to insure that the springs, cylinders, and
                            up-stop mechanism are correctly aligned. See FIGURE 17.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Assemble the seat by lowering the seat assembly onto the lower seat base. Once the
                        base components are correctly aligned, raise (disengage) the seat height lever and push down on
                        the seat. When the seat reaches its top position, release the lever to engage the seat height
                        locking pin. Step 11 is not required if proceeding to complete Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651217" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651217.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="288px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the seat is in its top position (3 holes visible in seat base cylinder).
                        See FIGURE 18. If the seat is equipped with an up-stop mechanism, install the limiting bolt and
                        nut that were removed at the beginning of this procedure. Do not over tighten the nut, or the
                        seat will not move up and down. The limiting bolt will prevent the seat from being raised beyond
                        its top position. Step 12 is not required if proceeding to complete Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Leaving the seat in its top position, connect the seat-to-floor tethers and adjust
                        them to a tight condition. Step 13 is not required if proceeding to complete Repair Procedure 3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651218" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="288px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Repair Procedure 3 - Supplemental Seat Height Spring and Spring Retainer - Manual Seats</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect any seat-to-floor tethers by unbolting them from the seat. DO NOT unbolt
                        the tethers from the vehicle floor. If continuing from Repair Procedure 2, this step should
                        already be complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If seat is equipped with an up-stop mechanism, remove the limiting bolt and nut. See
                        FIGURE 19. Retain this hardware for use during assembly. If continuing from Repair Procedure 2,
                        this step should already be complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the seat height adjustment lock knob enough to allow seat height adjustment.
                        If continuing from Repair Procedure 2, this step should already be complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651219" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With seat height lever raised to disengage, lift upper seat assembly off of lower
                        base. If continuing from Repair Procedure 2, this step should already be complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Partially remove the cover from the bottom seat cushion to allow access to the top
                        of the seat base frame. Unclip cover from seat frame as needed. See FIGURE 20.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651220" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651220.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install spring retainer plate on frame of seat bottom as indicated in FIGURE 21.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install supplemental seat height spring from kit inside of existing spring in seat
                        base. See FIGURE 22.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651221" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651221.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SPRING RETAINER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0651222" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651222.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The following step is a two person operation. While one person lowers the seat assembly,
                            the other person must guide the seat assembly to insure that the springs, cylinders, and
                            up-stop mechanism are correctly aligned. See FIGURE 23.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Assemble the seat by lowering the seat assembly onto the lower seat base. Once the
                        base components are correctly aligned, raise (disengage) the seat height lever and push down on
                        the seat. When the seat reaches its top position, release the lever to engage the seat height
                        locking pin. The lever will be in the down position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651223" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651223.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The tethers that limit seat height travel have not yet been installed. If the seat is NOT
                            equipped with an up-stop mechanism, do not allow the seat to rise above its top position, as
                            it could become disengaged from the lower seat base.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the seat is in its top position (3 holes visible in seat base cylinder).
                        See FIGURE 24. If the seat is equipped with an up-stop mechanism, install the limiting bolt and
                        nut that were removed at the beginning of this procedure. Do not over tighten the nut, or the
                        seat will not move up and down. The limiting bolt will prevent the seat from being raised beyond
                        its top position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651223" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Through the opening at the top of the seat base cylinder, use a screwdriver to
                        position the seat height springs away from the seat height locking pin. The springs should be
                        adjusted so that they arc away from the locking pin (push over with screwdriver as shown on the
                        left in FIGURE 25, push toward front of bus). This step creates the clearance needed to prevent
                        interference between the seat height locking pin and the springs.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651225" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651225.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SEAT HEIGHT LOCKING PIN</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install cover on bottom seat cushion. See FIGURE 20.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With the seat in its top position, adjust the seat-to-floor tethers to a tight
                        condition. See FIGURE 24. If continuing to Repair Procedure 4, this step is not necessary.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection for Seat Height Travel Limit (Prior To Repair Procedure 4)</title>
                <para>Before Completing Repair 4, inspect the seat in order to determine if it has an up-stop mechanism.
                    If your bus has this mechanism, Repair Procedure 4 will not have to be completed. See FIGURE 26.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0651226" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651226.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Repair Procedure 4 - National Bus Seat Service Letter - Installation of New Seat Travel Tether
                </title>
                <para>This kit is required on all manual seats that
                    <emph type="bold">do not</emph>
                    have a factory installed up-stop mechanism.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the seat height adjustment lock knob enough to allow seat height adjustment.
                        See FIGURE 27. If continuing from Repair Procedure 2 and 3, this step should already be
                        complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Raise the seat to its top position by lifting the seat height lever and lifting the
                        seat. With the seat in its top position, three holes are visible on the rear of the seat base
                        cylinder.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure the locking pin is in position in the hole of the top adjustment hole.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If seat-to-floor tethers prevent the seat from being raised to this position, loosen the
                            tethers enough to allow the seat to reach its top position. Then retighten both the seat to
                            floor tethers.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0651227" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651227.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use a center punch prior to drilling holes, to prevent drill bit from 'walking'.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a center punch, mark the location of the top hole on the front rail of the
                        seat frame, as indicated in FIGURE 28.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a 3/8 inch bit, drill the top hole.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0651228" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651228a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Secure the top of the seat height travel tether using a bolt and nut provided in the
                        kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following step insure that the bottom hole is located so that it DOES NOT interfere
                            with the seat base mechanism in any way. The bolt is a smaller diameter than the hole in the
                            tether end plate, so the drilled hole must be offset slightly towards the end of the tether
                            to insure that the tether is stretched tight when installed. See FIGURE 28.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Pull the tether tight and use the center punch to mark the location of the bottom
                        hole. See FIGURE 28.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a 3/8 inch bit, drill the bottom hole.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Secure the bottom of the tether with the bolt, washer, and nut provided in the
                        kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Leaving the seat in its top position, adjust the seat-to-floor tethers to a tight
                        condition.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>Please affix the Seat Adjustment Warning Label if there is not one attached to the seat already.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0651229" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g0651229.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             scalefitheight="248px"/>
                    <caption></caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">This label can be obtained by contacting</emph>
                    <emph type="boldital">Ali Rankin</emph>, National Seats Corp. at
                    <emph type="bold">(614) 880-2120</emph>.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0651201" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.31in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.94in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900192R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>National Drivers Seat - Seatbelt Retractor Cover Kit (Air and Manual Seats) - for
                                    repair 1
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900197R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>National Drivers Seat - Manual Seat Kit (Lever, Spring, Tether) - for repairs 2,
                                    3, and 4
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t0651202" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.34in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.48in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06512-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install retractor cover on seatbelt (Repair 1)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.4 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06512-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install Lever Replacement (Repair 2)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06512-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install Supplemental Spring and Retainer (Repair 3)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.2 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06512-4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect for Travel Stop (Inspection for Repair 4)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.1 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-06512-5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install Seat Travel Tether (Repair 4)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.1 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label_IC.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to replacement with
                an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a refund of the purchase price less a
                reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date. To avoid having to replace a vehicle or refund the purchase
                price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or
                her vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">POSSIBLE CUSTOMER REIMBURSEMENT</emph>
            </para>
            <para>There may be an occasion when a customer was charged for repairs related to this Recall prior to the
                Recall being released. The customer letter contains a statement for the customer to contact the Dealer
                if they believe they are entitled to reimbursement costs. The Dealer should follow the Customer
                Reimbursement guidelines in Warranty Policy Letter 03-001G. The Warranty Procedures and Administrative
                Policies manual (CTS1100) is in the process of being updated to include the information in Policy Letter
                03-001G.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed
                <emph type="bold">immediately</emph>
                to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your distributor location.
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to this Recall
                number.
            </para>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact your Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
