<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 95503 - Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000 Air Dryer, or Rockwell WABCO System Saver Twin Air Dryer
        (Sold Through Service Parts) - 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, 8000 and 9000 Models
    </stitle>
    <recall id="Rec95503">
        <recallnumber>95503</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., EXPORT</market>
        <recalldate>April, 1995</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000 Air Dryer, or Rockwell WABCO System Saver Twin Air Dryer (Sold Through
            Service Parts) - 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, 8000 and 9000 Models
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/24/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/07/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Rockwell</vendor>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04EAT</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, 8000, and 9000 models built from 03/24/1993 through
                03/07/1995 with code 04EAT Rockwell WABCO System 1000 Air Dryer.
            </para>
            <para>Air systems are designed so that when adequate air pressure is reached in the brake system air
                reservoirs, a signal is sent to the air compressor governor which actuates the unloader valve, stopping
                the air flow from the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>Rockwell WABCO has informed Navistar of a potential problem with the Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000
                or System Saver Twin Air Dryers because of no protective pressure relief valve between the air
                compressor and the air dryer. In the event of a blockage in the air dryer, or in the line between the
                air dryer and the supply reservoir, air would not be replenished in the reservoirs. This in turn would
                prevent the air compressor from receiving a signal to shut off at a predetermined air pressure level.
                Under this circumstance, air pressure would continue to build in the air dryer.
            </para>
            <para>Excessive pressure in the air dryer could result in the air dryer cartridge rupturing and separating
                from its mounting base and
                <emph type="bold">could result in property damage or injury to persons nearby who may be struck by
                    pieces of the air dryer cartridge.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The remedy for this defect is to install a pressure relief valve between the air compressor and the
                air dryer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Also involved are four different part numbers of Rockwell WABCO air dryers which were sold
                        through the Navistar Parts System or the Rockwell WABCO Direct Ship program.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t9550301" frame="all">
                <title>Air Dryer Part Numbers</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.63in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.94in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2017670C91 (Nav)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000 Air Dryer (12 volt)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>R955005 (Rockwell)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000 Air Dryer (12 volt)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>R955010 (Rockwell)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Rockwell WABCO System Saver Twin Air Dryer (12 volt)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>R955006 (Rockwell)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Rockwell WABCO System Saver 1000 Air Dryer (24 volt)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>The dealer should check his records for customers who purchased these dryers and contact the customers
                to bring their vehicles in to have the recall performed.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate engine until air compressor reaches cutout pressure and air dryer has completed
                    the purge cycle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn engine off and chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Exhaust air from all air reservoirs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air compressor air supply line from "Inlet" port #1 of the air dryer. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9550301">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9550301" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g9550301" filename="../recallfigures/g9550301.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove pipe-to-hose adapter fitting from "Inlet" port. Save fitting for
                    re-installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using street tee from repair kit, screw male end of tee into "Inlet" port #1 of air
                    dryer so that 1/2 inch (or 3/8 inch) female pipe thread of tee faces up or within 30 degrees of
                    vertical. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9550302">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9550302" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g9550302" filename="../recallfigures/g9550302.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Screw the pressure relief valve into vertical port of street tee. Do not exceed torque
                    of 30 ft-lbs. for 3/8 inch thread, or 65 ft-lbs. for 1/2 inch thread.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install pipe-to-hose adapter fitting removed in Step 5 into female port on end of the
                    street tee.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air line removed in Step 4 to adapter fitting in tee.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Be sure to check the inlet and outlet connections from the compressor to the Dryer and from the Dryer
                to the supply reservoir. Re-position and/or support any low spots found in the air lines to reduce the
                possibility of condensation collecting and freezing.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATIONAL CHECKS</title>
            <para>Once the modification is complete, start the engine, build up air pressure to 100 psi, and shut off
                the engine. Check for air leaks at the inlet and outlet of the dryer. Correct any leakage. Restart the
                engine and build up pressure to cut-out pressure. At cut-out pressure the air dryer purge valve opens
                and immediately expels a large volume of air, followed by a slow flow of air lasting approximately
                thirty seconds. Check for leakage at locations listed below to assure that the Rockwell WABCO System
                Saver 1000 Air Dryer does not cycle excessively.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Compressor Unloader Mechanism.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Governor.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Drain Cock and Pressure Relief Valve in Supply Reservoir.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All air connections leading to and from the supply reservoir.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9550302" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.38in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.29in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.34in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>8900055R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Kit, Air Dryer Relief Valve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Kit consists of:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Pressure Relief Valve</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Street Tee</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Rockwell Technical Bulletin TP-9557</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9550303" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-95503-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Install pressure relief valve kit in air dryer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
