<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 95501 - Side Marker Lights - Non-Compliance of 9600 Model With High Rise Cab Roof</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec95501">
        <recallnumber>95501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>February, 1995</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Side Marker Lights - Non-Compliance of 9600 Model With High Rise Cab Roof</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/30/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/29/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 9600 models with high rise cab roof, code 16173, and built from 09/30/1991
                through 11/29/1994.
            </para>
            <para>FMVSS-108 requires each truck to have side marker lights as far as practical toward the front of the
                vehicle and a minimum of 15 inches from the road surface. International vehicles have the side marker
                light combined with another light, such as clearance lights on top of the cab, wrap around parking
                lights, etc. The side marker lights must be visible from the side of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>The 9600 model with a standard cab roof uses the bullet type clearance light which also serves as a
                side marker light. The 9600 model built with the special high rise cab roof has clearance lights mounted
                flush in the cab roof. These flush mounted clearance lights are not visible from the side of the vehicle
                and therefore cannot also serve as side marker lights. No other provision was made for side marker
                lights on these units. These units must be modified to meet Federal requirements.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>In order to meet the side marker light requirements of FMVSS-108, a special marker light kit must
                    be installed on all 9600 models with the high rise cab roof.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>INSTALL MARKER LIGHTS</title>
                <para>Instructions to install the lights are for the left side of the vehicle; right side will be the
                    opposite.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove left and right forward side reflectors.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Drill a 3/8 inch hole through the side of the vehicle as illustrated in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9550101">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        for the light wire.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9550101" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9550101" filename="../recallfigures/g9550101.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the rear of the marker light base in the rear existing hole on the side of
                        the vehicle (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9550101">Figure 1</hotlnk>) with a #8-18 x 3/4 inch stainless steel pan hd.
                        screw (supplied in the kit). Tighten the screw.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Level the light. Hold a #8-18 x 3/4 inch stainless steel pan hd. screw in the
                        opposite hole in the light base and lightly tap it to start it. Turn the screw in until it is
                        tight.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Snap the light lens onto the light base. In the forward hole in the lens, install a
                        #8-18 x 3/4 inch stainless steel pan hd. screw. Tighten the screw.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Hold a #8-18 x 3/4 inch stainless steel pan hd. screw in the opposite hole in the
                        lens and lightly tap it to start it. Turn the screw in until it is tight.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the light and lens on the right side of the vehicle.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>INSTALL WIRING</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Pick the longer of the two cable assemblies from the kit and plug it into the left
                        light wire under the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Route and strap lock the left side cable assembly along the brake plumbing, down to
                        the front bumper.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Strap lock the left side cable assembly to the bottom side of both steps in the
                        front bumper (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9550102">Figure 2</hotlnk>) as you route the cable assembly to the right side
                        of the vehicle.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9550102" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9550102" filename="../recallfigures/g9550102.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">On the right side of the vehicle, route the left side cable assembly down through
                        the hose and harness retainer (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9550103">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9550103" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9550103" filename="../recallfigures/g9550103.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Plug the remaining cable assembly into the right marker light.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Route the right cable along the outside of the cable and harness retainer. Strap
                        lock the cable to the vehicle wiring.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Open the convolute tubing for the chassis harness just behind the hose and harness
                        retainer and locate wire no. 68. Cut wire no. 68 in two at this location and cut back the
                        insulation 5/16 inch on both ends of the wire.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cut back the insulation 5/16 inch on the ends of both marker light cable
                        assemblies.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Splice the marker light cables into wire no. 68 as illustrated in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9550104">Figure 4</hotlnk>. After the splice is complete, slide the heat shrink
                        sleeve over the splice and shrink in place with a heat gun. Secure the marker light cables to
                        the chassis harness at this location with strap locks.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9550104" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9550104" filename="../recallfigures/g9550104.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9550101" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.38in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.03in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.09in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>8900054R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Kit, Marker Lights</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Kit consists of:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2040242C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Marker Light</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2040230C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Cable Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2040231C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Cable Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2027573C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Splice</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2644002R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Heat Shrink</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>289862C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Straplock</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>10</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>27196R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>#8-18 x 3/4 Inch Pan Hd. Screw SST</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>8</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>1087646R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Instructions</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9550102" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-95501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Install side marker light kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1.0 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
