<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 95506 - 3700 and 3800 Bus Hand Throttle</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec95506">
        <recallnumber>95506</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>August, 1995</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>3700 and 3800 Bus Hand Throttle</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/13/1988</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/04/1991</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to all 3700 and 3800 buses built from 06/13/1988 through 03/04/1991 with hand
                throttle.
            </para>
            <para>The wire end of the hand throttle cable passes through a retainer (split plastic grommet) in the
                accelerator rod and has a "slug" on the end of the wire that activates the accelerator rod when the
                throttle knob is pulled. The hand throttle cable wire may work its way through the slot in the grommet
                and become lodged between the grommet and the edge of the hole in the accelerator rod.
            </para>
            <para>Should this happen, the accelerator could stick in the applied position without prior warning. Under
                these circumstances, the accelerator pedal would not readily return to the idle position. This could
                potentially affect the operator's ability to control the vehicle and
                <emph type="bold">could possibly result in an accident causing personal injury or property damage.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Reference
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9550601">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9550601" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9550601" filename="../recallfigures/g9550601.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut cable stop slug from end of hand throttle cable wire. (Cut wire as near to slug as
                    possible.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull hand throttle knob until end of wire is 2 inches or more inside cable housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove adjusting cable clip for hand throttle cable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut off 3/4 inch of cable outside housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove old hand throttle cable retainer (plastic grommet) from accelerator rod and
                    discard.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new hand throttle cable retainer (plastic grommet) in accelerator rod from back
                    side as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9550601">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Route hand throttle cable wire through grommet and install new cable stop on end of
                    wire.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the hand throttle adjusting clip leaving it loose so cable housing can be
                    moved in clip. Adjust hand throttle so with knob pushed in and accelerator pedal at idle position,
                    there is 1/8 inch clearance between cable stop and cable retainer (plastic grommet) in accelerator
                    rod. With approximately 1 inch of cable housing through the adjusting clip, tighten clip.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9550601" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.38in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.29in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.34in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>8900058R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Kit, Hand Throttle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>Kit consists of:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2042010C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Retainer (Plastic Grommet)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>288219C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Stop, Cable Wire</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>436747</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Screw, Pan Head Slot 10-32 UNF x 5/16</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9550602" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-95506-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Modify hand throttle cable installation at accelerator rod</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
