<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 95511 - Driveline Nut Torque - 9200, 9300, 9400 and 5000 Models</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec95511">
        <recallnumber>95511</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>September, 1995</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>PROPELLER SHAFT</subjectfile>
        <subject>Driveline Nut Torque - 9200, 9300, 9400 and 5000 Models</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/26/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/26/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/26/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/26/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/23/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to certain 9200, 9300, 9400 models built from 07/26/1995 through 08/21/1995, and
                5000 model built from 07/26/1995 through 08/23/1995.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Dealers may have corrected some units prior to receipt of this letter.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Corrected vehicles should have the Campaign Identification Label indicating that they have been
                inspected and corrected if necessary.
            </para>
            <para>The drivelines could potentially have low torque or no torque on the driveline nut retaining the yoke
                at the center bearing or bearings if the vehicle is equipped with multiple center bearings. The low
                torque condition could cause the driveline to separate.
            </para>
            <para>Should the driveline separate, it could result in personal injury or property damage from parts being
                thrown from the vehicle or scattered on the roadway.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Reference
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9551101">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9551101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9551101" filename="../recallfigures/g9551101.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the driveline at the rear of the center bearing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 1-5/8 inch socket, tighten the yoke nut to 475-550 ft-lbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect driveline and tighten driveline bolts to 115-135 ft-lbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grease U-joint.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9551101" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-95511-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Torque driveline yoke nut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
