<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 95512 - 3600 Bus Fuel Hose - 7.3 Liter Engine</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec95512">
        <recallnumber>95512</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., EXPORT</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1995</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FUEL TANKS</subjectfile>
        <subject>3600 Bus Fuel Hose - 7.3 Liter Engine</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/29/1992</startdate>
                        <enddate>02/01/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>12NAB</ucode>
                <ucode>12NAC</ucode>
                <ucode>12NAD</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 3600 buses built from 01/29/1992 through 02/01/1994 with a 7.3 Liter engine
                (codes 12NAB, 12NAC, or 12NAD).
            </para>
            <para>The fuel hose from the fuel filter to the fuel pump is routed in the vicinity of the alternator belt.
                Because of the proximity of the fuel hose to the alternator belt, either manufacturing routing variables
                or belt adjustment could cause the alternator belt to rub the fuel hose and result in a fuel leak.
                <emph type="bold">Should a leak occur in the fuel hose, there is a possibility a fire could develop
                    under the right circumstances and result in personal injury.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Reference
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9551201">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9551201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9551201" filename="../recallfigures/g9551201.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a plastic tie strap inserted thru a hole in the frame rail, position and clamp the
                    fuel hose away from the alternator belt. A minimum of 2-1/2 inches of clearance is required. After
                    tire strap is pulled taut, cut off excess strap material.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The fuel hose must be replaced if it has been rubbing and shows sign of wear.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9551201" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-95512-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Clamp fuel hose for clearance</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
