<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96304 - Rear Window Buzzer Switch</stitle>
    <recall id="rec96304">
        <recallnumber>96304</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subject>Rear Window Buzzer Switch</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/01/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/15/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The vehicles involved are AmTran RE model school buses built from May 1, 1995 through March 15,
                1996.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>The rear window buzzer switch does not comply with the requirements set forth in Federal Motor Vehicle
                Safety Standard (FMVSS) 217. FMVSS 217 requires the rear window buzzer to be activated when the latch is
                not in the closed
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
                locked position. The current rear window buzzer switch works independently from the latching mechanism
                and will activate the buzzer only if the window is not in the closed position. If the window is closed
                but the latch is not in the locked position, the buzzer
                <emph type="bold">will not</emph>
                be activated and the driver
                <emph type="bold">will not</emph>
                be alerted that the rear window is unlatched.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>The current mechanical rear window buzzer switch must be replaced with a proximity type switch
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630401">Figure 1</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630402">Figure 2</hotlnk>, and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630403">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9630401" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9630401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Switch Sensor Installation</title>
                <para>Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630402">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    for the following steps.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9630402" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9630402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove existing buzzer switch from window frame.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cut and remove foam seal in area of new switch.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Locate and drill (2) 3/32 inch holes per Detail A. New switch is to be located as
                        close to window frame vertical edge as possible.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Switch sensor requires counter sinking holes in top prior to installing screws.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Attach ring terminal to white wire and ground to window frame per Detail A.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connection of black wire requires removal of window to gain access under window
                        frame. Wire splice must be routed through rubber grommet and hidden under frame.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>*Wire splice can be made by pulling bottom of window out approximately 2 to 3 inches.</para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Magnetic Actuator Installation</title>
                <para>Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630403">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                    for the following steps.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9630403" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9630403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Mark window slide for magnetic actuator using notch as reference for hole location.
                        Actuator is located flush to the outside edge of window slide. Interference between sensor and
                        magnet may occur if located incorrectly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Drill (2) 3/32 inch holes in window slide. Do not install until vertical edge is cut
                        away per Detail B.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Use die grinder to remove vertical edge of window (see cutout detail).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install magnet to slide with #4 screws (Item 3). Pull slide out away from window and
                        use grinder to cut screw threads flush with bottom of slide (see detail).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Magnet must be centered on actuator within .25 inch for switch to operate
                        correctly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check all connections. Turn ignition key on. Pull window release handle. Buzzer
                        should sound. If not, check all wiring connections to switch.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9630401">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>431886001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Kit, Field Fix Warning Buzzer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9630402">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.76in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.19in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96304-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove and replace rear window latch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.5 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. As a precaution, you should
                not operate any of the vehicles subject to this recall campaign until they have been inspected for the
                presence of the nut assembled to the pinch bolt. In the event that the nut is missing, repairs must be
                made before the vehicle is driven.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
