<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96306 - Parking Brake Air Chamber</stitle>
    <recall id="rec96306">
        <recallnumber>96306</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Parking Brake Air Chamber</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/28/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/21/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The vehicles involved are AmTran RE model school buses 3302, 3505, and 3708 built from May 28, 1996
                through October 21, 1996.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>The air/spring actuated parking brake chambers manufactured by Midland, with date code 145B6K, were
                filled with the wrong lubrication by the supplier. The improper lubricant can cause the seals within the
                chamber to fail and result in loss of air. If air pressure drops below 55 psi and the operator does not
                heed the low air pressure warning and continues to drive, the parking brake may start to apply.
                Continuing to drive in this condition will cause the parking brake lining to overheat and have premature
                wear. A parking brake that has overheated and has premature wear may not operate properly when the bus
                is parked and the brake is applied.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A spring brake contains a very powerful compression spring. Failure to comply with all of the
                        following instructions may result in forceful release of the double diaphragm spring chamber and
                        its contents which could cause death, severe personal injury and/or property damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels to prevent vehicle from moving during inspection.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the air parking brake chamber (A) that is attached to a bracket on the side of
                    the transmission (under the vehicle). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9630601">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9630601" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9630601.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate serial number on case of air chamber.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not remove cover. Serious injury or death could occur due to release of powerful
                            compression.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Use a mirror if necessary to view serial number.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If date code 145B6K is present, the chamber must be replaced. Proceed to repair
                    procedures. If date code 145B6K is not present, no further action is necessary. Fill out and return
                    reply card.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURES</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>General Instructions</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Always block wheels to prevent vehicle rollaway when replacing spring brake
                        assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>The spring brake chamber portion of the assembly has been sealed for your protection.
                            There are no useable service parts inside the spring brake chamber. If the date code on the
                            spring brake chamber is 145B6K, replace the complete chamber as outlined in this section.
                            Never attempt to disassemble the spring brake chamber as serious personal injury, death
                            and/or property damage could result from accidental sudden release of the powerful
                            compression spring.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Never strike any part of the spring brake with a hammer or any other heavy object;
                        structural damage may result.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Do not drop the spring brake, as the jar may release the spring.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal of Spring Parking Brake Chamber</title>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Always cage the compression spring with the cage nut located on the threaded portion of
                            chamber shaft. Do not rely on air pressure to keep spring compressed. Failure to cage the
                            compression spring may result in forceful release of the compression spring which could
                            cause death, severe personal injury and/or property damage.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Block wheels to prevent vehicle from moving.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Release parking brake with valve on dash if air pressure is sufficient in system.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cage spring brake by tightening cage nut (F) to relieve spring pressure. If air
                        pressure is used to compress the spring, do not tighten the cage nut more than finger tight.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Release air pressure to spring brake chamber by applying parking brake with valve on
                        dash.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove air line from spring brake chamber.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the pin (E) that fastens the spring brake push rod clevis to the brake lever
                        (D).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the two nuts and washers (C) that fasten the chamber assembly (A) to the
                        mounting bracket (B).
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installation of Spring Parking Brake Chamber</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Inspect parking brake linings for abnormal wear and replace as necessary.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Pin (E) the spring brake pushrod clevis to the brake lever (D).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Fasten the chamber assembly (A) to the mounting bracket. Tighten the two mounting
                        nuts (C) to 105 - 125 ft-lbs. (142 - 169 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install air line to the spring brake chamber (A).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Uncage compression spring nut (F).</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>After re-assembly, check for proper spring brake operation. Check brake adjustment.</para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9630601">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>2005283C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Cylinder, air parking brake</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1*</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1" align="center">
                                <para>*Not required in all cases.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9630602">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.76in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.19in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96306-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect air parking brake chamber</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96306-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace air parking brake chamber</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.8 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. As a precaution, you should
                not operate any of the vehicles subject to this recall campaign until they have been inspected for the
                presence of the nut assembled to the pinch bolt. In the event that the nut is missing, repairs must be
                made before the vehicle is driven.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
