<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96509 - Accelerator Pedal to Floor Interference 3800 Bus with I6 Electronic Engine</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96509">
        <recallnumber>96509</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Accelerator Pedal to Floor Interference 3800 Bus with I6 Electronic Engine</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/01/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/07/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 3800 bus built 05/01/1996 through 11/07/1996 with the I6 electronic engine and
                the extra thick bus body floor.
            </para>
            <para>The accelerator pedal to floor clearance on bus chassis built by Navistar is approximately 1.2 inches
                with a standard bus body floor. However, some customers order buses with an additional 3/4 inch plywood
                floor and extra thick floor mat which serves as insulation in cold weather areas or as a sound deadener.
                When the extra thick flooring is used, there is the possibility the bottom edge of the accelerator
                pedal, when depressed, could come in contact with the floor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Should the accelerator pedal, while being depressed, come in contact with the floor,
                    there is the possibility the engine throttle may not return to the idle position. Should this happen
                    with the vehicle in motion, it could cause the operator to lose control of the bus and result in a
                    crash, causing personal injury, property damage or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9650901">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9650901" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9650901" filename="../recallfigures/g9650901.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With accelerator pedal fully depressed, inspect for 1/4 inch minimum clearance between
                    the bottom of the accelerator pedal and the floor. If there is less than 1/4 inch clearance, the
                    accelerator pedal must be reworked. During this procedure, the accelerator pedal should be rotated
                    through its full travel to assure that the 1/4 inch clearance is present when the accelerator pedal
                    is closest to the floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If rework is necessary, remove the accelerator pedal/rod assembly by removing 2 screws
                    attaching the pedal rod to electronic control unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut 1/2 inch from the bottom (non-tapered edge) of the pedal and grind the cut edge to
                    remove sharp burrs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install pedal/rod assembly to electronic control unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress accelerator pedal fully and check for a minimum of 1/4 inch clearance to the
                    floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>None required to perform this inspection and repair.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9650901" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96509-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect accelerator pedal to floor clearance</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96509-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect accelerator pedal to floor clearance; Rework accelerator pedal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7&#150;1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
