<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96507 - Bus Turn Signal - Lane Change Mode</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96507">
        <recallnumber>96507</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>November, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Bus Turn Signal - Lane Change Mode</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1981</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/01/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1981</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/01/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 1723, 1753, 1823, 1853, 3600, 3700 and 3800 buses built 01/01/1981 through
                08/01/1994.
            </para>
            <para>1981 to 1994 buses have a turn signal lever that can cause only the front lights to flash if it is
                used improperly. It will not operate consistently in the lane change mode unless the lever is moved to a
                position where resistance to movement is felt (unless it is used as the design was intended for it to be
                used). If it is moved only part way to the lane change position, the rear signal lamps may not flash
                even though the dash indicator lamp is flashing.
                <emph type="bold">If the turn signal is not used properly in the lane change mode, the defect could
                    result in a vehicular accident without warning which could result in personal injury or property
                    damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will issue a letter to customers informing them of the defect along with a Guideline for
                Proper Use of Turn Signals. One copy of the guideline will be provided to a customer. The customer will
                be requested to reproduce and provide a copy of the guideline for each of their International buses and
                operators. Navistar will also provide sufficient decals to the customer so they can be placed on the
                instrument panel of each bus built from 01/01/1981 through 08/01/1994.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This is an information letter only - no action is required by the dealer.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </defect>
    </recall>
</isis>
