<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96504 - 4700 LP Steering Column</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96504">
        <recallnumber>96504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>4700 LP Steering Column</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/23/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/27/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 4700 LP model vehicles built from 02/23/1993 through 06/27/1996 with straight
                steering column (non-tilt).
            </para>
            <para>The steering column on certain 4700 LP Models may have been manufactured incorrectly. The tube portion
                of the steering column has a welded end with a specified length of 5.5 inches as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9650401">Figure 1</hotlnk>. A 3.5 inch welded end was used by mistake. With the shorter
                end, it is possible there is insufficient engagement of the male end into the tube portion, and
                separation of the column could occur.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9650401" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9650401" filename="../recallfigures/g9650401.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Should the column separate, the operator would lose steering control and an accident causing personal
                injury and/or property damage could occur. The defect can cause a vehicle crash without prior warning.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Inspect steering column for 5.5 inch welded end as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9650401">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                <emph type="bold">Any steering column with a 3.5 inch welded end is defective and must be replaced.
                </emph>
                The specified steering column for these units is Navistar part number 2014986C91. The part number is
                located on a tag on the steering column as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9650401">Figure 1</hotlnk>. If a steering column is found with a part number other than
                the one specified above, it also
                <emph type="bold">must be replaced</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MATERIAL DISPOSITION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to R-5180 and R-5185 Reports for material disposition.</para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Only a total of 10 defective columns are in the total population in this recall. DO NOT order
                        any columns until a known defective column has been found.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t9650401" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.38in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.03in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.09in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2014986C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Steering Column Shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9650402" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96504-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect steering column shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96504-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect and replace steering column shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1.5 hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
