<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96506 - 1552SC Model with Hydraulic Brakes</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96506">
        <recallnumber>96506</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>1552SC Model with Hydraulic Brakes</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/03/1995</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/21/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 1552SC stripped chassis models built 11/03/1995 through 08/21/1996 with
                hydraulic brakes.
            </para>
            <para>A plugged brake line that will not transmit fluid to the front or rear brakes and possible missing
                brake pads, could cause the vehicle to pull to the right or left when applying the brakes and/or could
                result in a significant increase in vehicle stopping distance.
                <emph type="bold">This defect could cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in
                    personal injury or property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>The single customer involved will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar.</para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>CHECKING FOR BRAKE FUNCTIONING PROPERLY</title>
                <para>It will require 2 persons to perform this Operation.</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Jack up all four wheels on the vehicle and secure with jack stands.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Have one person apply brakes while other person attempts to rotate each of the four
                        wheels. Make sure wheels cannot be rotated. If any wheel can be rotated, it is an indication
                        that hydraulic pressure is not getting to the brake caliper. Inspect hydraulic lines to
                        determine if a line is plugged and a connector line is missing.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>INSPECTION FOR BRAKE PADS</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">While the vehicle is in the air, visually inspect all four wheels for inboard and
                        outboard brake pads. The outboard pad is visible through the wheel handhold unless, on dual
                        rears, the handholds are not aligned. In that case, it is possible to feel the end retainer
                        flange on the outboard pad, if in place.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If any brake pads are found to be missing, inspect for damage to rotor and caliper
                        piston and replace parts as necessary.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If a brake line is required, the line should be ordered by description direct from AmTran by
                        calling Randy Wolfe at phone number (501 327-7761. If a brake pad is found missing, all parts
                        required should be ordered through the normal process.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9650601" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96506-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect for brake system integrity and brake pads</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96506-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect and replace hydraulic lines and fittings</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1.0 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96506-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect and replace front brake pad</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96506-5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspect and replace rear brake pad</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
