<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96505 - 3600, 3800 and 3900FC Bus with Air Brakes and Antilock Brake Systems</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96505">
        <recallnumber>96505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>September, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>3600, 3800 and 3900FC Bus with Air Brakes and Antilock Brake Systems</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/30/1992</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/06/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 3600, 3800 and 3900FC model buses built 01/30/1992 through 09/06/1996 with air
                brakes and antilock brake system, code 04AZA.
            </para>
            <para>The antilock brake wiring may have been connected wrong during the assembly process. The wiring from
                the electronic control unit (ECU) may have been connected to the wrong wheel sensor and/or the wiring
                from the ECU may have been connected to the wrong brake modulator valve. Should the ABS wiring be
                crossed, it would result in a significant degradation in braking stability. A signal would be sent to
                the wrong brake chamber when a brake imbalance is detected.
                <emph type="bold">This defect could cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in
                    personal injury or property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Each bus must have the following functional check to determine if the antilock brake system wiring is
                connected properly.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition key on.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check ECU window displays and clear faults by placing a magnet against RESET and then
                    removing magnet.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It may be necessary to remove the paint mask on the ECU window. Also for easier visibility
                            of window displays, rub black grease across recessed letters in ECU windows.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug
                    <emph type="bold">left rear sensor</emph>
                    wires. Three red LEDs -
                    <emph type="bold">RER, LFT</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">SEN</emph>
                    should light up. If these three LEDs light up then the rear sensors are connected correctly. If
                    <emph type="bold">RHT</emph>
                    lights up instead of
                    <emph type="bold">LFT</emph>
                    then the sensor wires are reversed and must be switched.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear LED faults.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug wires at
                    <emph type="bold">left rear modulator</emph>. Three red LEDs -
                    <emph type="bold">RER, LFT</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">MOD</emph>
                    should light up. If these three LEDs light up then the rear modulators are connected correctly. If
                    <emph type="bold">RHT</emph>
                    lights up instead of
                    <emph type="bold">LFT</emph>
                    then the modulator wires are reversed and must be switched.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear LED faults.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug
                    <emph type="bold">left front sensor</emph>
                    wires. Three red LEDs -
                    <emph type="bold">FRT, LFT</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">SEN</emph>
                    should light up. If these three LEDs light up then the front sensors are connected correctly. If
                    <emph type="bold">RHT</emph>
                    lights up instead of
                    <emph type="bold">LFT</emph>
                    then the sensor wires are reversed and must be switched.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear LED faults.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug wires at
                    <emph type="bold">left front modulator</emph>. Three red LEDs -
                    <emph type="bold">FRT, LFT</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">MOD</emph>
                    should light up. If these three LEDs light up then the front modulators are connected correctly. If
                    <emph type="bold">RHT</emph>
                    lights up instead of
                    <emph type="bold">LFT</emph>
                    then the modulator wires are reversed and must be switched.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear LED faults.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off ignition key.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If any other diagnostics of the ABS system are required, refer to CTS-5252.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>None required to perform this inspection and repair.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9650501" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Functionally check ABS system wiring and reverse connections as required.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.png" type="png"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.png" type="png"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
