<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96502 - RA-42 (Code 14042) Rear Drive Axle Housing - S-Series and Cargostar Models</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96502">
        <recallnumber>96502</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1997</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>REAR AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>RA-42 (Code 14042) Rear Drive Axle Housing - S-Series and Cargostar Models</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/21/1982</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/07/1982</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to S-Series Bus Models 1723 and 1853; S-Series Truck Models 1724, 1754, 1824,
                1854, and 1925; and Cargostar Models CO-1710 and CO-1850. These vehicles were built from 02/21/1982
                through 04/07/1982.
            </para>
            <para>Certain RA-42 (code 14042) rear drive axle housings may have been manufactured with smaller than
                intended friction weld curl radius on the inside diameter of the spindle during the friction-weld
                process. With a small curl radius, increased stress concentration occurs at this location. After
                numerous operational loads, cracks may initiate at this location, grow, and eventually result in
                separation of the spindle from the housing.
            </para>
            <para>Because this type of crack initiates on the
                <emph type="bold">inside</emph>
                of the axle housing, the crack cannot be detected easily by inspecting the axle housing.
            </para>
            <para>However, if a crack were to develop which extends through the housing, axle lubricant MAY seep through
                the crack. If this seepage occurs, it would appear as either a wet spot or a lubricant leak (drip) from
                the axle housing near the brake mounting flange.
                <emph type="bold">If this condition is observed, the vehicle should not be operated until the axle
                    housing is replaced.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If a complete spindle weld separation were to occur, the disengaged wheel assembly could pose a hazard
                to other users of the roadway and adjacent property.
                <emph type="bold">This condition would also affect vehicle stability and control and could cause a
                    vehicle crash without prior warning possibly resulting in property damage or personal injury or
                    both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The axle housing serial number and manufacturing code is provided on an identification tag affixed to
                the rear of the axle housing to the right of the differential carrier bowl (as viewed from the rear of
                the vehicle).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Serial Number</emph>
                - The 7 digit serial number appears in the last line of data which appears on the tag (Example: KN45770)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Axle Manufacturing Code</emph>
                - This code appears in Julian format (Day-Year) and is hand stamped on the right hand portion of the tag
                (Example: 058 H 82). This information will be needed to obtain a repair authorization.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Only RA-42 axle housings which are identified with a serial number listed below
                    require replacement. Axle housings with other serial numbers do not require replacement.
                </emph>
                Should difficulty be encountered reading the data on the identification tag, it might be helpful to
                scrape any paint or road grime from the plate and rub it with chalk to highlight the serial number and
                axle manufacturing code information.
            </para>
            <table id="t9650201" frame="all">
                <title>Serial Number List</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Serial Number Range</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Serial Number Range</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Serial Number Range</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1045770 - 772</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1075837 - 930</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1081965 - 2000</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1045805</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1075932 - 951</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1083893 - 901</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1045807</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1075960 - 965</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1083903 - 908</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1045809 - 845</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1075967 - 6000</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1083910 - 912</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1045870 - 883</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1081789 - 948</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1083922 - 931</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1075831 - 835</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1081951 - 962</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>KN 1083933 - 992</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before replacing an axle housing, the servicing dealer MUST report the axle identification
                        information to Tom Bowman at Rockwell on (248) 435-1725 to obtain authorization to replace the
                        housing. The following information should be available at the time of the call:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Reference Rockwell Program CNAB or Navistar Recall 96502</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Name of person placing order</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Dealer's name and telephone number</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>17 digit Vehicle Identification Number (VIN)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Vehicle owner's name and address</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Vehicle DTU date</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Axle housing serial number (Sample: KN 1045770) - found on axle ID tag</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Axle manufacturing code (Sample: 343 P 81) - found on axle ID tag</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Ship-to address (including ZIP code)</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Rockwell will issue a Repair Authorization Number when the axle housing serial number
                    and manufacturing code fall within the suspect range. The Repair Authorization Number should be
                    referenced on the warranty claim.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Should the serial number plate with the serial number and axle manufacturing code not
                    be found on the axle housing, or if the serial number plate does not have a serial number as listed
                    above, Tom Bowman at Rockwell will provide proper guidance to the dealer.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Refer to the following Service Manual Sections as applicable:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4148 Wheels</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4080 Brakes, Air</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4084 Brakes, Hydraulic Single System</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4086 Brakes, Hydraulic Split System - code 4055</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4087 Brakes, Hydraulic Split System - code 4044, 4049</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4336 Brakes, Hydraulic Split System, Cargostar - code 4083</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CTS-4045 Rear Axle</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Plug any unused holes in housing.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Order via "Quick Ship Program" from Rockwell International, Florence, Kentucky. Refer to
                        PL-320KA.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t9650202" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="4" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.38in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.67in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.60in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Rockwell Part No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>461393C93</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>C3121W1843</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Housing, Axle Rear</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9650203" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96502-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Remove and replace rear axle housing</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>8.7 hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-96502-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Inspection only - axle housing replacement not required</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <title>MATERIAL DISPOSITION</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The removed axle housing should be held at the repair facility pending reimbursement
                    of the warranty claim. The warranty claim may be denied if the repair facility is requested to
                    provide the removed axle housing for inspection and is unable to do so. After the warranty claim is
                    approved, the axle housing must be destroyed to prevent inadvertent re-use.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>In addition to normal warranty information furnished with the warranty claim, the following additional
                information is required:
            </para>
            <para>Customer name and address, Removed axle housing serial number and build date, and Repair Authorization
                Number obtained from Rockwell.
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
