<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 96511 - Detroit Diesel Engines With Optimized Idle</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec96511">
        <recallnumber>96511</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1996</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Detroit Diesel Engines With Optimized Idle</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Detroit Diesel</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/03/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/03/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/03/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/03/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>Detroit Diesel</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 9200, 9300, 9400 and 9800 models built from 04/03/1996 through 09/16/1996 with
                code 12VWS, plus other vehicles with engines that could be retrofitted. Detroit Diesel will notify
                Navistar customers with vehicles involved in this recall. The Detroit Diesel Service outlets will
                install a new ECM and add a relay in the ignition circuit. No action is required by International
                dealers.
            </para>
            <para>Detroit Diesel will be conducting a safety recall on International 9000 series with the Optimized Idle
                option, code 12VWS, plus any vehicle with an engine that could be retrofitted with this feature.
                Optimized Idle is a software and hardware system which controls automatic starting and stopping of a
                diesel engine to maintain cab/sleeper temperature and engine temperature when the vehicle is sitting
                idle. The system has safeguards to keep the engine from cranking when the transmission is in gear or
                when the hood or cab is tilted. Because of a design error, the safety switches will not prevent the
                engine from cranking under certain conditions. With the ignition in the "ON" position and if power is
                broken to the electronic control module (ECM) from the fuses or ignition relay, the ECM can ground
                itself through a diode within the ECM and cause the engine to crank.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">An unexpected cranking of the engine could pose a hazard to a person positioned in the
                    vicinity of the engine and cause personal injury and/or the vehicle could unexpectedly move, which
                    could cause personal injury, property damage or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This is an information letter only - no action is required by the dealer.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </defect>
    </recall>
</isis>
