<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 97301 - Handrail Modification</stitle>
    <recall id="rec97301">
        <recallnumber>97301</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>February, 1997</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Handrail Modification</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/01/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The vehicles involved are Volunteer and AmTran Conventional model school buses with handrails mounted
                forward of the entrance door, built from January 1, 1991 through January 20, 1997.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran Conventional and Volunteer vehicles in connection with the handrails.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>Optional handrail mounted forward of the entrance door (to right when entering bus) on subject
                vehicles may have an entanglement hazard located at the lower attachment point of the handrail and the
                sidewall of the stepwell. Certain small objects may be caught in these areas such as coat tie strings
                with draw string clips or other objects attached. Should this happen, and the driver does not properly
                observe the person exiting the bus, the person may exit the bus with the string captured. The door may
                be closed and the bus moved causing possible injury or death to the passenger exiting the bus.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check bus to see if it is equipped with a handrail mounted forward of the entrance door
                    and with the lower attachment point on the vertical surface of the stepwell enclosure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a handrail is not present forward of the entrance door, or if lower attachment point
                    is on the horizontal floor surface, no other action is necessary. Fill out and return reply card. If
                    a handrail is present with the lower attachment, as described above, proceed to repair instructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard entire handrail and attachment brackets. Replace fasteners to fill
                    existing holes. Return reply card. No additional action is necessary.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: If the removal of this handrail prevents this bus from meeting state
                        specification (i.e., Ohio), proceed to Step 2 for rework instructions.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If local or state specifications do not allow removal of the handrail, order rubber
                    spacer repair kit #436496001 by returning the enclosed card or call AmTran Customer Service at (800)
                    843-5615. A repair kit containing hardware and detailed instructions will be sent to you. Install
                    the rubber spacer at the lower attachment point of the handrail using the fastener provided.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for correct installation. Tie 1/2 inch nut to one end of string (provided).
                    Gradually pull the string across all handrail attachment points making an effort to catch the string
                    or nut. Using nut and string, attempt to catch the nut between the handrail and any structure or
                    object near the handrail. A failure has occurred if the string or nut is caught in a crevice or
                    between the handrail and any other surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete and return the owners postage-paid "Recall - Repair Reply Card."</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9730101">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>436496001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Repair kit for handrail</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1*</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>*Required only if removal of handrail is not permitted due to state or local
                                    specification.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>The pre-approved labor time allowed for modification is twelve (12) minutes.</para>
            <para>TOOLS REQUIRED: 1/2 inch socket or 1/2 inch wrench</para>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. As a precaution, you should
                not operate any of the vehicles subject to this recall campaign until they have been inspected for the
                presence of the nut assembled to the pinch bolt. In the event that the nut is missing, repairs must be
                made before the vehicle is driven.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
