<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 97502 - 1652 SC, 3400, 3800, 4600, 4700, and 3000 RE Buses with 9x3 Powered Applied Parking Brake
    </stitle>
    <recall id="Rec97502">
        <recallnumber>97502</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 1997</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>1652 SC, 3400, 3800, 4600, 4700, and 3000 RE Buses with 9x3 Powered Applied Parking Brake</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/15/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/15/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/15/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The power applied parking brake can fail to apply or can release without warning. The power applied
                parking brake lever can move forward, because the cam lever pivot hole located on the transmission
                mounting boss is drilled too deep. This allows the cam lever to become disengaged from the parking brake
                shoes. Should the cam lever become disengaged from the parking brake shoes, the operator would have no
                warning that the parking brake was not applied.
                <emph type="bold">This defect could result in a vehicular accident without warning which could result in
                    personal injury or property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Owner Notification</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The hole in the transmission boss (brake lever retainer hole) must have washers installed in it per
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9750201">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9750201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9750201" filename="../recallfigures/g9750201.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place chocks at rear tires to prevent the vehicle from moving. Place the front axle of
                    the vehicle on jack stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the power applied parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the driveline from the transmission output flange.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cotter key and clevis pin from the park brake cam lever (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9750202">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9750202" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g9750202" filename="../recallfigures/g9750202.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the transmission output flange and parking brake drum.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 4 retaining bolts from the backing plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the backing plate and cam lever from the transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Next, just the right number of washers must be installed. To do this, follow the
                    procedure below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add three (3) washers (part number 28588R1) in the brake lever retainer hole in the
                    transmission boss.
                    <emph type="bold">Make sure the washers are as near the bottom of the hole as possible.</emph>
                    There is a very small machined ledge in the hole that the washers must pass to be properly seated
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9750203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9750203" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g9750203" filename="../recallfigures/g9750203.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install park brake cam lever and backing plate to the transmission, making sure the
                    cam lever is in the proper position, engaged in the brake shoes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the 4 retaining bolts of the backing plate,
                    <emph type="bold">being careful not to over-tighten and bend the backing plate should 3 washers be
                        too many.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To verify the proper addition of washers, check the fore and aft movement (end play) of
                    the lever. If there is fore and aft movement, remove the backing plate and cam lever and install
                    another washer. If there is no movement, remove the 4 retaining bolts and remove brake cam lever and
                    backing plate.
                    <emph type="bold">Remove</emph>
                    one washer. Re-install brake cam lever and backing plate to the transmission and again tighten the 4
                    retaining bolts. Verify the fore and aft movement of the lever. If there is fore and aft movement,
                    then skip to Step 14.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is no fore and aft movement, remove 1 more washer and re-check. It is important
                    that initially washers be added to remove all fore and aft movement of the lever, then remove one at
                    a time until there is a detectable brake lever end play. Procedure will normally require 2 or 3
                    washers to shim the hole to the correct depth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the verification procedure is complete and you have confirmed the lever does not
                    bind and has fore and aft movement, torque the 4 backing plate retaining bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install parking brake drum, transmission output flange, and driveline.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the clevis pin into the clevis and cam lever arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the cotter key into the clevis pin.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and verify proper park brake operation and adjustment (refer to CTS-5135TA).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply the park brake. Remove jack stands from the front axle and remove chocks from the
                    rear tires.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9750201" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>28588R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Flat Washers</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>*</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" valign="top">
                                <para>* Please check your stock prior to ordering washers to insure that you don't
                                    already have ample inventory. This washer comes in multiples of 100.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9750202" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-97502-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Adding washers to transmission boss</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1.5 hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward. The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle
                Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be
                adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
