<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 97506 - Standard Turn Signal Switch on 2000, 4000, and 8000 Series Tractors and 4000 Series Trucks
        Coded for 08WAT Turn Signal Switch
    </stitle>
    <recall id="Rec97506">
        <recallnumber>97506</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1997</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Standard Turn Signal Switch on 2000, 4000, and 8000 Series Tractors and 4000 Series Trucks Coded for
            08WAT Turn Signal Switch
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/04/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/31/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/04/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/31/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/04/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/31/1994</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>08WAT</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The turn signal switch shoulder bolt that holds the internal switch components together can
                progressively loosen, resulting in loss of turn signal function. Where this condition exists, it is
                always preceded by a significant loosening of the turn signal arm and the ability to move the emergency
                flasher outside of its channel. The loss of turn signal function will be apparent since the turn
                indicator in the dash will not flash. While a driver must exercise caution at all times to assure that
                other motorists are clear before executing a turn or lane change, the ability to warn the other
                motorists of the driver's intention before turning is lost if signal lights do not function. The
                combination of being unable to warn the motorists with signal lights, plus incorrect action of the part
                of the driver
                <emph type="bold">could cause a vehicular accident that could result in personal injury or property
                    damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If the date code number (located on the bottom of the turn signal lever) is higher
                        than 41411, no further action is required.
                    </emph>
                    If the date code number is between 13371 and 41411 and the turn signal lever arm is loose, then
                    continued to step 2 (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9750601">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9750601" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g9750601" filename="../recallfigures/g9750601.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove switch from steering column.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove plastic cover from switch by pulling bottom of the plastic cover out and up at
                    the tabs (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9750601">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the harness connector located on the bottom of the switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten shoulder bolt to ensure that it is fully seated.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not apply more than 25-32 in-lbs. (289-360 Ncm) torque; excessive torque will strip the
                            threads.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully back the shoulder bolt out two or three turns.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>The turn signal assembly will come apart when the shoulder bolt is loosened approximately
                            7 turns.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply one or two drops of Loctite in the threaded hole where the shoulder bolt threads
                    adjoin to the base threads (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9750601">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-tighten shoulder bolt to 25 to 32 in-lbs. (280 to 360 Ncm) torque.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not apply more than 25-32 in-lbs. (289-360 Ncm) torque; excessive torque will strip the
                            threads.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install plastic switch cover, attach harness and mount switch to steering column.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>SERVICE PARTS DEPARTMENT</title>
            </para>
            <para>Attached to this dealer letter is a poster that must be displayed at the Service Parts counter to
                notify aftermarket customers of this recall. The poster should be displayed until October 15, 1999. The
                purchaser of a turn signal switch that is subject to this recall may elect to apply the thread-locking
                compound, or may elect to have the dealer appy the compound at no charge to the customer.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Loctite 271 or equivalent thread-locking compound (readily available at retail stores).</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9750601" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.42in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.97in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.11in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-97506-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Remove turn signal switch, tighten bolts, apply Loctite and install switch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="label" filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles and aftermarket parts subject to this campaign at no charge to the
                owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, until October 15, 1999. The National Traffic
                and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is subject to a vehicle recall
                campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or turn signal switch or refund the purchase
                price, every effort must be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair the
                vehicle or aftermarket part as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="claim" filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
