<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98305 - Emergency Door Hinges</stitle>
    <recall id="rec98305">
        <recallnumber>98305</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Emergency Door Hinges</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/24/1988</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/18/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The vehicles involved are: AmTran RE and GENESIS buses built through October 18, 1996; Ward/AmTran
                Volunteer buses built February 24, 1988 through October 18, 1996; Ward Senator buses built January 5,
                1990 through January 1, 1992; Ward Patriot buses built February 24, 1988 through December 31, 1990;
                Ward/AmTran Vanguard buses built February 24, 1988 through October 18, 1996; Ward President buses built
                January 5, 1989 through October 30, 1990.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran RE, GENESIS, Ward/AmTran Volunteer, Ward/AmTran Vanguard, Ward Senator,
                Ward Patriot and Ward President vehicles in connection with the emergency door hinges.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>The buses contained in this recall have 2 (two) leaf type hinges per emergency door that consist of
                steel pins and/or lack zerk (grease) fittings. These hinges could bind from rust and/or corrosion. It
                has been determined that this could cause difficulty in opening the emergency door.
                <emph type="bold">This defect could cause entrapment of occupants in an emergency situation, which could
                    result in personal injury or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners have been notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran Bus Body or
                AmTran Alliance dealer to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the emergency door (doors if applicable) has 2 (two) leaf type hinges.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for the presence of a zerk fitting in each hinge.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine the material of the pin by scraping the surface at the end of the pin. Brass
                    pins will have a gold color and steel pins will have a silver color.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hinges with steel pins and/or those that lack zerk fittings require corrective action.
                    Corrective action requires replacing the hinges. Please complete and return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR
                    RECALL SERVICE" card checking box #8 and writing in your UPS shipping address if not stated. Some
                    buses involved in this recall have 2 (two) emergency doors. Please note this exception on the
                    returned card.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the unit inspected contains hinges with a brass pin and zerk fitting, no recall is
                        required. Please complete and return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card checking box
                        #1.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR</title>
            <para>Corrective action requires replacing the door hinges.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the door closed and the latch in the locked position, remove and replace one hinge
                    at a time. This will hold the door in place while the service is being performed. To remove the
                    hinges, remove the bolts retaining the hinges to the door and body. Install a new hinge by bolting
                    the hinge to the body and the door.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the hinges with Fleetrite EP2 Moly Grease or Equivalent NLGI #2 Multi-purpose
                    Lithium Grease. Move door during lubrication, for better distribution of the grease.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install Campaign Identification Label (see instructions below).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete and return the owners postage-paid "Recall - Repair Reply Card."</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9830501">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443243001</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hinge Assembly Emergency Door</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9830502">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Retrieval of unit, inspection and completion of documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.4 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace emergency door hinges (includes broken bolt replacement)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.4 Hour per door</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. As a precaution, you should
                not operate any of the vehicles subject to this recall campaign until they have been inspected for the
                presence of the nut assembled to the pinch bolt. In the event that the nut is missing, repairs must be
                made before the vehicle is driven.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS - AMTRAN ALLIANCE DEALERS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - OTHER AUTHORIZED REPAIR FACILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
