<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98503 - Double Neutral Shift Control Lever on Models with Allison AT545 Automatic Transmissions
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec98503">
        <recallnumber>98503</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subject>Double Neutral Shift Control Lever on Models with Allison AT545 Automatic Transmissions</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Allison</vendor>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>AT545</vendcode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 1652 SC, 3400, and 4700 models with an AT545 Allison automatic transmission
                built from 1/1/94 through 7/1/97.
            </para>
            <para>The double neutral shift control lever may bind as the driver attempts to put the lever in the park
                position. If this occurs, the lever does not actually reach the full park position which could result in
                a false park condition. If this condition occurs, the parking brake cannot be applied, thus causing the
                possibility of the vehicle rolling if parked on an incline. This could cause a vehicular accident
                resulting in property damage or personal injury, or both.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify the involved vehicle owners of this campaign. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable them to follow up with this recall
                campaign. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain information
                obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration
                data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SHIFT CONTROL REMOVAL</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9850301">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9850301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850301.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels so the vehicle cannot roll, and place the transmission in the Neutral
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 4 mounting screws holding the shift control to the dash brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the shift control from the dash.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the quadrant downward out of the dash-mounting bracket and disconnect shifter
                    wire harness from the vehicle harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shift cable hub mounting hardware from mounting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the quadrant until the hairpin cotter is visible. Remove the hairpin cotter and
                    shift cable pivot from the shift handle.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SHIFT CONTROL INSTALLATION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the shift cable pivot into the shift handle and install the hairpin cotter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the quadrant to install the shift cable mounting hardware to the cable-mounting
                    bracket. Torque at 30 in-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the shift assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the 4 mounting screws into the dash brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the shifter wire harness to the vehicle wire harness.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>VERIFICATION OF INSTALLATION</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Apply service brakes while verifying the installation.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insure that the engine starts in "P-B" and "Neutral" positions only.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While vehicle is running, see that the reverse switch (if so equipped) signals the
                    back-up lights or alarm as a result of placing shift control in the reverse position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While vehicle is running, move shift control handle into "P-B" position. The following
                    must occur:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Transmission shifts into neutral.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Park brake applies.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Refer to the Vehicle Identification list provided with the paper copy sent to the dealership. Look up
                the VIN of the vehicle involved and next to the VIN is the part number that is required for correct part
                installation.
            </para>
            <table id="t9850301" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>3515325C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Double Neutral Shifter</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>2023443C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Double Neutral Shifter</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>3507813C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Double Neutral Shifter</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9850302" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-98503-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Removing and installing of the double neutral shift control</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dearlers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
