<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98508 - Vehicle Recall for 9100, 9200, 9300, and 9400 Models with Spicer SPL170 Driveline</stitle>
    <recall id="rec98508">
        <recallnumber>98508</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>PROPELLER SHAFT</subjectfile>
        <subject>Vehicle Recall for 9100, 9200, 9300, and 9400 Models with Spicer SPL170 Driveline</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/07/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>SPL170</vendcode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 9100, 9200, 9300, and 9400 models built from 10/7/96 through 9/16/98 with a
                Spicer SPL170 driveline with a 55 mm diameter stub end and a center bearing.
            </para>
            <para>Certain 9000 Model Trucks equipped with an SPL170 driveline with 55 mm center bearing packages have
                experienced loosening of the end yoke retaining nut. If this condition occurs, the
                <emph type="bold">driveline may vibrate and could lead to a separation from the vehicle causing vehicle
                    damage or personal injury or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. An owner will call prior to
                bringing their vehicle in so that parts can be ordered and available when the appointment is scheduled.
                If a part is not readily available within 48 hours, then inform the customer that there is an interim
                action that should be implemented until the part is available. Please explain to the customer the
                interim action if parts are not readily available. (See SERVICE PROCEDURE below.) A listing of owner
                names and addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers for follow up with owners to have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE (Instructions for the Interim Procedure for Spicer SPL170 Driveline with 55 mm
                Center Bearing Package
            </title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure should only be completed as an interim action until parts for the customer are
                        readily available.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the positive battery cables at the batteries.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the threads of the driveline center bearing stub end and the rear side of the yoke
                    retaining nut, place one spot weld to eliminate the nut from backing off. Make sure you get good
                    weld penetration into the threaded stub end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the positive battery cables.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reschedule another appointment with the customer when the part is available.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The 55 mm stub end, yoke and center bearing are no longer available in service parts or from
                        Spicer.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Spicer SPL170 55 mm to 60 mm Driveline, Center Bearing and Center Bearing Bracket Upgrade
                Instructions
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Duplicate the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850801">Parts Order form</hotlnk>. Complete all requested information and fax to
                    Dana at the fax number listed. Dana will ship a kit specifically for the vehicle listed on the order
                    form. Delivery should be within 24 hours.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850801" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850801.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Parts Order Form</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The repair kit will be identified with the VIN and customer name. Compare the VIN # to
                    the kit received. The kit will contain the coupling shaft with assembled center bearing and center
                    bearing bracket needed for the VIN being serviced. The kit part number should match the last 8
                    characters of the VIN to be serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform a routine inspection of all drive shafts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Avoiding contact with the driveshaft slip boot; support the drive shaft connected to the
                    coupling shaft yoke in the chassis so it does not fall out when disconnected.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Referring to the Navistar service procedures for the chassis you are updating, remove
                    the U-joint attaching bolts and U-joint retainers from the center bearing yoke. Discard the U-joint
                    retainer bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the drive shaft U-joint from the coupling shaft yoke and support the drive
                    shaft in a position that allows replacement of the coupling shaft assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support the coupling shaft in the chassis so it does not fall out when disconnected.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the U-joint attaching bolts and U-joint retainers from the transmission output
                    yoke and bolts holding the center bearing to the center bearing bracket on the crossmember. The
                    center bearing bracket bolts will be re-used.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the coupling shaft and center bearing assembly from the vehicle. Discard the
                    coupling shaft assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the center bearing bracket from the vehicle crossmember. Discard the bracket. The
                    bolts for the bracket will be re-used.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the
                    <emph type="bold">NEW</emph>
                    center bearing bracket from the kit using the bolts removed earlier (P/N 414052C1 1/2 inch bolt
                    Grade 8). Torque the bolts to 100 - 120 ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the
                    <emph type="bold">NEW</emph>
                    coupling shaft from the kit into the chassis and support it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the center bearing to the new bracket using the bolts previously removed (P/N
                    414052C1 1/2 inch bolt Grade 8). Torque the bolts to 100 - 120 ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the U-joint bearing retainers at the transmission end yoke and install the
                    <emph type="bold">NEW bearing retainer bolts</emph>
                    from the kit. Torque the bolts to 100 - 120 ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the drive shaft to the coupling shaft by placing the drive shaft U-joint into
                    the coupling shaft end yoke at the center bearing. Be sure to properly seat the U-joint bearing
                    caps. Install the
                    <emph type="bold">NEW bearing retainer bolts</emph>
                    from the kit. Torque the bolts to 100 - 120 ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly lubricate
                    <emph type="bold">ALL</emph>
                    U-joints in the vehicle. Following the Navistar Service Manual CTS-5000 recommendations, fully purge
                    all U-joints until
                    <emph type="bold">CLEAN</emph>
                    grease appears at
                    <emph type="bold">ALL FOUR BEARING CAPS</emph>
                    of each U-joint. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850802">Figure</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850802" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850802.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Use a copy of the provided
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9850801">fax sheet</hotlnk>
                to order correct coupling shaft kit for each VIN. Part numbers are set up according to VIN numbers.
                Reproduce fax sheet locally. Use 1 fax sheet for each vehicle. Part Kits will be supplied at no cost.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>HANDLING ALLOWANCE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Since parts for this campaign are being supplied on a "no charge" basis, a $30 dealer handling charge
                will be allowed. This charge should be submitted as an outside charge on the Warranty Claim as "Handling
                Allowance."
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9850801" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-98508-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Perform spot weld on stub end threads and retaining nut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-98508-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Replace coupling shaft yoke and center bearing bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1.0 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">Campaign Identification Label</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">Recall Coding</hotlnk>
                be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim. Complete instructions will be found in
                the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
