<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98501 - Air Compressor Discharge Line on Caterpillar C10 and C12 Engines on 9100 and 9200 Model
        Vehicles
    </stitle>
    <recall id="rec98501">
        <recallnumber>98501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Air Compressor Discharge Line on Caterpillar C10 and C12 Engines on 9100 and 9200 Model Vehicles
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Caterpillar</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/09/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/20/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/09/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/20/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>Caterpillar</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 9100 and 9200 Models with Caterpillar C10 and C12 engines built from 4/9/96
                through 11/20/97.
            </para>
            <para>A P-clamp was omitted from the rear of the engine that supports the air compressor discharge line.
                Vehicle vibration could cause the unsupported line to fail. This could deplete the air system and cause
                the parking brakes to apply. This condition could cause the vehicle to slow down or stop unexpectedly,
                and
                <emph type="bold">could cause a vehicular accident resulting in property damage or personal injury, or
                    both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses will have been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers of follow up with owners to
                have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the bracket P/N 864340R1 to the back of the engine. Mount the bracket so it has
                    between a 20 - 45 degree downward angle. This will lower the compressor discharge line to clear the
                    floor. Attach the P-clamp P/N 505194C1 to the compressor discharge line and bolt to the bracket.
                    Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850101">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850101" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850101.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the stud that is located just beneath the bracket with bolt P/N 477884C1 as the
                    stud interferes with the fuel hosing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850101">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel line P-clamp along with the compressor discharge line P-clamp on the new
                    bracket. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850102">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850102" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850102.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tie the fuel hosing with a tie strap at either side of the P-clamp. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850102">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9850101" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>864340R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>505194C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>P-clamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>477884C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Bolt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9850102" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description
                                    <emph type="bold"></emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-98501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Attach bracket and P-clamp. Remove stud and replace bolt.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dearlers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
