<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98504 - AKW Recall</stitle>
    <recall id="rec98504">
        <recallnumber>98504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>WHEELS</subjectfile>
        <subject>AKW Recall</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>AKW</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>Pursuant to Part 573.5, this Vehicle Safety Defect Initial Information Report is submitted by Navistar
                International Transportation Corp. Reference NHTSA Recall number 98E-012.
            </para>
            <para>This report relates to certain 22.5 X 8.25 15-degree tubeless one-piece aluminum dual wheels
                manufactured by:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>AKW</line>
                <line>3560 West Market Street</line>
                <line>Suite 315</line>
                <line>Akron, OH 44333</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>Our contact at AKW is Mr. George F. Anderson (330) 665-6900.</para>
            <para>(1) NAVISTAR RECALL NUMBER ASSIGNED: 98504</para>
            <para>(2) VEHICLE MODELS INVOLVED: All Models that use certain 22.5 X 8.25 15-degree one-piece aluminum dual
                wheels.
            </para>
            <para>(3) MODEL YEARS INVOLVED: 1997 and 1998</para>
            <para>(4) OTHER IDENTIFICATION NECESSARY TO DESCRIBE VEHICLES: Certain 22.5 X 8.25 15-degree one-piece
                aluminum dual wheels
            </para>
            <para>(5) VEHICLE MANUFACTURING DATES: 10/2/97 through 3/13/98</para>
            <para>(6) VEHICLE POPULATION INVOLVED: 3041, The quantity represents the total suspect population that
                contains the AKW 22.5 X 8.25 15-degree tubeless one-piece aluminum dual wheels in question.
            </para>
            <para>(7) PORTION OF POPULATION ESTIMATED TO CONTAIN DEFECT: 100%</para>
            <para>(8) DESCRIPTION OF DEFECT: Certain design revisions combined with process conditions can cause
                potential fatigue cracks under severe loading and/or environmental conditions.
            </para>
            <para>(9) RISK TO MOTOR VEHICLE SAFETY: Potential fatigue cracks can cause potential wheel failures. Over a
                period of time, with cracks developing from handhole to handhole a wheel separation could result. This
                defect could cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in personal injury or
                property damage, or both.
            </para>
            <para>(10) CHRONOLOGY OF PRINCIPAL EVENTS WHICH LED TO DETERMINATION OF A SAFETY DEFECT: Navistar was
                informed by AKW on their intent to recall vehicles manufactured with the subject wheels per NHTSA recall
                number 98E-012 on May 6, 1998. Navistar was furnished a list of part numbers, quantities, and ship
                dates; and was requested to supply customer names and addresses. An investigation was initiated. Vehicle
                owner information was sent to AKW on June 9, 1998.
            </para>
            <para>(11) PROGRAM TO BE TAKEN TO REMEDY DEFECT: AKW to replace wheels.</para>
            <para>(12) THE SCHEDULE FOR THIS RECALL IS: AKW to provide recall schedule and quarterly completion
                reports.
            </para>
            <para>(13) OWNER LETTER AND TECHNICAL LETTER: Will be provided by AKW.</para>
            <para>Rick Van Laar should be contacted for any additional information regarding this recall on (219)
                461-1890.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para></para>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para></para>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para></para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para></para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
