<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 98505 - Tie Rod Arm Fracture on Fabco Front Drive Axles</stitle>
    <recall id="rec98505">
        <recallnumber>98505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1998</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Tie Rod Arm Fracture on Fabco Front Drive Axles</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/01/1992</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/30/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Fabco</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The tie rod arm can fracture from the spindle yoke due to excessive loads placed on the casting. A
                failure of the tie rod arm can result in the loss of steering control to the right wheel that could
                cause a vehicular accident resulting in property damage or personal injury, or both.
            </para>
            <para>Models involved are 4800 4x4s and 4900 6x6s with 12,000 lb. Fabco front drive axles built from 4/1/92
                through 4/30/95.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify the involved vehicle owners of this campaign. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable them to follow up with this recall
                campaign. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain information
                obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle registration
                data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="8">
            <title>REMOVE AND REPLACE SPINDLE YOKE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>This recall involves two general areas of instruction as follows:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove and replace the Spindle Yokes and tie rod adjuster, which will include toe in and
                            wheel stop adjustment.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicle poppet re-adjustment for steering gear. Instructions provided in kit.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Remove/Replace Spindle Yoke</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Prepare a clean place to work. It is important that no dirt or foreign material be allowed
                            to enter the unit during repairs. The outside of the unit should be carefully cleaned before
                            starting disassembly.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Block the rear wheels.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Raise the front of the truck with a jack and support with jackstands of suitable
                        capacity.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the front wheels.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Follow all procedures for working with brake material dust. OSHA standards should be
                            consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as well as for suggested procedures to
                            minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1910.1001.)
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the brake drum.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the eight outer drive flange locknuts.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the large flanged axle locknut.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The drive flange should be loose enough to remove by hand. If it is not, use two
                        3/8-16 bolts in the extractor holes provided for this purpose. Set the colored drive flange
                        shims aside for reuse during assembly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Remove bearings in a manner that will not damage those bearings as they will be re
                            -used.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the wheel-bearing locknut, washer, and adjusting nut from the spindle. Rock
                        the hub lightly to loosen the outer wheel-bearing cone. Remove the cone and wrap it
                        protectively.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the hub, by pulling the assembly straight off to avoid cocking the inner
                        bearing cone (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850501">Figure 1</hotlnk>). If the cone binds against the spindle, try lightly
                        rocking the hub to free it. Wipe off any oil that may have reached the brake shoe before it
                        reaches the brake lining.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850501" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850501.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Remove Hub</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Wheel Spindle</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the brake assembly. Refer to GROUP 04-BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                        Manual for procedures to remove the foundation brakes.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">2. Remove the ten 5/8" locknuts which secure the spindle and the dust shield /brake
                        spider assembly. Remove the spindle (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850502">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850502" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850502.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Remove Spindle</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Spindle Yoke</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully remove the axle shaft by withdrawing it from the differential through the
                        spindle yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the tie rod end. Remove the tie rod adjuster link, from the tie rod and
                        discard the old adjuster.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new adjuster between tie rod end and tie rod.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the upper kingpin adjusting screw jam nut and back out the adjusting screw
                        until the spindle yoke stops moving downward and is resting on the suspension yoke. Remove the
                        four 3/4" steering arm or upper kingpin cap locknuts, and pull the arm or cap up off its
                        mounting studs. If difficulty is encountered, turn the adjusting screw back in to force the arm
                        or cap off the studs (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850503">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850503" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850503.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Turn Adjusting Screw</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using Fabco tool number 866-0687-007 ( refer to CTS-5149 page 28) or equivalent,
                        loosen the lower kingpin locknut and completely remove the locknut, lock washer and lower
                        kingpin ball stud from the spindle yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the 7/8" upper kingpin bolt and its locknut and two attendant washers from
                        the suspension yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Use Fabco special tool number 866 706 or equivalent (refer to CTS-5149 page 27).
                        Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850504">Figure 4</hotlnk>, to pull the upper kingpin ball stud from the
                        suspension yoke. The tool is available from Fabco, or it can be fabricated. Do not try to remove
                        the ball stud by rocking the spindle yoke as this may affect the critical press fit between the
                        ball stud and suspension yoke. Fit the tool's two tubes over two diagonally located steering arm
                        or upper kingpin cap studs. Insert the 1 " - 14 bolt through the washer and the tool's central
                        hole and start it in the threads in the top of the upper kingpin ball stud. Tighten the bolt
                        until the ball stud is pulled free of the suspension yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850504" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850504.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Pull Upper Kingpin Ball Stud</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the tool, grasp the spindle yoke at the top, and rotate it outward and down
                        to disengage it from the suspension yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Re-assemble With New Spindle Yoke</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Screw the lower kingpin ball stud into the new spindle yoke until the top of the
                        threaded portion is flush with the inside surface of the yoke. Ensure that the locating pin for
                        the kingpin lockwasher is in position in the yoke, then loosely install the lockwasher and new
                        nut (do not engage the locating pin into the lockwasher at this time).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Smear the spherical portion of the lower kingpin ball stud and seal with chassis
                        grease. Grasping the spindle yoke with both hands, place the lower ball stud into its bearing in
                        the suspension yoke. Rotate the top of the spindle yoke over the upper suspension yoke.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Smear chassis grease in the upper kingpin bearing and seal and start the upper ball
                        stud through the bearing and into its bore in the suspension yoke. Place one upper kingpin
                        washer on the upper kingpin bolt and insert the bolt up through the suspension yoke and upper
                        kingpin ball stud. Install the other washer and the 7/8" locknut on the bolt and tighten to 500
                        ft-lbs. (678 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After wiping both mounting surfaces clean of grease, push the steering arm or upper
                        kingpin cap down over its mounting studs, install the four 3/4" nuts, and tighten to 250 ft-lbs.
                        (339 Nm). Make sure the top king pin adjusting screw is still backed out.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Slowly tighten the upper kingpin adjusting screw until upward motion of the spindle
                        yoke stops. If a finger is placed near the gap between the suspension and spindle yokes, the
                        point at which upward travel stops can be determined. Significant additional resistance will
                        also be felt in the effort required to turn the adjusting screw.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Fill the gap between the suspension and spindle yokes in the area of the lower
                        kingpin ball stud with a stack of feeler gauges. There should be enough gauges in the stack to
                        fit the gap snugly (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850505">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850505" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850505.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Fill Gap With Feeler Gauges</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the lower kingpin ball stud until the feeler gauge stack loosens, indicating
                        that the ball stud threads are actually beginning to spread the suspension and spindle yokes
                        apart.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the lower kingpin ball stud just enough to allow the closest hole in the
                        lower kingpin lockwasher to engage the retaining dowel pin. Tighten the locknut to 600 ft-lbs.
                        (813 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Back out the upper kingpin adjusting screw 1/16 turn and tighten the jam nut to 45
                        ft-lbs. (61 Nm), while holding the adjusting screw from turning.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Insert the tip of the axle shaft carefully through the inner axle seal and continue
                        to push the assembly in until it can be felt to contact the differential. Rotate the assembly,
                        so the yoke shaft mounting faces are horizontal. By using a bar placed between the universal
                        joint and the yoke shaft as a lever, the tip of the axle shaft inside the housing can be raised
                        sufficiently to allow it to engage with the differential splines (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850506">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850506" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850506.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Raise Tip of Axle Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Wheel Spindle Re-assemble</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate the bearing's inner surface, and pack the cavity between bearing and seal
                        with wheel bearing grease.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Slide the spindle over the axle shaft and spindle yoke studs. The large keyway must
                        be located at the 12 o'clock position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the dust shield/brake spider assembly onto the spindle yoke studs with the
                        large hole positioned to receive the air chamber mounting bracket. Install the ten 5/8" locknuts
                        and tighten to 175 ft-lbs. (237 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-install the tie rod and tighten the castle nut to 100 ft-lbs. (136 Nm), and
                        install a new cotter pin.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Re-install Brake Assembly</title>
                <para>Refer to GROUP 04-BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for procedures to install the
                    foundation brakes.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Wheel Bearings, Hub, and Brake Drum</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lightly coat the outer surface of the spindle with grease to reduce the chance of
                        the inner wheel bearing cocking upon installation of the hub.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Grasping the outer circumference of the hub at the 12 and 6 o'clock positions, push
                        the hub straight on to the spindle. If difficulty is encountered, try rocking the hub slightly
                        to free the inner bearing.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the outer bearing and adjusting nut.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the bearing adjusting nut to 50 ft-lbs. (68 Nm) while simultaneously
                        rotating the hub assembly. Loosen the nut and repeat this procedure 2-3 times to ensure that the
                        bearings are seated properly. After the final tightening, back off the nut 1/8 turn (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850507">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9850507" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850507.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Back Off Nut 1/8 Turn</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the wheel bearing lockwasher. If the lockwasher doesn't engage the dowel pin
                        retainer, back off the adjusting nut just enough to allow its dowel pin to engage in the
                        lockwasher's closest hole. Install and tighten the locknut to 400 ft-lbs. (542 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The wheel bearing end play should be checked with a dial indicator as part of the
                        adjustment procedure. The correct end play is.002" to .004" (0.05 to 0.10mm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install all removed drive flange shims and drive flange over the drive studs.
                        Install the 8 drive flange locknuts and tighten to 100 ft-lbs. (136 Nm). Install and tighten the
                        large flanged axle locknut to 400 ft-lbs. (542 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Mount the brake drum over the wheel studs.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-install wheel assembly and torque wheel nuts to 450-500 ft-lbs.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Grease all lubrication points before returning the vehicle to service.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace the other front axle spindle yoke using these instructions. After both
                        spindle yokes have been replaced, it will be necessary to adjust toe-in and front axle wheel
                        stops.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Toe-In Adjustment</title>
                <para>To adjust toe-in, rotate the tie rod adjuster until 1/16" + or - 1/16" is achieved. After
                    adjustment, tighten both tie rod adjuster clamp bolts to 75 ft-lbs. (102 Nm). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850508">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9850508" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850508.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Adjust Toe-In</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Wheel Stop Adjustment</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Toe-in must be correctly adjusted before performing this procedure. The inside wheel
                            turning should be 35 degrees. To adjust, loosen the steering stop jam nut on the rear of the
                            spindle yoke and adjust with the 12 point adjusting screw. After adjustment, tighten the jam
                            nut to 75 ft-lbs. (102 Nm).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="9">
            <title>On-Vehicle End of Travel Poppet Re-Adjustment Procedures for TAS Steering Gears</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine, and allow the vehicle to idle for 5-10 minutes to warm the hydraulic
                    fluid. Shut off the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Assemble adjusting screw into nut</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the new poppet adjusting screw and nut from kit # 8900066R91. Turn the screw into
                    the non-sealing end of the jam nut until the drive end of screw is flush with the nut. Your steering
                    gear will have either a fixed stop bolt or an adjusting screw (Navistar production is a fixed stop
                    bolt, however, if the poppets have ever been reset it will have an adjusting screw.). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850509">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850509" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850509.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Remove Poppet Stop Bolt</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the engine is off and the road wheels are in straight ahead position. Remove
                    and discard the poppet fixed stop bolt (if equipped) and washer (if equipped) from the lower end of
                    housing. If the unit has a poppet adjusting screw and sealing nut, remove and discard them. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850510">Figure 1</hotlnk>0.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850510" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850510.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Remove Poppet Adjusting Screw and Sealing Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Turn adjusting screw assembly into housing</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the adjusting screw and sealing nut assembly, without rotating the nut on the
                    screw, into the housing until the nut is firmly against the housing using a 7/32" allen wrench.
                    Tighten the sealing nut against the housing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850511">Figure 11</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850511" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850511.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Turn Adjusting Screw and Sealing Nut Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Refill reservoir</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refill system reservoir with approved hydraulic fluid. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850512">Figure 12</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850512" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850512.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Refill System Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not mix fluid types. Mixing of transmission fluid, motor oil, or other hydraulic fluids
                        will cause seals to deteriorate faster.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Jack Up Vehicle</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a jack under the center of the front axle and jack up the front end of the vehicle
                    so the steer axle tires are off the ground. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850513">Figure 13</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850513" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850513.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Place Jack Under Center of Front Axle</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Push Upper Poppet Out to Prepare it for Setting</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not hold the steering wheel at full turn for more than 10 seconds at a time; the heat
                        build-up at pump relief pressure may damage components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the following:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Start the engine and let it run at idle speed.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Note which output shaft timing mark is nearest the housing piston bore.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in the direction that makes this timing mark move toward the
                        adjusting screw just installed. Turn in this direction until axle stop contact is made.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pull hard on the steering wheel (put 30 lbs. rim pull on a 20" dia. steering wheel)
                        after the axle stop is contacted. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850514">Figure 14</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850514" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850514.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Pull Hard on Steering Wheel After Axle Stop is Contacted</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Set Upper Poppet</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in the opposite direction (end of timing mark away from
                        adjusting screw) until the other axle stop is contacted.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pull hard on the steering wheel (put 30 lbs. rim pull on a 20" dia. steering
                        wheel).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Release the steering wheel and shut off the engine. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850515">Figure 15</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850515" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850515.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Other Axle Stop Contacted</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Back Out Adjusting Screw</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the sealing nut and back out the adjusting screw until 1 " is past the nut.
                    Tighten the sealing nut against the housing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9850516">Figure 16</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850516" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850516.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Back Out Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Set Lower Poppet</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Start the engine and let it idle.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in the original direction (end of timing mark toward
                        adjusting screw), until axle stop contact is made.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Hold the steering wheel in this position (with 30 lbs. rim pull) for 10 seconds,
                        then release. Repeat this hold and release process as many times as necessary while completing
                        Step 11. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9850517">Figure 17</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9850517" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9850517.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Hold Steering Wheel in This Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Position Adjusting Screw</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With steering wheel held at full turn, loosen the screw jam nut and hold it in place
                        with a wrench.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the adjusting screw in (clockwise) using finger-pressure only (don't use a
                        ratchet), until the Allen wrench comes to a stop. Do not attempt to turn it in farther. Pause
                        the turning-in process each time the driver releases the steering wheel; continue turning only
                        while the wheel is held at full turn.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Back off the adjusting screw 31/4 turns and tighten the sealing nut. Torque the
                        sealing nut to 33-37 Ibf-ft.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The Procedure is Complete</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The poppets have now been completely reset. Lower the vehicle. Check the reservoir and
                    fill if required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The length of the adjusting screw beyond the nut must be no more than 1 1/16" for proper
                        thread engagement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The length of adjusting screw beyond the sealing nut may be different for each vehicle.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Part number 8900063R91 and 8900064R91 must be ordered via fax. Please use the attached fax form
                provided in the dealer letter.
            </para>
            <para>Part number 8900066R91 must be ordered using the Recall order form attached to the safety recall via
                Navistar's PDC's.
            </para>
            <table id="t9850501" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900063R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Short Wheel Base (up to 182 inches)</emph>
                                    Front axle spindles, tie rod arm, and tie rod adjuster
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900064R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Long Wheel Base (183 inches and above)</emph>
                                    Front axle spindles, tie rod arm, and tie rod adjuster
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8900066R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Steering gear adjustment screw kit with poppet adjustment screw, poppet adjustment
                                    jam nut, and instructions
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <title>Handling Allowance</title>
            </para>
            <para>Since Fabco is furnishing the replacement yokes at no charge to the dealer, a $50.00 handling
                allowance should be included on the warrantee claim.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9850502" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description
                                    <emph type="bold"></emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-98505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Removal and installation of spindle yokes, tie rod adjuster, and reset steering
                                    gear poppets
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>6.0 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
