<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99001 - Rear Window Assemblies</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99001">
        <recallnumber>99001</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Rear Window Assemblies</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/16/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to AmTran RE&#8482; buses built from March 1, 1998 through July 16, 1999.</para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Transportation Products, Inc. has determined that some emergency exit windows, manufactured and
                shipped to AmTran for use in AmTran RE buses, fail to conform to Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard
                No. 217, "Bus Emergency Exits and Window Retention and Release" [Part 49 CFR 577.5(b)(2)]. Failure of
                the emergency exit latches can inhibit exit from the vehicle in an emergency.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>The buses contained in this recall have windows that may have one or more of the following conditions:
                (a) latch operating instruction error, (b) high opening forces, (c) failure of window to fully latch or
                unlatch, (d) inability to deactivate warning buzzer, and/or (e) rivet missing from exterior latch cable
                lever.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners are being notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran Alliance dealer
                to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="5">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Condition "a" - interior latch operation instruction error</title>
                <para></para>
                <para>If the interior latch operating decal reads "1. PULL RED HANDLE UPWARD 2. PUSH LOWER EDGE OF GLASS
                    OUT" corrective action must be taken.
                </para>
                <para>Corrective action requires replacement of the interior latch operating decal with one that reads "
                    <emph type="bold">1. LIFT TO UNLATCH 2. PUSH TO OPEN</emph>." Please complete and return the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #8.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Condition "b" - high opening forces</title>
                <seqlist style="alphauc">
                    <item>
                        <para>Open window by lifting up on the interior latch and pushing out.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Window should open with minimal effort from the operator.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>If the window fails to open with minimal effort from the operator, corrective action must be
                    taken. Corrective action requires replacing the gas cylinders on the window. Please complete and
                    return the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #9.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Condition "c" - failure of window to fully latch or unlatch</title>
                <para>This is a two-part condition and will be referred to as Condition c1 and Condition c2.</para>
                <para>Inspection procedure for Condition c1:</para>
                <seqlist style="alphauc">
                    <item>
                        <para>From the inside of the bus, push outward on window as shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9900101">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                            without operating the emergency release latch. Window should not push open.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>If the window can be pushed open corrective actions must be taken.</para>
                <para>Corrective action requires adding a spacer under the egress keepers. Please complete and return
                    the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #10.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9900101" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9900101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Push out on window from inside of bus here. Interior view of window shown.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Inspection procedure for Condition c2:</para>
                <seqlist style="alphauc">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check interior egress latch handle for correct positioning (see
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9900102">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Incorrect positioning of latch handle is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9900103">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>If the interior latch handle will not stay in the correct position as described in the inspection
                    procedure, corrective action must be taken.
                </para>
                <para>Corrective action requires replacement of the interior egress latch. Please complete and return
                    the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #11.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9900102" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9900102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Latch handle in correct position</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9900103" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9900103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Latch handle in incorrect position</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Condition "d" - inability to deactivate warning buzzer</title>
                <para>Inspection procedure for Condition "d":</para>
                <seqlist style="alphauc">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn bus ignition to "on" position. Window warning buzzer should not operate if window is
                            in fully closed position. If the buzzer is activated, follow procedure "C".
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Open window. Window warning buzzer should operate as soon as handle is activated to
                            release the latch.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Depress warning buzzer switch actuation lever to stop buzzer operation. If the buzzer does
                            not stop operating with the lever depressed, the switch will need replacing. See corrective
                            action "a". If warning buzzer stops when the lever is depressed, adjustment is required. See
                            corrective action "b".
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>Corrective Action "a" - requires replacement of the warning buzzer switch. Please complete and
                    return the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #12.
                </para>
                <para>Corrective Action "b" - Warning Buzzer Switch Activation Bracket Adjustment Procedure:</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Raise window to fully opened position.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen screws on warning buzzer switch activation bracket (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9900104">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Slide warning buzzer switch activation bracket toward switch.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn bus ignition switch to "on" position (warning buzzer should be activated) and
                        lower window carefully to the closed position (warning buzzer should be deactivated).
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Do not allow window to slam closed. Damage to the warning buzzer switch may result
                                unless proper adjustment is achieved.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Warning buzzer bracket should be adjusted as close to the switch body as possible. Switch
                        lever may be bent outward to provide for more adjustment if necessary.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9900104" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9900104.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Adjustment screws</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Condition "e" - rivet missing from exterior latch cable lever</title>
                <para>Check exterior latch for rivet as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9900105">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <para>If the rivet is not in the exterior latch, corrective action must be taken. Please complete and
                    return the "
                    <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card checking box #13.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9900105" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9900105.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Rivet should be located here</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Adjustment of warning buzzer switch activation bracket - 0.2 hour.</para>
            <para>Inspection and documentation completion time for all of the above is 0.25 hour.</para>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>RECALL CLAIMS AND SUPPORT</para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice to Transportation
                Products, Inc. with the following information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall
                Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
            <para>Total Hours Spent:___________</para>
            <para>Additional support may be obtained by contacting Transportation Products, Inc. at the following
                numbers:
            </para>
            <para>Phone: 334-578-1267</para>
            <para>Fax: 334-578-5213</para>
            <para>Please send invoices to the following address:</para>
            <para>Transportation Products, Inc.</para>
            <para>P.O. Box 586</para>
            <para>Evergreen, AL 36401</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
