<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99307 - Anchor Seat Mounting Hardware</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99307">
        <recallnumber>99307</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Anchor Seat Mounting Hardware</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/10/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to AmTran RE and FE, GENESIS, and AmTran Conventional buses built from October 1,
                1998 through September 10, 1999.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran RE&#8482;, AmTran FE&#8482;, GENESIS&#8482;, and AmTran Conventional&#8482;
                buses. This defect involves the seat mounting bolts for the rear leg of the two leg anchor (seat belt
                ready) seats mounted in buses without the plywood floor option.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>Some of the buses involved in this recall were built with seat mounting bolts that failed during
                testing meeting the requirements of FMVSS 210.
                <emph type="bold">In the event of an accident, this defect could result in personal injury.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners are being notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran Alliance dealer
                to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>This photo (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930701">Figure 1</hotlnk>) shows the type of seat that is involved in this recall.
                Count the number of seats that match this photo. Please complete and return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR
                RECALL SERVICE" card checking one of the boxes, #3 through #6 or box #8. When checking box #8 enter the
                quantity of seats that match the photo. Make sure that your correct UPS shipping address (i.e., not a
                P.O. Box number) is on the card. This will enable AmTran to ship replacement bolts to your location.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930701" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The repair procedure will involve replacing the existing two (2) bolts that secure the rear leg of the
                seat to the floor with bolts that have a shoulder between the head of the bolt and the threaded section.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Inspection and completion of documentation 0.2 hour.</para>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS - AMTRAN DEALERS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the recall claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - OTHER AUTHORIZED REPAIR FACILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
            <para>Hours Charged:___________</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
