<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99303 - Flip Seat Modesty Panels</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99303">
        <recallnumber>99303</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Flip Seat Modesty Panels</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/03/1992</startdate>
                        <enddate>02/24/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to AmTran RE, AmTran FE, GENESIS, AmTran Conventional and AmTran/Ward Volunteer
                buses built from June 3, 1992 through February 24, 1999.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran RE&#8482;, AmTran FE&#8482;, GENESIS&#8482;, AmTran Conventional&#8482; and
                AmTran/Ward Volunteer buses. This defect involves the flip seats located at the side emergency doors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>Some of the above buses were built with flip seats that can cause injury when being deployed to the
                sitting position. The seat cushion hinge located on the aisle side of our standard flip seat is located
                close to the edge of the seat and within reach of the passenger. The two halves of the hinge assembly
                pass near each other creating a scissors action. The seat cushion hinge on our combination flip seat is
                located in such a manner that it is within easy reach of the passenger seated in the seat located behind
                the combo flip seat. The hinges on the combo flip seat could cause a pinching condition.
                <emph type="bold">These defects could result in personal injury.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners are being notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran Alliance dealer
                to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>There are several different flip seats available and are located in different locations within the
                bus. To make sure that we send you the correct kit or kits to remedy the above issue, we are asking you
                to document on your "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card, the type and location of flip seats in this
                unit. We have records on this unit identifying the seats that were installed at the time of manufacture,
                but need to verify the flip seat information. Refer to the Figures below.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9930301">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        shows the typical standard automatic flip seat located adjacent to the left side (driver's side)
                        emergency door and requires type "A" kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9930302">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                        shows the typical standard automatic flip seat located adjacent to the right side (opposite from
                        the driver's side) emergency door and requires type "B" kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9930303">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                        shows the special automatic flip seat located adjacent to the right side (opposite from the
                        driver's side) emergency door located at the most rear position at the engine compartment and
                        requires type "C" kit. This is available only on AmTran RE products.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9930304">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                        shows the combination automatic flip seat located adjacent to the left side (driver's side)
                        emergency door and requires type "D" kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f9930301" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Typical Standard flip seat located on the left side of the bus.
                <emph type="bold">Requires Type "A" kit.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930302" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Typical standard flip seat located on the right side of the bus between the wheel pockets on all
                models or behind the rear wheel pocket on all models except AmTran RE.
                <emph type="bold">Requires Type "B" kit.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930303" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Right side flip seat located behind the rear wheel pocket just in front of the engine compartment on
                AmTran RE buses only.
                <emph type="bold">Requires Type "C" kit.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930304" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Combination flip seat showing unique wider rear seat back versus the narrow seat.
                <emph type="bold">Requires Type "D" kit.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Please complete and return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card checking one of the boxes, #1
                through #6 or box #8. When checking box #8 enter the type of kit(s) required. Therefore, if you require
                only the left standard flip seat kit, enter "A" in the (_). Example: SEND TYPE (A) KIT. If you require
                both the left and right standard flip seat kit enter "A" in the (__) on the first line and "B" in the
                (__) on the second line. Example: SEND TYPE (A) KIT. SEND TYPE (B) KIT.
            </para>
            <para>Normally only the type "A" kit is required except for those units that have two flip seats or a
                special combination seat as depicted by the Figures.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All flip seats except for the combination flip seat will require a modesty panel be
                    installed on the aisle side of the seat. The combination flip seat will require a modesty panel
                    mounted under the seat cushion frame. Kits with parts and instructions are available to make the
                    repair.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete and install the "Campaign Identification Label" (see instructions below) that
                    is included in the kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete and return the owner's postage-paid "Recall - Repair Reply Card" that is
                    included in the kit. This card is included with left side and combination seats only.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9930301">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443628001 Type "A"</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Modesty panel std. left flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1 as required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443628002 Type "B"</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Modesty panel std. right flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1 as required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443701001 Type "C"</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Modesty panel right rear (RE) flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1 as required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>443732001 Type "D"</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Guard combination flip seat</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>1 as required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>With the use of battery powered or hand tools, these panels and/or guards can be installed without
                moving the units from their normal parking location. Time below is the required time to assemble and
                install the different variations.
            </para>
            <table id="t9930602">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Accessing the unit, inspection and completion of documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.4 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Installing standard left or right standard flip seat modesty panel</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Installing right rear (RE model only) modesty panel</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Installing combination flip seat guard</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS - AMTRAN ALLIANCE DEALERS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - OTHER AUTHORIZED REPAIR FACILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
            <para>Hours Charged:___________; Number of Kits Installed:___________________.</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
