<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99304 - Tire Pressure Error on Certification Label</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99304">
        <recallnumber>99304</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S.</market>
        <recalldate>March, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>Tire Pressure Error on Certification Label</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000 FE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/15/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/27/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000 RE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/15/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/27/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>American Transportation has mailed to the affected customers the following notice. This notice is sent
                to you in accordance with the requirements of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act.
                American Transportation Corporation has determined that the
                <emph type="bold">certification label</emph>
                in certain AmTran RE&#8482; and AmTran FE&#8482; buses fail to conform to federal regulation
                requirements for tire pressure.
            </para>
            <para>On some of the above AmTran RE&#8482; and AmTran FE&#8482; buses the air pressure specified, on the
                certification label, for the front axle and/or rear axle is in error.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>The affected AmTran FE&#8482; and AmTran RE&#8482; model buses were built from February 15, 1994
                through January 27, 1999.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>The customer has been sent a recall letter asking them to complete and return the "
                <emph type="bold">AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE</emph>" card that was enclosed with their notice.
                When the card is returned to us with box number 8 checked, we will forward, to their attention, a new
                certification label that will have the correct tire pressures stated. We also requested that the
                customer refer to the driver's manual for proper tire pressure.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CERTIFICATION LABEL REPLACEMENT</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>The
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9930401">certification label</hotlnk>
                    is located on the forward overhead panel above the driver.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9930401" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Metal Certification Label Located Above Driver</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Paper Certification Label</title>
                <para>To repair, remove the backing off of the new label and apply it directly over the existing
                    certification label.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Metal Certification Labels</title>
                <para>To repair, remove the rivets using a # 27 bit, drill through the center of all four rivets that
                    retain the metal tag to the bulkhead panel. Remove and destroy the old metal tag. Install the new
                    enclosed metal tag in the same location using four rivets (part #400050000) enclosed.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9930401">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.98in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.58in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Install new Paper Certification</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.1 hour or</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove and install new Metal Certification (when required)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Locate vehicle and complete recall information</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer's Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer
                Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory. All inventory vehicles subject
                to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to sale, transfer, or delivery. If vehicles have been
                sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and Authorization for Recall
                Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer
                <emph type="bold">must be notified from your distributor location.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Export locations are to submit warranty claims in the usual manner making reference to Safety Recall
                99304.
            </para>
        </responex>
    </recall>
</isis>
