<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99302 - Brake Mounting Nuts to Rear Axle</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99302">
        <recallnumber>99302</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>March, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Brake Mounting Nuts to Rear Axle</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/16/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>02/09/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/16/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>02/09/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to AmTran RE, AmTran FE, and GENESIS buses, and 1652 stripped chassis built from
                October 16, 1998 through February 9, 1999.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran RE&#8482;, AmTran FE&#8482;, GENESIS&#8482; buses, and 1652 stripped
                chassis. This defect involves the rear brake monting hardware to the rear axle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>Some the units in this recall may have been built with "grade 5" lock nuts instead of "grade 8" lock
                nuts or a mixture of "grade 5" lock nuts and "grade 8" lock nuts. "Grade 5" lock nuts in this
                application may strip prior to achieving the specified torque. Improper torque of the fastener or
                fasteners that retain the brakes to the rear axle may allow brake groups to separate from the rear axle.
                <emph type="bold">This defect could cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in
                    personal injury or property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners are being notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran Alliance dealer
                to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>Inspection of this defect requires the removal and installation of the wheel assemblies, including the
                brake drum, with air brake equipped units or the rotor with hydraulic equipped units.
                <emph type="bold">Caution!</emph>
                Refer to your truck or bus service manual for precautions and instructions to remove tires and rim
                assemblies, hubs, drums, and brakes. Make sure that all fasteners are reassembled correctly and the
                correct torque is applied per the service manual instructions. Failure to follow proper procedures for
                removal of parts could result in personal injury and/or property damage. We strongly suggest that the
                rear wheel seal be replaced any time that the bearings and hub are removed.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clearly identify each nut that secures the brakes system to the axle, making sure that
                    each one has the correct nut installed. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9930203">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9930204">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                    to identify location of subject nuts. If any of the nuts do not have the required markings of a
                    "grade 8" lock nut then it must be replaced. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9930201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9930202">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    for identification of the nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9930201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Grade 5 Lock Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This nut has three (3) markings; one each on every other hex corner. The markings consist of a dot or
                a combination of dots and a letter. This is the nut that must be replaced.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930202" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Grade 8 Lock Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This nut has six (6) markings; one on every hex corner or on the flat side of the nut. The markings
                look like dots. The nuts with the markings on the flat side will also have three triangular markings at
                the top of the nut close to the threaded opening. This style on nut is the correct part and
                <emph type="bold">does not</emph>
                need to be replaced.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930203" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Typical Air Brake</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Typical air brake assembled to the axle showing nuts involved in recall.</para>
            <figure id="f9930204" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930204.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Typical Hydraulic Brake</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Typical hydraulic brake assembled to the axle showing nuts involved in recall.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Please complete and return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card checking one of
                    the boxes, #1 through #6 that is applicable to the particular unit identified on this card.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the "grade 5" lock nut with the "grade 8" lock nut. Torque nuts to 115 - 125 lb.
                    ft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the "Campaign Identification Label" (see instructions below).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete by checking box #2 and return the owners' postage-paid "AUTHORIZATION FOR
                    RECALL SERVICE" card.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Cost of purchasing new "grade 8" lock nuts and the cost of the wheel seals should be added to the
                recall claim.
            </para>
            <table id="t9930201">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>27293R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>9/16-18 Phos/Oil NF Grade 8 Lock Nut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>As required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Variable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Wheel Seal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>As required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>We are not specifying the wheel seal part number since wheel seals vary in size for the different
                axles. Refer to your parts manual for your application or use the removed seal for reference. These nuts
                and seals should be available in your parts department.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9930202">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Retrieval and return of unit and completion of documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect units with hydraulic brakes</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.5 Hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect units with air brakes and disc wheels</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.8 Hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect units with air brakes and cast wheels</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.2 Hours</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace mounting nuts at axle flange per side</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS - AMTRAN ALLIANCE DEALERS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - OTHER AUTHORIZED REPAIR FACILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
            <para>Hours Charged:___________; Material Cost:___________________.</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
