<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99306 - AmTran FE Forward Handrail</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99306">
        <recallnumber>99306</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BUS BODY</subjectfile>
        <subject>AmTran FE Forward Handrail</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/19/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>06/14/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to AmTran FE buses built from February 19, 1999 through June 14, 1999.</para>
            <para>
                <title>DEFECT DESCRIPTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>American Transportation Corporation (AmTran) has determined that a defect relating to motor vehicle
                safety exists in some AmTran FE&#8482; buses. This defect involves the forward handrail (handrail
                mounted on the windshield side of the step well) on buses with outward opening entrance doors only.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>PROBLEM:</title>
            </para>
            <para>The forward handrail involved in this recall is mounted to the bus at three points (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930601">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930602">Figure 2</hotlnk>). There are two "U" shaped brackets mounting the handrail to
                the side of the step well near the entrance door and one flange/cup assembly mounted to the floor near
                the engine cover. Some of the units in this recall may have been built with the flange/cup assembly
                (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930603">Figure 3</hotlnk>) mounted too close to the engine cover. Certain small
                objects may be caught in this area such as coat tie strings with drawstring clips or other objects
                attached. Should this happen, and the driver does not properly observe the person exiting the bus, the
                person may exit the bus with the string caught between the engine cover and the flange/cup assembly. The
                door may be closed and the bus moved causing possible injury or death to the passenger exiting the bus.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930601" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930601.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Figure 1 was taken from behind the door opening, and looking into the door entrance. This photo shows
                the outward opening doors and the location of the handrail.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930602" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930602.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Figure 2 was taken from the first seat behind the entrance door looking down into the step well. This
                photo shows all three mounting locations of the handrail and its shape.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9930603" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9930603.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Figure 3 was taken at floor level looking toward the front of the bus. This photo shows the flange/cup
                assembly mounted to the floor adjacent to the engine cover. This is the area that the nut with string
                must be dragged to determine if the bus needs repair as stated in the INSPECTION procedure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners are being notified of this recall and have been directed to contact an AmTran FE&#8482; dealer
                to make arrangements for inspection and remedy of the defect.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>Review
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930601">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9930602">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                to make sure that the unit has the handrail involved in this recall. If the handrail in the bus does not
                match the one illustrated in Figures 1 and 2, return the "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card making
                sure that box #1 (Inspected - No corrections necessary) is checked.
            </para>
            <para>If the handrail in the bus matches the one illustrated in Figures 1 and 2, proceed with the following
                inspection procedure.
            </para>
            <para>Inspection of this defect requires dragging a 1/2" hex nut (3/4" across the flats) attached to a 36"
                long piece of 1/8" cotton string between the engine cover and the flange/cup assembly which is mounted
                to the floor (refer to Figure 3).
            </para>
            <para>If the nut passes through the opening without catching, the bus does not require repair. Please
                install the Campaign Identification Label (see instructions below), and complete and return the
                "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card making sure that box #1 (Inspected - No corrections necessary)
                is checked.
            </para>
            <para>If the nut catches between the engine cover and the flange/cup assembly, follow the following repair
                procedure.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four screws that attach the flange/cup assembly to the floor. Move the
                    flange/cup assembly by rotating the handrail to provide a minimum of one (1) inch clearance between
                    the engine cover and the tube portion of the flange/cup assembly. Drill new holes as required using
                    an 11/64 size drill. Re-install the four screws securing the flange/cup assembly to the floor. If
                    there are any exposed holes left empty from the original screw locations, install #12 x 1 1/4-inch
                    pan head zinc plated screws to fill the holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install Campaign Identification Label (see instructions below).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete and return the owners' postage-paid "AUTHORIZATION FOR RECALL SERVICE" card
                    making sure that box #2 (Corrections made) is checked.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Because the movement of the flange/cup assembly may result in unknown number of exposed holes, the
                purchase of the screws to plug the exposed holes should be added to the recall claim.
            </para>
            <table id="t9930601">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.43in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>091301600</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Screw #12 x 1 1/4-inch long pan head zinc plated</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>As required</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>With the use of battery powered or hand tools, these panels and/or guards can be installed without
                moving the units from their normal parking location. Time below is the allowable time for each
                procedure.
            </para>
            <table id="t9930602">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.95in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Completion of documentation</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspection</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Repair if required</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES (U.S. &#38; POSSESSIONS)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">RECALL CLAIMS - AMTRAN ALLIANCE DEALERS</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Policy Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Dealer Policy Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention
                should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>RECALL CLAIMS - OTHER AUTHORIZED REPAIR FACILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>To assist in processing the recall, it is important that you provide an invoice with the following
                information along with the return of the "Authorization for Recall Service" card.
            </para>
            <para>Body Serial #_______________; Vin #_______________;</para>
            <para>Recall Campaign #___________; Facilities Repair Labor rate____________;</para>
            <para>Hours Charged:___________; Parts:___________________.</para>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
