<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99501 - Tie Rod Separation on 6000 and 8000 Pound Capacity Dana Spicer Steer Axle</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99501A">
        <recallnumber>99501</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>June, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Tie Rod Separation on 6000 and 8000 Pound Capacity Dana Spicer Steer Axle</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/01/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/01/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/01/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/31/1997</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 1552, 1652, 3400, 3600, 3800, 4700, and 4900 models built from 05/01/1996
                through 10/31/1997 with a Dana Spicer 6000 or 8000 pound rated capacity steer axle.
            </para>
            <para>The tie rod ends can loosen, pull outboard or even separate from the tie rod tube due to improper
                thread surface contact between the male tie rod end and the female tube. Insufficient clamp load on the
                tube clamp nut could also be a contributing factor. A separation of the tie rod end could result in loss
                of steering control and
                <emph type="bold">cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in personal injury,
                    property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TIE ROD ASSEMBLY REPLACEMENT</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete tie rod assembly from vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure tie rod arm hole and ball stud surface is clean and free of nicks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new tie rod assembly and torque left and right ball stud nuts to 80 ft-lbs. If
                    cotter pin cannot be installed, tighten nut to the next opening on the castellated nut that will
                    permit cotter pin installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cotter pin in left and right ball stud nut and bend end of cotter pin over to
                    lock position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grease tie rod ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set front axle toe-in to 1/16 inch &#177; 1/16 inch. Toe-in should be set only by
                    trained mechanics.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SETTING TOE-IN</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If electronic equipment is used to set toe-in, the equipment must be in calibration to insure
                        an accurate toe reading.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following procedure may be used to set toe-in when electronic alignment equipment is not
                available. To obtain an accurate reading, two mechanics are required to insure that the pointers are
                always placed or adjusted to be exactly in front of the line scribed on both tires. Toe-in is the amount
                in fractions of an inch that the front wheels are closer together at the front than at the back (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950101">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f9950101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Toe-in and Toe-out</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block rear wheel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up front axle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe off excess dirt and moisture from the center of both front tire treads complete 360&#176;.
                    Use a piece of chalk or white spray paint to mark the center area of both tires around the complete
                    circumference.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a scribe or pointed instrument against the center of the whitened area of each tire
                    and rotate the tires 360&#176;. The scribe must be held in place so that a single thin straight line
                    is marked all the way around the tires.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a floating radius gauge plate under each wheel. Lower the vehicle and remove the
                    lock pins from the radius gauge plates to allow the front wheels to return to the normal operating
                    position. If full floating radius gauge plates are not available, lower the vehicle to the floor and
                    roll it forward 12 to 15 feet (3.65 to 4.57 m) to neutralize the front suspension. Neutralizing the
                    front suspension is extremely important especially if the vehicle has been jacked up to scribe the
                    tires; otherwise, the front wheels will not return to the normal operation position due to the tires
                    gripping the floor surface when the vehicle is lowered.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the sliding scale end of the trammel bar to zero (0) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9950102">Figure 2</hotlnk>) and lock the scale in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9950102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Lock Scale in Place</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SCRIBED LINE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the trammel bar at the rear of the front tires so that the sliding scale that was
                    set to zero in Step 6 is centered against the scribed line on one of the tires (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9950102">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the pointer on the end of the trammel bar opposite the sliding scale so it lines
                    up with the scribed line on the rear of the opposite front tire. Lock the pointer in place on the
                    trammel bar. Remove the trammel bar being careful not to contact either of the pointers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the trammel bar against the front of the tires so the pointer end is aligned against
                    the scribed line on the front tire. Loosen and remove the sliding scale pointer on the opposite end
                    of the trammel bar so it is also aligned against the scribed line on the opposite tire. Lock the
                    scale in place (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9950103">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9950103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Sliding Scale End Adjusted</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. POINTER END</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SLIDING SCALE END ADJUSTED TO SCRIBED LINE TO INDICATE ACTUAL TOE SETTING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read the toe-in or toe-out on the sliding scale. If toe-in is correct, it will read 1/16
                    &#177; 1/16 inch (0 - 1/8 inch toe-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If toe-in is within the specification, position and tighten tie rod clamps to 70 - 85
                    ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If toe-in adjustment is necessary, use the following procedure:</emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TOE-IN ADJUSTMENT</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the tie rod clamps that secure the tie rod ends in position in the tie rod.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the tie rod to set the toe-in.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in each direction to center the steering linkage (if the vehicle
                    has power steering, start the engine before turning wheel). Make sure the front wheels are in a
                    straight ahead position (stop engine), and re-check the toe-in setting by repeating "SETTING TOE-IN"
                    Steps 6 through 10.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat above Steps 2 and 3 until the toe-in reading is 1/16 &#177; 1/16 inch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and tighten tie rod clamps to 70 - 85 ft-lbs.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>When repositioning the tie rod clamps, check bolt clearance between the bolt and axle
                            I-beam at the maximum turn position, right and left (turn). Interference may restrict proper
                            steering linkage movement, and/or cause damage to clamp bolts.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Tie rod assemblies will be shipped direct from Dana Corporation (included with the new tie rod will be
                a shipping label for returned parts). Tie rods should be ordered from Dana Corporation using the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950104">fax form</hotlnk>. The fax form should be reproduced locally.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9950104" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950104a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Fax Form</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>REMOVED PARTS DISPOSITION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Return all removed tie rods to Dana Corporation. To avoid any shipping charges, be sure to use the
                shipping label provided with each new tie rod. Please write the vehicle's VIN number on each shipping
                label. If you have questions regarding shipping parts to Dana Corporation, call 405-671-8350.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>HANDLING ALLOWANCE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Since the tie rods are being direct shipped from the supplier on a "no charge" basis, a $40 handling
                allowance will automatically be credited to Dealer accounts for each Warranty Claim processing Safety
                Recall 99501. No outside charges should be on Warranty Claims for this allowance.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9950101" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0">
                                <para>A40-99501-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1">
                                <para>Replace tie rod assembly and set toe-in</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                                <para>0.8 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-99501-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Additional time for Low Profile models</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
