<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99505 - 9000 Conventional and Cabover Series</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99505">
        <recallnumber>99505</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>9000 Conventional and Cabover Series</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/01/1996</startdate>
                        <enddate>05/31/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>FF-982</vendcode>
                <vendcode>FF-987</vendcode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 9000 Conventional and Cabover Series that have FF-982 or FF-987 non-driving
                front axles in vehicles built from 01/01/1996 through 05/31/1998.
            </para>
            <para>The front disc wheel hub flange could experience fatigue cracking under normal operating conditions.
                This defect could result in wheel separation that could cause a vehicular accident without warning that
                could result in personal injury and / or property damage, or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. During the recall process, a listing
                of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up
                with owners to have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign
                since the list may contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the
                use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law
                in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="6">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE FOR REPLACING THE FRONT AXLE HUBS</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">This issue relates to the new unitized hub and bearing assembly with no
                        serviceable parts (bearings that are lubricated for life) referred to as a truck hub unit. All
                        removed wheel hub units must be returned along with warranty claim number and VIN identification
                        number. Follow the instructions in the hub and stud assembly kit. Use the shipping labels and
                        fill out the warranty claims and VIN number information. All vehicles in this recall must have
                        both wheel hubs replaced. No recall cards should be returned to Navistar with the number one box
                        checked.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The procedure below begins with the wheels already off and starts with steps to remove the
                            wheel hub. If instructions are needed at any point in this repair procedure, refer to the
                            CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. Follow all standard safety precautions and procedures
                            recommended by the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removing The Wheel Hub Unit From The Steering Knuckle Procedure</title>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When the threaded protective cap is removed or tightened, use a size 3-1/2 inch socket to
                            avoid damaging the unit.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the threaded protective cap from the hub by turning it in a counter-clockwise
                        direction.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Bend back the outer "D" lock washer tab away from the flat edge of the outer wheel
                        bearing nut. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950501">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950501" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Bend Back Outer "D" Lock Washer Tab</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the outer wheel bearing nut and the outer washer from the axle spindle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Use a torque multiplier or 24-inch breaker bar to remove inner wheel bearing nut and
                        inner washer from the spindle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Discard removed hub cap, both washers and nuts.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When removing the wheel hub unit from knuckle spindle, take care not to misalign or wedge
                            wheel hub unit into the spindle threads to prevent the wheel hub unit from becoming jammed
                            or wedged onto the spindle.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove wheel hub unit carefully. Draw hub assembly straight away from spindle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the wheel hub unit is difficult to remove from the spindle, continue with the following
                            procedures.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Procedure For Using A 17.5 Ton Cross Block Puller Tool To Remove The Wheel Hub Unit From The
                    Spindle
                </title>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Use a brass or leather mallet for removal and disassembly procedures. Do not hit steel
                            parts with a steel hammer. Pieces can break off and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a brass hammer, drive out two studs from opposite sides of the wheel hub unit
                        to provide access for two Grade 8 bolts used with the cross block puller.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Assemble the cross block puller with two 8" x 7/8" Grade 8 bolts onto the face of
                        the wheel hub unit assembly. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950502">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950502" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Assemble Cross Block Puller</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the inner wheel bearing nut just until it is flush with the end of the
                        spindle. Once the hub is loose and is sliding off, remove the nut.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>You must follow these notes:</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Always use the shortest legs possible for an application to reduce the chance of
                                    tool or equipment damage.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Apply force gradually. The part should "give" a little at a time. Do not try to
                                    speed the operation by using an impact wrench on the forcing screw.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If maximum force has been applied, and the part has not moved, use a tool with a
                                    larger capacity. Do not hit the part with a hammer in an attempt to jar it loose.
                                    Hitting the part with the hammer could result in damage to components.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the forcing nut and washer against the cross block to apply force to the
                        tool and separate the wheel hub unit from the knuckle spindle. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950503">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950503" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Tighten Forcing Nut and Washer</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Repeat this procedure to remove the wheel hub unit on the opposite side of axle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installing The Replacement Wheel Hub Units Onto The Axle Spindle</title>
                <para>Two different kits are provided for different wheel hub unit replacement.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Two kits are required to completely service one axle.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <table id="t9950501">
                    <title>Kit Part Numbers</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.99in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.01in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.03in"/>
                        <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">GAWR Easy Steer Plus</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Long Wheel Stud Kit #</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Short Wheel Stud Kit #</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                    <para>13,200 Lb.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                    <para>P/N Kit 1447</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                    <para>P/N Kit 1448</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                    <para>Long Wheel Studs are only on aluminum wheels. Long Wheel Studs measure
                                        approximately 2.9" from the outboard face of the flange to the end of the stud.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                    <para>Short Wheel Studs are only on steel wheels. Short Wheel Studs measure
                                        approximately 2.5" from the outboard face of the flange to the end of the stud.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the knuckle spindle for scratches, nicks or marks. Minor surface damage may be
                        repaired using a crocus or emery cloth. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950504">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950504" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Minor Surface Damage May Be Repaired</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean knuckle spindle with a clean dry rag.
                        <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                        apply any solvent.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate the inside bore of the replacement hub and the entire axle spindle with
                        NLGI #1 or #2 grease.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Take care to align unit carefully. Install the new hub unit straight onto spindle. Do not
                            allow the hub unit to misalign and wedge onto spindle threads. Bearing damage could occur.
                            If the wheel hub unit does not slide on easily, do not force it on the spindle. The wheel
                            hub unit can become jammed on the spindle if care is not taken to align it properly with the
                            spindle. If the wheel hub unit becomes jammed on the spindle, carefully remove the wheel hub
                            unit from the spindle so as not to disassemble or loosen the inner bearings from the wheel
                            hub unit and repeat procedures.
                        </para>
                        <para>Disassembly of the wheel hub unit could contaminate the lubricant and will void the
                            manufacturer's warranty. Disassembled hub units cannot be used and require replacement.
                        </para>
                        <para>Check the bore of the wheel hub unit for any obstructions and check the spindle for any
                            nicks or burrs.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully align the new wheel hub unit bore with the spindle and then slide the hub
                        straight onto the spindle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>The inner wheel bearing nut and outer wheel bearing nut torque values are unique to the
                            wheel hub unit. Failure to follow the specified torque may result in possible component
                            damage, wheel separation and serious personal injury and / or property damage, or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The inner wheel bearing nut and the outer wheel bearing nut are identical but torque
                            values are different.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new thick inner washer and the new wheel bearing nut onto the spindle
                        threads. Tighten the inner wheel bearing nut onto spindle 500 to 700 ft-lbs. (678-949 Nm) while
                        rotating the hub in both directions. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950505">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950505" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950505.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Tighten Inner Wheel Bearing Nut</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">For ABS equipped axles, check that the original ABS sensor has not moved from the
                        sensor holder. Check the sensor wiring to the chassis wiring. Refer to the CTS-5000 Master
                        Service Manual for sensor adjustments.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the new tabbed washer onto the spindle threads.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the new outer wheel bearing nut onto the spindle threads. Tighten the outer
                        wheel bearing nut from 200 to 300 ft-lbs. (271-406 Nm) torque.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Bend tabs of the new outer replacement tabbed washer over the flats of the outer
                        wheel bearing nut and the inner wheel bearing nut. Bend washer tabs onto at least one flat edge
                        to each nut. Use care to ensure that tool used to bend tabs does not slip past tabs and damage
                        the spindle hub threads.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply the spindle warning label provided in the kit to the spindle end before
                        installing the hub cap. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950506">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9950506" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950506.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                    <caption>Spindle Warning Label</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply a light coating of NLGI #1 or #2 grease to the axle spindle nuts to protect
                        against corrosion.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the new hub cap from the kit into the hub threads. Tighten from 200 to 250
                        ft-lbs. (271-339 Nm).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the brake drum and the tire-wheel assembly. Refer to the International
                        Service Manual CTS-5017K for instructions and torque specifications and tightening sequence.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">All replaced wheel hub units must be returned along with warranty claim and VIN
                        numbers, according to the instructions packaged with the replacement kits. Shipping details and
                        labels are also included.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>For additional information on other techniques to service, or for complete maintenance procedures
                    on the Easy Steer Plus Axle Series, call 800-535-5560 or 888-725-9355.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Follow the instructions included with the Hub Kits and return all hubs.</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="t9950502">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="9">
                                <para>KIT 1447</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>13,200 Lb. GAWR Long Wheel Stud Kit. 1 Kit contains:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2 Kits</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub and Stud Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Cap</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inner Washer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Wheel Nuts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Tabbed Washer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Technical Bulletin</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Return Address Label</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Return Instruction</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spindle End Warning Label</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="9">
                                <para>KIT 1448</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>13,200 Lb. GAWR Short Wheel Stud Kit. 1 Kit contains:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2 Kits</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub and Stud Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Cap</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inner Washer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Wheel Nuts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Tabbed Washer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Technical Bulletin</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Return Address Label</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Hub Return Instruction</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spindle End Warning Label</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9950503">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99505-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace both front wheel hubs</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.7 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
