<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99503 - Inner Wheel Bearings on 16,000, 18,000, 20,000, or 22,000 Pound Steer Axles</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99503a">
        <recallnumber>99503</recallnumber>
        <revision>SECOND Notice</revision>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>February, 2001</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Inner Wheel Bearings on 16,000, 18,000, 20,000, or 22,000 Pound Steer Axles</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/16/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">REASON FOR THIS SECOND NOTICE:</emph>
                International Truck and Engine Corporation has issued this SECOND Notice to customers and dealers to
                improve completion rates for this campaign. Customers that have not had their vehicle repaired for this
                Safety Recall as of January 2001 will be receiving a notification letter in February 2001. Please refer
                to service letter G-99503 dated April 1999, for Parts, Labor, Warranty and detailed information
                regarding this recall.
            </para>
            <para>This Recall applies to 2500, 2600, 4700, 4900, 5000, 8100, 9200, 9300, and 9400 models built from
                03/01/1998 through 10/16/1998 with 16,000, 18,000, 20,000 or 22,000 pound rated capacity steer axles.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">THINGS YOU SHOULD DO</emph>
            </para>
            <para>All dealers can help improve the completion rates for Safety Recalls and Authorized Field Changes by
                following the guidelines below.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Check every vehicle that comes in for service for uncompleted Safety Recalls and Authorized
                        Field Changes.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Make arrangements to have uncompleted Safety Recalls and Authorized Field changes performed
                        before the vehicle leaves your facility.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the owner's mailing address and phone number and make all necessary updates to your
                        records before the customer leaves your facility.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Selling Dealers are to contact their customers who have not had required Safety Recalls
                        performed on their vehicles and track completion rates by using the green bar reports (VIN list)
                        provided with each campaign.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>The inner wheel bearing cone on the front steer axle may not seat properly against the wheel seal
                flange of the steering knuckle. An improper fit increases the stress level on the knuckle spindle, and
                over a long period of time could cause a fatigue failure of the spindle. A failure of the front steer
                axle spindle could result in loss of steering control and
                <emph type="bold">cause a vehicular accident without warning which could result in personal injury,
                    property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Improper seating of the bearing may also cause the bearing to move, resulting in excessive bearing
                endplay, which could result in premature bearing wear.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have
                the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Etched 120 degrees apart on the face of the inner wheel bearing cone is the manufacturer name,
                        part number 6461A, and the manufacturing date code. The wheel bearings that
                        <emph type="bold">may not</emph>
                        fit the spindle properly are identified with date codes C N 7, D N 7, E N 7, F N 7, H N 7, and J
                        N 7. Any bearings purchased in the after market should be checked for the above codes. Bearings
                        with these codes should not be used.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Reference CTS-5136S for removal and replacement of wheel bearings and wheel seals.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950301">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9950301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Examples of Bearing Not Seated and Bearing Seated</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front steer axle left and right hub and tire as an assembly. It may be necessary
                    to use a gear puller to assist removal (gear puller cap screws should be installed in hub cap
                    holes).
                    <emph type="bold">After removing hub and tire assembly, if inboard bearing is seized to spindle with
                        oil seal, proceed to Steps 2 through 9</emph>. If bearing and seal come off with hub, proceed to
                    Step 11.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use two crow foot pry bars to remove the seized bearing from the spindle. Be careful not
                    to damage the spindle with the pry bars. Discard removed bearing and wheel seal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean spindle including seal running surface with cleaning solvent on a cloth.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine spindle for signs of unusual wear under the inner bearing at the radius point of
                    contact. Use emery cloth to sand any imperfections observed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect inboard bearing cup in hub for signs of damage or unusual wear. If any signs of
                    abnormal wear or damage are observed, remove and replace inner bearing cup.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount
                    <emph type="bold">new</emph>
                    inboard bearing cone assembly onto the spindle and insure bearing seats against spindle shoulder
                    (wheel seal flange) without any gap. (Coating the bearing and spindle with oil will make it easier
                    to slide bearing on spindle.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bearing from spindle and insert into hub. If bearings are grease lubricated, pack
                    the bearing with wheel bearing grease before inserting into hub.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all grease or oil from brake drum and lining.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount hub and tire assembly to spindle. Be sure wheel cavity lube is replenished and
                    bearing endplay is set to specified tolerance referencing CTS-5136S Service Manual Section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Steps 11 through 21 are to be used if the inboard bearing cone and wheel seal come off
                    with the hub and tire assembly.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean spindle including seal running surface with cleaning solvent on a cloth.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine spindle for signs of unusual wear under the inner bearing at the radius point of
                    contact. Use emery cloth to sand any imperfections observed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil seal from hub and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and clean inboard bearing cone assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the original inboard bearing cone assembly onto the spindle and insure bearing
                    seats against spindle shoulder (wheel seal flange) without any gap. (Coating the bearing and spindle
                    with oil will make it easier to slide bearing on spindle.) If the bearing cone seats properly
                    without any gap, skip to Item 18. If the original bearing cone does not seat properly, remove and
                    discard it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect inboard bearing cup in hub for signs of damage or unusual wear. If any signs of
                    abnormal wear or damage are observed, remove and replace inner bearing cup.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount
                    <emph type="bold">new</emph>
                    inboard bearing cone assembly onto the spindle and insure bearing seats against spindle shoulder
                    without any gap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bearing from spindle and insert into hub. If bearings are grease lubricated, pack
                    the bearing with wheel bearing grease before inserting into hub.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install
                    <emph type="bold">new</emph>
                    wheel seal into hub.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all grease or oil from brake drum and lining.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount hub and tire assembly to spindle. Be sure wheel cavity lube is replenished and
                    bearing endplay is set to specified tolerance, referencing CTS-5136S Service Manual Section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">All removed parts should be destroyed locally.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9950301" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>250704C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Wheel Bearing Cone, Front Inner</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>794408C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Wheel Seal (Standard)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>388249C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gasket, Hub Cap</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Per Lineset Code 29XXX</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Wheel Seal (Optional)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9950302" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A40-99503-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove and install two wheel bearings, two wheel seals and two hub cap gaskets
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2.0 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
