<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99502 - Windshield Wiper Linkage on 5000 and 9000 Series</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99502">
        <recallnumber>99502</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>May, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subject>Windshield Wiper Linkage on 5000 and 9000 Series</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/26/1998</startdate>
                        <enddate>12/15/1998</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The knurled pivot shaft (which operates the windshield wiper arm) is welded to a lever, which connects
                to linkage from the wiper motor. The weld at the pivot shaft to lever may fail. This failure can occur
                on either the right or left side causing the wiper arm to be inoperative for that side. Should one side
                fail, the other side would still be operational. Should a failure occur during inclement weather on the
                driver's side with the vehicle in motion, the operator's vision would be partially obscured which could,
                under certain circumstances,
                <emph type="bold">cause a vehicular accident, resulting in personal injury, property damage, or both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. A listing of owner names and addresses
                has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>STALL TEST</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT PERFORM THE FOLLOWING STALL TEST ON A CUSTOMER'S VEHICLE UNLESS YOU HAVE 2 KITS IN
                        STOCK (PART NUMBER 8900067R91). REPAIR PARTS MUST BE ON HAND TO REPAIR THE VEHICLE SHOULD A PART
                        FAIL DURING THE STALL TEST.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This is a test to cause failure of weak
                <emph type="bold">suspect welds. Do not restrain both arms at the same time. Follow the instructions
                    below.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Restrain the
                    <emph type="bold">left wiper arm</emph>
                    at the point of wiper blade attachment.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not restrain the wiper blade assembly.</emph>
                    Operate the wiper switch for 5 seconds in the
                    <emph type="bold">low speed position</emph>
                    and then return the switch to the off position.
                    <emph type="bold">Remove the wiper arm restraint.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat step one above on the right side.
                    <emph type="bold">Perform the test one side at a time.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cycle the wipers on low for 5 seconds and then on high for 5 seconds. Should one or both
                    of the wiper arms not cycle properly, follow the replacement procedure below for the defective
                    side(s).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPLACEMENT OF LINKAGE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A repair kit should be installed
                        <emph type="bold">ONLY IF</emph>
                        a wiper arm fails the stall test. A failed test results in an inoperative wiper arm due to a
                        broken weld at the pivot shaft.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock the wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wiper arm from the knurled pivot shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove 4 screws from the pivot shaft housing and dislodge it from the cowl. Retain the
                    screws for the new pivot shaft housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the wiper motor linkage arm to keep it from falling into the cowl.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the e-clip and washer securing the wiper motor linkage to the lever connected to
                    the pivot shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the washer hose and remove the pivot shaft, housing, and gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the washer hose to the new pivot shaft housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the washer and e-clip securing the wiper motor linkage to the lever connected to
                    the pivot shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the pivot housing in position with the new gasket in place and secure it with 4
                    screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and install the wiper arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the procedure for the opposite side
                    <emph type="bold">ONLY IF</emph>
                    both arms fail the stall test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cycle the wipers and adjust the wipe pattern if required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Destroy the defective parts locally.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Since less than 30% of the vehicles are expected to need one part kit, do not order
                <emph type="bold">a kit</emph>
                for more than 30% of your total number of vehicles involved.
            </para>
            <table id="t9950201">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.74in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.34in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>8900067R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Kit, Wiper Pivot Housing/Lever (Kit includes pivot housing/lever, gasket, washer
                                    and e-clip)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9950202">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.74in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.74in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99502-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Perform Stall Test Only on both wiper arms.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" charoff="50" char="">
                                <para>A40-99502-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" charoff="50" char="">
                                <para>Perform Stall Test and replace one Pivot Housing Assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>0.7 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" charoff="50" char="">
                                <para>A40-99502-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" charoff="50" char="">
                                <para>Perform Stall Test and replace two Pivot Housing Assemblies.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>1.0 Hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <title>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
                </title>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair their vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
