<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99504 - Meritor Brake Automatic Slack Adjusters</stitle>
    <recall id="rec99504">
        <recallnumber>99504</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>April, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Meritor Brake Automatic Slack Adjusters</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04753</ucode>
                <ucode>04LAB</ucode>
                <ucode>504302</ucode>
                <ucode>504306</ucode>
                <ucode>04754</ucode>
                <ucode>504355</ucode>
                <ucode>804MAG</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>This Recall applies to 2500, 2600, 3800, 4700, 4800, 4900, 5000, 8100, 9100, 9200, 9400, 9800, 9900,
                and FE Bus models built from 01/11/1999 through 01/20/1999.
            </para>
            <para>Certain automatic slack adjusters on the front and rear brakes may have insufficient torque applied to
                the guide pawl cap screw. The front brake codes involved are 04753, 04LAB, 504302, and 504306. The rear
                codes involved are 04754, 504355, and 804MAG.
            </para>
            <para>Without sufficient torque on the guide pawl cap screw, the brakes may gradually lose adjustment.
                Without the automatic adjustment, the brakes will lose adjustment until they eventually become
                ineffective. Under certain conditions, an ineffective brake may increase the vehicle stopping distance.
                Should this happen,
                <emph type="bold">it could result in a vehicle accident causing personal injury, property damage, or
                    both.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Owners will be notified of this campaign on their vehicles by Navistar. A listing of owner names and
                addresses will have been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to
                have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may
                contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor
                vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off engine and chock rear wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check torque on all brake slack adjuster guide pawl cap screws. If the torque reads less
                    than the required 15-20 ft-lbs., adjust the brake and tighten the guide pawl cap screw to 15-20
                    ft-lbs. Reference
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9950401">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9950401" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Guide Pawl Positions</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove chocks from rear wheels.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <table id="t9950401" frame="all">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-99504-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>4x2 Model - Check torque on guide pawl cap screws and adjust brakes as required
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>A40-99504-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>6x4 Model - Check torque on guide pawl cap screws and adjust brakes as required
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.6 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified from your dealer location. Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no
                charge to the owner, regardless of mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired within 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty
                claim. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should
                be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
