<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99507 - Hydraulic Park Brake Hoses on 4700 Models</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99507">
        <recallnumber>99507</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>October, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Hydraulic Park Brake Hoses on 4700 Models</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/02/1997</startdate>
                        <enddate>09/03/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04GAG</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The park brake hand control valve hydraulic hoses may leak at any time without warning under normal
                driving conditions. Improper hose routing may induce hose rupturing due to chafing, scraping, or
                rubbing. The park brake will automatically apply if pressure is lost due to a ruptured park brake hose
                and could cause a vehicular accident, resulting in possibly one or more of the following: property
                damage, personal injury, or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. A listing of owner names and addresses
                has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="7">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service repair, please read and understand the following
                    instructions completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent eye injury, always wear safe eye protection.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">This service procedure includes:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>1. Inspecting all park brake hoses for chafing.</para>
            <para>2. Replacing any damaged park brake hoses found during the inspection.</para>
            <para>3. Re-routing the hoses at the park brake hand control valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>4. Installing a hose routing kit (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">INSPECT ALL PARK BRAKE HOSES FOR CHAFING. Follow all park brake hoses from the hand
                    control valve down to the transmission looking for spots on the hoses that may be chaffed and may
                    lead to a rupture.
                </para>
                <para>Chafing is most likely to be caused by one of the following conditions.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Fender well rubbing hoses as the hood is raised or lowered.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The corner of the cab sled runner mounted stand-off bracket cutting into hoses (see
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9950702">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fender well edge cutting hoses as hood vibrates in the closed position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Hoses rubbing on shock absorber stud and upper shock mount.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the park brake hoses that were damaged from chafing.</para>
                <para>The most common hose to be damaged is the supply port hose (the most inboard hose) because it is
                    furthest forward at the valve and is most likely to be scraped by the fender well. Part numbers for
                    the supply port hose are provided in the Parts section of this letter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-route the hoses at the park brake hand control valve from the vertical routing to a
                    horizontal routing (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the hand control valve.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Loosen but do not remove the three hoses at the hand control valve.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the cotter pin at the end of the control cable.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the two screws holding the valve to the bracket.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Completely remove the three hoses at the valve.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Re-clock the fittings on the hand control valve (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Gently secure the valve in a brass jawed vise to allow access to the three fittings.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Note: The valve ports are labeled on the valve body: exhaust, delivery, and supply. Remove
                            the 90 degree fitting in the supply port (most inboard fitting) and replace it with the
                            straight fitting from kit # 8900068R91. Apply some pipe sealant to the threads of the
                            fitting before installing it (see
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Remove the 90 degree exhaust port fitting from the valve (most outboard fitting). This
                            fitting is the one that has the push on hose with a hose clamp.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Rotate the 90 degree delivery port fitting approximately 270 degrees clockwise
                            (tightening) so that it directs the hose in the same direction as the straight fitting that
                            you installed in the supply port (step 3.B.2. above). If the fitting cannot be tightened
                            enough to allow the hose to be directed in the same direction as the supply port then remove
                            the fitting and re-install it with some pipe sealant on the threads to obtain the desired
                            fitting direction.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Re-install the exhaust port fitting, with pipe sealant, to direct the hose in the same
                            horizontal direction as the supply and delivery ports (see
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Re-install the valve on the mounting bracket.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Do not install the hoses at the valve until instructed below.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the hose routing kit.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the p-clamp and stand-off bracket that holds the hoses to the cab sled
                        runner. Set these parts aside. The p-clamp, bolt, and washer will be reused on vehicles with I-6
                        engines but these parts will not be used for V-8 engines.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Untangle the three hoses that go to the valve to improve the hose routing.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Be sure the blue hose that goes to the brake booster is routed behind the three
                        hoses that go to the valve. This will prevent the blue hose from contacting the moving
                        hood/fender well parts (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect and tighten the supply hose to the valve.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect and tighten the delivery hose to the valve (the middle port).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Route the exhaust hose from the power steering reservoir so that it lays on top of
                        the other hoses going to the valve (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950703">Figure 3</hotlnk>). Reconnect and tighten the hose to the valve with
                        the hose clamp.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use one of the three new p-clamps from the hose routing kit and put the p-clamp
                        around the hoses at the cab sled runner (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Mount p-clamp to sled runner with the self tapping
                        screw from the kit (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950704">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                        for screw hole location).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install a tie-strap around the hoses between the valve and the p-clamp (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the engine ground bolt at the frame rail then install the extension clip in
                        a vertical position, without the p-clamps, on the engine ground bolt by using the nut and lock
                        washer from the kit (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950705">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950707">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the p-clamps around the hoses and bolt the p-clamps to the extension clip
                        (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950705">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950706">Figure 6</hotlnk>). Route the hoses along the frame rail through the
                        lower p-clamp. Route the supply port hose, the delivery hose, and the blue hose through the
                        upper p-clamp on the extension clip (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950705">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950706">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950706">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                        shows the proper orientation of the p-clamps to the extension clip with the bolt coming up from
                        the bottom, then through the lower p-clamp, then through the extension clip, then through the
                        upper p-clamp. The lock washer and nut should be on top.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install a tie-strap around all the hoses directly above the shock absorber stud (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950703">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">For V-8 engines: Slide under the vehicle and check all hoses along the side of the
                        transmission for chafing points. Install tie straps as necessary to avoid chafing of hoses.
                        <emph type="bold">Note: V-8 model repairs are complete after step L is performed. The following
                            additional steps are specifically for I-6 engines.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using the 1/4 inch bolt, washer, and p-clamp that was removed from the stand-off
                        bracket, install the p-clamp to the bracket just above the left engine mount (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950707">Figure 7</hotlnk>). This bracket has a hole in it with a weld nut for
                        the 1/4 inch bolt. One of the hoses might not fit in this p-clamp. If one of the hoses does not
                        fit, then tie strap it to the hoses that are routed through the p-clamp.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install tie straps around the hoses, one about 8 inches forward of the p-clamp
                        installed in step M and one about 10 inches rearward of the p-clamp (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9950707">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the hoses at the side of the engine and transmission for chafing points.
                        Install tie straps as necessary to avoid chafing of hoses.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fill power steering fluid reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Start engine and apply and release park brake a few times. Be sure the power
                        steering reservoir does not run dry.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check all hose and fitting connections for leaks.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check park brake for proper operation.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Top off power steering reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9950701" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Re-Routing Park Brake Hoses at the Hand Control Valve to Horizontal Routing</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950702" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Corner of Sled Runner Mounted Stand-Off Bracket Cutting into Hoses</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950703" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950703.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Hose Routing Above the Shock Absorber</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950704" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950704.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>P-Clamp Mounting Location on the Cab Sled Runner</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950705" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950705.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Extension Clip Mounted on Engine Ground Bolt</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950706" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950706.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>P-Clamp Orientation and Assembly on Extension Clip</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9950707" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950707.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>P-Clamp Added to Bracket on I-6 Engines</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SUPPLY PORT HOSE</emph>: Replace hose only if damaged from chafing.
            </para>
            <table id="t9950701">
                <title>Part Application</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.05in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.95in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Application</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>3516355C2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4700 4x2 and 4700 LP Models with V-8 Engines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>3516356C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4700 4x2 and 4700 LP Models with I-6 Engines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>3516357C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4700 LPX Models with V-8 Engines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="t9950702">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>289862C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Strap Lock</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>528182C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Extension, Clip</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>299275C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>P-Clamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>25483R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1/4-20 UNC x 1.0 PHC Grade 8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>25519R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Nut, Hex 1/4-20 UNC, PHC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>120380</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Washer, Lock, 1/4 Regular stl-zn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>24200R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Screw, Self Tapping, Hex Head 1/4-14 x 3/4 Type AB</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>433972C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Nut, Special, Hex Head 3/8-16 UNC Ground Application</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>120382</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Washer, Lock 3/8 ZP</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>610082C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Straight Fitting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Every vehicle in this recall must have labor operation one or two performed and some may have labor
                operation three performed.
            </para>
            <table id="t9950703">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99507-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect hoses and install hose routing kit for
                                    <emph type="bold">V-8 engines</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.6 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99507-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect hoses and install hose routing kit for
                                    <emph type="bold">I-6 engines</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.7 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99507-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace one chafed hydraulic park brake hose, 0.3 hour/ hose.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hr./hose</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired with 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair their vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
