<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99506 - Lower Steering Shafts on 9000i Models</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99506">
        <recallnumber>99506</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>August, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subject>Lower Steering Shafts on 9000i Models</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/22/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>The steering could fail at any time without warning under normal driving conditions. The potential for
                failure is due to a mis-located weld on the lower steering shaft. If the vehicle has a defective
                steering shaft, the result could be a complete loss of steering control causing an accident resulting in
                property damage and personal injury, or death.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. During the recall process, a listing
                of owner names and addresses will be furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up
                with owners to have the vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign
                since the list may contain information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the
                use of such motor vehicle registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law
                in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE FOR REPLACING THE LOWER STEERING SHAFT</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions
                    completely.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If the shaft has already been inspected or replaced, it will be marked with a blue paint spot. The
                blue paint spots were applied to the round tube section of the steering shaft and could be located on
                the engine compartment side or on the inside of the cab.
            </para>
            <para>All removed steering shafts must be returned along with warranty claim number and VIN identification
                number.
            </para>
            <para>Follow the instructions in the steering shaft assembly kit. Use the shipping label for returning parts
                and complete the warranty claim and VIN number information.
            </para>
            <para>All vehicles in this recall must have the steering shaft replaced if the shaft is not marked with the
                blue paint spot on the round section of the steering shaft.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety stands.
                        Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over resulting in
                        serious personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If further instructions are needed at any point in this repair procedure, refer to the
                        CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. Follow all standard safety precautions and procedures
                        recommended by the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position steering wheel to provide access to steering yoke pinch bolt at bottom of
                    steering column.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off engine, apply brakes, and chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove plastic tie straps at cowl boot bushings, both inside and outside the cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note on some models the outside bushing hole is vertically offset. Please note position
                    and re-install in the same position. Pull both plastic bushings out of the boot and remove from
                    shaft by separating the two pieces of the bushing. Becareful not to damage the bushings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the yoke pinch bolt at the lower end of the shaft (at steering gear).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the yoke pinch bolt at the upper end of the shaft (at bottom of steering
                    column).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip both end yokes off the splined shafts and compress the steering shaft. Carefully
                    slide the shaft thorugh the cowl boot from the inside out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip the new shaft back through the boot from outside the cab. Be careful not to damage
                    the boot during installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the yoke on the steering gear shaft. Torque pinch bolt to
                    <emph type="bold">60 ft-lbs. or 81 Nm</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the yoke on the steering column shaft and torque pinch bolt to
                    <emph type="bold">60 ft-lbs. or 81 Nm</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install upper and lower plastic bushings and slip in position inside boot.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new plastic tie straps around the boot at both bushings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removed shaft must be returned to Douglas Autotech using the shipping label.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>If you have questions regarding this service procedure or require further information, please contact
                Douglas Autotech by calling 1-800-773-1440.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>PARTS INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>FOLLOW THE INSTRUCTIONS INCLUDED WITH THE STEERING SHAFT KITS AND RETURN ALL SHAFTS.</para>
            <para>See the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9950601">parts order fax form</hotlnk>
                for: specific part numbers by model, fax number, and the phone number to call to check on your orders.
                Each steering shaft will be shipped with two replacement tie straps, complete replacement instructions,
                and a return shipping label.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9950601" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9950601.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <caption>Parts Order Fax Form</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The address on the return shipping label is:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Douglas Autotech Corporation</line>
                <line>558 Mill Street</line>
                <line>Bronson, MI 49028</line>
                <line>RE: Navistar CRA# 100859</line>
            </verbatim>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>A $30.00 handling allowance will be
                <emph type="bold">automatically added</emph>
                to all dealer claims submitted for this recall. Please do not request the $30.00 handling allowance.
            </para>
            <table id="t9950601">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99506-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace lower steering shaft.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.6 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified
                <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>
                from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired with 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair his or her vehicle as soon as
                possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
