<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99513 - Air Brake S-cam Interference on Front Drive Axles (02064) and Installed on 4800 and 4900
        Models
    </stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99513">
        <recallnumber>99513</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Air Brake S-cam Interference on Front Drive Axles (02064) and Installed on 4800 and 4900 Models
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/04/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/11/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/04/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/11/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>02064</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>There is interference between the air brake s-cam on Dana front drive axles (Navistar code 02064) on
                vehicles built 5/4/94 through 8/11/99. As the brake shoe lining wears, the s-cam rotation may be limited
                by the interfering knuckle stud. If the s-cam cannot rotate through its full range of motion, the
                braking force cannot be fully transmitted from the brake shoe linings to the brake drums.
                <emph type="bold">This interference condition may, without warning and under normal driving conditions,
                    result in a longer stopping distance or a dragging brake condition. An increased stopping distance
                    or a dragging brake could cause a vehicular accident, resulting in possible property damage,
                    personal injury, or death.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. A listing of owner names and addresses
                has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Before performing the service, please read and understand the following
                        instructions completely.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent serious eye injury, ALWAYS wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                            maintenance or service.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety
                            stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over
                            resulting in serious personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Please read the following steps carefully before proceeding.</para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Park unit on level ground, apply parking brake, and block rear tires.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Jack up front axle and set firmly on safety stands.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the eight-drive flange retaining lock nuts from the left front wheel.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the drive flange and shims from hub (keep shims with drive-flange).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Straighten locking tab on wheel bearing retaining nut lock washer.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove outer wheel bearing retaining nut.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove locking washer.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove inner wheel bearing retaining nut.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the thrust washer, outer wheel bearing, and wheel and hub assembly.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Grinding Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cover the spindle with a wet rag to protect it during grinding of stud end.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Locate the spindle-mounting stud closest to the brake S-Cam. Using a small grinder
                        with a small abrasive pad or cut-off disk, grind down or cut off the stud end until there is
                        approximately zero to one thread extending beyond the lock nut. Be careful not to nick any parts
                        with the grinding disc and don't grind into the lock nut (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9951301">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        below).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9951301" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Actuate the brakes to assure there is adequate clearance between the brake S-Cam and
                        the spindle stud as the S-Cam passes over the stud. If the brake S-Cam travel isn't far enough
                        to determine the clearance, the slack adjuster may need to be adjusted until the S-Cam passes
                        over the stud to verify proper clearance.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean spindle of all debris and apply a light coat of oil to seal diameter area of
                        spindle.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Assembly Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace wheel seal in hub.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install wheel and hub back on the spindle.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install outer wheel bearing, bearing thrust washer and wheel bearing inner retaining
                        nut.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Adjust wheel bearings. See CTS-5000 Service Manual for proper wheel bearing
                        adjusting procedure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install wheel bearing retaining nut-locking washer.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install outer wheel bearing retaining nut and bend locking washer tabs over both the
                        inner and outer nuts to hold them in position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install original drive flange shims and drive flange. Torque drive flange lock nuts
                        to 64 - 70 ft. lbs. 85 - 93 N.m.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Perform the same repair to the spindle stud on the right front wheel.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check front brake adjustment and adjust if necessary. See the CTS-5000 Service
                        Manual for proper brake adjustment procedure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Two replacement wheel seals (PN: 402856R91) are required for this repair.</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9951301">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99513-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Pull front hubs/ wheels, cut off knuckle studs, replace wheel seals</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.4 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified IMMEDIATELY from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired with 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair their vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
