<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99512 - Quality Connect Check Valves in the Primary and Secondary Air Tanks on 9000i Models Built
        06/21/99 through 07/20/99
    </stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99512">
        <recallnumber>99512</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>December, 1999</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Quality Connect Check Valves in the Primary and Secondary Air Tanks on 9000i Models Built 06/21/99
            through 07/20/99
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/21/1999</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/1999</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard 121 requires the air brake system pressure increase from 85 psi
                to 100 psi within 27 seconds based on the reservoir capacity for these models. The check valves on these
                vehicles are defective because they do not comply with FMVSS 121.
                <emph type="bold">This noncompliance could potentially affect the vehicle's braking ability and should
                    be corrected in accordance with this letter.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>OWNER NOTIFICATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Navistar will notify owners of this campaign on their vehicles. A listing of owner names and addresses
                has been furnished to the involved dealers to enable dealers to follow up with owners to have the
                vehicles corrected. You must limit the use of this listing to this campaign since the list may contain
                information obtained from state motor vehicle registration records and the use of such motor vehicle
                registration data for purposes other than this campaign is a violation of law in several states.
            </para>
        </defect>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="6">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Before performing the service, please read and understand the following instructions completely.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, ALWAYS wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support the vehicle with safety stands.
                        Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over resulting in
                        serious personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Please read the following steps carefully before proceeding.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This recall applies to the plastic check valves mounted directly in the end of the air tanks
                        and not the threaded brass check valves which are external to the tanks. One of the check valves
                        is located in the rear of the primary air tank, which is the tank closest to the left frame
                        rail. And the second check valve is located in the front of the secondary air tank, which is the
                        tank closest to the right frame rail.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the vehicle has the defective check valves by using
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9951201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9951202">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    below.
                    <emph type="bold">If the vehicle does not have this type of check valve the inspection is over and
                        the repair does not apply to the vehicle.
                    </emph>
                    But, if the vehicle has this check valve continue with the service procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9951201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9951202" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Step 4.D describes how to use the air line to remove the valve.</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Step 5.B instructs installer to add non petroleum lube to O-ring.</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. This is the check valve.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain the air tanks by opening the drain valves. Leave drain valves open where
                    possible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air lines from the check valves.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removing the check valves from the air tanks (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9951201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9951202">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Carefully remove/scrape dirt and paint from the check valve retaining snap ring
                        area.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Carefully remove the snap ring by prying the tapered end of the snap ring inward
                        towards the port center. Only one end of the snap ring has a taper (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9951203">Figure 3,</hotlnk>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9951204">Figure 4,</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9951205">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                        below).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To prevent contaminants from entering the tank, clean all dirt and paint from the
                        snap ring groove area before removing the valve.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To remove the check valve, either, re-install the air line and pull out the valve or
                        use the plug that came with the new valve. When using the plug to aid in valve removal, firmly
                        insert the plug into the valve opening and pry under the top of the plug using the top of the
                        bushing/port for leverage (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9951206">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Immediately destroy and discard the defective check valves and snap rings.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9951203" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9951204" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951204.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9951205" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951205.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9951206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/g9951206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Installing the new check valves in the air tanks.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Wipe out the air tank ports with a clean rag.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply some silicone base lube to the O-rings before installing them into the air
                        tanks. Do not use petroleum base lubes (Liquid soap with no grit may also be used).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the new check valves into the air tanks.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the new snap rings into the tanks, ensuring the snap ring is fully seated.
                        If the snap ring does not seat into the groove, apply gentle pressure to the center of the check
                        valve to make sure it is fully inserted and attempt to seat the snap ring again.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the air lines into the check valves. No unpainted portion of the air line
                    will be exposed when the air line is properly re-inserted. Close all drain ports that were not
                    closed previously.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and build air pressure and check for air leaks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Two check valves are required to repair each vehicle in this campaign that is found to have the
                Quality Connect Check Valves. A vehicle with Quality Connect check valves will need two of part number
                <emph type="bold">3545290C1</emph>.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>A Warranty Claim for this recall may have Labor Operations one
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
                one and two performed to complete the repair. Therefore, the minimum labor time is 0.3 hour and the
                maximum labor time is 0.5 hour.
            </para>
            <table id="t9951201">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99512-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Identify check valves</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99512-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Replace two check valves (3545290C1)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.2 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <responuscan>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE/DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Proceed immediately to make necessary correction to units in inventory.
                <emph type="bold">All inventory vehicles subject to this recall campaign must be corrected prior to
                    sale, transfer or delivery.
                </emph>
                If vehicles have been sold or transferred and you are in receipt of Customer Notification Letters and
                Authorization for Recall Service cards for those vehicles, transfer location or customer must be
                notified IMMEDIATELY from your dealer location.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers must correct all vehicles subject to this campaign at no charge to the owner, regardless of
                mileage, age of vehicle, or ownership, from this time forward.
            </para>
            <para>The National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act, as amended, provides that each vehicle that is
                subject to a vehicle recall campaign must be adequately
                <emph type="bold">repaired</emph>
                within a reasonable time after the owner has tendered it for repair. A failure to adequately repair
                within
                <emph type="bold">60 days</emph>
                after a tender of a vehicle is prima facie evidence of failure to repair within a reasonable time. If
                the condition is not adequately repaired with 60 days, the owner may be entitled to
                <emph type="bold">replacement</emph>
                with an identical or reasonable equivalent vehicle at no charge, or to a
                <emph type="bold">refund</emph>
                of the purchase price less a reasonable allowance for depreciation.
            </para>
            <para>However, consistent with the customer notification, dealers are expected to complete the repairs on
                the mutually agreed upon service date.
            </para>
            <para>In order to avoid having to replace an owner's vehicle or refund the purchase price, every effort must
                be made to promptly schedule an appointment with each owner to repair their vehicle as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </responuscan>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>WARRANTY CLAIMS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <responex>
            <para>We ask for your full cooperation and follow-up to this important subject matter. If you have any
                questions, or need further assistance, please contact the Regional Service Manager at your regional
                office.
            </para>
        </responex>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
