<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Recall 99514-R2 - EPA Low NOx Rebuild Information on Overhauled Engines</stitle>
    <recall id="Rec99514">
        <recallnumber>99514-R2</recallnumber>
        <market>U.S., Export</market>
        <recalldate>July 2005</recalldate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>EPA Low NOx Rebuild Information on Overhauled Engines</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>530E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <defect>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">REVISION DESCRIPTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Recently, the California Air Resources Board mailed a letter to certain owners of trucks with diesel
                engines. This letter instructs the owner that, "installation of this software on eligible vehicles is
                required by a California Air Resources Board (ARB) regulation effective March 21, 2005."
            </para>
            <para>This letter was sent to ALL owners of diesel engine vehicles built between 1993 and 1998 and may
                mislead owners of International vehicles to believe their vehicle is involved in this campaign.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">Only those International vehicles marked in ISIS as requiring this campaign are
                    eligible for the Low NOx Rebuild Kit.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>A copy of the ARB letter is attached at the end of thisrecall pdf in ISIS.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">ALWAYS ENSURE VEHICLE MEETS THE CRITERIA IN THIS VEHICLE RECALL LETTER AND IS
                    MARKED IN ISIS BEFORE PERFORMING THIS CAMPAIGN.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>See below for an explanation of the ARB letter to help in taking customer calls:</para>
            <para>Page 1 of the ARB letter contains the following table:</para>
            <table id="t9951405" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Required Installation Dates for Low NOx Rebuilt Kit</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.01*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.99*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine Model Year</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Required Installation Date for Low NOx Rebuild Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1993 and 1994</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>April 30, 2005*</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1995 and 1996</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>August 31, 2005</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1997 and 1998 other than MHDDE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>December 31, 2005</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1997 and 1998 MHDDE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>December 31, 2006</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>*Citations will not be issued until June 30, 2005</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>This table may cause owners to call and schedule an appointment. Please refer them to page 5 and 7 of
                the ARB letter.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9951406" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/G9951406.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Figure A - Found on 5th page of ARB letter</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Page 5 of the ARB letter instructs owners to, "
                <emph type="bold">Compare your engine manufacturer and model with the attached List of Low NOx Rebuild
                    Engines.</emph>"
            </para>
            <para>A review of the attached list on page 7 of the ARB letter indicates the following:</para>
            <figure id="f9951407" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/G9951407.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Figure B - Found on 7th page of the ARB letter</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Page 7 indicates the correct International MY1998 I6 engines and EPA Family numbers.</para>
            <para>The information contained in the ARB letter is NOT in conflict with the current Service Procedure for
                this campaign. Some vehicle owners, however, may misinterpret the ARB letter and believe their vehicle
                is involved when it is not.
            </para>
            <para>If you believe a vehicle should be involved in this campaign, but it is not marked in ISIS, please
                contact Tech Service for more information.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">CAMPAIGN DESCRIPTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <exhotlnk document="../recalls/Rec99514.pdf" bookname="RECALL">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the dealer
                    letter
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation has entered into an agreement with the U.S. Environmental
                Protection Agency (EPA). This letter is being issued to meet certain requirements of the consent decree,
                thus making International Dealers and engine rebuilders aware of their responsibility when certain
                International engines receive major repairs or overhaul.
            </para>
            <para>Linked to this letter is the following information:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <exhotlnk document="../recalls/99514Carb.pdf" bookname="Recall">Letter to International's
                            California Dealers and Service Managers
                        </exhotlnk>
                        (
                        <emph type="italic">This attachment was only mailed to International's dealers in the State of
                            California.</emph>)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <exhotlnk document="../recalls/99514FaxForm.pdf" bookname="Recall">G-99514 Recalibration Fax
                            Form
                        </exhotlnk>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <exhotlnk document="../recalls/99514EPA.pdf" bookname="Recall">Letter from U.S. EPA</exhotlnk>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>This complete letter and attachments must be filed with safety recall letters under G-99514, and be
                maintained indefinitely.
            </para>
            <para>Please read these letters carefully, as the procedures are unique. Should you have any questions,
                please contact your customer service engineer (CSE).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MODELS INVOLVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Family:</emph>
                International DT 466E Engine Model Year 1998 Federal and California Engines Only
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EPA Emission Family Names (found on emission label on valve cover):</emph>
                WNVXH0466FNA, WNVXH0466CCB, WNVXH0466FNC, WNVXH0466CCD
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Family:</emph>
                International 530E Engine Model Year 1998 Federal and California Engines Only
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EPA Emission Family Names (found on emission label on valve cover):</emph>
                WNVXH0530FNA, WNVXH0530CCB, WNVXH0530FNC, WNVXH0530CCD
            </para>
            <para>The above engines were used in truck model series 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, 8000.</para>
        </defect>
        <ownernote>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation has NOT notified customers of the availability of the
                Engine Software Upgrades. Dealers are to inform owners of vehicles involved in this recall, of the
                availability of the software upgrade at the time of an engine overhaul. See
                <emph type="bold">SERVICE PROCEDURE</emph>
                to determine when the Engine Software Upgrade is required.
            </para>
        </ownernote>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Disabling ECM Cruise Power Feature</title>
                <para>This ECM recalibration will disable the Cruise Power feature as required by an agreement between
                    International Truck and Engine Corporation, the United States EPA, and the California Air Resources
                    Board. It is the engine rebuilder's responsibility to ensure that a Low NOx Calibration is flashed
                    whenever a listed engine is rebuilt. Non-compliance with the Low NOx Rebuild requirements may be
                    treated as tampering under the Clean Air Act.
                </para>
                <para>To perform the Low NOx Reflash, International Service Centers will recalibrate the Diamond Logic*
                    controller to remove the Cruise Power feature when servicing the engine at any of the following
                    events:
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">FOR ALL STATES</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Any listed engine which when rebuilt has accumulated more than 185,000 miles; or</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Any listed engine which when rebuilt has less than 185,000 miles and requires replacement
                            or reconditioning of more than one piston assembly, cylinder liner, connecting rod, or
                            piston ringset in all of the engine's cylinders.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">ADDITIONAL REQUIREMENTS FOR THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Whenever the owner/operator of any CALIFORNIA REGISTERED vehicle that is involved in this
                            recall requests installation of a Low NOx Engine Software Upgrade; or
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If, as part of a regular service visit, the owner/operator of a CALIFORNIA REGISTERED
                            vehicle that is involved in this recall agrees to the installation of a Low NOx Engine
                            Software Upgrade.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>International Service Centers will offer and install, at no cost to the owner or nonaffiliated
                    engine rebuilder, a Low NOx Engine Software Upgrade upon request or anytime parts normally involved
                    in rebuilding or overhauling an engine are purchased from that dealer, distributor, repair or
                    rebuild facility.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection/Repair Procedure</title>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>ECM reprogramming will be conducted through Navistar Electronic Technical Support (NETS)
                            at qualified facilities only. This procedure must be used for any owner or nonaffiliated
                            engine rebuilder.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>For vehicles
                            <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                            registered in the state of California, utilize the FAX form; reproduce, complete, and fax
                            the request to Vehicle Programming per instructions on the form. Upon confirmation of the
                            request from Vehicle Programming, perform the NETS upload/download using the normal
                            procedure.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">For vehicles registered in the state of California, the FAX form
                                        is NOT required. The new calibrations are already available for you to perform
                                        the NETS upload/download.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>New calibration numbers are listed below. For International DT 466E calibration numbers,
                            see Table 2, and for 530E engines, see Table 3. Reprogramming may take approximately thirty
                            (30) minutes. Should you have questions concerning these procedures of programming, call
                            Vehicle Programming at 1-800-336-4500, press Option 2, then Option 3.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Upon completion of the reprogramming, a "Campaign Identification Label" must be attached
                            on the driver's side door pillar near the VIN plate. Using the spaces provided on the label,
                            indicate the campaign number, VIN, Engine Serial Number, and Service Location Code who
                            reprogrammed the ECM.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <table id="t9951401">
                    <title>International DT 466E ECM Calibration Numbers</title>
                    <tgroup cols="5" align="center">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Application</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">DT 466E Standard Torque Federal</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">DT 466E Standard Torque California</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">DT 466E High Torque Federal</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">DT 466E High Torque California</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" morerows="4">
                                    <para>Old Calibration Numbers for Engine Family</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB1AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB1AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB2AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB2AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB1AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB1AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB2AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB2AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB1AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB1AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB2AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB2AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB1AG01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB2AG01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB2AG01</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB2AG02</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">New Calibration Number (Replace Old Number if Listed Above)
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PFB1AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PCB1AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PFB2AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PCB2AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <table id="t9951402">
                    <title>International 530E ECM Calibration Numbers</title>
                    <tgroup cols="5" align="center">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Application</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">International 530E Governed Power Federal</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">International 530E Governed Power California</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">International 530E High Torque Federal</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">International 530E High Torque California</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" morerows="3">
                                    <para>Old Calibration Numbers for Engine Family</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB5AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB5AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB6AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB6AF00</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB5AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB5AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB6AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB6AF01</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>PFB5AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>PCB5AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB6AF02</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB6AF02</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>-</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>PFB6AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>PCB6AG00</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">New Calibration Number (Replace Old Number if Listed Above)
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PFB5AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PCB5AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PFB6AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">PCB6AG10</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <table id="t9951403">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A40-99514-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Reprogram ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.9 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <label>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="flabel">CAMPAIGN IDENTIFICATION LABEL</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="flabel" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/label.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"/>
            </figure>
        </label>
        <claims>
            <para>Refer to Dealer Warranty Manual for procedures to conduct Recall Campaigns.</para>
            <para>It is important that the Recall Coding be completed properly to assist in processing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="fclaim">warranty claim</hotlnk>. Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty
                Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be given to Items 39 through 44:
            </para>
            <figure id="fclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../recallfigures/claim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
        <dist/>
        <repro/>
    </recall>
</isis>
