<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - BOLT AND TORQUE INFORMATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0100103">
        <title>BOLT AND TORQUE INFORMATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Most frames are assembled with bolts and nuts. Others are riveted.
                <emph type="bold">Bolts must always be used when attaching a reinforcement.</emph>
                Rivets should be replaced by bolts as required when the frame is repaired and reinforced.
            </para>
            <para>In bolted joints, the majority of the load is transferred by frictional force or clamping force
                between the members of the joint. The bolts must be properly tightened to develop and maintain the
                desired clamping force. Operation of the joint with loose or improperly tightened bolts can lead to
                failure of the joint. The bolts and nuts should be inspected periodically to insure that proper torque
                is maintained.
            </para>
            <para>Bolts of high strength material conforming to SAE Grade 8 bolts should be used on all frames. For
                installation of reinforcements, 0.5 inch (13 mm) diameter flange head bolts are recommended. The SAE
                Grade 8 bolt is identified by six radial line markings on the head of the bolt (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100106">Figure 6</hotlnk>). Nuts must be Grade 8 flange type.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100106" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Bolt Identification</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SAE GRADE 5 BOLTS ARE IDENTIFIED BY 3 RADIAL LINES</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SAE GRADE 8 BOLTS ARE IDENTIFIED BY 6 RADIAL LINES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>These bolts, 0.5 inch (13 mm) diameter flange head type, should be tightened to 110 to 120 ft-lbs.
                (149 to 163 Nm) based on new bolts and nuts lubricated with engine oil. Whenever possible, hold the bolt
                and tighten the nut.
            </para>
            <para>If frame components are aluminum, flange head bolts and nuts, or bolts with hardened flat washers must
                be used. If modification or repair requires replacement of existing bolts with new bolts or bolts of a
                greater length, the old flange head nuts should not be used with new standard bolts.
            </para>
            <para>Careful consideration is given to the number, location and sizes of frame bolt holes in the design of
                a vehicle. The number, location and sizes of additional bolt holes put in the frame subsequent to
                manufacture of the vehicle can adversely affect frame strength. The adverse effect of additional bolt
                holes can be minimized by following the guidelines.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_REPAIRPROCEDURES.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
