<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - REPAIR AND REINFORCEMENT RECOMMENDED PROCEDURES - FLAT PLATE WELD REPAIR REINFORCEMENTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="repairprocedures" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FLAT PLATE WELD REPAIR REINFORCEMENTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This reinforcement is intended for the less critical, web portion of the sidemember section where
                typical cracking is due to local stresses which tend to "diaphragm" or "dish" the web without creating
                appreciable stresses for overall bending of the section. Typical crack patterns radiate out from the
                edge of a mounting bracket or crossmember or from a hole in the web. Cracks which radiate from a web
                hole occupied by a fastener are frequently an indication of a defective joint, whether by the loosening
                of the fastener or poor joint design (
                <hotlnk document="s01001_19.xml" xrefid="f0100105">Figure 5C</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Recommended Applications</title>
            <para>The flat plate reinforcements are recommended for weld repairs in which the weld does not extend
                beyond the zone defined in
                <hotlnk document="s01001_19.xml" xrefid="f0100105">Figure 5D</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Application Procedures</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A typical installation is shown in
                    <hotlnk document="s01001_19.xml" xrefid="f0100105">Figure 5C</hotlnk>. The length and height of the
                    plate will vary with the size of the weld repair area. In general it should be such that it will
                    accommodate an array of reinforcement attachment bolts at a typical 3 to 5 inch (76 to 127 mm)
                    spacing all around the weld repair area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The plate should generally be installed on the side opposite the component which
                    transferred the local bending load into the web.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The edges of the plate should be staggered with respect to the edges of other relatively
                    stiff web mounted components to avoid the creation of stress concentrations.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100103.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
