<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - MXT - REPAIR AND REINFORCEMENT RECOMMENDED PROCEDURES - GENERAL WELD REPAIR REINFORCEMENT
        PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL WELD REPAIR REINFORCEMENT PROCEDURES</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The thickness and material strength of the local plate, "L" and channel reinforcements
                should match the section being reinforced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The corners of the reinforcements which will be in contact with the sidemember along the
                reinforcement edges must be chamfered to prevent damage to the sidemember.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All sidemember reinforcements must be bolted to the web section within the zone shown in
                <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100102.xml" xrefid="f0100108">Figure 12</hotlnk>
                . The bolts must be of SAE Grade 8 or better, with integral flanges or with hardened flat washers and
                must be tightened to Grade 8 levels.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Crossmember modification or replacement may be required if the reinforcement is on the same
                side as the crossmember.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Consider the potential effects of the reinforcements on the various components mounted to
                the frame. Check clearances for suspension, wiring, plumbing and other controls.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For attachment of reinforcements, use existing bolts wherever this is practical.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The weld repaired area of the sidemember and all of the reinforcement should be primed and
                painted before reinforcement installation. For corrosive environments, additional treatment of the
                interface may be needed.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
