<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - WELDING AND REINFORCEMENT - REINFORCEMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0100107" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REINFORCEMENT</title>
        <para>Reinforcements (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0100101">Figure 1</hotlnk>) to increase load capacity are generally "full length." The
            actual length of the reinforcement varies with the model. Shorter, (approximately 7 feet) rear suspension
            bogie liner reinforcements are available for some tractor models. Inverted "L" and "C" channel
            reinforcements are available for most models. For models which do not have reinforcements available, it will
            be necessary to contact Sales Engineering to obtain reinforcement recommendations.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0100101" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Frame Rails and Reinforcements (Typical)</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. STANDARD SIDEMEMBER SECTION</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HEAVY DUTY SIDEMEMBER SECTION</callout1>
                <callout1>3. L-REINFORCEMENT SIDEMEMBER SECTION</callout1>
                <callout1>4. C-REINFORCEMENT SIDEMEMBER SECTION</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>These reinforcements are generally installed on the outside of the sidemember, although certain models
            require "C" channel reinforcements installed to the inside of the sidemember. Contact your International
            Truck dealer regarding the required type of reinforcement.
        </para>
        <para>Depending on model application, there will be other parts affected, such as spring brackets for example,
            which are bolted to the flange as well as the web of the sidemember. To maintain proper alignment of the
            springs, these brackets may require replacement with new brackets designed to accept the reinforcements.
            These brackets are available through your International Truck dealer parts department.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When an inside reinforcement is added, the lengths of the crossmembers will be affected.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100108.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
