<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - FIFTH WHEEL INSTALLATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>FIFTH WHEEL INSTALLATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Outlined below are recommended guidelines for installation of fifth wheels on vehicles. The more
                common combinations of frame, suspension, fifth wheel and fifth wheel offset dimensions are covered in
                this section. For mounting applications not covered in this section, refer to the fifth wheel
                manufacturer for installation instructions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It must be recognized that the ultimate responsibility for the durability and security of the
                        fifth wheel mounting lies with the installer/user. Therefore, the installer/user is cautioned to
                        consult the fifth wheel manufacturer's installation recommendations and whatever legal
                        requirements and regulations are applicable.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>It is also the responsibility of the installer/ user to make sure that the vehicle frame is adequate
                for the fifth wheel offset location from the centerline of the single rear axle (4 x 2 vehicles) or
                tandem rear axle (6 x 4 vehicles).
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <para>As with any aftermarket modification, care must be taken when installing a fifth wheel. The following
                precautions must be taken when installing a fifth wheel.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not weld or drill the top or bottom flanges of the vehicle frame. Welding or drilling the
                        flanges will severely weaken the frame. Refer to restrictions in
                        <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100102.xml" xrefid="f0100107">Figure 21</hotlnk>
                        through
                        <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100102.xml" xrefid="f0100111">Figure 25</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Do not drill frame sidemember(s) other than as specified in
                <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100105.xml" xrefid="x0100105">DRILLING</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Fifth wheel attachments must not be welded directly to the sidemember.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100106.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
