<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - MXT - WELDING AND REINFORCEMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>WELDING AND REINFORCEMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The guidelines below deal with the general procedures for weld repair and reinforcement. Because of
                the many variables associated with these repairs, it is recommended that your field service
                representative be consulted prior to undertaking the repair. This will also help to determine whether a
                specific set of recommendations has already been developed for the case in question.
            </para>
            <para>The essential elements of repairing the sidemembers are the restoring of
                <emph type="bold">both</emph>
                the shape and local strength so that the load capacity is at least as good as before the damage
                occurred. The sidemembers may
                <emph type="italic">look</emph>
                like new, but may have local strength reduction due to small cracks or material strength reduction. Even
                if the frame has acceptable alignment and there is no gross deformation, local deformations may reduce
                the strength in the area to be weld repaired. Examples of this are local bulges in the web (vertical
                portion) of the section and buckling of the flanges. These local deformations must be repaired by
                straightening before proceeding with the weld repair.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>WELDING PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <para>When welding on any vehicle, care must be taken to prevent damage to the electronic components.
                Vehicles with ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEMS require additional precautions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>On any vehicle, disconnect both the positive and negative battery cables from the battery
                        before welding on the vehicle. Attach the welder ground cable as close as possible to the part
                        being welded.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>With an electronic engine controller (such as Celect), do not connect the ground cable to the control
                module(s) or the cooling plate. To protect the control module(s), it is mandatory to remove all
                connectors going to the control modules.
            </para>
            <para>The following is a general guideline for the steel frames (36,000, 50,000, and 110,000 PSI yield
                strength).
            </para>
            <para>Welding and reinforcing the frame rails is a satisfactory repair method for mild steel (36,000 PSI
                yield strength) frame rails.
            </para>
            <para>Welding of the HSLA (50,000, 60,000 and 80,000 PSI yield strength) steel side member and the
                heat-treated (110,000 PSI yield strength) steel sidemember involves a significant reduction in the
                strength of the frame in the heat affected zones of the weldment. This means that the frame in the
                welded region is no longer capable of carrying the same load or stress as the original section.
            </para>
            <para>To restore the strength of the frame rails after welding, the welded area must be reinforced using
                reinforcements as indicated in
                <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100101.xml" xrefid="x0100101">REPAIR AND REINFORCEMENT RECOMMENDED PROCEDURES
                    .
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Welding must be done properly to make an effective repair. Therefore, only those who are properly
                trained and qualified should perform the welding repairs in this section.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100107.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
