<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - FRAME ALIGNMENT - METHOD OF CHECKING FRAME ALIGNMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="align" graphiccount="1">
        <title>METHOD OF CHECKING FRAME ALIGNMENT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>A satisfactory method of checking the frame and axle alignment, particularly when a body and cab is on
                a chassis, is to:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Place a plumb bob against the point of measurement. All measurements must be taken with the
                        plumb bob positioned against bare metal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tack or tape pieces of paper to the floor directly under each point of measurement on the
                        chassis as indicated by the letter "K" in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0100102">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0100102" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Centerline of Chassis</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Method of Checking</title>
            <para>After each measurement point has been carefully marked on the floor, proceed as follows:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate centerline of chassis by measuring front and rear end widths, using marks on
                    floor.
                </para>
                <para>If frame widths are within specification, draw centerline on floor, the full length of the chassis
                    and continue with step 2.
                </para>
                <para>If frame widths are out of specification, lay out centerline as follows:</para>
                <para>Centerline can be drawn through the intersection of any one pair of equal diagonals (A-A, B-B,
                    C-C, D-D) and center point of one end of frame or through points of intersection of any two pairs of
                    equal diagonals.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure distance from centerline to opposite points marked over entire length of frame.
                    Measurements should not vary more than 0.12 inch (3.0 mm) at any point.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measuring diagonals (A-A, B-B, C-C, D-D) will indicate point where misalignment occurs.
                    If diagonals in each pair are within 0.12 inch (3.0 mm), that part of the frame included between
                    points of measurement may be considered in satisfactory alignment. These diagonals should intersect
                    within 0.12 inch (3.0 mm) of the centerline.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the diagonals are not within specification, try loosening and re-tightening all cross-members. Then
                re-check alignment. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s01001_37.xml" xrefid="x0100104">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="x0100104"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . If frame is still out of alignment, the vehicle must be taken to a suitable frame alignment
                establishment to confirm frame misalignment. If misalignment is confirmed, suitable measures must be
                taken to repair the damage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Side Elevation Dimensions</title>
            <para>Dimensions for side elevation of the frame should be checked at the points indicated and should not
                vary more than 0.12 inch (3.0 mm) from side to side. (They will differ fore and aft due to typical frame
                rake.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
