<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - AFTERMARKET MODIFICATIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>AFTERMARKET MODIFICATIONS</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Cutting the frame behind the rear axle to shorten the frame is acceptable. Mechanical cutting or
                sawing is preferred to torch cutting. Whenever it is necessary to cut the frame, the sidemember should
                be cut at an angle of 90 degrees to the longitudinal axis.
            </para>
            <para>For information on cutting of the frames to lengthen the frames or modify the wheelbase, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100106.xml" xrefid="x0100106">WHEELBASE ALTERATIONS</hotlnk>
                below.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Where mounting angles are to be welded to fifth wheel assemblies, refer to fifth wheel
                        manufacturer's recommendations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>In some cases, specialized equipment such as hoists, winches, lifts, snowplows, pusher and tag axles
                are added to the vehicle by distributors, installers or dealers. Unless otherwise specified by the
                customer at the time of assembly, the vehicle is generally equipped with a standard chassis frame and
                the manufacturer has not made special allowances for the special equipment which is being added.
            </para>
            <para>The addition or installation of this special equipment on the vehicle can significantly affect the
                loading of the chassis frame. In some cases, it may be necessary to reinforce the frame. Care must be
                exercised to insure that the gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR) and/or the gross axle weight ratings
                (GAWR) are not exceeded.
            </para>
            <para>Installation of this special equipment may involve State and Federal requirements which affect vehicle
                certification for noise emissions, exhaust emissions, brake requirements, lighting system requirements,
                etc. The specialized equipment installer is responsible for the safety and durability of their product
                and, in addition, is responsible to insure that the equipment and its installation comply with all
                applicable State and Federal Department of Transportation requirements and OSHA regulations.
            </para>
            <para>Addition of specialized equipment may have a significant effect on other vehicle components, such as
                the brake system, steering system, suspension system, etc. Simple reinforcement of the chassis frame may
                not be adequate to provide safe operation of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>In any modification of the chassis frame, the addition of holes, reinforcements, welds, clamps,
                splices, etc. may cause an increase in the local stress in the frame at the point of the modification.
                These local stress concentrations can significantly affect the life of the chassis frame. The specific
                effect which the stress concentrator will have on the life of the chassis frame is influenced by the
                location of the stress concentration, the frequency and severity of the loading, and the type of stress
                concentration. Any modification of the frame may void the manufacturer's warranty.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ALUMINUM SIDEMEMBERS OR CROSSMEMBERS</title>
            <para>To prevent the formation of a galvanic cell, isolation techniques such as non-conductive or barrier
                type spacers or sealers must be used. It is recommended that a sealer, such as Tectyl 400C or
                equivalent, be painted onto the surface of both the aluminum frame and steel reinforcement. Steel bolts
                passing through the aluminum frame and the steel reinforcement, as well as the washers under the head of
                the bolts and nuts, should be sealed also.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100102.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_X0100106.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
