<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - MXT - REPAIR AND REINFORCEMENT RECOMMENDED PROCEDURES - REINFORCEMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REINFORCEMENT</title>
        <para>The strength of the sidemember in the weld joint repair region has been reduced by welding and this region
            must be reinforced sufficiently to insure that the service life of the frame is not shortened. Reinforcement
            of the frame after welding is intended to reduce the stresses in the weld repair region to a lower level
            than was previously permitted. Improper drilling will also reduce the strength of the sidemembers. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100105.xml" xrefid="x0100105">DRILLING</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">The type, length, material and attachment techniques for reinforcements vary with the type
                and location of the crack and with the loading conditions associated with the crack.
            </emph>
            It is not practical to give specific recommendations for all cases of frame cracking, therefore the various
            types of reinforcements are identified with general descriptions of their applications and installation
            procedures. To aid in making the distinctions between the more critical flange area and the less critical
            web area, critical zones are defined as shown (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0100105">Figure 11D</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0100105" figsize="full-pg">
            <graphic filename="../figg01/g0100140.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Figure 11. Reinforcement Application</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Cracks which occur in the critical zones have a greater probability of growing vertically through the
            section, and the reduced strength after weld repair necessitates a more substantial reinforcement.
        </para>
        <para>These guidelines potentially affect the structural integrity of the frame assembly and are intended for
            those who have the equipment and experience required to qualify as frame repair specialists.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
