<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - FIFTH WHEEL INSTALLATION - MOUNTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="11">
        <title>MOUNTING</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mounting Angles</title>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100112">use of mounting angles to mount the fifth wheel</hotlnk>
                to the vehicle frame is recommended
                <xref refid="f0100112"/>. Mounting angles provide for more direct transfer of the load to the frame
                sidemembers for better stress distribution. Some fifth wheels incorporate integral mounting angles as
                part of the fifth wheel assembly.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100112" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100112.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Fifth Wheel Mounting Angle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRAME</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FIFTH WHEEL MOUNTING ANGLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Mounting angles must be made of steel conforming to SAE J410, grade 965X, 0.312 inch (8 mm) thick; or
                ASTM A572, grade 50, 0.38 inch (.6 mm) thick; or conform to fifth wheel manufacturer's specifications
                that cover your particular circumstances.
            </para>
            <para>It is permissible to cut mounting angles to provide clearance for spring mounting brackets, etc.
                Cutouts in the vertical flanges of the mounting angles should be minimized in number and size. Cutouts
                must be rounded at the inside corners. Inner radii of cutouts should be 0.5 inch (13 mm) minimum; 0.75
                inch (19.0 mm) radii are preferred.
            </para>
            <para>To
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100113">make cutouts in mounting angles</hotlnk>, drill holes at radii of cutouts
                <xref refid="f0100113"/>. Then, saw or torch cut to remove remaining material. Cut edges should be
                ground smooth.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100113" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100113.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Mounting Angle Cutout</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 2 INCHES (51 mm) RECOMMENDED MINIMUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRILL HOLES AT CORNERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 0.5 INCH (13 mm) RADIUS (MINIMUM)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Some vehicles have spring mounting brackets designed to permit
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100114">installation of fifth wheel mounting angle</hotlnk>
                between the spring bracket and vehicle frame
                <xref refid="f0100114"/>. Remove factory installed spacers to install mounting angles. Re-tighten bolts
                as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s01001_37.xml" xrefid="x0100104">Torque Chart</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100114" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. Mounting Angle Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPACER (REMOVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MOUNTING ANGLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Mounting angles should be secured to frame sidemembers using quantity and spacing of bolts as
                determined by following the guidelines provided in this section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mounting Bolts</title>
            <para>The use of phosphate and oil coated SAE Grade 8 flanged fasteners is recommended. Where flanged
                fasteners are not available, the use of hardened steel flat washers under bolt head and nut is
                recommended.
            </para>
            <para>Where locations of mounting bolts are limited by cutouts, the new bolt pattern should conform as
                closely as possible to recommendations in terms of number of fasteners, edge distances and spacings.
            </para>
            <para>For horizontal bolt applications (mounting angle-to-frame sidemember), use 0.625- inch (16 mm)
                diameter bolts. Tighten nuts as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s01001_37.xml" xrefid="x0100104">Torque Chart</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>For vertical bolt applications (fifth wheel-to-mounting angle, fifth wheel-to-support plate, fifth
                wheel-to-cross tie, cross tie-to-mounting angle), use 3/4-inch (19 mm) diameter bolts. These bolts must
                be flanged head or hex head with hardened flat washers. Tighten nuts as specified in
                <hotlnk document="s01001_37.xml" xrefid="x0100104">Torque Chart</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Some sliding and fixed fifth wheels are designed to use 0.625-inch (16 mm) diameter vertical
                        bolts. These are acceptable where specified by design.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Care must be taken to prevent fretting (chafing) damage to frame top flange by sharp edges on fifth
                wheel mounting parts. The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100115">Figure below</hotlnk>
                illustrates methods of preventing fretting (chafing) damage at leading and trailing edges. These methods
                include:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chamfering the edges of fifth wheel mounting parts contacting frame top flange.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use of a "flex-lip" to gradually diminish contact forces.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0100115" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0100115" filename="../figg01/G0100115.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 29. Methods of Preventing Fretting Damage</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FIFTH WHEEL BASE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CHAMFER (30-45&#176;)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 1.5 INCH (38.1 mm) MINIMUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FLEX LIP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Fifth wheel and mounting parts should be positioned on the vehicle frame to provide maximum contact
                between the parts which transfer the vertical load onto the upper flange of the frame. Clamp to assure
                contact before tightening bolts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fixed (Non-Sliding) Fifth Wheels</title>
            <para>Typical installations of fixed (non-sliding) fifth wheels are illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100116">Figure 30,</hotlnk>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100117">Figure 31,</hotlnk>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100118">Figure 32,</hotlnk>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100119">Figure 33,</hotlnk>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100120">Figure 34</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100121">Figure 35</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Mounting angles should be secured to frame sidemembers with a minimum of five bolts per side with bolt
                spacing as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100116">Figure 30</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Recommended fixed fifth wheel mounting dimension limits are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100116">Figure 30</hotlnk>. These limits are as follows:
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100116" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100116.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 30. Fixed Fifth Wheel Mounting Dimension Limits (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Dimension "A" (Trunnion centerline spacing) 29 to 34 inches (736 to 863 mm).</para>
            <para>Dimension "B" (Fifth wheel offset with respect to rear axle or tandem rear axle centerline) 0 to 24
                inches (0 to 609 mm).
            </para>
            <para>Dimension "C" (Fifth wheel pivot height above frame) 6 inches (152.4 mm) maximum.</para>
            <para>Be sure to refer to the segments in this section for mounting angle and cutout information, bolt sizes
                and torque specifications and corrosion protection on aluminum frames.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to follow the recommended procedures in this section may result in damage to the
                        vehicle frame and possible injury to the operator.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>For vehicle frame assemblies without bogie gussets or "C" channel frame reinforcements, install a set
                of flat cross ties as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100117">Figure 31</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100118">Figure 32</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Cross Tie Installation (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0100118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100118.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Cross Tie Welding (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>For bolted base type fifth wheels, bolt the cross ties and spacers as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100117">Figure 31</hotlnk>. For fifth wheels with integral mounting angle, weld the
                cross ties as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100118">Figure 32</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Cross ties should be a minimum of 0.31 inch (8.0 mm) thick x 5 inches (127 mm) wide. Recommended
                material is 0.31 inch (8.0 mm) thick HSLA 80,000 PSI yield material (SAE 980X).
            </para>
            <para>For bolted base type fifth wheels, a single flat plate or a corrugated plate can be used instead of
                cross ties. The flat plate should have the bolt pattern shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100119">Figure 33</hotlnk>
                (top view). The corrugated plate should be installed as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100119">Figure 33</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100119" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100119.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Plate Installation (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>For vehicle frame assemblies which have bogie gussets (such as a typical Hendrickson suspension) many
                fifth wheel installations may be made without cross ties as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100120">Figure 34</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100121">Figure 35</hotlnk>. Cross ties may be required in some cases, as indicated.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100120" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100120.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Fifth Wheel Installation Without Cross Ties (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0100121" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100121.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Fifth Wheel Installation Without Cross Ties (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sliding Fifth Wheels</title>
            <para>These guidelines apply to sliding fifth wheel assemblies where the rails or tracks are tied together
                on a mounting plate or with cross ties.
            </para>
            <para>A typical installation of a sliding fifth wheel is illustrated in the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100122">Figure below</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0100122" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg01/G0100122.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Sliding Fifth Wheel Installation (Typical)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Mounting angles should be secured to frame sidemembers with bolts, the minimum number of which are to
                be determined by dividing the distance between the front and rear bolt holes, as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0100122">Figure 36</hotlnk>, by 7.0 inches (177.8 mm) and adding 1.
            </para>
            <para>Recommended sliding fifth wheel mounting dimension limits are as follows:</para>
            <para>Dimension "B" (Fifth wheel offset with respect to bogie centerline) 0 to 36 inches (0 to 914 mm)
                maximum.
            </para>
            <para>Dimension "C" (Fifth wheel pivot height above frame) 6.0 inches (152.4 mm) maximum.</para>
            <para>Sliding fifth wheels, because of their length and construction techniques, are prone to warping and
                misalignment. This along with vehicle frame variations makes it necessary to check and correct for
                proper fit where needed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_35.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001_37.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
