<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRAME - MXT - WHEELBASE ALTERATIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0100106" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WHEELBASE ALTERATIONS</title>
        <para>Shortening or lengthening a wheelbase is an added expense for the customer. Therefore, it is often to the
            customer's benefit to order a chassis from the factory with the desired wheelbase rather than to alter the
            wheelbase of the chassis on-site.
        </para>
        <para>The preferred method for altering the wheelbase is to slide the rear axle forward or rearward as required.
            Invariably, this requires the lengthening or shortening of air lines, brake lines, electrical lines, and
            driveline. Extreme care should be taken in the modification of the air lines, brake lines, electrical lines
            and driveline to insure that they operate as reliably as those with which the vehicle was manufactured.
        </para>
        <para>If the wheelbase is lengthened, a reinforcement may be required. Consult your International dealer before
            lengthening the wheelbase.
        </para>
        <para>In those instances when it is necessary to cut and weld the frame to alter the wheelbase, the frame must
            be reinforced with a channel-type reinforcement of the same strength as the original frame material in the
            area where the frame has been cut, extending at least two feet on either side of the cut.
        </para>
        <para>If the frame was built with both a main frame and a reinforcement, the reinforcement should be removed
            before cutting the main frame.
            <emph type="bold">It is essential that a new one-piece outer channel reinforcement be obtained rather than
                cutting and re-using the original reinforcement.
            </emph>
            The original frame should also be reinforced with an inner channel reinforcement, extending at least two
            feet beyond the cut(s) on either side of the cut(s). The reinforcement must be of the same material as the
            original frame. Blank and pre-punched chassis channel reinforcements are available through your dealer parts
            department.
        </para>
        <para>On both medium and high strength aluminum frames, re-welding to lengthen the frame is not recommended.
            Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100107.xml" xrefid="x0100107">REINFORCEMENT</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk document="s01002_X0100108.xml" xrefid="x0100108">REINFORCEMENT ATTACHMENT</hotlnk>
            for additional information.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s01002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
