<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RT-6613 SERIES - PRECAUTIONS -
        REASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Make sure interiors of the case and housings are clean. It is important that dirt and other foreign
            materials be kept out of the transmission during reassembly. Dirt is an abrasive and can damage polished
            surfaces of bearings and washers. Use certain precautions, as listed below, during reassembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">O-RlNGS - Lubricate all O-rings with silicone lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GASKETS - Use new gaskets throughout transmission as it is being rebuilt. Make sure all
                gaskets are installed. Omission of any gasket can result in oil leakage or misalignment of bearing
                covers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BOLTS - To prevent oil leakage, use Loctite 242 thread sealant on all bolts. For torque
                ratings, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13030_58.xml" xrefid="hl1303002">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="hl1303002"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">ASSEMBLY - Refer to the illustrations provided in the detailed disassembly instructions as a
                guide to reassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">INITIAL LUBRICATlON - Coat all limit washers and splines of shafts with Lubriplate during
                reassembly to prevent scoring and galling of such parts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">AXIAL CLEARANCES - Maintain original axial clearances of mainshaft forward speed gears of
                .005 to .012 inch. Mainshaft reverse gear clearance is a minimum of .005 inch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARINGS - Use of flanged-end bearing drivers is recommended for the installation of
                bearings. These special drivers apply equal force to both bearing races, preventing damage to
                balls/rollers and races while maintaining correct bearing alignment with bore and shaft. Avoid using a
                tubular or sleeve-type driver, whenever possible, as force is applied to only one of the bearing races.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">UNIVERSAL JOINT COMPANION FLANGE OR YOKE - Pull the companion flange or yoke tightly into
                place with mainshaft nut, with 450 to 500 ft-lbs. (610 to 678 N&#183;m). Make sure speedometer drive
                gear has been installed. If a speedometer gear is not used, a replacement spacer of the same width must
                be used. Failure to pull companion flange or yoke tightly into place will permit output shaft to move
                axially with resultant damage to the rear bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
