<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>8 SPEED, 9 SPEED, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON SERIES - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1301807">
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Transmissions are designed so that the internal parts operate in a bath of oil circulated by the
                motion of gears and shafts.
            </para>
            <para>Thus, all parts will be amply lubricated if these procedures are closely followed:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Maintain oil level. Inspect regularly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Change oil regularly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use the correct grade and type of oil. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master
                        Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Buy from a reputable dealer.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The use of mild EP gear oil or multi-purpose gear oil is not recommended, but if these gear oils are
                used, be sure to adhere to the following limitations:
            </para>
            <para>Do not use mild EP gear oil or multi-purpose gear oil when operating temperatures are above 230
                degrees F (110 degrees C). Many of these gear oils, particularly 85W140, break down above 230 degrees F
                and coat seals, bearings and gears with deposits that may cause premature failures. If these deposits
                are observed (especially a coating on seal areas causing oil leakage), change to Eaton Roadranger CD50
                transmission fluid, heavy duty engine oil or mineral gear oil to assure maximum component life and to
                maintain your warranty with Eaton.
            </para>
            <para>In addition, transmission oil coolers are not recommended with these gear oils since the oil cooler
                materials may be attacked by these gear oils. The lower temperature limit and oil cooler restriction
                with these gear oils generally limit their success to milder applications.
            </para>
            <para>Additives and friction modifiers are not recommended for use in Eaton Fuller transmissions.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PROPER OIL LEVEL</title>
            <para>Make sure oil is level with filler opening. Because you can reach oil with your finger does not mean
                oil is at proper level. One inch of oil level is about one gallon of oil.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Proper Lubrication Levels as Related to Transmission Installation Angles</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the transmission operating angle is more than 12 degrees, improper lubrication can occur. The
                operating angle is the transmission mounting angle in the chassis plus percent of upgrade (expressed in
                degrees).
            </para>
            <para>Anytime the transmission operating angle of 12 degrees is exceeded for an extended period of time, the
                transmission should be equipped with an oil pump or cooler kit to insure proper lubrication.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_99.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_101.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
