<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - DRIVETRAIN FAILURE ANALYSIS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection division="TRUCK" id="s13002" svcsectype="prodspec" formnum="CTS-5198" date="06/03/96">
        <title>DRIVETRAIN FAILURE ANALYSIS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="description" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
            <para>It is the intent of this publication to help the user identify the cause of component failures. When a
                failure occurs, we need to understand what happened so that it can be prevented in the future. In
                general there are three reasons for component failure: misapplication, improper vehicle operation and
                lack of maintenance.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Misapplication.</emph>Components fail because the design limits have been exceeded.
                The engine horsepower, GCW and duty cycle are some of the criteria used when selecting drivetrain
                components. To deviate to a lesser design will result in a shorter service life or an immediate failure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Improper vehicle operation.</emph>Components that are within design limits will fail
                due to improper or abusive operation. It is important that the driver understands how to operate the
                vehicle correctly. Failures from abuse may not occur immediately but many miles later.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Lack of maintenance.</emph>Lack of maintenance or improper maintenance will result in
                premature component failure regardless of how well the vehicle is operated or the design strength of the
                component. It is important to follow the adjustment and lubrication recommendations in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Before making repairs, talk with the driver about the failure. Review the service history of the
                vehicle to find out if this failure occurred before. Do not clean the component before carefully
                examining it. Use the illustrations in this publication as a guide for the probable cause of the
                failure.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13002_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
