<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - PRECAUTIONS - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Make sure that interiors of case and housings are clean. It is important that dirt and other foreign
            materials be kept out of the transmission during reassembly. Dirt is an abrasive and can damage polished
            surfaces of bearings and washers. Use certain precautions, as listed below, during reassembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GASKETS-Use new gaskets throughout the transmission as it is being rebuilt. Make sure all
                gaskets are installed. An omission of any gasket can result in oil leakage or misalignment of bearing
                covers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BOLTS-To prevent oil leakage, use Loctite 242 thread sealant on all bolts. For torque
                ratings, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13024_X1302403.xml" xrefid="x1302403">TORQUE CHART.</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">O-RINGS-Lubricate all O-rings with silicon lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARING RETAINING NUTS-Use Loctite on threads of all drive gear bearing nuts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">INITIAL LUBRICATION-Coat all thrust washers and splines of shaft with Lubriplate during
                reassembly to prevent scoring and galling of such parts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">AIR SYSTEM-Use Loctite hydraulic sealant on all air fittings; coat air cylinder bores with
                transmission oil.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARINGS-Use of flanged-end bearing drivers is recommended for the installation of the
                bearings. These special drivers apply equal force to both bearing races, preventing damage to
                balls/rollers and races while maintaining correct bearing alignment with bore and shaft. Avoid using a
                tubular or sleeve-type driver, whenever possible, as force is applied to only one of the bearing races.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">UNIVERSAL JOINT COMPANION FLANGE-Pull the companion flange or yoke tightly into place with
                the output shaft nut, using 400 to 450 ft-lbs. (542 to 610 N&#183; m) of torque. Make sure the
                speedometer drive gear or a replacement spacer has been installed. Failure to properly tighten the nut
                can result in damage to the mainshaft rear bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_X1302401.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
