<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 -
        Assembly - Input Bearing Cage and Oil Pump Assembly Installation, Bearing End Play Adjustment and Transfer Case
        Final Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Input Bearing Cage and Oil Pump Assembly Installation, Bearing End Play Adjustment and Transfer Case
            Final Assembly
        </title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the transfer case so that the front is facing UPWARD.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the shim pack for the input bearing cage and oil pump assembly over the front input
                opening. Position so that the open areas of the shims face the bottom of the transfer case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the input bearing cage large O-ring, oil pump, helical drive gear and bearing cone
                before installation. Use synthetic SAE 50 oil (Meritor specification O-81).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the input bearing cage and oil pump assembly. Position the assembly so that the
                inlet oil tube fitting is facing the correct direction.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install at least three input bearing cage to housing capscrews. Tighten the capscrews to
                85-115 lb-ft (115-156 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">MTC-4208 and -4210 transfer cases only:</emph>
                Install the large 3-inch (76 mm) diameter nut onto the rear end of the input shaft. Tighten the nut to
                700-900 lb-ft (949-1220 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the input shaft yoke nut to 700-900 lb-ft (949-1220 Nm).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set up a dial indicator to check input shaft bearing end play. Center the dial indicator
                over the shaft using a ball bearing for accuracy (Figure 60).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303560" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303560.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 60. Center Dial Indicator</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a pry bar to lift the yoke to obtain a measurement. To obtain a consistent and averaged
                reading, perform this operation two or three times. Record the reading for the input shaft.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is greater than 0.001- to 0.005-inch (0.025-0.127 mm)
                            for MTC-4208 and -4210 transfer cases, or 0.002 &#177; 0.001-inch (0.025 mm) for the
                            MTC-4213 transfer case:
                        </emph>
                        Remove shims to decrease end play.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is less than specification:</emph>
                        Add shims to increase end play. Bearing shims come in 0.003-, 0.005- and 0.010-inch (0.08, 0.13
                        and 0.25 mm) thicknesses.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If it is necessary to add or remove shims, remove the input bearing cage and oil pump
                assembly capscrews and lift the assembly enough to insert or remove shims.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>This can be done without completely removing the pump and shaft assembly from the housing.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The nut on the rear end of the shaft on MTC-4208 and -4210 transfer cases must be removed
                        first. Refer to the Figures at the beginning of this manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the correct shim pack is chosen, reinstall all seven input bearing cage and oil pump
                assembly capscrews. Tighten the capscrews to 85-115 lb-ft (115-156 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recheck input shaft bearing end play. Adjust end play as necessary.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If necessary, install the breather into the front case (Figure 61).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the oil inlet tube to the lower and upper fittings. Tighten the fitting nuts to
                35-40 lb-ft (48-54 Nm) (Figure 62).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, install the speed sensor into the top of the transfer case (Figure 61). Fasten
                with a capscrew and washer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the PTO engagement and disengagement switch assemblies, if equipped. Otherwise,
                install a nut and washer in the open port.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall all other pipe threaded plugs using Loctite&#174; 592 sealant.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303561" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303561.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 61. Install Speed Sensor</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PTO SWITCHES</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SPEED SENSOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. BREATHER</callout1>
                <callout1>4. FRONT AXLE DECLUTCH PORT</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1303562" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303562.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 62. Install Oil Inlet Tube</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. INLET OIL TUBE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
