<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER AUTOMATE-2 - TROUBLESHOOTING (MECHANICAL) - BEARINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BEARINGS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DIRT</title>
            <para>More than 90% of all ball bearing failures are caused by dirt which is always abrasive.</para>
            <para>Dirt may enter the bearings during assembly of the units or be carried into the bearing by the
                lubricant while in service. Dirt may enter through seals, breather or even dirty containers used for
                addition or change of lubricant.
            </para>
            <para>Softer material such as dirt, dust, etc., usually forms abrasive paste or lapping compounds within the
                bearings themselves since the unit pressure between the balls and raceways makes a perfect pulverizer.
                The rolling motion tends to entrap and hold the abrasives. As the balls and raceways wear, the bearings
                become noisy. The lapping action tends to increase rapidly as the fine steel from the balls and rollway
                adds to the lapping material.
            </para>
            <para>Hard, coarse materials such as chips, etc. may enter the bearings during assembly from hammers,
                drifts, power chisels, etc., or be manufactured within the unit during service from raking teeth, etc.
                These chips produce small indentations in balls and races. Jamming of these hard particles between balls
                and races may cause the inner face to turn on shaft, or the outer race to turn in the housing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FATIGUE</title>
            <para>All bearings are subject to fatigue and must be replaced eventually. Your own operating experience
                will dictate mileage replacement of bearings showing only normal wear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CORROSION</title>
            <para>Water, acid and corrosive materials formed by deterioration of lubricant will produce reddish-brown
                coating and small etched holes over outer and exposed surfaces of race. Corrosive oxides also act as
                lapping agent.
            </para>
            <para>Brinelling caused by improper assembly or removal-usually hammering with off-center blows. Use
                drivers, preferably under an arbor, or pullers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SHAFT FITS</title>
            <para>Excessive looseness under load is very objectionable because it produces a creeping or slipping of the
                inner ring on the rotating shaft. This causes the surface metal of shafts to scrub or wear off.
            </para>
            <para>Bearing fits on rotating shafts are usually specified as tight. When play or looseness, even .001
                inch, exists between the bearing and shaft, there is a very powerful force tending to rotate the inner
                race on the shaft; this force is caused by the looseness or lost motion between the parts and disappears
                when no looseness exists.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>REMOVAL OF BEARINGS</title>
            <para>It is far more difficult to remove bearings from a shaft than to put them on. In most cases it is
                necessary to remove the bearing by pulling on the outer race, which can damage the balls or races. Since
                such damage is seldom visible, it does not become known until after complete reassembly. It is good
                preventive maintenance to replace most ball bearings during the overhaul period. If a bearing is not
                going to be replaced, avoid removal during low mileage rebuild.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>INTERCHANGEABILITY</title>
            <para>All ball bearings (whether manufactured here or abroad) are interchangeable in regard to standardized
                dimensions, tolerances and fits. However, for a given shaft size, there are standard bearings for light,
                medium and heavy-duty service.
            </para>
            <para>Numbers and symbols stamped on inner and outer races of bearings designate size and type.</para>
            <para>Numbering systems of different bearing manufacturers, however, have not been standardized. Consult
                interchangeable tables and use proper bearings for replacement parts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_32.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
