<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - CLEAN AND
        INSPECT - INSPECT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="8">
        <title>INSPECT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>It is important to inspect all parts before the transmission is assembled. Check all parts for wear
                and replace damaged parts. Replacement of damaged parts now will prevent failure of the assembly later.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tapered Roller Bearing Cone</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The bearing cup and bearing cone must be replaced as an assembly except when the cup is loose
                        in the bore. If the cup is loose in the bore, install an oversize cup. In all other situations,
                        do not replace the cup or the cone separately. Replace the cup and cone in a matched set from
                        the same manufacturer.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Inspect the cup, cone, rollers and cage of all tapered roller bearings. If any of the following
                conditions exist, the cup and cone must be replaced.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The outer surface of the large diameter end of the rollers is worn level with or below
                    the center (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303312">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The radius at the large diameter end of the rollers is worn to a sharp edge (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303312">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303312" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Worn Outer Surface and Worn Radius</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A visible roller groove is worn in the inner race surfaces of the cup or the cone. The
                    groove can be seen at the small or large diameter end of both parts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303313">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303313" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Visible Roller Groove</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Deep cracks or breaks in the surface of the cup, cone inner race or roller (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303314">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303314" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303314.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Deep Cracks or Breaks</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bright wear marks on the outer surface of the roller cage (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303315">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Etching or pitting on rollers and on the surfaces of the cup and cone inner race that
                    touch the rollers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303315">Figure 15.</hotlnk>)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303315" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303315.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Bright Wear Marks and Etching or Pitting</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spalling or flaking on the cup and cone inner face surfaces that touch the rollers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303316">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303316" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303316.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Spalling or Flaking</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.2. Tapered Roller Bearing Cups</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The bearing cup and bearing cone must be replaced as an assembly except when the cup is loose
                        in the bore. If the cup is loose in the bore, install an oversize cup. In all other situations,
                        do not replace the cup or cone separately. Replace the cup and cone in a matched set from the
                        same manufacturer.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Normal cup wear is shown as an even wear across the surface of the cup (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303317">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Small indentations are acceptable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303317" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303317.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Normal Cup Wear</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace cups with small spalling or flaking marks or light bruising (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303318">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303318" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303318.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Cup with Small Spalls And Bruises</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace cups with large spalls and deep indentations
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303319">(Figure 19).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303319" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303319.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Cup With Large Spalls</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.3. Ball Bearings</title>
            <para>Inspect ball bearings for wear and damage. Make sure the bearings rotate in the race. Make sure the
                outer race is not worn or damaged. On bearings with grooves, make sure the grooves are not worn or
                damaged. Replace any worn or damaged bearings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.4. Gears</title>
            <para>Inspect the teeth of the gears for wear and damage. Inspect the splines inside the gears for wear and
                damage. Inspect the gears for cracks or pits. Replace gears that are worn, damaged, or cracked.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.5. Shafts</title>
            <para>Inspect the splines and groves for wear and damage. Make sure the shafts are not twisted. Make sure
                threads on the end of the shafts are not worn or damaged. Replace any worn or damaged shafts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.6. O-Rings and Oil Seals</title>
            <para>Inspect the O-rings and oil seals for cuts and cracks. Make sure the parts are not brittle or hard.
                Replace any worn, damaged or hard O-rings and oil seals.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.7. Clutch Collars</title>
            <para>Inspect the teeth of the outside of the clutch collar for wear and damage. Inspect the splines inside
                the clutch collar for wear and damage. Replace any worn or damaged clutch collars.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.8. Case Housings</title>
            <para>Inspect the case housings for cracks. Replace cracked housings.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.9. Top Cover</title>
            <para>Inspect tips of the forks for wear and damage. Make sure forks are not bent. Make sure the shift rails
                are not worn or damaged. Inspect balls and springs for wear or damage. Replace any worn or damaged
                parts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5.1.10. Output Yokes</title>
            <para>Inspect the seal surface, splines and end of the output yoke for wear and damage. Do not sand or grind
                the seal surface. Replace any worn or damaged parts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
