<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - DRIVETRAIN FAILURE ANALYSIS - TRANSMISSION COMPLAINTS -
        NOISE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>NOISE</title>
        <para>There will always be a certain level of noise due to normal transmission operation. However, excessive
            noise or unusual noise such as a whine, growl or squeal indicates some kind of problem.
        </para>
        <para>The transmission can be the source of excessive noise or the noise can originate elsewhere in the vehicle
            and appear to be coming from the transmission. The following are examples of noise originating in the
            transmission:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Knocking or Thudding.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Gears - Bumps or swells on gear teeth. These can be identified as highly polished spots
                    on the face of the gear tooth. This noise is more prominent when the gear is loaded which helps
                    locate the source at a specific gear position. Bumps or swells can be removed with a hone or small
                    hand grinder.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Bearings - Noise comes in at low shaft speeds in any position. It is caused by bearings
                    with damaged balls or rollers, or with pitted and spalled raceways.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cracked Gear - A cracked gear or broken shock loading or by pressing on the shaft during
                    installation will produce this sound at low speeds. At high speeds, a howl will be present.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">High Pitch Whine or Squeal.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Gear Wear - This noise will develop from normal gear wear including tooth pitting from
                    excessive use. In advanced deterioration, a howl will result.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Mismatched Gear Set - The wear pattern on the face of the gear teeth will be uneven.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Bearings - Pinched bearings, having inadequate radial or axial clearance.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Growling.</para>
            <para>Timing Error - Incorrect timing of the transmission during assembly or due to a gear turning on the
                countershaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Jarring.</para>
            <para>Bearings - Countershaft and mainshaft bearings with excessive axial and radial clearances. Excessive
                radial clearance in countershaft bearings increases the center distance between shafts and results in
                loading the tips of the gear teeth. This can result in tooth fracture.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13002_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13002_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
