<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER AUTOMATE-2 - TROUBLESHOOTING (ELECTRICAL) - CONFIRMING PROPER OPERATION OF
        SPEED SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1302218" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONFIRMING PROPER OPERATION OF SPEED SENSOR</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the gap adjustment of the sensor on the output shaft. The sensor should be softly
                bottomed against the gear and then backed out 1/2 turn and locked (.031 inch gap).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After adjusting the sensor correctly, measure the coil resistance between pins A and B on
                each output connector. Resistance should be a maximum of 1,500 ohms.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check for shorts to the sensor housing case (ground) and between coils. If there are any
                doubts, replace the sensor and check for proper functioning.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the Controller to Transmission Wiring Harness by placing a jumper across the 2 pin
                sensor connector and measuring resistance between pins 8 and 9 of the J5 transmission computer
                connector. Refer to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x1302218">Controller to Transmission Wiring Harness diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If resistance is less than 5 ohms</emph>, the Controller to Transmission Wiring
                Harness is functioning properly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If resistance is greater than 5 ohms</emph>, replace the Controller to
                Transmission Wiring Harness.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Some engines and vehicles use the speed information that the transmission computer makes
                available. This information is sent out on the Controller to Vehicle Wiring Harness. Check for opens or
                shorts in this system. For complete troubleshooting information, obtain the specific wiring information
                for the vehicle being serviced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13022m7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13022m7" filename="../figg13/G13022m7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 227. AUTOMATE-2 WIRING DIAGRAM</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302217.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_52.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
