<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - AIR SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x1302701">
        <title>AIR SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>If the transmission fails to make a range shift or shifts too slowly, the fault may be in the Range
                Shift Air System or actuating components of the shifter housing assembly.
            </para>
            <para>To locate the trouble, the following checks should be made with normal vehicle air pressure applied to
                the system, but with the engine off.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>NEVER WORK UNDER A VEHICLE WHILE THE ENGINE IS RUNNING as personal injury may result from the
                        sudden and unintended movement of vehicle under power. Always place transmission in the neutral
                        position.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">INCORRECT AIR LINE HOOK-UPS</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, move the control that provides range selection UP and
                    DOWN.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the air lines are crossed between control valve and slave valve, there will be
                        CONSTANT AIR flowing from the exhaust port of control valve WHILE IN HIGH RANGE.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the air lines are crossed between the slave valve and range cylinder, the
                        transmission gearing will not correspond with the range selection. A LOW RANGE selection will
                        result in a HIGH RANGE engagement and vice versa.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">AIR LEAKS</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, coat all air lines and fittings with soapy water and check
                    for leaks, moving the control that provides range selection UP and DOWN.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there is a steady leak from the exhaust port of control valve, O-rings and/or
                        related parts of the control valve are defective.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there is a steady leak from breather of slave valve: an O-ring in the valve is
                        defective, or there is a leak past O-rings of range cylinder piston.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If transmission fails to shift into LOW RANGE or is slow to make the range shift and
                        the case is pressurized, see Check No. 7 of this section.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tighten all loose connections and replace defective O-rings and parts.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">AIR FILTER/REGULATOR</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, check the breather of air filter/regulator assembly. There
                    should be NO AIR leaking from this port. The complete assembly should be replaced if a steady leak
                    is found.
                </para>
                <para>Cut off the vehicle air supply to the air filter/regulator assembly, disconnect the air line at
                    fitting in Supply OUTLET and install an air gauge in the opened port. Bring the vehicle air pressure
                    to normal. Regulated air pressure should be 57.5 to 62.5 psi.
                </para>
                <para>DO NOT ADJUST SCREW AT BOTTOM OF REGULATOR TO OBTAIN CORRECT READINGS. The air regulator has been
                    PRE-ADJUSTED within the correct operating limits. Any deviation from these limits, especially with
                    regulators that have been in operation for some time, is likely to be caused by dirt or worn parts.
                    If replacement or cleaning of the filter element does nothing to correct the air pressure readings,
                    replace the complete assembly, as the air regulator is non-serviceable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">RANGE VALVE</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, select HIGH RANGE and disconnect the 1/8 inch O.D. air line
                    at the OUTLET or "P" Port of the control valve.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When LOW RANGE is selected, a steady blast of air will flow from opened port. Select
                        HIGH RANGE to shut off air flow. This indicates the control valve is operating properly.
                        Reconnect air line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the control valve does not operate properly, check for restrictions and air
                        leaks. Leaks indicate defective or worn O-rings.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">HIGH RANGE OPERATION</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, select LOW RANGE and disconnect the 1/4 inch I.D. air line
                    at the port of the range cylinder cover. Make sure this line leads from the High Range or "H" Port
                    of the slave valve.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When HIGH RANGE is selected, a steady blast of air should flow from the disconnected
                        line. Select LOW RANGE to shut off air flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Move the shift lever to a gear position and select HIGH RANGE. There should be NO
                        AIR flowing from disconnected line. Return the gear shift lever to the neutral position. There
                        should now be a steady flow of air from the disconnected line. Select LOW RANGE to shut off air
                        flow and reconnect the air line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the air system does not operate accordingly, the slave valve or actuating
                        components of the shifter housing assembly are defective.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>RANGE PRESELECTION</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The plunger pin, located in the case bore between the slave valve and actuating plunger of the shifter
                housing, prevents the slave valve from operating while the shift lever is in a gear position. When the
                lever is moved to or through the neutral position, the pin is released and the slave valve becomes
                operational.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">LOW RANGE OPERATION</para>
                <para>With the gear shift lever in neutral, select HIGH RANGE and disconnect the 1/4 inch I.D. air line
                    at the fitting on the range cylinder housing. Make sure this line leads from the LOW Range or "L"
                    Port of the slave valve.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When LOW RANGE is selected, a steady blast of air should flow from the disconnected
                        line. Select HIGH RANGE to shut off air flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Move the shift lever to a gear position and select LOW RANGE. There should be NO AIR
                        flowing from the disconnected line. Return the gear shift lever to the neutral position. There
                        should now be a steady flow of air from the disconnected line. Select HIGH RANGE to shut off air
                        flow and reconnect the air line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the air system does not operate accordingly, the slave valve or actuating
                        components of the shifter housing assembly are defective.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">RANGE CYLINDER (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302704">Figure 4</hotlnk>)
                </para>
                <figure id="f1302704" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1302704" filename="../figg13/G1302704.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Range Cylinder</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>If any of the seals in the range cylinder assembly are defective, the range shift will be
                    affected.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A leak at O-ring A results in complete failure to make a range shift; steady flow of
                        air from breather of slave valve in both ranges.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A leak at gasket B results in a steady flow of air to atmosphere while in HIGH
                        RANGE.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A leak at O-ring C results in a slow shift to LOW RANGE; pressurizing of
                        transmission case.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
