<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="7">
            <title>UPPER AND LOWER MAIN COUNTERSHAFT ASSEMBLIES</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The upper and lower countershafts are each serviced in the same way.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g5">Figure 165</hotlnk>
                        to identify the components of the countershaft assembly for the transmission models.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f13033g5" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033g5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 165. Components Of The Upper and Lower Main Countershaft Assemblies</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate all the parts with new oil that is used in the transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Transmissions:</emph>
                    install the roll pin in the hole in the groove for the key
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g6">(Figure 166)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are worn
                        or damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a punch and a hammer to install the key in the groove. On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Transmissions</emph>, make sure the taper on the end of the key is
                    installed toward the roll pin
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g6">(Figure 166)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033G6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG13/G13033G6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 166. Make Sure Taper on End of Key is Toward Roll Pin</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the first or the second gear on a press so that the hub is toward the bottom of the
                    press. Put the shaft in the gear. Make sure the slot in the gear is aligned with the key. Press the
                    shaft until the first gear touches the gear on the countershaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g7">Figure 167)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033G7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033g7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 167. Put First or Second Gear on a Press</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the second or third gear on a press. Put the shaft in the gear. Make sure the slot
                    in the gear is aligned with the key. Press the shaft until the hub of the second gear touches the
                    hub of the first gear (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g8">Figure 168).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033g8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033g8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 168. Put Second or Third Gear on a Press</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the third or overdrive gear on a press so that the hub is away from the top of the
                    press. Put the shaft in the gear. Make sure the slot in the gear is aligned with the key. Press the
                    shaft until the hub of the third gear touches the hub of the second gear
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033g9">(Figure 169)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033g9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033g9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 169. Put Third or Overdrive Gear on a Press</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the PTO gear on the press so that the chamfered side of the teeth is toward the top
                    of the press. Put the shaft in the gear. Makes sure the slot in the gear is aligned with the key in
                    the shaft. Press the PTO gear on the shaft until the PTO hub touches the hub of the third or
                    overdrive gear.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the main drive gear on a press so that the large hub of the gear is toward the PTO
                    gear. Put the shaft in the gear. Make sure the slot in the gear is aligned with the key in the
                    shaft. Put a sleeve on top of the shaft. Press the shaft into the gear until the hub of the main
                    drive gear touches the hub of the PTO gear
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033h0">(Figure 170).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033h0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033h0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 170. Put Main Drive Gear on a Press</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use the bearing inner race for installation. If pressure is applied to the bearing cage, the
                        bearing will be damaged.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front and rear countershaft bearing cones in one of the following ways:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a sleeve or a bearing installation tool to install the cones. Make sure the
                        bottom of the cone touches the shoulder on the shaft
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13033h1">(Figure 171).</hotlnk>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Wear insulated gloves or similar protection to prevent possible burns when handling
                                hot components.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Heat the bearing cone to install the cone on the shaft. Make sure the bottom of the
                        cone touches the shoulder on the shaft.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13033h1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033h1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 171. Install Cones</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_46.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
