<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Transmission Drive Cycle Test</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If equipped, turn the power take-off (PTO) unit off for correct test results. For a description of
                    PTO operation, refer to Transmission Electronic Control System in this section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Always drive the vehicle in a safe manner according to driving conditions and obey all traffic
                    laws.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The Transmission Drive Cycle Test must be followed exactly. Malfunctions must occur 4 times
                    consecutively for the shift error DTC to be set. Torque converter clutch (TCC) failures must occur 5
                    times consecutively for a continuous TCC DTC code to be set.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When carrying out the Transmission Drive Cycle Test, refer to the Solenoid Operation Chart for
                    correct solenoid operation.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>After carrying out the Quick Test, use the Transmission Drive Cycle Test for checking continuous codes.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Record and then erase the Quick Test codes.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Warm the engine to normal operating temperature.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Make sure the transmission fluid level is correct.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With the transmission range selector lever in (D), moderately accelerate from stop to 80 km/h (50
                    mph). This allows the transmission to shift into 5th gear. Hold the vehicle speed and throttle
                    position steady for a minimum of 15 seconds.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With the transmission in 5th gear and a steady vehicle speed and throttle position, lightly apply
                    and release the brake pedal enough to operate the stop lamps. Hold the vehicle speed and throttle
                    position steady for a minimum of 15 seconds.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Brake to a stop and remain stopped for a minimum of 20 seconds.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Repeat Steps 4 through 6 at least 5 times.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Carry out Quick Test and record continuous codes.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">After On-Board Diagnostics</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The vehicle wiring harness, transmission control module (TCM) and non-transmission sensors can
                    affect transmission operations. Repair these concerns first.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>After the On-Board Diagnostics procedures are completed, repair all DTCs.</para>
        <para>Always repair all non-transmission-related DTCs first, then repair any transmission-related DTCs. Refer to
            the Diagnostic Trouble Code Charts in this section for information on condition and symptoms. This chart
            will be helpful in referring to the correct manual(s) and to aid in diagnosing internal transmission
            concerns and external non-transmission inputs. The pinpoint tests are used in diagnosing electrical concerns
            of the transmission. Make sure the vehicle wiring harness and the TCM are diagnosed as well. The Engine
            Diagnostics Manual will aid in diagnosing non-transmission-related electronic components.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Before Pinpoint Tests</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Prior to entering pinpoint tests, check the transmission control module (TCM) wiring harness for
                    correct connections, bent or broken pins, corrosion, loose wires, correct routing, correct seals and
                    their condition. Check the TCM, sensors and actuators for damage.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a concern still exists after electrical diagnosis has been carried out, refer to Diagnosis By
                    Symptom in this section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>If DTCs appear while carrying out the on-board diagnostics, refer to the Diagnostic Trouble Code Charts in
            this section for the appropriate procedure. Prior to entering pinpoint tests, refer to any TSIs and ISIS
            messages for transmission concerns.
        </para>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
