<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DISASSEMBLY</title>
            <para>It is assumed in the detailed disassembly instructions that the lubricant has been drained from
                transmission, the necessary linkage and air lines disconnected and the transmission has been removed
                from vehicle chassis. Removal of the gear shift lever housing assembly (or remote control assembly) is
                included in the detailed instructions (DISASSEMBLE and REASSEMBLE, GEAR SHIFT LEVER ASSEMBLY); however,
                this assembly MUST be detached from shifter housing before the transmission can be removed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FOLLOW CLOSELY EACH PROCEDURE IN THE DETAILED INSTRUCTIONS, MAKING USE OF THE TEXT,
                    ILLUSTRATIONS AND PHOTOGRAPHS PROVIDED.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">BEARINGS-Carefully wash and relubricate all reusable bearings as removed and
                    protectively wrap until ready for use. Remove bearings planned to be reused with pullers designed
                    for this purpose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ASSEMBLIES-When disassembling the various assemblies, such as the mainshaft,
                    countershafts, and shifter housing, lay all parts on a clean bench in the same sequence as removed.
                    This procedure will simplify reassembly and reduce the possibility of losing parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SNAP RINGS-Remove snap rings with pliers designed for this purpose. Snap rings removed
                    in this manner can be reused, if they are not sprung or loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">INPUT SHAFT-The input shaft can be removed from transmission without removing the
                    countershafts, mainshaft, or main drive gear. Special procedures are required and provided in this
                    manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">CLEANLINESS-Provide a clean place to work. It is important that no dirt or foreign
                    material enters the unit during repairs. Dirt is an abrasive and can damage bearings. It is always
                    good practice to clean the outside of the unit before starting the planned disassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">WHEN USING TOOLS TO REMOVE OR INSTALL PARTS-Always apply force to shafts, housings,
                    etc., with restraint. Movement of some parts is restricted. Never apply force to the part being
                    driven after it stops solidly. The use of soft hammers, bars and mauls for all disassembly work is
                    recommended.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
