<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>9 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS INTERNATIONAL PS125-9A, PS140-9A, PSO125-9A, PSO140-9A AND PSO150-9A - TROUBLESHOOTING
        - NOISY OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>NOISY OPERATION</title>
        <para>Noise is usually a very elusive problem, and is generally not the fault of the transmission. Mechanics
            should road test the vehicle to determine if the driver's complaint of noise is actually in the
            transmission.
        </para>
        <para>In numerous instances drivers have insisted noise was coming from the transmission. Investigations
            revealed it was caused by one of the following conditions:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>Fan out of balance or blades were bent.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Defective vibration dampers.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Crankshaft out of balance.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Flywheel out of balance.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Loose flywheel mounting bolts.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Rough engine idle producing rattle in gear train.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch assembly out of balance.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Loose or broken engine mounts.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Power take-off was engaged.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Worn universal joints.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Driveshaft out of balance.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Universal joint angles out of plane or at excessive angles.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Center bearings in driveline dry. not mounted properly.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wheels out of balance.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Tire treads humming or vibrating at certain speeds.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Air leaks on suction side of induction system. especially with turbo-chargers.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>Mechanics should try to locate and eliminate noise by means other than a transmission removal or an
            overhaul. However, if the noise appears to be in the transmission, try to determine what position the gear
            shift lever is in when the noise occurs. If the noise is evident in only one gear position, the problem is
            generally traceable to the operating gears. Next, try to break the noise down into the following
            classifications:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">Growling, humming and grinding.</emph>
                    These noises are caused by worn, chipped, rough or cracked gears. As gears continue to wear, the
                    grinding noise will be noticeable, particularly in the gear position that throws the greatest load
                    on the worn gear.
                </para>
                <para>A lack of lubricant or use of improper lubricant can also result in growling and grinding noises.
                    This is because there is insufficient lubricant to cool and cover the gears, which allows
                    metal-to-metal contact.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">Hissing, thumping and bumping.</emph>Hissing noises can be caused by bad
                    bearings. As bearings wear and retainers start to break up, etc., the noise could change to a
                    thumping or bumping.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">Gear whine.</emph>
                    This is usually caused by lack of backlash between mating gears. Improper PTO shimming is the big
                    offender here.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">Vibration.</emph>Today's improved highways mean entire power trains are cruising
                    at higher RPMs. These higher speeds mean damage caused by driveline vibration is more obvious than
                    in the past.
                </para>
                <para>When the maximum RPM of a shaft is reached, it begins to bow. A resonant hum can be heard, and a
                    vibration will be set up. This type vibration can cause gear seizures, broken synchronizer pins,
                    bearing failures, brinelling and corrosion.
                </para>
                <para>During acceleration and deceleration, the shaft may pass through half-critical vibration (half the
                    maximum RPM of the shaft). A whine or boom may be heard at this point.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="italic">Metallic rattles.</emph>
                    These noises within the transmission usually result from a variety of conditions. Engine torsional
                    vibrations are transmitted to the transmission through the clutch. In heavy duty equipment, clutch
                    discs with vibration dampers are not used, so a rattle-particularly in neutral-is common with diesel
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <para>In general, engine speeds should be 600 RPM or above to eliminate objectionable rattles and
                    vibration during the idle. A defective or faulty injector would cause a rough or lower idle speed,
                    and possibly a rattle in the transmission. A rattle can also be caused by excessive backlash between
                    the PTO input gear and the transmission output gear.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
