<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 -
        Lubrication and Maintenance - Lubrication
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Lubrication</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use only SAE Grade 50W oil, Meritor specification O-81, in the transfer case.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>For complete lubrication information for Meritor's transfer cases, refer to Maintenance Manual 1,
                Lubrication. To obtain a copy of this publication, call Arvin Meritor's Customer Service Center at
                800-535-5560 or check the web at arvinmeritor.com/tech_library/home.asp
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lubricant Temperatures</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Meritor transfer cases may operate above 190&#176;F (88&#176;C) without damage. However, if
                        the oil temperature reaches 250&#176;F (121&#176;C), stop the vehicle immediately. Check for the
                        cause of overheating. Maximum continuous oil temperature must not exceed 225&#176;F (107&#176;C).
                        Damage to components can result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The transfer case oil sump should have a maximum continuous operating temperature of 225&#176;F (107&#176;C)
                and an absolute maximum temperature of 250&#176;F (121&#176;C).
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the vehicle temperature reaches 250&#176;F (121&#176;C):</emph>
                        Stop the vehicle immediately. Check for the cause of overheating.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the transfer case continuous sump temperature is over 225&#176;F (107&#176;C)
                            caused by high input speeds with high ambient temperatures and poor air circulation:
                        </emph>
                        Use a lighter viscosity oil recommended by Meritor. Also use a lighter viscosity oil in
                        extremely cold climates.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Multi-Viscosity Oils</title>
            <para>Meritor does not approve multi-viscosity motor oils. Refer to Maintenance Manual 1, Lubrication, for a
                list of approved oils.
            </para>
            <para>Meritor does approve petroleum-base and synthetic-base oils.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Do Not Install API GL-5 Oils</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only use oil specified by Meritor in a transfer case. Do not install API GL-5 oils, which
                        contain extreme pressure (EP) additives. These additives can form sludge at normal operating
                        temperatures. Damage to components will result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Do not install API GL-5 oils in a transfer case. This specification contains extreme pressure (EP)
                additives that can form sludge at normal operating temperatures and damage transfer case components.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Petroleum-Base and Synthetic-Base Oils</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not mix or switch petroleum-base synthetic-base oils in a transfer case. Damage to
                        components will result. Only install the same oil type that was originally specified throughout
                        the life of the transfer case.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Meritor approves both petroleum-base and synthetic-base oils. However, do not mix or switch these oils
                in a transfer case. Damage to components will result. Use the same oil type that was originally
                specified in the transfer case.
            </para>
            <para>Synthetic oils must be approved by Meritor's engineering department. Refer to publication TP-90114 for
                a list of approved distributors. To obtain this publication, call Arvin Meritor's Customer Service
                Center at 800-535-5560 or check the web at arvinmeritor.com/tech_library/home.asp
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_41.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_43.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
