<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Torque Converter Diagnosis</title>
        <para>Prior to installing a torque converter, all diagnostic procedures must be followed. This is to prevent the
            unnecessary installation of new or remanufactured torque converters. Only after a complete diagnostic
            evaluation can the decision be made to install new or remanufactured torque converters.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If equipped, turn the power take-off (PTO) unit off for correct test results. For a description of
                    PTO operation, refer to Transmission Electronic Control System in this section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>During PTO operation, the on-board diagnostics will be disabled. However, the circuit checks made by the
            diagnostic system and the FMEM will continue. The PTO must be turned off to do on-board diagnostics.
        </para>
        <para>Begin with the normal diagnostic procedures as follows:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Preliminary Inspection.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Know and Understand the Customer's Concern.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify the Concern - Carry out the Torque Converter Clutch Operation Test in this section.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Carry out Diagnostic Procedures.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Run on-board diagnostics. Refer to On-Board Diagnostics with diagnostic tool in this
                            section.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>Repair all non-transmission-related DTCs first.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Repair all transmission DTCs.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Rerun on-board diagnostics to verify repair.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Carry out Line Pressure Test in this section.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Carry out Stall Speed Test in this section.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Carry out Diagnostic Routines in this section.</para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>Use the Diagnosis by Symptom Index to locate the appropriate routine that best
                                    describes the symptom(s). The routine will list all possible components that may
                                    cause or contribute to the symptom. Check each component listed. Diagnose and repair
                                    as required, before repairing the torque converter.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Torque Converter Operation Test</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This test verifies that the torque converter clutch control system and the torque converter are operating
            correctly.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Carry out Quick Test, refer to On-Board Diagnostics with diagnostic tool in this section. Check
                    for DTCs. Refer to the Diagnostic Trouble Code Chart in this section.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect a tachometer to the engine.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Bring the engine to normal operating temperature by driving the vehicle at highway speeds for
                    approximately 15 minutes in (D) position.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>After normal operating temperature is reached, maintain a constant vehicle speed of about 80 km/h
                    (50 mph) and tap brake pedal with the left foot.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine rpm should increase when brake pedal is tapped and decrease about 5 seconds after pedal is
                    released. If this does not occur, refer to Diagnosis By Symptom - Torque Converter Clutch Operation
                    Concerns in this section.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
