<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - REMOVE - AUXILIARY SECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="6">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the transmission in the vertical position. Put blocks under the clutch housing to
                prevent damage to the input shaft. Removal can also be completed in the horizontal position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the four bolts and the auxiliary countershaft rear bearing cover, gasket, and rear
                bearing shim (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302728">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1302728" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302728" filename="../figg13/G1302728.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Remove Auxiliary Countershaft Rear Bearing Cover, Gasket, and Rear Bearing Shim
            </caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Auxiliary countershaft retaining straps may be installed to hold countershafts in place (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302729">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Auxiliary can be removed without straps; use caution.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1302729" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302729" filename="../figg13/G1302729.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 29. Auxiliary Countershaft Retaining Straps May Be Installed to Hold Countershafts in
                Place
            </caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install an auxiliary countershaft retaining strap with three 3/8 inch x 1 inch clean bolts.
                Place a flat washer under the strap to prevent damage to the rear auxiliary countershaft bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not use an air gun. Tighten by hand until the bolts are snug.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat Steps 2 and 3 for the remaining auxiliary countershaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the 19 bolts that hold the auxiliary section to the transmission case (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302730">Figure 30</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1302730" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302730" filename="../figg13/G1302730.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 30. Remove Bolts Holding Auxiliary Section to Transmission Case</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>There are three lengths of bolts; note their location.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert three bolts in the tapped holes of the housing flange (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302731">Figure 31</hotlnk>). Tighten evenly to move auxiliary section to the rear and
                just far enough from the front section to break the gasket seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1302731" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302731" filename="../figg13/G1302731.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 31. Insert Bolts in Housing Flange</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolts and attach a chain hoist to the auxiliary section. Move the assembly to the
                rear until free of the front section and remove the gasket (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302732">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1302732" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302732" filename="../figg13/G1302732.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 32. Move Assembly to Rear</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The auxiliary section can also be removed with the transmission set in the vertical position
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302733">Figure 33</hotlnk>). Block under the clutch housing to prevent damage to the
                input shaft. Remove the retaining bolts from the housing flange. Lift the assembly from the front
                section. Remove the gasket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1302733" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302733" filename="../figg13/G1302733.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 33. Auxiliary Section Can Be Removed With Transmission Set in Vertical Position</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
