<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 18 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14618 AND RTLO-16618
        SERIES - MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1301902">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1301902" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1301902" filename="../figg13/G1301902.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Maintenance Checkpoints</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The following items refer to callout numbers in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1301902">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Air System and Connections. Check for leaks, worn air lines, loose connections and bolts.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13019_9.xml" xrefid="hl1301902">AIR SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl1301902"/>
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Housing Mounting. Check clutch housing bolts for looseness.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Release Bearing (Not Shown). Remove hand hole cover and check the radial and axial
                clearance of the release bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Pedal Shaft and Bores. Pry upward on shafts to check wear. If excessive movement is
                found, remove the clutch release mechanism and check bushings in bores and wear on shafts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricant. Change at specified service intervals. Use only the types and grades as
                recommended in GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill and Drain Plugs. Remove fill plugs and check level of lubricant at specified intervals.
                Tighten fill and drain plugs securely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Bolts and Gaskets. Check all bolts, especially those on PTO covers and rear bearing covers
                for looseness which would cause oil leakage. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13019_81.xml" xrefid="hl1301903">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="hl1301903"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . Check PTO opening and rear bearing covers for oil leakage due to faulty gasket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever. Check for looseness and free play in the housing.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever Housing Assembly. Remove the air lines at the air valve and remove the gear
                shift lever housing assembly from the transmission. Check the tension spring and washer for set and
                wear. Check the gear shift lever pivot pin and slot for wear. Check bottom end of gear shift lever for
                wear and check the slot of yokes and blocks in the shifter housing for wear at contact points with the
                shift lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Universal Joint Companion Flange Nut (Not Shown). Check for tightness. Tighten to
                recommended torque. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13019_81.xml" xrefid="hl1301903">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="hl1301903"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Output Shaft (Not Shown). Pry upward against the output shaft to check radial clearance in
                the mainshaft rear bearing.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If necessary, use solvent and shop rag to clean sealing surface of companion flange or yoke.
                        DO NOT USE CROCUS CLOTH, EMERY PAPER OR OTHER ABRASIVE MATERIALS THAT WILL MAR SURFACE FINISH.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Splines on Output Shaft (Not Shown). Check for wear from movement and chucking action of the
                universal joint companion flange or yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mainshaft Rear Bearing Cove. Check the oil seal for wear.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
