<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 -
        Assembly - Idler Shaft Bearing End Play Adjustment
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Idler Shaft Bearing End Play Adjustment</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Determine idler shaft bearing end play before final assembly. Seals should not be installed until
                    end plays are set.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Temporarily install at least six case-to-cover capscrews evenly spaced around the case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the transfer case so that the front of the case faces UPWARD.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the 3/8-inch (9.5 mm) pipe plugs at the idler shaft locations on the front of the
                case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To prepare to check idler shaft bearing end play, insert a 1/2"-13 bolt into the shaft
                through the pipe plug hole, until the bolt is fully seated. The bolt should extend out of the transfer
                case enough for you to use it to lift the idler shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the bolt so that it bottoms in the shaft for an accurate end play measurement.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the idler shaft several times to help seat the bearing cones.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set up the dial indicator to check idler shaft bearing end play. Center the dial indicator
                on the bolt head. Zero the indicator (Figure 51).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303551" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303551.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 51. Center Dial Indicator on Bolt Head</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use pry bars to lift up on the bolt head to obtain a measurement. To obtain a consistent and
                averaged reading, perform this operation two or three times. Record the reading for this shaft.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is greater than 0.001- to 0.005-inch (0.025-0.127
                            mm):
                        </emph>
                        Add shims to reduce end play.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is less than specification:</emph>
                        Remove shims to increase end play. Bearing shims come in 0.003-, 0.005- and 0.010-inch (0.08,
                        0.13 and 0.25 mm) thicknesses.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolt from the shaft. Install the 3/8-inch pipe plug or breather assembly
                depending on shaft measured. Tighten the bolt to 20-25 lb-ft (27-34 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">MTC-4213 transfer case only:</emph>
                Check idler shaft bearing end play on the second idler shaft following Steps 4-9. Record the reading for
                this shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the bearing end play on all other shafts before splitting the case to adjust bearing
                end play on the idler shafts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the shims to achieve the correct bearing end play on all shafts as required. Refer to
                Shim Assembly in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
