<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RT-6613 SERIES - MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <figure id="f1303002" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1303002" filename="../figg13/g1303002.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Maintenance Checkpoints</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1303002">Figure 2</hotlnk>
            for the following items.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Air System and Connections. Check for leaks, worn air lines, loose connections and bolts.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13030_6.xml" xrefid="hl1303001">AIR SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl1303001"/>
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Housing Mounting. Check clutch housing bolts for looseness.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Release Bearing. Remove hand hole cover and check the radial and axial clearance of
                the release bearing. Check relative position of thrust surface of release bearing with thrust sleeve on
                push-type clutches.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Pedal Shaft and Bores. Pry upward on shafts to check wear. If excessive movement is
                found, remove the clutch release mechanism and check bushings in bores and wear on shafts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricant. Change at specified service intervals. Use only the types and grades as
                recommended in GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill and Drain Plugs. Remove fill plugs and check level of lubricant at specified intervals.
                Tighten fill and drain plugs securely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever. Check for looseness and free play in the housing. If the lever is loose in
                the housing, proceed with Step 8.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever Housing Assembly. Remove the air lines at the air valve and remove the gear
                shift lever housing assembly from the transmission. Check the tension spring and washer for set and
                wear. Check the gear shift lever pivot pin and slot for wear. Check the bottom end of the gear shift
                lever for wear and check the slot of yokes and blocks in the shifter housing for wear at contact points
                with the shift lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Universal Joint Companion Flange Nut (Not Shown). Check for tightness. Tighten to
                recommended torque. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13030_58.xml" xrefid="hl1303002">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="hl1303002"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Splines on the Output Shaft (Not Shown). Check for wear from movement and chucking action of
                the universal joint companion flange.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mainshaft Rear Bearing Cover (Not Shown). Check the oil seal for wear.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Output Shaft (Not Shown). Pry upward against the output shaft to check the radial clearance
                in the mainshaft rear bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
