<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 18 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14618 AND RTLO-16618
        SERIES - INSTALL - AUXILIARY SECTION AND SHIMMING PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="8">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION AND SHIMMING PROCEDURE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the middle bolt on each countershaft strap until the countershafts are snug. Shift
                the reduction sliding clutch into reduction. Attach a chain hoist to the output shaft.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The front box sliding clutches must be in the neutral position.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the transmission set in the vertical position, block under the clutch housing to
                prevent damage to the input shaft, and position the new gasket on the transmission case (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s2">Figure 282</hotlnk>). Lower the auxiliary assembly on the front case rear.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s2" filename="../figg13/G13019S2.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 282. Position New Gasket on Transmission Case</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Shift the reduction sliding clutch into deep reduction before installing the auxiliary.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite 242 or equivalent to the retaining bolt threads and install in the housing
                flange (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s3">Figure 283</hotlnk>). Tighten to 35 to 45 ft-lbs. (47 to 61 N&#183;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s3" filename="../figg13/G13019S3.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 283. Install Retaining Bolts in Housing Flange</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the countershaft straps. Make sure a 0.125 countershaft rear bearing shim is
                installed (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s4">Figure 284</hotlnk>). Be sure the countershaft rear bearing races are seated
                in the bearing bores.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s4" filename="../figg13/G13019S4.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 284. Install Countershaft Rear Bearing Shim</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install two clean 3/8" x 1" bolts without washers directly across from each other in each
                bearing cover (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s5">Figure 285</hotlnk>). Tapped holes in auxiliary case must be free of thread
                adhesive.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s5" filename="../figg13/G13019S5.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 285. Install Bolts Without Washers Directly Across From Each Other in Each Bearing
                    Cover
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the bolts to 7 in-lbs. (0.8 N&#183;m). DO NOT INSTALL THE COUNTERSHAFT REAR BEARING
                COVER GASKET (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s6">Figure 286</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s6" filename="../figg13/G13019S6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 286. Tighten Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the output shaft six times in the clockwise direction, then six times
                counterclockwise to seat the countershaft rear bearings. Use a feeler gauge, as close to one bolt
                location as possible, and measure the gap between the countershaft rear bearing cover and the auxiliary
                case (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s7">Figure 287</hotlnk>). Record the measurement. Using the average measurement,
                refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13019_76.xml" xrefid="hl1301910">Shimming Chart
                    <xref refid="hl1301910"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . Select the numbers in the left column that compare to the average measurement recorded from the
                countershaft rear bearing cover. Follow the column to the right to identify the proper shim to be used
                in the counter- shaft shim bores. Repeat this procedure for the other countershaft rear bearing cover.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s7" filename="../figg13/G13019S7.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 287. Measure Gap Between Countershaft Rear Bearing Cover and Auxiliary Case</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the countershaft rear bearing covers and gauging shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s8">Figure 288</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019s8" filename="../figg13/G13019S8.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 288. Remove Countershaft Rear Bearing Covers and Gauging Shims</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the correct shim has been selected, place the shim on the rear countershaft bearing
                race, and install the countershaft rear bearing cover and gasket (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019s9">Figure 289</hotlnk>). Check for proper shim alignment. If misaligned, the rear
                bearing cover may be damaged when the cover bolts are tightened. Position a new gasket on each
                countershaft rear bearing cover mounting surface and install both rear bearing covers. Apply Loctite 242
                or equivalent to the bolt threads. Install and tighten the bolts to 35 to 45 ft-lbs. (47 to 61 N&#183;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019s9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G13019S9.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 289. Install Countershaft Rear Bearing Cover and Gasket</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_69.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_71.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
