<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - AIR SYSTEM - SPLITTER SHIFT AIR SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="3">
        <title>SPLITTER SHIFT AIR SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>If the transmission fails to shift or shifts too slowly to or from the "split" position, the fault may
                be in the Splitter Shift Air System or related components of the Range Shift Air System.
            </para>
            <para>To locate the trouble, the following checks should be made with normal vehicle air pressure supplied
                to the system, but with the engine off.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>NEVER WORK UNDER A VEHICLE WHILE ENGINE IS RUNNING as personal injury may result from the
                        sudden and unintended movement of vehicle under power. Always place transmission in the neutral
                        position.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is assumed that correct PSl readings were obtained from the air filter/regulator and all
                        air lines have been checked for leaks.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Air Supply. With the gear shift lever in neutral, select HIGH or LOW RANGE and loosen
                    the connection at the "S" Port of the Roadranger Valve until it can be determined that AIR is
                    supplied to valve. Reconnect air line.
                </para>
                <para>If there is NO AIR, check for a restriction in the air line between the Roadranger valve and slave
                    valve. Make sure this line is connected to the fitting at the Supply Port of the slave valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Roadranger Valve. With the gear shift lever in neutral, disconnect the air line at the
                    Left Port of the splitter cylinder cover, making sure this line leads from the "SP" Port of the
                    Roadranger Valve.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">WHILE IN HIGH or LOW RANGE, move the Splitter Control Button FORWARD. There should
                        be AIR flowing from the disconnected line. Move the button REARWARD to shut off air flow and
                        reconnect the air line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the preceding conditions did not exist, the Roadranger valve is defective, or
                        there is a restriction in the air lines.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Splitter Cylinder (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302708">Figure 8</hotlnk>). If any of the seals in the splitter cylinder assembly
                    are defective, the splitter shift will be affected. The degree of air lost will govern the degree of
                    failure, from slow shifting to complete shift failure.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Leak at O-ring A results in a slow shift to engage rear auxiliary drive gear;
                        pressurizing of transmission case; auxiliary gearing can be disengaged.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Leak at O-ring B results in slow shifting or complete failure to engage and
                        disengage front or rear auxiliary drive gearing; steady flow of air from exhaust port of
                        Roadranger valve and/or cylinder cover when Splitter Control Button is in the REARWARD position.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Leak at gasket C results in a slow shift to disengage rear auxiliary drive gearing;
                        steady flow of air to atmosphere.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1302708" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1302708" filename="../figg13/g1302708.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Splitter Cylinder</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert Valve (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302709">Figure 9</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302710">Figure 10</hotlnk>). Any constant flow of air from the exhaust port of the
                    cylinder cover usually indicates a faulty insert valve. Exhaust should occur ONLY BRIEFLY when the
                    Splitter Control Button is moved FORWARD WHILE IN HIGH RANGE.
                </para>
                <para>A faulty insert valve, leaking at the O-rings of valve O.D. or from inner seals will result in
                    shift failure. Two indications of defective O-rings or seals are:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CONSTANT AIR flowing from the exhaust port of the cylinder cover.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CONSTANT AIR flowing from Exhaust Port "E" of the control valve WHILE SPLITTER
                        CONTROL BUTTON IS REARWARD (providing the control valve is operating properly).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>The three O-rings in position on the valve O.D. can be replaced. However, if an inner seal is damaged,
                the complete assembly MUST be replaced.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1302709" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1302709" filename="../figg13/g1302709.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Insert Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1302710" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1302710" filename="../figg13/g1302710.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Insert Valve</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
