<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Step numbers correspond to numbers in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1302401">Figure 1.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1302401" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1302401" filename="../figg13/G1302401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Maintenance Check Locations</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Air System and Connections. Check for leaks, worn air lines, loose connections and
                    bolts. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s13024_X1302401.xml" xrefid="x1302401">AIR SYSTEM.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clutch Housing Mounting. Check clutch housing bolts for looseness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clutch Release Bearing. Remove hand hole cover and check the radial and axial clearance
                    of the release bearing. Check relative position of thrust surface of release bearing with thrust
                    sleeve on push-type clutches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clutch Pedal Shaft and Bores. Pry upward on shafts to check wear. If excessive movement
                    is found, remove the clutch release mechanism and check bushings in bores and wear on shafts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricant. Change at specified service intervals. Use only the types and grades as
                    recommended in GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill and Drain Plugs. Remove fill plugs and check level of lubricant at specified
                    intervals. Tighten fill and drain plugs securely.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever. Check for looseness and free play in housing. If lever is loose in
                    housing, proceed to Step 8.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever Housing Assembly. Remove the air lines at the air valve and remove the
                    gear shift lever housing assembly from the transmission. Check tension spring and washer for set and
                    wear. Check the gear shift lever pivot pin and pivot pin slot for wear. Check bottom end of gear
                    shift lever for wear, and check slot of yokes and blocks in the shifter housing for wear at contact
                    points with shift lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Universal Joint Companion Flange or Yoke Nut (Not Shown). Check for tightness. Tighten
                    to recommended torque. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s13024_70.xml" xrefid="t1302403">TORQUE CHART.</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If necessary, use solvent and shop rag to clean sealing surface of companion flange or yoke.
                        DO NOT USE CROCUS CLOTH, EMERY PAPER OR OTHER ABRASIVE MATERIALS THAT WILL MAR SURFACE FINISH.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Splines on Output Shaft. Check for wear from movement and chucking action of the
                    universal joint companion flange or yoke.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mainshaft Rear Bearing Cover. Check oil seal for wear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Output Shaft. Pry upward against the output shaft to check radial clearance in the
                    mainshaft rear bearing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
