<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE -
        THIRTEEN-SPEED AUXILIARY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="29">
        <title>THIRTEEN-SPEED AUXILIARY</title>
        <figure id="f13033m9" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033m9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 229. 13-Speed Auxiliary</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m9">Figure 229.</hotlnk>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate all the parts of the auxiliary cover with new oil used in the transmission. Refer
                to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put timing marks on the OD gear. Mark one tooth with paint. Mark a second tooth opposite
                (180 degrees) the first timing mark
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n0">(Figure 230)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 230. Put Timing Marks on OD Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft on the work bench. Make sure the splined end of the shaft is up.</para>
            <para>Install the spacer on the output shaft. Make sure the small shoulder of the spacer is toward the
                splined end of the shaft for the output yoke
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n1">(Figure 231)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 231. Install Spacer on Output Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary OD gear on the output shaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n2">(Figure 232)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 232. Install Auxiliary OD Gear on Output Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft and OD gear assembly on a press. Support the shaft on the bottom of the
                shaft. Make sure the large threads on the shaft are toward the top of the press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a bearing cone on the shaft. Make sure the letters on the cone assembly are toward
                the gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n3">(Figure 233)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the cone. Press the cone on the shaft until the cone touches the gear. Make
                sure the gear and bearing cone rotates on the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n3">Figure 233</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 233. Install Bearing Cone</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the spacer on the shaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n4">(Figure 234).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 234. Install Spacer on Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the auxiliary cover in a press so that the outside of the cover is toward the top of the
                press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the inner bearing cup in the cover. Make sure the letters on the cup are toward you.
                Install a sleeve or a bearing installation tool on the race of the bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the inner cup into the cover until the top of the cup is 3/8 inch below the outer
                surface of the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n5">(Figure 235)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 235. Press Inner Cup into Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the outer cup on top of the inner cup. Make sure the letters on the cup are toward you (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n6">Figure 236</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve or installation tool on the top of the outer cup. Press both cups into the
                bore. The cups are correctly installed when the flange on the outer cup touches the shoulder in the bore
                of the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n6">(Figure 236</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 236. Put Outer Cup on Top of Inner Cup</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft and OD gear assembly in a press. Put a support under the gear. Make
                sure the large threads on the shaft are toward the top of the press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the auxiliary cover on the output shaft assembly. Rotate the cover to make sure the
                output shaft inner bearing cone is installed in the cup.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the spacer on the top of the inner bearing cone of the output shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the outer bearing cone on the output shaft. Make sure the letters on the cone are
                toward the top of the press.
            </para>
            <para>Install a sleeve on the outer bearing cone. Press the cone on the shaft and into the cup in the bore
                of the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n7">(Figure 237</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 237. Press Cone on Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the gear and cover assembly on a bench. Make sure the inside of the cover is toward
                you.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use paint to put timing marks on two teeth of each countershaft OD gear. Make sure the mark
                is aligned with the dot on the countershaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n8">(Figure 238).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 238. Put Timing Marks on Teeth of Countershaft OD Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the shaft in the fork. Make sure the holes in the shaft and fork are aligned (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033n9">Figure 239)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033n9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033n9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 239. Install Shaft in Fork</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bolt. Tighten to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new lockwire in the bolt and fork.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the low synchronizer on the hub and LO gear assembly
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o0">(Figure 240</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 240. Install Low Synchronizer on Hub and LO Gear Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the countershaft in a press so that the auxiliary gear is toward the bottom of the
                press. Support the countershaft on the gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the key in the groove on the shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the splitter gear on the shaft. Make sure the key is aligned with the slot in the
                gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the gear and press the gear on the shaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o1">(Figure 241)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 241. Press Gear on Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the rear cone on the countershaft so that the bottom of the cone is toward the gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the inner race of the cone. Press the cone on the countershaft. The cone is
                correctly installed when the bottom of the cone touches the gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o2">(Figure 242).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 242. Press Cone on Countershaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the countershaft over so that the splitter gear is toward the bottom of the press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the front cone on the countershaft so that the bottom of the cone is toward the gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the inner race of the cone. Press the cone on the countershaft. The cone is
                correctly installed when the bottom of the cone touches the gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o3">(Figure 243)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 243. Press Front Cone on Countershaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary countershafts in the cover. Make sure the timing marks on the OD gears
                are aligned. Make sure the countershaft bearing is completely installed in the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o4">(Figure 244)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 244. Install Auxiliary Countershafts in Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the collar on the output shaft. Install the splitter fork and shaft assembly on the
                splitter gear assembly. Move the fork so that the fork will not touch the splitter gear assembly during
                installation
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o5">(Figure 245).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 245. Install Collar, and Install Splitter Fork and Shaft Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the LO gear and synchronizer assembly on the output shaft inside the auxiliary
                cover. Make sure the high synchronizer is toward you. Makes sure the timing marks on all the gears are
                aligned
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o6">(Figure 246)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The end play of the auxiliary countershaft is checked when the auxiliary cover is installed on the
                    transmission.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f13033o6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 246. Install LO Gear and Synchronizer Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Transmissions</emph>: install the cups on the cones of the auxiliary
                countershafts. Install the correct selective snap rings that fasten the cups in the cover. Make sure the
                snap ring is completely installed in the groove
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o7">(Figure 247)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 2 Transmissions:</emph>
                install the cups on the cones of the auxiliary countershafts. Install the correct selective washers in
                front of the cups. Make sure the tabs in the washers are in the slots in the case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 247. Install Correct Selective Snap Rings</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the holding plates on both auxiliary countershafts. Use bolts to fasten the plates to
                the countershaft and cover. DO NOT CHANGE THE POSITION OF THE TRANSMISSION IN THE REPAIR STAND
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o8">(Figure 248).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 248. Put Holding Plates on Auxiliary Countershafts</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new nut and washer that fasten the LO gear to the output shaft. Tighten the nut to
                298 to 353 Nm (220 to 260 ft-lbs.)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033o9">(Figure 249).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033o9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033o9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 249. Install New Nut and Washer</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the HI-LO shift fork in position so that the fork engages the synchronizer collar. Makes
                sure the bore of the fork is aligned with the bore of the piston housing. Make sure the lock pin hole in
                the fork is installed away from the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p0">(Figure 250).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the HI-LO shift shaft from inside the front of the auxiliary cover. Make sure the
                threads on the end of the shaft are installed first. Rotate the shaft while pushing the shaft through
                the O-ring (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p0">Figure 250).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a pin and clip were used to fasten the HI-LO fork to the shaft, replace the pin and clip with a
                    nut and shoulder bolt.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the hole of the shaft with the hole of the shift fork. Install the bolt and lock nut.
                Tighten the nut to 11 to 16 Nm (8 to 12 ft-lbs.) (Figure 250).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 250. Install HI-LO Shift Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the cover in the fixture so that the outside of the cover is toward you.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a suitable tool to install a new bushing for the speedometer gear inside the output
                bearing retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new oil seal in the output bearing retainer
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p1">(Figure 251)</hotlnk>. Lubricate the outer diameter of the seal. Put the oil
                seal in the cover. Make sure the letters on the seal are installed away from the retainer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Hold the seal only on the outer diameter. Do not touch the inner diameter of the seal.
                        Touching contaminates the inner diameter of the seal and causes a leak between the shaft and
                        seal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use the correct tool to install the oil seal. If the correct tool is not used, the seal will
                        leak.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Use seal driver tool ZTSE-4424 to drive the seal into the cover. The seal is correctly installed when
                the flange of the seal touches the retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 251. Install New Oil Seal in Output Bearing Retainer</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a sealant dispenser and Loctite RTV Sealant #5699 or equivalent to make a 3 mm (1/8
                inch) gasket pattern on the cover for the output bearing retainer. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p2">Figure 252</hotlnk>
                for the gasket pattern. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13033_11.xml" xrefid="x1303304">INSTALLING THE SEALANT</hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the output bearing retainer on the auxiliary cover. Make sure the oil passage in the
                retainer is aligned over the oil hole in the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p2">(Figure 252)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 252. Gasket Pattern</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the mounting bolts for the output bearing retainer. Tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm
                (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-rings and bores of the piston housing with a silicone lubricant such as Dow
                Corning #111 Silicone Grease or equivalent. Install the O-rings in the grooves in the bores of the
                piston housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p3">(Figure 253).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 253. Install O-Rings in Grooves</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a sealant dispenser and Loctite RTV Sealant #5699 or equivalent to make a gasket pattern
                on the piston housing. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p4">Figure 254</hotlnk>
                for the gasket pattern. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13033_11.xml" xrefid="x1303304">INSTALLING THE SEALANT</hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 254. Make Gasket Pattern on Piston Housing</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install piston housing on the auxiliary cover. Make sure the shafts are in the correct bores
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p5">Figure 255</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-ring for the pistons with a silicone lubricant such as Dow Corning #111
                Silicone Grease or equivalent. Install the O-rings on the outer diameter and in the bore of the pistons.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the pistons on the shafts in the piston housings. Make sure the pistons are
                installed on the correct shafts
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p5">(Figure 255).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 255. Install O-Ring and Install Pistons</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new nut and washer that fasten the pistons on the shafts. Tighten the nut to 47 to
                68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs.)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p6">(Figure 256)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-rings on the shuttle valve with a silicone lubricant such as Dow Corning
                #111 Silicone Grease or equivalent.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the shuttle valve. Make sure the rod of the valve is toward the piston. Install and
                tighten the fitting
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p6">(Figure 256)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 256. Install Shuttle Valve</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new gasket between the piston housing and piston housing cover.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bolts and washers that fasten the piston housing cover to the piston housing.
                Tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
            <para>Install the cups for the rear bearing cones of the auxiliary countershafts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033p7">Figure 257)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033p7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033p7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 257. Install Cups for Rear Bearing Cones</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_48.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_50.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
