<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 -
        Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Assembly</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                    <para>Take care when you use silicone gasket materials to avoid serious personal injury. Follow the
                        manufacturer's instructions to prevent irritation to the eyes and skin.
                    </para>
                    <para>Small amounts of acid vapor are present when applying silicone gasket material. To prevent
                        possible serious personal injury, make sure there is adequate ventilation in the work area. If
                        silicone gasket material gets in your eyes, flush your eyes with water for 15 minutes. Have your
                        eyes checked by a doctor.
                    </para>
                    <para>Take care when you use Loctite' products to avoid serious personal injury. Follow the
                        manufacturer's instructions to prevent irritation to the eyes and skin.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="6">
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate all bearing cups and cones, gears and shaft assemblies before installation
                    into the case. Use synthetic SAE 50 oil (Meritor specification O-81).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the inside of the front case facing UPWARD, install the single-gear, or rear output
                    shaft on MTC-4208 and -4210 transfer cases, and double-gear idler shaft assemblies (Figure 42).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303542" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303542.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Install Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the clutch collar onto the stamped shift fork. Position the shift fork and
                    clutch collar onto the front output shaft clutch hub.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the front output shaft, shift fork and clutch collar over the front output shaft
                    tapered roller bearing in the front case (Figure 43).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303543" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303543.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Install Front Output Shaft, Shift Fork and Clutch Collar</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While holding the shift fork and clutch collar in place, insert the push rod through the
                    case and through the stamped shift fork (Figure 44).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Temporarily install the shift cylinder onto the case to secure the push rod in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The shift cylinder requires Loctite&#174; sealant for final assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the release spring over the push rod and shift fork.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303544" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303544.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 44. Insert Push Rod</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the high and low shift fork and shift shaft into position in the front case
                    (Figure 45).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine all shaft bearing end plays before final assembly. Refer to the procedures in
                    this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the two locating dowel pins in the corresponding holes in the front case.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303545" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303545.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 45. Install Shift Fork and Shift Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a suitable lifting device to install the rear cover and output shaft as an assembly
                    over the front case (Figure 46). Guide the cover over the shift fork and push rod as the cover is
                    being set in place over the case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the locating dowel pins have engaged both the case and the cover and that
                    the cover is fully seated on the case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the case to the cover joint by assembling at least six equally spaced
                    case-to-cover capscrews.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble all remaining case-to-cover capscrews upon achieving correct end play
                    measurement on all shafts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303546" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303546.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Use Suitable Lifting Device</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate and install the O-ring in the rear cover push rod journal. Use a light coat of
                    lithium based grease, Meritor specification O-688, prior to cover installation (Figure 47).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Loctite&#174; 518 sealant to the case-to-cover flange. Apply a 1/8-inch (3 mm)
                    bead of sealant around the entire flange between each bolt hole making sure to encircle each hole.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the rear cover over the front case. Guide the high and low shift shaft and
                    push rod through the cover as necessary. Verify that the cover is aligned with the locating dowel
                    pins and correctly seated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the capscrews are not pre-covered, apply Loctite&#174; 272 sealant to the first three
                    threads of the cover-to-case capscrews.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install all cover-to-case capscrews and flat washers. Tighten the capscrews to 60-75
                    lb-ft (81-102 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303547" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303547.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Lubricate and Install O-Ring</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOW RANGE PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. NEUTRAL PORT (MTC-4208 AND -4210 ONLY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HIGH RANGE PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. O-RING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
