<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - INSTALL - RIGHT REVERSE IDLER GEAR ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1302704" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>RIGHT REVERSE IDLER GEAR ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, thread pipe plug in the rear of the reverse idler shaft and tighten (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13027m7">Figure 227</hotlnk>). Install the thrust washer to the end of the idler plate
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13027m7">inset, Figure 227</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13027m7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13027m7" filename="../figg13/G13027m7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 227. Thread Pipe Plug in Rear of Reverse Idler Shaft and Install Thrust Washer</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If previously removed, replace the needle bearing into the bore of the reverse idler gear.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing inner race on the idler shaft and insert shaft into the case bore,
                threaded end of shaft to the front. As the idler shaft is moved forward, install the reverse idler gear
                on the shaft, long hub to the front and seating on the bearing inner race. Position the thrust washer on
                the shaft between the gear and support boss in the case and continue with movement of the idler shaft
                forward into the bore of the support boss (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13027m8">Figure 228</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13027m8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13027m8" filename="../figg13/G13027m8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 228. Insert Idler Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Making sure that the reverse idler shaft is seated in the bore of support boss and forward
                as far as possible, install the washer and stop nut on the front of the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13027m9">Figure 229</hotlnk>). Tighten nut to 50 to 60 ft-lbs. (68 to 81 N&#183; m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13027m9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13027m9" filename="../figg13/G13027m9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 229. Install Washer and Stop Nut on Front of Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the OUTER RACE of auxiliary countershaft front bearing into the case bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13027n0">Figure 230</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13027n0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13027n0" filename="../figg13/G13027n0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 230. Install Outer Race of Auxiliary Countershaft Front Bearing</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The bearing INNER RACE is installed on the front of the auxiliary countershaft and never with the
                    outer race.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_54.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_56.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
