<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>8 SPEED, 9 SPEED, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON SERIES - CHANGING THE INPUT SHAFT - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If necessary, install a new bushing in the pocket of the input shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the new input shaft in the splines of the main drive gear, just far enough to expose
                the snap ring groove in the I.D. of the drive gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the snap ring in the groove of the drive gear.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the spacer on the input shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a flanged-end driver, install the drive gear bearing on the shaft and into the case
                bore. When applying force to driver, use caution so as not to damage the bearing shield.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Engaging the sliding clutch into the main drive gear and blocking it forward will hold the input
                    shaft forward.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When drive gear bearing nut is used, degrease the threads of input shaft and use a new nut.
                DO NOT REUSE OLD NUT. When snap ring is used, install the snap ring in the groove of the input shaft and
                proceed to Step 10.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Fuller Transmission adhesive sealant #71204 or equivalent to the cleaned threads on
                the input shaft and nut, using caution so as not to contaminate the bearing with sealant.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Engage two mainshaft sliding clutches into gear to prevent the mainshaft from rotating and
                install the new drive gear bearing nut, left hand threads, on the input shaft. Tighten nut to 250 to 300
                ft-lbs. (339 to 407 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With a punch and maul, peen nut into the two milled slots of the input shaft, using caution
                so as not to distort the O.D. of the nut.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To facilitate proper re-installation of the shifter housing assembly on the case, make sure
                the mainshaft sliding clutches are placed in the neutral position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install the shifter housing assembly, the front bearing cover and all other parts and
                assemblies previously removed, making sure to replace the gaskets used.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_HL1301801.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
