<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 5 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER ES60-5 - CLEAN AND INSPECT -
        INSPECT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Gears</title>
            <para>Both the internal and external teeth must have sharp edges. Check for chipped or broken teeth, or
                teeth with rounded corners. Also examine fork slots for wear. Replace clutch gears if any of these
                conditions exist.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Gears</title>
            <para>Examine for broken or cracked clutch teeth. Also check for any unusual wear patterns. If any of the
                preceding exists, replace the gear. If a gear must be replaced, also remember to replace its mating
                gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thrust Washers</title>
            <para>Check for flatness, excessive face wear, cracks, scoring, or signs of heat damage.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Snap Rings</title>
            <para>New snap rings are recommended with every rebuild.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mainshaft</title>
            <para>Check for signs of twisting or misalignment, and for worn or damaged splines. Also inspect the shift
                bar support bracket for cracks or worn slots.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bearings</title>
            <para>New bearings are recommended with every rebuild.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Housings</title>
            <para>Inspect the housing sections for cracks. If cracks exist, replace that section of the housing. Also
                inspect the shift bar support bracket for cracks or worn slots. Replace if either of these conditions
                exist.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>REPAIR OR REPLACE WORN PARTS. Many times the parts or critical adjustments causing the trouble
                        are not replaced or corrected because the mechanic only inspects and replaces parts that have
                        failed completely. All pieces should be carefully examined because broken parts are often just
                        the result-not the cause-of the problem. All parts that are broken or worn and no longer meet
                        specifications should be replaced.
                    </para>
                    <para>Also, parts that are worn to the extent that they do not have a long service life remaining
                        should be replaced. Replacing these parts now will avoid another teardown of the unit in the
                        near future.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13012_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13012_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
