<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE - COUNTERSHAFT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="4">
        <title>COUNTERSHAFT</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c3">Figure 123</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Determine if the countershaft is the upper or lower countershaft, and mark it if necessary. The
                    lower countershaft has a larger 47 tooth PTO gear, and if the transmission has an oil pump, the rear
                    of the shaft will be extended to support the oil pump drive gear.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, install the key in the countershaft keyway.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To ease assembly, lightly lubricate the shaft and inside diameter of each gear.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Refer to the countershaft cross section in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c3">Figure 123</hotlnk>
                    while reassembling the countershaft and gears. If assembled correctly, the countershaft will have
                    the same shape as that shown in the cross section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f13032c3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032C3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 123. Cross Section Of Countershaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the 2nd speed gear (smallest gear). To install it, align the gear keyway with the
                countershaft key as shown, and press the gear on the countershaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c4">Figure 124</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032C4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 124. Align Gear Keyway With Countershaft Key</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the 3rd speed gear (next smallest gear). To install it, align the gear keyway with
                the countershaft key, and press the gear on the countershaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform one of the two following steps:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">For overdrive transmissions, select the largest diameter gear, place it over the shaft,
                    and press it into place.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">For direct drive transmissions, install the 4th speed gear (next smallest gear). To
                    install it, align the gear keyway with the countershaft key, long hub to countershaft front, and
                    press the gear on the countershaft.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the PTO gear. This gear is identified by the rounded teeth on one side. To install
                the PTO gear, align the gear keyway with the countershaft key, rounded teeth facing up (shaft rear), and
                press the gear on the countershaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the countershaft drive gear. This gear is identified by the tooth marked with a "0".
                To install the drive gear, align the gear keyway with the countershaft key, "0" to the front, and press
                the gear on the countershaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>DO NOT try to install the countershaft in the transmission if you cannot install the snap ring.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the countershaft drive gear retaining snap ring in the groove on the shaft front (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c5">Figure 125</hotlnk>). If the snap ring groove is not fully exposed, either the
                gears are not oriented properly, or not seated properly. The countershaft may have to be disassembled
                partly or fully to correct the problem.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032C5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 125. Install Countershaft Drive Gear Retaining Snap Ring</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For timing purposes, use a highly visible toolmaker's dye to mark the tooth with a "0" or
                the tooth lined up with the keyway (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c6">Figure 126</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032C6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 126. Mark Tooth</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_68.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_70.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
