<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - AIR SYSTEM - CONTROL VALVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONTROL VALVE</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1302405">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1302405" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302405" filename="../figg13/G1302405.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 5. Control Valve Exploded View</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>If the O-rings or parts in the control valve are defective, there will be a constant air leak out the
            exhaust located on the bottom of the control valve.
        </para>
        <para>A defective insert valve O-ring will result in a constant leak through the exhaust in both ranges and
            valve will not make range shifts.
        </para>
        <para>A defective housing O-ring will result in a constant, low volume leak through the exhaust in low range
            only.
        </para>
        <para>If the slide is assembled backwards, there will be a constant leak through the exhaust in high range. When
            installing the slide in the control valve, make sure that the slot in the slide faces the outlet port.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the control valve with rear housing (inlet side) on a bench and remove the four screws
                to separate front and rear housings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the slide and the two position balls and springs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the flat metal seal from the outlet side and remove O-ring from the body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the valve insert from the front housing and remove the O-ring from the valve
                insert.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the wave washer installed under valve insert.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the two felt wipers from the valve housings.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Punch out the roll pin and remove the control button from the slide.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
