<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Transmission - Automatic Transaxle/Transmission - 5R110 - General Procedures</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="9">
        <title>General Procedures</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Fluid Cooler - Backflushing and Cleaning</title>
            <figure id="f0701023" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0035930.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Typical Cooler Line and Remote Filter Fluid Flow</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Remote filter adapter assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing from remote filter back
                        into transmission)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Radiator in-tank cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing out)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing in)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing into remote filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler tube (fluid flowing into radiator in-tank
                        cooler)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0701024" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0018695.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Remote Fluid Filter</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Housing</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Spring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure plate/ magnet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filter element</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">O-ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Bracket</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Whenever the transmission has been serviced or a remanufactured transmission has been
                        installed, the transmission fluid cooler tubes and the remote filter manifold must be cleaned
                        and backflushed to remove any contaminants or transmission failure will occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This transmission is equipped with a remote transmission fluid filter which is located on the
                        driver side rear of the transmission. When carrying out an overhaul or installing a
                        remanufactured transmission a new filter element must be installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a suitable torque converter/fluid cooler cleaner, flush the transmission fluid
                    cooler and tubes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If equipped, remove and discard the transmission fluid in-line filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0701025" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0027074.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the remote filter element.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The transmission cooler tubes must be disconnected prior to flushing out the cooler tubes.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 4 transmission fluid cooler tubes at the remote filter housing. For
                    additional information, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070260.xml" xrefid="x3070260">Transaxle/ Transmission Cooling</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leave the transmission fluid cooler tubes disconnected from the transmission case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both transmission fluid cooler tubes from the radiator in-tank cooler.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flush each transmission fluid cooler tube independently.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the cleaner pressure and return lines correctly.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the pressure line-to-fluid cooler inlet tube.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the return line-to-fluid cooler outlet tube.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the outlet end of the return line in the fluid tank reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Cycling the solvent pump on and off will help dislodge contaminants in the cooler system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch the pumps ON. Allow the fluid to circulate a minimum of 5 minutes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch the pump OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the cleaner pressure line at the fluid cooler tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using compressed air, blow through the fluid cooler inlet tube until all fluid is
                    removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rubber hoses from fluid cooler tubes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the cleaner pressure and return lines correctly.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the pressure line to the radiator in-tank fluid cooler.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the return line to the other side of the radiator in-tank fluid cooler.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the outlet end of the return line in the fluid tank reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Cycling the pump on and off will help dislodge contaminants in the cooler system.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch the pumps ON. Allow the fluid to circulate a minimum of 5 minutes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch the pump OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the cleaner pressure line at the fluid cooler tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using compressed air, blow through the fluid cooler inlet tube until all fluid is
                    removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rubber hoses from fluid cooler tubes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flush the remote filter manifold and make sure that the small bypass orifice is free of
                    foreign material.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flush the remote filter housing and clean the magnet.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Backflush and then flush the radiator in-tank cooler.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new remote filter element.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carry out the transmission fluid cooler flow test. For additional information, refer to
                    Transmission Fluid Cooler in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Fluid Drain and Refill - Automated Equipment (if available)</title>
            <table id="t07010133">
                <title>Special Tool</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.94*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figST2/ST2654A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Automatic Transmission Flush and Fill Machine</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <title>Draining</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Always refer to the instructions supplied with the flush and fill machine.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Raise and support the vehicle with the transmission in PARK. For additional information, refer
                        to
                        <exhotlnk document="../S10/S10019.htm" bookname="S10019">Jacking and Lifting in
                            S10019</exhotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use a suitable flush and fill machine to change the fluid, and follow the manufacturer's
                        instructions.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When connecting the flush and fill machine, connect the machine to the fluid cooler tube after
                        the fluid cooler on the cooler return line. This will help remove any foreign material trapped
                        in the fluid coolers.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Refill</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the fluid exchange has been completed, disconnect the flush and fill machine.
                    Reconnect any disconnected fluid cooler tubes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The use of any other transmission fluid than specified can result in the transmission failing
                        to operate in a normal manner or transmission failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the vehicle in NEUTRAL, engine running and the transmission at normal operating
                    temperature 66-77&#176;C (150-170&#176;F), check and adjust the transmission fluid level and check
                    for any leaks. If fluid is needed, add fluid in increments of 0.24 liter (0.5 pint) until the
                    correct level is achieved (fluid should be in the cross-hatched area of the fluid level indicator).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Fluid Drain and Refill - Without Torque Converter Drain Plug and With Fluid Pan Drain
                Plug
            </title>
            <para>
                <title>Draining</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0701026" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0055937.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The radiator in-tank transmission fluid cooler will need to be flushed.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Raise and support the vehicle with the transmission in PARK. For additional information, refer
                        to
                        <exhotlnk document="../S10/S10019.htm" bookname="S10019">Jacking and Lifting in
                            S10019</exhotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the transmission fluid pan drain plug and allow the fluid to drain.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Only flush the cooler tubes and fluid coolers if carrying out a transmission overhaul. For
                        additional information, refer to Transmission Fluid Cooler - Backflushing and Cleaning in this
                        section.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Refill</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the transmission fluid drain plug.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Tighten to 25 Nm (18 lb-ft).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0701027" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0055937.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The use of any other transmission fluid than specified can result in the transmission failing
                        to operate in a normal manner or transmission failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the transmission.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Add 7.1 liters (7.5 qts) of clean automatic transmission fluid to the transmission through
                    the fluid filler tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine. Move the transmission range selector lever through all the gear
                    ranges, checking for engagements.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the vehicle in NEUTRAL, engine running and the transmission at normal operating
                    temperature 66-77&#176;C (150-170&#176;F), check and adjust the transmission fluid level and check
                    for any leaks. If fluid is needed, add fluid in increments of 0.24 liter (0.5 pint) until the
                    correct level is achieved (fluid should be in the cross-hatched area of the fluid level indicator).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Converter</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A new or remanufactured torque converter must be installed if one or more of the
                    following statements are true:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>A torque converter malfunction has been determined based on the complete diagnostic
                            procedures.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Converter stud(s), impeller hub or bushing is damaged.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Discoloration of the torque converter (due to overheating).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Evidence of transmission assembly or fluid contamination due to the following transmission
                            or converter failure modes:
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>Major metallic failure.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Multiple clutches or clutch plate failures.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Sufficient component wear which results in metallic contamination.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0701028" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figAD2/AD2358A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Converter Contamination Inspection</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use water-based cleaners or mineral spirits to clean or flush the torque converter or
                        transmission damage will occur. Use only clean automatic transmission fluid designated for the
                        transmission and converter being serviced.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a new or remanufactured torque converter is not being installed, the following steps
                    must be completed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the torque converter on a bench, pour a small amount of transmission fluid from the
                    torque converter onto an absorbent white tissue or through a paper filter and examine the fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Observe the color and odor of the fluid. The fluid should be red, not brown or black.
                    Odor may indicate an overheating condition such as clutch disc or band failure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine the stain on the tissue for evidence of particles (spec of any kind). Examine
                    the fluid level indicator for signs of antifreeze (gum or varnish). If particles are present in the
                    fluid or there is evidence of engine coolant or water, a new torque converter must be installed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there are no particles or contamination present, drain the remainder of the
                    transmission fluid from the torque converter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add 1.9 liter (2 qt.) of clean automatic transmission fluid into the converter and
                    agitate by hand.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly drain the fluid.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Fluid Remote Filter</title>
            <para>
                <title>Remote Fluid Filter Removal</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0701029" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024721.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Remote Fluid Filter</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Housing</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Spring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure plate</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filter element</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Bracket</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">O-ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Magnet</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The remote filter for this vehicle is located on the LH side of the transmission.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Raise and support the vehicle with the transmission in NEUTRAL. For additional information,
                        refer to
                        <exhotlnk document="../S10/S10019.htm" bookname="S10019">Jacking and Lifting in
                            S10019</exhotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the remote filter housing by unscrewing it.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the spring/retainer and magnet assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove and discard the remote filter element.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Installation</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the O-ring for damage (nicks or cuts). Install a new O-ring if damage is
                    indicated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new remote filter element.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the spring/retainer and magnet assembly and install it into the remote filter
                    element.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the remote filter housing and install.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Tighten to 50 Nm (37 lb-ft).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill with clean automatic transmission fluid.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Fluid In-Line Filter</title>
            <figure id="f0701030" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0035930.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Typical Cooler Line and Remote Filter Fluid Flow</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Remote filter adapter assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing from remote filter back
                        into transmission)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Radiator in-tank cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing out)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing in)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler fitting (fluid flowing into remote filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid cooler tube (fluid flowing into radiator in-tank
                        cooler)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use the following guidelines for installing the transmission fluid in-line filter.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the transmission was overhauled and the vehicle was equipped with an in-line fluid filter,
                        install a new in-line fluid filter.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the transmission was overhauled and the vehicle was not equipped with an in-line fluid
                        filter, install a new in-line fluid filter kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the transmission is being installed for a non-internal repair, do not install an in-line
                        fluid filter or kit.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If installing a new or remanufactured transmission, install the transmission fluid filter that
                        is supplied.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise and support the vehicle with the transmission in NEUTRAL. For additional
                    information, refer to
                    <exhotlnk document="../S10/S10019.htm" bookname="S10019">Jacking and Lifting in S10019</exhotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove a section of rubber hose as close to the radiator as possible.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Section of hose 76.2 mm (3 inch)</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The filter has a bypass valve in it. The red arrow on the filter indicates the direction of
                        fluid flow through the filter. The filter must be installed in the cooler return line with the
                        red on the filter pointing away from the radiator in-tank cooler and toward the transmission
                        (the return line has fluid coming out of the cooler going to the transmission). If the fluid
                        filter is not installed correctly, it will cause internal damage.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not install any rubber hoses or steel tubing with a bend entering the filter greater than
                        60 degrees.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the in-line fluid filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean a section of the transmission fluid pan and install the sticker.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The use of any other transmission fluid than specified can result in the transmission failing
                        to operate in a normal manner or transmission failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill with clean automatic transmission fluid.</para>
                <para>&#8226; With the vehicle in NEUTRAL, engine running and the transmission at normal operating
                    temperature 66-77&#176;C (150-170&#176;F), check and adjust the transmission fluid level and check
                    for any leaks. If fluid is needed, add fluid in increments of 0.24 liter (0.5 pint) until the
                    correct level is achieved (fluid should be in the cross-hatched area of the fluid level indicator).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
