<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>9 SPEED AND 11 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTO-1X707LL/DLL/MLL AND RTO-1X709MLL MODELS - MAINTENANCE.</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="2">
        <title>MAINTENANCE.</title>
        <para>Step numbers refer to numbers in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1302002">Figure 2</hotlnk>
        </para>
        <figure id="f1302002" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302002" filename="../figg13/G1302002.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. AIR SYSTEM AND CONNECTIONS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CLUTCH HOUSING MOUNTING</callout1>
                <callout1>3. CLUTCH RELEASE BEARING (NOT SHOWN IN THIS VIEW)</callout1>
                <callout1>4. CLUTCH PEDAL SHAFT AND BORES</callout1>
                <callout1>5. LUBRICANT</callout1>
                <callout1>6. FILLER AND DRAIN PLUGS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Air System and Connections. Check for leaks, worn air lines, loose connections and bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Housing Mounting. Check all bolts on the clutch housing flange for looseness.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Release Bearing (Not Shown). Remove hand hole cover and check radial and axial
                clearance in the release bearing. Check relative position of thrust surface of release bearing with
                thrust sleeve on push-type clutches.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clutch Pedal Shaft and Bores. Pry upward on shafts to check wear. If excessive movement is
                found, remove clutch release mechanism and check bushings in bores and wear on shafts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricant. Change at the service intervals and with the type of lubricant specified in GROUP
                10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Filler and Drain Plugs. Remove filler plugs and check level of lubricant at specified
                intervals. Tighten fill and drain plugs securely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Step numbers refer to numbers in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1302003">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1302003" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1302003" filename="../figg13/G1302003.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>7. BOLTS AND GASKETS</callout1>
                <callout1>8. GEAR SHIFT LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>9. GEAR SHIFT LEVER HOUSING ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>10. UNIVERSAL JOINT COMPANION FLANGE OR YOKE NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>11. OUTPUT SHAFT (NOT SHOWN IN THIS VIEW)</callout1>
                <callout1>12. SPLINES ON OUTPUT SHAFT (NOT SHOWN IN THIS VIEW)</callout1>
                <callout1>13. MAINSHAFT REAR BEARING COVER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Bolts and Gaskets. Check all bolts, especially those on PTO covers and rear bearing covers
                for looseness which would cause oil leakage. Check PTO opening and rear bearing covers for oil leakage
                due to faulty gasket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever. Check for looseness and free play in housing. If lever is loose in
                housing, proceed with step 9.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gear Shift Lever Housing Assembly. Remove the air lines at the slave valve and remove the
                gear shift lever housing assembly from the transmission. Check the tension spring and washer for set and
                wear. Check the gear shift lever spade pin and slot for wear. Check the bottom end of the gear shift
                lever for wear and check the slot of the yokes and blocks in the shifter housing for wear at contact
                points with the shift lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Checks with Drive Line Dropped</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Universal Joint Companion Flange or Yoke Nut. Check for tightness. Tighten to recommended
                torque.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Output Shaft (Not Shown). Pry upward against output shaft to check radial clearance in
                mainshaft rear bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Checks with Universal Joint Companion Flange or Yoke Removed</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If necessary, use solvent and shop rag to clean sealing surface of companion flange or yoke. Do
                    not use crocus cloth, emery paper, or other abrasive materials that will mar surface finish.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Splines on Output Shaft (Not Shown). Check for wear from movement and chucking action of the
                universal joint companion flange or yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mainshaft Rear Bearing Cover. Check oil seal for wear.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13020_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13020_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
