<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE -
        NINE- AND TEN-SPEED AUXILIARY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="26">
        <title>NINE- AND TEN-SPEED AUXILIARY</title>
        <figure id="f13033k3" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 203. Nine-And Ten-Speed Auxiliary Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k3">Figure 203</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The bearing cup and bearing cone must be replaced as an assembly. Do not replace the cup or the
                    cone separately. Replace the cup and cone in a matched set from the same manufacturer.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate all the parts of the auxiliary cover with the oil used in the transmission. Refer
                to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Nine-Speed Transmissions</emph>, if removed, install the snap ring in
                the groove inside the auxiliary low gear. Make sure the round side of the snap ring is installed toward
                the gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k4">Figure 204</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put timing marks on the auxiliary low gear. Mark one tooth with paint. Mark a second tooth
                opposite (180 degrees) the first tooth (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k4">Figure 204)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 204. Put Timing Marks on Auxiliary Low Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use paint to put timing marks next to each other on two teeth of each countershaft low gear.
                Make sure the mark is aligned with the "O" stamping on the countershaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k5">Figure 205</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 205. Put Timing Marks Next to Each Other</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the output shaft and low gear assembly according to the following procedure (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k6">Figure 206</hotlnk>):
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put the output shaft on the work bench. Make sure the threaded end of the shaft is up.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1, Model 115 and 125 Transmissions</emph>, install the output shaft
                    spacer with the shoulder. Make sure the spacer is installed with the large section toward the bottom
                    of the shaft.
                </para>
                <para>On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1, Model 135 and 145 Transmissions</emph>, install the output shaft
                    spacer with the shoulder. Make sure the spacer is installed with the large section toward the bottom
                    of the shaft. Install the small spacer on top of the spacer with the shoulder.
                </para>
                <para>On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 2, Model 115 and 125 Transmissions</emph>, install the flat output
                    shaft spacer on the shaft.
                </para>
                <para>On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 2, Model 155 and 165 Transmissions</emph>, install the large output
                    shaft spacer on the shaft. Install the small output shaft spacer on top of the large spacer.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Nine-Speed Transmissions</emph>, install the toothed spacer in the
                    low gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Nine-Speed Transmissions</emph>, install the snap ring in the low
                    gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the auxiliary low gear on the output shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k6">Figure 206</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On
                    <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Nine-Speed Transmissions</emph>, install the thrust washer on top
                    of the low gear
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k6">(Figure 206).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k6" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 206. Assemble Output Shaft and Low Gear Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The bearing cone may be heated to ease installation. Insulated gloves or similar protection should
                    be worn to prevent burns.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft and low gear assembly on a press. Support the shaft on the bottom of
                the shaft. Make sure the threads on the shaft are toward the top of the press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a bearing cone on the shaft. Make sure the large diameter of the gear is toward the
                cone (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k7">Figure 207</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 207. Install Bearing Cone</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the cone. Press the cone on the shaft until the cone touches the thrust
                washer or the low gear. Make sure the gear and bearing cone rotate on the shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the spacer on the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k8">Figure 208</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 208. Install Spacer</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the cover in a press so that the outside is toward the top of the press. Support the
                cover under the output shaft bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k9">Figure 209)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the inner bearing cup in the cover. Make sure the letters on the cup are toward you.
                Install a sleeve or a bearing installation tool on the race of the bearing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k9">(Figure 209</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the inner cup into the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033k9">(Figure 209)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033k9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033K9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 209. Press Inner Cup into Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the outer cup on top of the inner cup. Make sure the slots of the outer cup are against
                the inner cup (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l0">Figure 210</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 210. Put Outer Cup on Top of Inner Cup</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on installation tool on the top of the outer cup. Press both cups into the
                bore. The cups are correctly installed when the outer cup touches the shoulder in the bore of the cover
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l1">Figure 211)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 211. Press Both Cups into Bore</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A bearing heater can be used to install the bearing cone. Follow the instructions of the
                    manufacturer of the bearing heater. Wear gloves or other protective clothing to prevent personal
                    injury while handling the heated bearing.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the countershaft in a press so that the front of the countershaft is toward the top of
                the press. Support the countershaft on the gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the front cone on the countershaft so that the bottom of the cone is toward the gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l2">(Figure 212)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a sleeve on the inner race of the cone. Press the cone on the countershaft. The cone is
                correctly installed when the bottom of the cone touches the gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l2">(Figure 212).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the shaft over so that the opposite end is toward the top of the press. Repeat steps 15
                through 17 to install the rear cone.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft and low gear assembly in a press. Make sure the threads on the shaft
                are toward the top of the press
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l2">(Figure 212).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 212. Press Cone on Countershaft and Put Output Shaft and Low Gear Assembly in a Press
            </caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put each auxiliary countershaft next to the output shaft. Make sure the timing marks on each
                countershaft and low gear are aligned
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l3">(Figure 213)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 213. Make Sure Timing Marks are Aligned</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the auxiliary cover on the output shaft and low gear assembly and auxiliary
                countershafts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l4">Figure 214</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 214. Put Auxiliary Cover on</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the outer bearing cone on the output shaft. Make sure the letters on the cone are
                toward the top of the press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a sleeve on the outer bearing cone. Press the cone on the shaft and into the cup in
                the bore of the cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l5">(Figure 215)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 215. Press Cone into Cup</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the output shaft so that the cover is in the upright position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the timing marks on the low gear and each auxiliary countershaft are in
                alignment.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the synchronizer assembly on the output shaft inside the auxiliary cover. Make sure
                the high synchronizer is toward you
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l6">(Figure 216).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 216. Install Synchronizer Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the correct cup on the rear bearing of the upper auxiliary countershaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l7">Figure 217</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the correct cup on the rear bearing of the lower auxiliary countershaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l7">(Figure 217</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 217. Install Cups on Rear Bearings</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Nine-Speed Transmission:</emph>
                Install the snap ring that retains the cups in the case. Use the snap ring that was removed during
                disassembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 2 Nine-Speed and Ten-Speed Transmissions:</emph>
                Install the selective washers in front of the cups. Make sure the tabs on the washers are in the slots
                in the case (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l8">Figure 218)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install Holding Cover Tools on each countershaft. Use bolts to fasten the cover tools to the
                countershafts and cover
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l8">(Figure 218</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 218. Install Holding Cover Tools</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, use a suitable tool to install a new bushing for the speedometer gear inside the
                output bearing retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a sealant dispenser and Loctite RTV Sealant or equivalent to make a 2 mm (1/8 inch)
                sealant pattern for the output bearing retainer. Make sure the sealant material does not cover the oil
                passage. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033l9">Figure 219</hotlnk>for the sealant pattern. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13033_11.xml" xrefid="x1303304">INSTALL THE SEALANT</hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033l9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033L9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 219. Sealant Pattern</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the output bearing retainer on the auxiliary cover. Make sure the oil passage in the
                retainer is aligned over the oil hole in the cover (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m0">Figure 220)</hotlnk>. Tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 220. Install Output Bearing Retainer</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the oil seal in the output bearing retainer
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m1">(Figure 221)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13033m1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 221. Install Oil Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Hold the seal only on the outer diameter. Do not touch the inner diameter of the seal.
                        Touching contaminates the inner diameter of the seal and causes a leak between shaft and seal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Lubricate the outer diameter of the seal. Make sure the letters on the seal are installed away from
                the retainer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use the correct tool to install the oil seal. If the correct tool is not used, the seal will
                        leak.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Use seal driver tool ZTSE-4424 to drive the seal into the cover. The seal is correctly installed when
                the outer flange of the seal touches the retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the HI-LO shift fork in position so that the fork engages the synchronizer collar. Make
                sure the bore of the fork is aligned with the bore of the range cylinder. Make sure the hole in the fork
                is installed away from the cover (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m2">Figure 222</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the HI-LO shift shaft from inside the front of the auxiliary cover. Make sure the
                threads on the end of the shaft are installed first
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m2">(Figure 222).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 222. Install HI-LO Shift Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a pin and clip were used to fasten the HI-LO fork to the shaft, replace the pin and clip with a
                    nut and shoulder bolt.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the hole of the shaft with the hole of the shift fork. Install the bolt and the lock
                nut. Tighten the nut to 11 to 16 Nm (8 to 12 ft-lbs.) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m3">Figure 223</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 223. Install Bolt and Lock Nut</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not use too much silicone lubricant on the O-rings and bore of the range cylinder housing. If
                    too much lubricant is used, the range may shift slowly.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-rings and bore of the range cylinder housing with a silicone lubricant such
                as Dow Corning #111 Silicone Grease or equivalent. Install the O-ring in the groove in the bore of the
                range cylinder housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m4">(Figure 224</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 224. Install O-Ring in Groove</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a sealant dispenser and Loctite RTV Sealant or equivalent to make a 3 mm (1/8 inch)
                sealant pattern for the range cylinder housing. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m5">Figure 225</hotlnk>
                for the sealant pattern. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13033_11.xml" xrefid="x1303304">INSTALLING THE SEALANT</hotlnk>
                section. Install the range cylinder housing on the auxiliary cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 225. Sealant Pattern</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-rings for the piston with a silicone lubricant such as Dow Corning #111
                Silicone Grease or equivalent. Install the O-rings on the outer diameter and inner diameter of the
                piston
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m6">(Figure 226)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 226. Install O-Rings</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the piston on the shaft in the range cylinder. Install the nut that fastens the
                piston on the shaft. Tighten the nut to 47 to 68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs.) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m7">Figure 227).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 227. Install Piston</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the gasket between the range cylinder cover and the range cylinder housing. Install
                the cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bolts and washers that fasten the range cylinder cover to the auxiliary cover.
                Tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the auxiliary cover in the LO range.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the outer diameter of the cups for the front bearing cones of the auxiliary
                countershafts. Put the cups in the correct bores in the transmission case
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033m8">(Figure 228)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033m8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033M8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 228. Put Cups in Correct Bores</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
