<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 10 SPEED AND 15 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RT, RTO, AND RTX
        SERIES - AIR SYSTEM - INSERT VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
        <title>INSERT VALVE</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1301507">Figure 7</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1301507" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1301507" filename="../figg13/g1301507.png" type="png"/>
            <caption>Figure 7. Insert Valve</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The insert valve is a self-contained valve assembly located in the reduction cylinder cover. It CANNOT be
            disassembled except for the three O-rings on the outer diameter. The O-rings provide a stationary seal and
            do not move in the cylinder.
        </para>
        <para>When installing the insert valve in the bottom bore of the cover, apply Fuller Transmission #71206
            silicone lubricant or its equivalent to the O-rings and cylinder walls. Install the valve in the bore with
            the flat surface to the inside. When installing the special valve retaining nut, apply Fuller Transmission
            #71204 adhesive/sealant or its equivalent to the threads and tighten. Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s13015_64.xml" xrefid="hl1301502">TORQUE CHART
                <xref refid="hl1301502"/>
            </hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <para>Travel of the small insert valve piston is only 1/32 inch. As shown in the illustrations (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1301508">Figure 8</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1301509">Figure 9</hotlnk>), when NO AIR is applied to the top side of the valve piston,
            CONSTANT AIR supplied from the regulator passes freely through the insert valve and to the backside of the
            cylinder piston, moving the yoke bar forward to disengage deep reduction gearing (LO RANGE AND HI RANGE).
            When air is applied to the top side of the valve piston through the signal line, the piston moves down to
            cut off air supplied to the backside of the cylinder piston. This air is exhausted out the bottom port of
            the cover when CONSTANT AIR supplied from the regulator is directed to the front side of the cylinder
            piston, moving the yoke bar rearward to engage the deep reduction gearing (DEEP REDUCTION).
        </para>
        <figure id="f1301508" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1301508" filename="../figg13/g1301508.png" type="png"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Air Flow When No Air Applied to Top Side of Valve Piston</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1301509" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1301509" filename="../figg13/g1301509.png" type="png"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Air Flow When Air Applied to Top Side of Valve Piston</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13015_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13015_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
