<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - INSTALL - AUXILIARY
        SECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If not previously installed, install the output yoke (or flange) and the output nut. Tighten
                the output nut to 610 to 677 Nm (450 to 500 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the dowel pins to the proper depth 3/8 inch to 1/2 inch of the shoulder on the pins
                must be visible (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032f8">Figure 158</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032f8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032f8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 158. Installing Dowel Pins</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use crocus cloth to clean the dowel pins and dowel pin holes of all paint and corrosion. Apply a
                    light coating of grease to the dowel pin holes.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the auxiliary section is in low gear. If it is not, use one of two large
                screwdrivers or prybars to apply even rearward pressure to move the range sliding clutch back into the
                low gear position (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032f9">Figure 159</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032f9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032f9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 159. Move Range Sliding Clutch Back Into Low Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the shift bar housing is installed, make sure the range bar lock cover is rotated
                counterclockwise into the unlock position (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032g0">Figure 160</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032g0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032g0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 160. Rotate Lock Cover Counterclockwise</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the gasket on the main case mounting surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the auxiliary section hanger bracket to the top of the auxiliary section and attach
                the chain of the lifting device to the bracket (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032g1">Figure 161</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032g1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032g1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 161. Attach Chain To Bracket</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow the lifting device to support the weight of the auxiliary section, and position the
                auxiliary section on the two dowel pins. Slide the auxiliary section forward.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The range yoke bar must slide into the bore in the main case.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To help the auxiliary countershafts mesh with the auxiliary drive gear, rotate the output yoke to
                    turn the gearing.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the auxiliary countershafts drop excessively, the auxiliary countershaft shim tools can be used
                    to support the countershafts.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The auxiliary section can be assembled to the transmission with the transmission in the vertical
                    position.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the auxiliary section hanger bracket.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not force or pull the auxiliary section into position with bolts when sliding it into place. It
                    should slide into place fairly easily. If excessive force is necessary, the countershaft(s) is
                    drooping and the gearing is not in proper mesh. Remove the auxiliary section and try again.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Slide the auxiliary section fully into position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite 242 or equivalent to the bolt threads and install the 19 bolts. Tighten them
                to 54 to 61 Nm (40 to 45 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolt securing the range bar lock cover in the unlock position and rotate the
                cover to the lock position. Insert the two bolts to secure the lock cover in position. Tighten them to
                27 to 31 Nm (20 to 23 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To properly align the lock cover, the auxiliary section must be in low range when the bolts are
                    tightened.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_83.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_85.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
