<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER PS110-7, PS145-7 - OPERATION - HOW TO SHIFT SPICER PS110-7A, PS145-7A, AND
        PS110-7B TRANSMISSIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>HOW TO SHIFT SPICER PS110-7A, PS145-7A, AND PS110-7B TRANSMISSIONS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This single-stick transmission has seven lever positions (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1301601">Figure 1</hotlnk>) with no splitter or range necessary.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1301601" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1301601" filename="../figg13/g1301601.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Shift Pattern</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A clutch brake is required for use with this transmission. It is recommended that the torque limiting
                clutch brake be used instead of the three-piece type.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Starting</title>
            <para>With the engine idling, depress clutch and move the shift lever into first gear. Gradually release
                clutch and accelerate engine to governed speed (1900 - 1950 RPM).
            </para>
            <para>A clutch brake is used to stop gear rotation to complete a shift into first or reverse when the
                vehicle is stationary. The clutch brake on this transmission is actuated by depressing the clutch pedal
                all the way to the floor. For normal upshifts and downshifts, only a partial disengagement of the clutch
                is necessary to break engine torque.
            </para>
            <para>If a butt-toothed condition exists between the clutching teeth, a momentary re-engagement of the main
                clutch will allow the gear train to move into a smooth engagement.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Upshifting</title>
            <para>Once governed engine speed has been attained, depress the clutch and move the shift lever to neutral.
                Engage the clutch and allow RPM to drop approximately 750. (RPM drop may vary with engines of different
                governed speeds*.) Depress the clutch and move the lever into second gear. Re-engage the clutch and
                accelerate to governed speed. Continue upshifting through seventh gear in this manner.
            </para>
            <para>*All RPM drops are based on the PS110-7A, PS145-7A and PS110-7B transmission ratios and an engine
                governed speed of 1900 - 1950 RPM. These drops will vary with other transmission ratios or with engines
                of higher governed speeds.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Downshifting</title>
            <para>When downshifting from seventh gear, allow RPM to drop approximately 475. Depress the clutch pedal and
                move the shift lever to neutral. Engage the clutch. Accelerate to governed speed. Continue by depressing
                the clutch and moving the stick into sixth gear, then re-engage the clutch. Continue downshifting
                through first gear in this manner.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacement Parts</title>
            <para>The exploded views of subassemblies which are incorporated here are for the mechanic's convenience and
                show the latest material. The parts are arranged in their correct order and may also be used as a
                reference for assembly or disassembly of this unit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13016_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13016_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
