<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - SPECIAL PROCEDURES -
        AUXILIARY SECTION IN CHASSIS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION IN CHASSIS</title>
        <para>The following procedure covers the removal of the auxiliary section with the transmission remaining in the
            chassis.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the range selector on the shift knob in the down position to shift the transmission
                into low range. Removing the auxiliary section when the transmission is in low range will aid in
                reassembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303212">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303212" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303212.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Auxiliary Section In Chassis</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain the transmission oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the driveshaft and U-joint from the output yoke.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the auxiliary section is to be disassembled, remove the output nut using a 2-3/4 inch or
                70 mm socket. To prevent the output shaft from rotating while removing the nut, shift the transmission
                to 1st gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If the shift bar housing is still installed, you MUST perform steps 5 and 6 or the transmission
                    will be damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolts from the range bar lock cover, and rotate the lock cover counter-clockwise
                until the notch on the cover lines up with the unlock symbol (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303213">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the system still contains air pressure, greater force is required to turn the lock cover.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the right bolt to secure the cover in the unlock position (Figure 13).</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303213" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 13. Remove Bolts From Range Bar Lock Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This step unlocks the range yoke bar in the auxiliary from the range piston bar in the shift bar
                    housing.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drive the two dowel pins forward, and remove them (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303214">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove 18 of the 19 bolts that secure the auxiliary section to the main section. Leave one
                bolt to secure housing until it is ready to be removed (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303214">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Bolts are different lengths. Note their locations for reassembly purposes.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean and oil the three threaded pusher holes in the auxiliary section flange. To clean
                them, thread an M10x1.5 tap into each hole to remove paint, rust, and other debris
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303214">(Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303214" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303214.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. Remove Dowel Pins and Bolts</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Use proper equipment with safety chains attached to remove auxiliary section. The auxiliary
                    section can slide rearward and could fall, causing you serious injury and/or damage to the auxiliary
                    section.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the chain and lifting device to the auxiliary section hanger, or attach the support
                jack to the auxiliary section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thread bolts into each of the three previously cleaned pusher holes in the auxiliary section
                flange. Run the bolts in evenly to break the gasket seal and move the auxiliary housing rearward
                approximately 1/4 inch. After breaking the gasket seal, remove pusher screws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The weight of the auxiliary section must be supported during removal to avoid damage to the range
                    yoke bar.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the weight of the auxiliary section with the lifting device or support jack and move
                the auxiliary section rearward until it is free from the front section of the transmission.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
