<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - AIR SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x1302401">
        <title>AIR SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The range shift air system consists of an air filter, regulator, air valve, control valve, an air
                cylinder which is built into the auxiliary housing, fittings, and connecting lines.
            </para>
            <para>Range shifts can only be made when the gear shift lever is in, or passing through, neutral. Thus, the
                range desired can be pre-selected while the shift lever is in a gear position. As the lever is moved
                through neutral, an actuating plunger in the shifter housing releases the air valve piston, allowing it
                to move to the range position selected.
            </para>
            <para>Constant regulated air is supplied to the tee in the top port of the air valve and to the "IN" port of
                the control valve. With the control button down, the control valve is open, and air passes through the
                control valve and to the end port of the air valve. This permits air from the constant supply to flow
                through the low range port in the air valve to the air cylinder in the auxiliary housing. Air at the
                cylinder moves the shift piston and shaft to the rear to engage the low range gear.
            </para>
            <para>With the control button up, the control valve is closed, and air is removed from the end port of the
                air valve. This permits movement of the air valve piston; air from the constant supply now flows through
                the high range port of the air valve and to the high range port of the air cylinder in the auxiliary
                housing. The shift piston and shaft are moved forward to engage the high range or direct gear.
            </para>
            <para>When the control button is moved from one position to another, air from the previously charged line
                exhausts through the breather in the air valve.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
