<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Output Shaft and Rear Bearing Assemblies</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the output shaft in a vise with the threaded end up (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018p8">Figure 258</hotlnk>). For models so equipped, install the stepped washer on
                the shaft, large diameter step down (arrow), then install the splined spacer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018p8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018p8" filename="../figg13/G13018p8.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 257. Install Stepped Washer on Shaft, Large Diameter Step Down</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For 14609 Models, install the spacer with the large diameter splines down (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018p9">Figure 259</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018p9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018p9" filename="../figg13/G13018p9.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 258. Install Spacer With Large Diameter Splines Down</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT: Mark any two adjacent teeth on low range gear and repeat the procedure for
                    the two adjacent teeth directly opposite the first set marked (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q0">Figure 260</hotlnk>). A highly visible color of toolmaker's dye is
                    recommended.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q0" filename="../figg13/G13018q0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 259. Mark Teeth on Low Range Gear</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, install the snap ring in the low range gear of models so equipped (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q1">inset, Figure 261</hotlnk>). Install the gear on the output shaft, clutching
                teeth down and engaged with the splines of the spacer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q1" filename="../figg13/G13018q1.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 260. Install Snap Ring in Low Range Gear, and Install Gear on Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the washer on the shaft; 11609, 12609 Models flat side of washer facing up, 14609
                Models flat side of washer facing down (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q2">Figure 262</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q2" filename="../figg13/G13018q2.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 261. Install Washer on Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Heat the front bearing cone and install on shaft against washer, bearing taper up (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q3">Figure 263</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q3" filename="../figg13/G13018q3.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 262. Heat and Install Front Bearing Cone on Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not heat bearing above 275 degrees F (136 degrees C). If possible, use heat lamps as
                        source.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing inner spacer on the output shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q4">Figure 264</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q4" filename="../figg13/G13018q4.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 263. Install Bearing Inner Spacer on Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the front bearing cup in the auxiliary housing bore, taper to the inside (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q5">Figure 265</hotlnk>) and use a soft bar to start cup into the bore.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q5" filename="../figg13/G13018q5.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 264. Place Front Bearing Cup in Auxiliary Housing Bore</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the bearing outer spacer against cup (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q6">Figure 266</hotlnk>). Use a soft bar or a flanged-end driver to move both
                parts evenly into the bore.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q6" filename="../figg13/G13018q6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 265. Place Bearing Outer Spacer Against Cup</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the rear bearing cup against the spacer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q7">Figure 267</hotlnk>). Use a flanged-end driver to move all three parts evenly
                into the bore until the lip of the rear bearing cup seats on the auxiliary housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q7" filename="../figg13/G13018q7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 266. Place Rear Bearing Cup Against Spacer</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary housing over the end of the output shaft assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q8">Figure 268</hotlnk>). Heat the rear bearing cone and install on shaft, taper
                down and inside bearing cup.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q8" filename="../figg13/G13018q8.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 267. Install Auxiliary Housing Over End of Output Shaft Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not heat bearing above 275 degrees F (136 degrees C).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, install the oil seal in the rear bearing cover with a flanged driver
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018q9">inset, Figure 269</hotlnk>). Seal should be installed so the spring is to the
                front of the transmission.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018q9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018q9" filename="../figg13/G13018q9.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 268. Install Oil Seal in Rear Bearing Cover With Spring to Front of Transmission
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the assembly upright in vise and secure on flange of the auxiliary housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018r0">Figure 270</hotlnk>). Position the new gasket on the cover mounting surface
                and install the rear bearing cover. Use the nylon collar and brass washer with bolt at the chamfered
                hole which intersects speedometer bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018r0">inset, Figure 270</hotlnk>). Apply Loctite 242 to the bolt threads and tighten
                the bolts to 35 to 45 ft-lbs. (47 to 61 Nm) to secure the cover to the auxiliary housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018r0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018r0" filename="../figg13/G13018r0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 269. Secure Assembly on Flange of Auxiliary Housing, and Use Nylon Collar and Brass
                    Washer
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Because the collar becomes distorted when compressed, DO NOT REUSE OLD NYLON COLLAR.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_68.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_70.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
