<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Preliminary Inspection</title>
        <para>The following items must be checked prior to beginning the diagnostic procedure:</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Know/Understand the Concern</emph>
        </para>
        <para>In order to diagnose a concern correctly, you must first understand the customer complaint or condition.
            Customer contact may be required in order for the technician to begin to verify the concern. You must also
            understand the conditions when the concern occurs, for example:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>hot or cold vehicle temperature.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>hot or cold ambient temperature.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>vehicle driving conditions.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>After understanding when and how the concern occurs, proceed to Verify the Condition.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify the Condition</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This section provides information that must be used in both determining the actual cause of customer
            concerns and carrying out the appropriate procedures.
        </para>
        <para>The following procedures must be used when verifying customer concerns for the transmission:</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Determine Customer Concern</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Some transmission conditions can cause engine concerns. An electronic pressure control short
                    circuit can cause engine misfiring. The torque converter clutch not disengaging will stall the
                    engine.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Determine customer concerns relative to vehicle use and dependent driving conditions, paying attention to
            the following items:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Hot or cold vehicle operating temperature</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Hot or cold ambient temperature</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Type of terrain</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle loaded/unloaded</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>City/highway driving</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Upshift</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Downshift</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Coasting</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engagement</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Noise/vibration - check for dependencies, either rpm dependent, vehicle speed dependent, shift
                    dependent, gear dependent, range dependent or temperature dependent.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicles equipped with power take-off (PTO), the PTO must be turned OFF. For a description of PTO
                    operation, refer to Transmission Electronic Control System in this section.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Check Fluid Level and Condition</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fluid Level Check</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The vehicle should not be driven if the fluid level indicator shows the fluid below the DO NOT
                    DRIVE mark or internal failure could result.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the vehicle has been operated for an extended period of time at highway speeds, in city
                    traffic, in hot weather or while pulling a trailer, the fluid needs to cool down to obtain an
                    accurate reading.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The fluid level reading on the indicator will differ depending on operating and ambient
                    temperatures. The correct reading should be within the normal operating temperature range.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Under normal circumstances, the fluid level should be checked during normal maintenance. If the
            transmission starts to slip, shifts slowly or shows signs of leaking, the fluid level should be checked.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>With the transmission in (P) PARK, the engine at idle and foot pressed on the brake, move the
                    range selector lever through each gear and allow engagement of each gear. Place the range selector
                    lever in the PARK position.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wipe the fluid level indicator cap and remove the indicator.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wipe the indicator with a clean cloth.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Install the indicator back in the filler tube until it is fully seated, then remove the indicator.
                    The fluid level should be within the normal operating temperature range.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <figure id="f0701009" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figa00/a0060219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Cold Temperature Range</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Normal Operating Temperature Range</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DO NOT DRIVE IF BELOW THIS LEVEL AND OUTSIDE TEMPERATURE IS ABOVE 10&#176;C (50&#176;F)
                    (Underfill). Recheck fluid level at normal operating temperature and adjust as required.
                </callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DO NOT DRIVE LEVEL (Overfill). Remove excess fluid. Recheck fluid level at
                    normal operating temperature and adjust as required.
                </callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">High Fluid Level</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A fluid level that is too high may cause the fluid to become aerated due to the churning action of the
            rotating internal parts. This will cause erratic control pressure, foaming, loss of fluid from the vent tube
            and possible transmission malfunction or damage. If an overfill reading is indicated, refer to Transmission
            Fluid Drain and Refill - Without Torque Converter Drain Plug and With Fluid Pan Drain Plug in this section.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Low Fluid Level</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A low fluid level could result in poor transmission engagement, slipping, malfunction and/or damage. This
            could also indicate a leak in one of the transmission seals or gaskets.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Adding Fluid</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The use of any other type of transmission fluid than specified could result in transmission
                    malfunction and/or damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>If fluid needs to be added, add fluid in 0.25-L (1/2-pint) increments through the filler tube. Do not
            overfill the fluid. For fluid type, refer to the Fluid Type specification chart.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fluid Condition Check</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Check the fluid level.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Observe the color and the odor. The color under normal circumstances should be dark reddish, not
                    brown or black or have a burnt odor.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Hold the fluid level indicator over a white facial tissue and allow the fluid to drop onto the
                    facial tissue and examine the stain.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If evidence of solid material is found, the transmission fluid pan should be removed for further
                    inspection.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the stain is a foamy pink color, this may indicate coolant in the transmission. The engine
                    cooling system should also be inspected at this time.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If fluid contamination or transmission failure is confirmed by the sediment in the bottom of the
                    fluid pan, the transmission must be disassembled and completely cleaned. This includes the torque
                    converter, coolers, cooler tubes and remote filter.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Carry out diagnostic checks and adjustments. Refer to Diagnosis By Symptom in this section.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <figure id="f0701010" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../fign00/n0005722.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 4. Remote Fluid Filter</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The 5R110 transmission is equipped with a remote transmission fluid filter which is located on the driver
            side rear of the transmission. Most of the transmission fluid which leaves the front fluid cooler tube
            connector passes through the remote filter and is directed into the cooling circuit. The remote filter takes
            10 percent of the incoming hot fluid and directs it through a small orifice and into a serviceable filter
            element. The filtered transmission fluid is then directed back into the rear lubrication circuit through the
            larger opening in the remote filter manifold. For additional information, refer to Transmission Fluid Cooler
            - Backflushing and Cleaning or
            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070260.xml" xrefid="x3070260">Transaxle/Transmission Cooling</hotlnk>.
        </para>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
