<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER AUTOMATE-2 - TROUBLESHOOTING (ELECTRICAL) - CONFIRMING PROPER OPERATION OF
        GEAR POSITION SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1302210" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CONFIRMING PROPER OPERATION OF GEAR POSITION SENSOR</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the ignition on. (Do not start the vehicle.) Place the transmission in high range and
                move the shift lever to the Auto position. The transmission light on the dashboard should turn on.
                Remove the lever from the Auto position, and the light should go out. If this does not occur, the Auto
                Switch system is not working properly. Continue to Step 2.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the Gear Position Sensor from the top of the transmission shift tower by removing the
                screw that secures it. Carefully connect a 12-volt DC power supply between pin A (positive) and pin D
                (negative) of the sensor connector.
            </para>
            <para>Connect an ohm meter positive lead to pin D and a negative lead to pin C.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Supplying voltage to any other terminal will destroy the sensor.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a permanent magnet, pass the south pole across the round bottom face of the Gear
                Position Sensor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If the meter reading is less than 30 ohms</emph>, the Gear Position Sensor is
                functioning properly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If the meter reading is 30 ohms or greater</emph>, replace the Gear Position
                Sensor. This should correct the fault.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Pass the north pole of the magnet across the bottom of the sensor.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If the meter reading is greater than 100,000 ohms</emph>, the Gear Position Sensor
                is functioning properly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">If the meter reading is less than 100,000 ohms</emph>, replace the Gear Position
                Sensor. This should correct the fault.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the Controller to Transmission Wiring Harness (J5) Refer to the electrical schematic
                and check for open or short circuits.
                <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302208.xml" xrefid="g13022m5">See Diagram.</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302208.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302211.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
