<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE - MAINSHAFT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>MAINSHAFT</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c7">Figure 127</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Any spline can be used for the key location.</para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>While assembling the components, refer to the cross section in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c7">Figure 127</hotlnk>. When the mainshaft and gears are assembled correctly,
                    the assembly will have the same shape as the cross section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With mainshaft pilot-end (small end) down, secure the mainshaft in a vise with brass jaw
                protectors (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c8">Figure 128</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032c7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 127. Cross Section Of Mainshaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f13032c8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032c8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 128. Secure Mainshaft in Vise</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Identify and set aside the reverse gear. The reverse gear has three notches on the inside
                diameter that face the rear of the main case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Slide a splined washer over the mainshaft into the lowest groove, and rotate the washer to
                offset the splines and hold the washer in place.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A spare piece of 12 inch long 5/32 inch air line can be used as a temporary key to assist in
                    assembly. From the bottom, feed the air line up the keyway through the splined washers and gears to
                    hold the components in place. After the mainshaft is assembled, the key can be inserted from the top
                    as the air line is withdrawn (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c8">Figure 128</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>Any spline can be used for the keyway.</para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>Six of the washers are the same size. Unlike previous Eaton Fuller transmissions, this
                    transmission does not require gear endplays to be set.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the smallest gear on the mainshaft with clutching teeth down.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a splined washer in the second groove against the gear. Rotate the washer to capture
                it in its groove.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With clutching teeth up, install the next smallest gear, making sure it rests against the
                splined washer below it.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a splined washer in the third groove. Rotate the washer to capture it in its
                groove.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the missing internal splines aligned with the keyway, install the middle position
                sliding clutch (28 teeth).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position a splined washer in the next available groove.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the next smallest gear on the mainshaft with clutching teeth down.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position a splined washer against the gear. Rotate the washer to capture it in its groove.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the next smallest gear on shaft against 2nd speed gear with the clutching teeth
                up.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position a washer against the gear. Rotate the washer to capture it in its groove.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the missing internal splines aligned with the keyway, install the rear sliding clutch
                (28 teeth).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the reverse gear on the mainshaft and over the rear sliding clutch with clutching
                teeth down.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the reverse gear splined washer (large diameter washer) in the remaining groove.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the shape of the mainshaft against the cross section in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c7">Figure 127</hotlnk>. If the mainshaft is assembled correctly, the shapes will
                be identical. If the shapes are different, disassemble the mainshaft and assemble it again.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the key from the rear of the mainshaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the mainshaft from the vise, being careful that the key does not slide back out.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lay the mainshaft on its side, and from the front, install the front sliding clutch (26
                teeth). Make sure the missing spline lines up over the keyway.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_69.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_71.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
