<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION SHIFT LINKAGE - INSTALL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TRANSMISSION SHIFT LEVER</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place transmission shift lever down and rearward (
                    <hotlnk document="s13031_1.xml" xrefid="f1303102">Item 11, Figure 2</hotlnk>) onto the transmission
                    selector shaft (
                    <hotlnk document="s13031_1.xml" xrefid="f1303102">Item 15, Figure 2</hotlnk>) far enough to install
                    retaining nut. Move transmission shift lever to a detent position other than reverse or first gear
                    detent position. Reverse and first are at opposite ends of the transmission shift lever travel arc.
                    Position lever in a midway detent position which is between reverse and first. Do not drive lever
                    onto shaft. Be sure lever is indexed with flats on the selector shaft. Install nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Since the mating parts are a tapered fit, the lever cannot be fully installed initially. The
                        lever will go onto the machined flats of shaft far enough to be properly indexed, then it is
                        moved against the shoulder of the shaft by tightening retaining nut. If lever is forced onto
                        shaft by hammering or bumping, the selector shaft components inside transmission housing will be
                        damaged. The lever should be held when tightening the retaining nut in Step 2 because of
                        possible damage to selector detent lever and spring roller components inside transmission. Push
                        selector lever onto flats of selector shaft.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grasp lever and while holding it, tighten nut to 15 to 20 ft-lbs. (20 to 27 Nm).</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Torque in excess of 20 ft-lbs. (27 Nm) will damage threads on selector shaft.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Upon completing installation of shift lever, move lever thru detent range positions to
                    check for freedom from binding and positive detent engagement.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13031_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13031_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13031.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
