<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 - Prepare
        Parts for Assembly - Inspect Parts
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="11">
        <title>Inspect Parts</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>It is very important to inspect all parts carefully and completely before the transfer case is
                assembled. Check all parts for wear and stress. Replace all damaged parts.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect tapered roller bearings. Inspect the cup, cone, rollers and cage of all tapered
                    roller bearings in the assembly. If any of the following conditions exist, the bearing MUST be
                    replaced.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1303531" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303531.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 31. Inspect Cup, Cone, Rollers and Cage</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. WORN RADIUS</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. WORN SURFACE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The center of large diameter end of rollers is worn level with or below the outer
                        surface.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The radius at the large diameter end of rollers is worn to a sharp edge (Figure
                        31).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A visible roller groove is worn in the inner race surfaces of the cup or cone. The
                        groove can be seen at the small or large diameter end of both parts.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Deep cracks or breaks in the cup, cone inner race or roller surfaces (Figure 32).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Bright wear marks appear on the outer surface of the roller cage (Figure 33).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Damage on rollers and on surfaces of the cup and cone inner race that touch the
                        rollers (Figure 34).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Damage on the cup and cone inner race surfaces that touch the rollers (Figure 35).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303532" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303532.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Deep Cracks or Breaks</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CRACK</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WEAR GROOVES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303533" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303533.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Wear Marks</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WEAR MARKS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303534" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303534.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Etching and Pitting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ETCHING AND PITTING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303535" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303535.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Spalling and Flaking</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPALLING AND FLAKING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the gears for wear or damage. Replace worn or damaged gears.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the housing:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove all dirt from the housing and oil lubrication passages, troughs, slots and
                        holes.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect machined surfaces for cracks and damage. Repair or replace damaged parts.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all shafts, flanges and yokes for wear, stress and cracks at the splines, shaft
                    and yoke ears. Replace shafts, flanges and yokes that are worn or cracked.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that any oil passages in the shafts are clean and free of debris.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the declutch and output shaft components, if applicable:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the clutch collar internal splines, external declutch teeth and shift for
                        grooves. Replace worn, cracked or damaged collars.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the collar pads of the shift fork for wear. If the pads are worn, replace
                        the shift fork.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the declutch shaft and yoke for wear, stress and cracks at the splines,
                        shaft and yoke ears. Replace worn or cracked shafts and yokes.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the declutch or PTO push rod and piston for wear or damage. Replace worn or
                        damaged parts.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the splines on the pump inner rotor for cracks along the spline area. Also,
                    check for excessive wear. Replace the pump if these conditions exist.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and inspect the restrictor plug at the end of the input shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the orifice is clear of debris.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Helical Gears</title>
            <para>Inspect the helical gear teeth, splines and journals. If any of the following conditions exist,
                replace the gear:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A crack in the root of a tooth or along the tooth flank (Figure 36).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Severe scoring or fretting on the surface of a tooth. Gears with scoring and fretting on the
                        teeth, but without cracks, may continue to operate satisfactorily with higher noise (Figure 37).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracks along the internal journal of the input gears (Figure 38).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Deep gouges or metal transfer along the input gear journals (Figure 39).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or severely worn shifting splines on the input gears.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or cracked splines on the output gears.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f1303536" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303536.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Crack in Root of Tooth</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CRACK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303537" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303537.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Scoring or Fretting on Surface of Tooth</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPALLING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303538" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303538.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Crack Along Input Gear Journal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CRACK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303539" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303539.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Gouge Along Input Gear Journal</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Shafts</title>
            <para>Inspect the input and output shafts for damage to the gear journals, shifting splines, threads and
                gear retaining splines. If any of the following conditions exist, replace the shaft:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Deep gouges or metal transfer along the input shaft journals (Figure 40).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or worn shifting splines on the input shaft.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or cracked splines on the output shaft (Figure 41).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracks along the yoke splines, bearing journal abutments or cross-drilled holes. Magnaflux may
                        be necessary to see small cracks.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f1303540" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303540.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Metal Transfer Along Input Shaft Journal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. METAL TRANSFER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303541" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/g1303541.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Chipped Splines</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHIPPED SPLINES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PTO Components</title>
            <para>Inspect the PTO housing, shaft, taper bearings, shift collar, shift fork and sensors for damage. If
                any of the following conditions exist, replace the component:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cracks in the housing.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracks along the shaft yoke spline or ball bearing abutment. Magnaflux may be necessary to see
                        small cracks.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or cracked shifting splines on the shift collar or shaft.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The rollers of the taper bearings do not roll easily or lack lubrication. The raceway is
                        cracked or dented.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or missing tangs on the shift fork arms.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The sensor ball sticks or does not return to its resting position. The sensors do not complete
                        a circuit when tested with a volt-ohm meter (VOM).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>High and Low Shifting Components</title>
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the shift collar, shift fork, shift shaft, retaining pins, shift cylinder, piston, O-ring and
                case halves for damage. If any of the following conditions exist, replace or repair the component:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or missing tangs on the shift fork arms.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chipped or cracked shifting splines on the shift collar.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracks or deep gouges on the shift shaft.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The retaining pins in the shift shaft are not 0.100-inch (2.54 mm) above the shaft diameter.
                        Remove and set to the correct position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Gouges on the inside of the shift cylinder.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torn or feathered areas on the O-ring.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Deep gouges in the shifting bores of the case halves.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil and Lubrication System</title>
            <para>The lubrication system is extremely important to the performance of the transfer case. Inspect all
                parts closely for excessive wear or damage. Perform the following checks:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the oil for metal shavings, dirt and consistency. Perform an analysis if the oil
                    appears contaminated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the magnets for metal shavings. A small amount of metal shavings is normal.
                    However excessive build-up indicates gear and bearing damage. Thoroughly remove all metal shavings
                    from the magnets. The magnets must be firmly fastened to the case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the sump screen. Remove any material that may restrict oil flow through the
                    mesh.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the seals closely. Look for nicks and tears on all sealing lips. Any damage is
                    likely to result in a seal leak.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the pump for easy rotation. If the internal gear does not spin easily or jams when
                    rotating the crescent plate, replace the pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the oil line for damage. Replace if it is dented or kinked.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the pump drive pins are 0.63-inch (1.6 mm) above the diameter of the shaft.
                    Remove and set to the correct position if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transfer Case Halves</title>
            <para>Inspect the case halves for cracks and internal wear. If any of the following conditions exist,
                replace the damaged parts:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A crack in either case half.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Deep gouges in the shifting bores.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Preparing Case and Cover and Seal Replacement</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pry out all oil seals using a suitable pry bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">As necessary, use a suitable puller to remove the bearing cups pressed into the transfer
                    case halves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean and inspect the transfer case and cover for cracks, worn threaded holes or other
                    wear or damage. Clean the gasket surfaces of both transfer case halves using a suitable gasket
                    scraper or wire wheel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press new bearing cups into the case halves as necessary. Refer to Idler Shaft Bearing
                    End Play Adjustment in the ASSEMBLY Section for bearing setting procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect bearing end play to ensure that it's within specification. Adjust end play, if
                    required. Refer to the ASSEMBLY Section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new oil seals into the case halves. Use Meritor's seal driver, part number
                    R4422402 for a 3.25-inch nominal diameter seal. The seal driver is included in Meritor's Kit 4454.
                    To order this Kit, call ArvinMeritor's Commercial Vehicle Aftermarket at 888-725-9355 and specify
                    Meritor Kit 4454.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
