<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 5 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER ES43-5 AND ES53-5 -
        TROUBLESHOOTING - BEARINGS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BEARINGS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dirt</title>
            <para>More than 90% of all ball bearing failures are caused by dirt, which is always abrasive.</para>
            <para>Dirt may enter the bearings during assembly of unit or may be carried into the bearing by the
                lubricant while in service. Dirt also may enter bearings through seals, the breather or even dirty
                containers used for addition or change of lubricant.
            </para>
            <para>Hard, coarse material, such as metal chips, may enter the bearings during assembly from tools such as
                hammers, drifts, and power chisels. It may also be manufactured within the unit during service from
                raking teeth. These chips produce small indentations in balls and races. When these hard particles jam
                between the balls and races, it may cause the inner race to turn on the shaft, or the outer race to turn
                in the housing.
            </para>
            <para>Softer material, such as dirt or dust, usually forms abrasive paste or lapping compounds within the
                bearings. The pressure between the balls and raceways makes a perfect pulverizer. The rolling motion
                tends to entrap and hold the abrasives. As the balls and raceways wear, the bearings become noisy. The
                lapping action tends to increase rapidly as the fine steel from the balls and rollway adds to the
                lapping material.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fatigue</title>
            <para>All bearings are subject to fatigue and must be replaced eventually. Your own operating experience
                will dictate mileage replacement of bearings showing only normal wear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Corrosion</title>
            <para>Water, acid and corrosive materials formed by deterioration of lubricant, will produce a reddish-brown
                coating and small etched holes over outer and exposed surfaces of the race. Corrosive oxides also act as
                lapping agents.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Shaft Fits</title>
            <para>Bearing fits on rotating shafts are usually specified as tight. Excessive looseness-even .001"-under a
                load produces a creeping or slipping of the inner race on the rotating shaft. The result is that surface
                metal of the shafts scrub or wear off. The force causing the inner race to rotate disappears when the
                bearing fits properly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation and Removal of Bearings</title>
            <para>Improper installation or removal of bearings, especially hammering the bearing on the shaft with
                off-center blows, can result in brinelling. Since such damage is seldom visible, it does not become
                known until after failure or complete disassembly. The correct drivers (preferably under an arbor press)
                and pullers should be used.
            </para>
            <para>Removing bearings is more difficult than installing them. In most cases, it is necessary to remove the
                bearing by pulling on the outer race, which can damage the balls or races. Therefore, it is a good idea
                to replace bearings during an overhaul, to prevent problems. However, if a bearing is not going to be
                replaced, avoid removal during low mileage rebuilds.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Interchangeability</title>
            <para>All ball bearings, whether manufactured here or abroad, are interchangeable in regard to standardized
                dimensions, tolerances, and fits. However, for a given shaft size there are standard bearings for light,
                medium, and heavy duty service.
            </para>
            <para>Numbers and symbols stamped on inner and outer races of bearings designate size and type. Note that
                the numbering systems of different bearing manufacturers have not been standardized. Consult
                interchangeable tables and use the proper bearings for replacement parts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13009_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13009_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
