<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER - CLEAN AND INSPECT - INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Inspect parts thoroughly for wear or damage. Parts damaged or worn from previous service must be
                replaced to ensure maximum rebuild life. Suggested inspection procedures include the following.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Collars</title>
            <para>Both the internal and external teeth must have sharp edges. Check for chipped or broken teeth, or
                teeth with rounded corners. Also, examine fork slots for wear. Replace collars if any of these
                conditions exist.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Gears</title>
            <para>Examine for broken or cracked operating and clutching teeth. Also check for any unusual wear patterns.
                If any of the preceding exist, replace the gear. If a gear is replaced, also replace the mating gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thrust Washers</title>
            <para>Check for flatness or excessive face wear, cracks, scoring, or signs of heat damage. Replace if any of
                these conditions exist.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Snap Rings</title>
            <para>New snap rings are recommended with every rebuild.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mainshaft</title>
            <para>Check for signs of twisting or misalignment. Also check for worn or damaged splines. Replace the shaft
                if any of these conditions exist.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Control</title>
            <para>Check the shift fingers, bushing bores and rods for excessive wear or scuffing. Replace springs,
                bearing races, boots and seals. Clean all reusable parts thoroughly and apply a light coat of grease to
                the pivot points when reassembling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bearings</title>
            <para>New bearings are recommended with every rebuild (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13023x_11.xml" xrefid="hl1302304">BEARINGS</hotlnk>
                for further information.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Housings</title>
            <para>Inspect the housing sections for cracks. If cracks exist, replace that section of the housing. Also
                inspect the shift bar support bracket for cracks or worn slots. Replace if either of these conditions
                exist.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
