<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE - AUXILIARY
        SECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="10">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To aid in reassembling the auxiliary section, use a fixture that will hold the countershafts in
                    the proper positions. The dimensions of the fixture are shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b3">Figure 113</hotlnk>. The fixture is constructed from a 2 inch x 12 inch x
                    24 inch piece of wood.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f13032b3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 113. Auxiliary Section Dimensions</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For timing purposes, identify and mark with toolmaker's dye the two teeth on each
                countershaft that are identified with a "0" (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b4">Figure 114</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032b4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 114. Mark Two Teeth on Each Countershaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the countershafts in the fixture (or on a clean, flat surface if you don't have a
                fixture) with the marked teeth turned to the middle of the fixture (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b5">Figure 115</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032b5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 115. Place Spacer Between Countershafts</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position a 2 inch high spacer, such as a socket, between the countershafts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b5">Figure 115</hotlnk>). (If a fixture is not used, a 3 inch spacer is required.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the synchronizer assembly on the output shaft. The low range synchronizer ring (side
                with external friction material) must be facing the auxiliary mainshaft reduction gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b6">Figure 116</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032b6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 116. Install Synchronizer Assembly on Output Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Match the timing marks on the auxiliary mainshaft reduction gear with the timing marks on
                the countershafts. The output shaft will rest on the spacer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b7">Figure 117</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the round hole in the range yoke bar facing up, slide the range yoke assembly into the
                groove on the range synchronizer
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b7">(Figure 117).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032b7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 117. Match Timing Marks and Slide Range Yoke Assembly into Groove</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lightly oil the bearing bores on the auxiliary housing, and place the auxiliary housing over
                the countershaft assemblies and the output shaft assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b8">Figure 118</hotlnk>). Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the output shaft bearing race in the housing bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b8">Figure 118</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the output shaft bearing inner spacer is on the output shaft. (The spacer should
                have been installed when the output shaft components were assembled).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear insulated gloves or similar protection to prevent possible burns when handling hot
                    components.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Heat the rear output bearing cone (or use an appropriate driver) and install the outer
                bearing cone, tapered side down, on the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b8">Figure 118</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032b8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 118. Install Output Shaft Bearing Race and Outer Bearing Cone</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new gasket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the marks made during disassembly as a guide, install the rear bearing cover in the same
                position as when removed (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032b9">Figure 119</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The rear bearing cover can be installed in two positions 180 degrees opposite each other. If the
                    rear bearing cover is not installed in the same position in which it was removed, the speedometer
                    cable may not reach the speedometer after the transmission is installed in the vehicle. If the
                    speedometer cannot be connected, the auxiliary bearing cover must be removed and reassembled
                    properly.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f13032b9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032b9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 119. Install Rear Bearing Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite 242 or equivalent to the six (6) rear bearing cover retaining bolts and
                install them. Tighten the bolts to 54 to 61 Nm (40 to 45 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the countershaft bearing races in their bores (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c0">Figure 120</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032c0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 120. Insert Countershaft Bearing Races in Their Bores</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the original parts are being re-used and installed in their original locations, the shims can
                    also be installed at this time.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If shimming will be required, temporarily install the auxiliary countershaft shim and
                support tools. Final installation and shimming of the countershafts will be done after the auxiliary
                section is installed on front section (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c1">Figure 121</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032c1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 121. Install Countershaft Shim and Support Tools</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If shimming will not be required, the auxiliary countershaft bearing covers can be installed at
                    this time. However, the shim tools will help prevent the countershafts from dropping excessively
                    when the auxiliary section is installed.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the auxiliary section in a vise with brass jaw protectors.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the auxiliary housing back, install the range alignment lock cover and O-ring. Rotate the
                cover to the unlock position, and secure the cover in place with a bolt (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c2">Figure 122</hotlnk>, left).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the O-ring over the output shaft, and insert it against the output bearing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c2">Figure 122</hotlnk>, right).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the speedometer rotor seal/sleeve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13032c2">Figure 122</hotlnk>, right).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the output yoke.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the output nut for damage. If the nylon locking material is damaged or excessively
                worn, replace the nut. The nylon locking material must be in good condition to prevent the nut from
                loosening during operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lightly oil the threads and install the output yoke nut. Tighten the nut to 610 to 678 Nm
                (450 to 500 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13032c2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13032c2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 122. Secure Cover (Left), and Install Speedometer Rotor Seal/Sleeve (Right)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_67.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_69.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
