<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>6 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS INTERNATIONAL MODEL ES52-7A AND ESO65-7A 6-PLUS - TROUBLESHOOTING - WALKING OR JUMPING
        OUT OF GEAR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WALKING OR JUMPING OUT OF GEAR</title>
        <para>If the units are walking out of gear, it could be caused by:</para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>External interference, such as the floorboard opening, preventing full engagement,
                    <emph type="italic">or</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>An internal malfunction, such as worn clutching teeth, allowing the transmission to shift out of
                    position.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>If a remote control is being used, make sure it is functioning properly before the transmission is blamed
            for the problem. Note whether the unit walks out of gear under drive while pulling a load, or on a coast
            load. Also, notice whether the gear hop occurs on smooth roads or only on rough roads. Items that would
            prevent full engagement of gears are:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>Improperly positioned forward remote control which limits full travel forward and backward from
                    the remote neutral position.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Improper length shift rails or linkage that limits travel of forward remote from neutral
                    position.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Loose bell cranks, sloppy ball and socket joints.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Shift rails, cables, etc., too spongy or flexible, or not secured properly at both ends.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Worn or loose engine mounts if forward unit is mounted to frame.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Forward remote mount too flimsy, or loose on the frame.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Setscrews loose at remote control joints, on shift forks inside remote or even inside transmission
                    unit.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Shift fork pads or groove sliding gear or collar worn excessively.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Transmission and engine out of alignment either vertically or horizontally.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>A few items which could move the gear or shaft out of proper position, particularly on rough roads are:
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Use of heavy shift lever extensions.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Broken shift rail poppet springs.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Worn shift rail poppet notches.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Bent or sprung shift rails.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Excessive end-play in drive gear or countershaft, caused by worn bearings or retainers.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Worn or missing thrust rings.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
