<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 18 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14618 AND RTLO-16618
        SERIES - REASSEMBLE - RIGHT REVERSE IDLER GEAR ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1301909" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="5">
        <title>RIGHT REVERSE IDLER GEAR ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, thread pipe plug in the rear of the reverse idler shaft and tighten (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019k4">Figure 204</hotlnk>). Install the thrust washer to the end of the idler shaft.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If previously removed, replace the needle bearing into the bore of the reverse idler gear.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f13019k4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019k4" filename="../figg13/G13019K4.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 204. Thread Pipe Plug in Rear of Reverse Idler Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing inner race on the idler shaft and insert shaft into the case bore,
                threaded end of shaft to the front. As the idler shaft is moved forward, install the reverse idler gear
                on the shaft, long hub to the front and seating on the bearing inner race. Position the thrust washer on
                the shaft between the gear and support boss in the case and continue with movement of the idler shaft
                forward into the bore of the support boss (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019k5">Figure 205</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019k5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019k5" filename="../figg13/G13019K5.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 205. Install Reverse Idler Gear on Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure that the reverse idler shaft is seated in the bore of support boss and forward as
                far as possible. Install the washer and stop nut on the front of the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019k6">Figure 206</hotlnk>). Tighten nut to 50 to 60 ft-lbs. (68 to 81 N&#183;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019k6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019k6" filename="../figg13/G13019K6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 206. Install Washer and Stop Nut on Front of Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the OUTER RACE of auxiliary countershaft front bearing into the case bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13019k7">Figure 207</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13019k7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019k7" filename="../figg13/G13019K7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 207. Install Outer Race of Auxiliary Countershaft Front Bearing</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Mark the countershaft drive gear for timing purposes. On the drive gear of each countershaft
                        assembly, mark the tooth aligned with the keyway of the gear and stamped with an "O" for easy
                        identification (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13019k8">Figure 208</hotlnk>). A highly visible color of toolmaker's dye is
                        recommended for making timing marks.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f13019k8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13019k8" filename="../figg13/G13019K8.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 208. Mark Countershaft Drive Gear For Timing Purposes</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_52.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019_54.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
