<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - INSTALL - AUXILIARY SECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="3">
        <title>AUXILIARY SECTION</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The two reverse gears, including the washers, must be in perfect alignment with the center of the
                    case bores as the front of the auxiliary countershafts must be inserted in these parts during
                    auxiliary installation. A heavy grease or lubriplate will help hold the washers in place. Also check
                    the rear of the front section to make sure all snap rings have been installed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13024h3">Figure 173</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f13024h3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13024h3" filename="../figg13/G13024H3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 173. Make Sure All Snap Rings Have Been Installed</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary section on the front section, aligning the auxiliary section on the
                dowel pins and the extended portion of the auxiliary countershafts with the reverse idler gears. It may
                make assembly easier if someone slowly rotates the input shaft during installation (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13024h4">Figure 174</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13024h4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13024h4" filename="../figg13/G13024H4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 174. Install Auxiliary Section on Front Section</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The auxiliary can also be installed with the front section in a vertical position. Place the
                    clutch housing on blocks and use chain hoist to lower the auxiliary section into position (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13024h5">Figure 175</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the auxiliary with attaching bolts. Tighten bolts to 35 to 45 ft-lbs. (47 to 61 N&#183;
                m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13024h5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g13024h5" filename="../figg13/G13024H5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 175. Auxiliary Can Be Installed With Front Section in Vertical Position</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
