<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>9 SPEED AND 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON 16709 AND 16710 SERIES - PRECAUTIONS - INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECTION</title>
        <para>Before reassembling the transmission, check each part carefully for abnormal or excessive wear and damage
            to determine reuse or replacement. When replacement is necessary, use only genuine Fuller Transmission parts
            to assure continued perform- ance and extended life from your unit.
        </para>
        <para>Since the cost of a new part is generally a small fraction of the total cost of downtime and labor, avoid
            reusing a questionable part which could lead to additional repairs and expense soon after initial
            reassembly. To aid in determining the reuse or replacement of any transmission part, consideration should
            also be given to the unit's history, mileage, application, etc.
        </para>
        <para>Recommended inspection procedures are provided in the following checklist.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARINGS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wash all bearings in clean solvent. Check balls, rollers and raceways for pitting,
                    discoloration, and spalled areas. Replace bearings that are pitted, discolored, or spalled.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Lubricate bearings that are not pitted, discolored, or spalled and check for axial and
                    radial clearances.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Replace bearings with excessive clearances.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check bearing fits. Bearing inner races should be tight to the shaft; outer races
                    slightly tight to slightly loose in the case bore. If the bearing spins freely in the bore, however,
                    the case should be replaced.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GEARS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">.Check gear teeth for frosting and pitting. Frosting of gear tooth faces presents no
                    threat of transmission failure. Often in continued operation of the unit, frosted gears will "heal"
                    and not progress to the pitting stage. And in most cases, gears with light to moderate pitted teeth
                    have considerable gear life remaining and can be reused. But gears with advanced stage pitting
                    should be replaced.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check for gears with clutching teeth abnormally worn, tapered, or reduced in length from
                    clashing in shifting. Replace gears found in any of these conditions.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Checkaxial clearance of gears. Where excessive clearance is found, check gear snap ring,
                    washer, spacer, and gear hub for excessive wear. Maintain .005" to .012" axial clearance between
                    mainshaft gears.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SPLINES</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check splines on all shafts for abnormal wear. If companion flange, clutch hub, or
                    sliding clutch gears have worn into the sides of the splines, replace the specific shaft affected.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">TOLERANCE/ LIMIT WASHERS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check surfaces of all limit washers. Washers scored or reduced in thickness should be
                    replaced.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">REVERSE IDLER GEAR ASSEMBLIES</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check for excessive wear from action of roller bearings.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GRAY IRON PARTS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check all gray iron parts for cracks and breaks. Replace or repair parts found to be
                    damaged.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">CLUTCH RELEASE PARTS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check clutch release parts. Replace yokes worn at cam surfaces and bearing carrier worn
                    at contact pads.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check clutch pedal shafts. Replace those worn at bushing surfaces.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SHIFTER HOUSING ASSEMBLY</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check for wear on shift yokes and blocks at pads and lever slot. Replace excessively
                    worn parts.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the yokes for correct alignment. Replace sprung yokes.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check lockscrews in yokes and blocks. Tighten and rewire those found loose.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the housing has been disassembled, check the neutral notches of the shift bars for
                    wear from the interlock balls.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GEAR SHIFT LEVER HOUSING ASSEMBLY</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check spring tension on the shift lever. Replace the tension spring and washer if the
                    lever moves too freely.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the housing is disassembled, check the spade pin and corresponding slot in the lever
                    for wear. Replace both parts if excessively worn.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARING COVERS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Checkcovers for wear from the thrust of the adjacent bearing. Replace covers damaged
                    from the thrust of the bearing outer race.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the bores of the covers for wear. Replace those worn oversize.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">OIL RETURN THREADS AND SEALS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check oil return threads on the input shaft. If the sealing action of the threads has
                    been destroyed by contact with the bearing cover, replace the input shaft.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the oil seal in the rear bearing cover. If the sealing action of the lip has been
                    destroyed, replace the seal.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SLIDING CLUTCHES</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Checkall shift yokes and yoke slots in the sliding clutches for extreme wear or
                    discoloration from heat.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the engaging teeth of the sliding clutches for partial engagement pattern.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SYNCHRONIZER ASSEMBLY</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the synchronizer for burrs, uneven and excessive wear at the contact surface, and
                    metal particles.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the blocker pins for excessive wear or looseness.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the synchronizer contact surfaces on the auxiliary drive and low range gears for
                    excessive wear.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">O-RlNGS</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check all O-rings for cracks or distortion. Replace if worn or damaged.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
