<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FULLER 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - ASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="10">
            <title>SHIFT BAR HOUSING</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Steps 1 and 2 are for overdrive models only.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the actuator arm over the pivot pin, and secure it with the snap ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303292">Figure 92</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303292" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303292.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 92. Install Actuator Arm</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>On overdrive models, if the direct/ overdrive yoke was not previously removed, install the oil
                        trough and temporarily tie the yoke to the trough to prevent the yoke from falling toward the
                        shift shaft and interfering with assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the housing with the bottom facing upward and the front of the housing (marked
                    FRONT) toward you.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To aid assembly, lightly oil the inside of the shift yokes, overdrive shift block, shift
                    shaft, detent key, shift key, and the inside of the shift shaft bores on the shift bar housing.
                    Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the shift yokes (and actuator shift block for overdrive models) in the
                    approximate position in the shift bar housing that they will be in when the shift shaft is
                    installed. Make sure the yokes are installed with the word FRONT facing the front of the shift bar
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the detent key (it has rounded, protruding notches) from the front of the shift
                    bar housing. Install the key with the word FRONT facing the front of the shift bar housing. To
                    install the key, slide it down the left side of the shift shaft bore and through each shift yoke
                    (and actuator shift block). One of the rectangular notches should fit in each yoke (and the shift
                    block). The key fits between the front and rear bores of the shift bar housing. The three notches
                    face away from the centerline of the bore (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303293">Figure 93</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303294">Figure 94</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not hammer or force the shift shaft into position at step 7 or the shift bar housing
                        components will be damaged. When all the components are in the proper positions, the shift shaft
                        will slide in easily.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1303293" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303293.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 93. Install Detent Key</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1303294" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303294.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 94. Install Detent Key</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Starting at the front of the shift bar housing, slide the shift shaft into position,
                    making sure the bolt hole in the shift shaft faces downward. Use one hand to hold and position the
                    detent key and yokes and the other to insert the shift shaft. The detent key fits in the groove on
                    the shift shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303295">Figure 95</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not allow the detent key to slide rearward into the shift bar housing bore. It should butt
                        against the boss.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1303295" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303295.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 95. Slide Shift Shaft into Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, reposition the shift shaft yokes (and actuator shift block) in the neutral
                    position by aligning the detent key notches with the yokes (and actuator shift block).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the rear of the shift bar housing, slide the shift key into the right-hand shift
                    shaft groove. While sliding the key into place, align the key with the yokes (and actuator shift
                    block) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303296">Figure 96</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Casting flash may need to be removed from the rear opening for the shift key.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1303296" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303296.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 96. Install Shift Key</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the shift bar front, install the bias plate and snap ring. To properly install the
                    bias plate and snap ring, the shift shaft or shift key may need to be pushed rearward (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303297">Figure 97</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303297" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303297.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Install Bias Plate And Snap Ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Loctite 242 or equivalent to the Allen head plug threads, and install the bias
                    plunger, bias spring(s), and Allen head plug. Tighten the Allen head plug to 9.5 to 13. 6 Nm (84 to
                    120 in-lbs) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303298">Figure 98</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303298" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303298.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Install Allen Head Plug And Bias Plunger</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If previously removed, position the direct/overdrive shift yoke and yoke bar in the
                    shift bar housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1303299">Figure 99</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1303299" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303299.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Position Yoke and Yoke Bar in Shift Bar Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the yoke bar roll pin, and drive it into place.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If previously removed, position the oil trough, and install the oil trough retaining
                    bolts. Tighten the bolts to 27 to 31 Nm (20 to 23 ft-lbs).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the shift bar housing over so the shift block can be installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the detent spring(s) and detent plunger in the shift block.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the shift block on the shift shaft using the following procedure:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tilt the shift block so the plunger faces slightly upward.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the plunger in the center of the detent notch, and press the plunger in to
                        compress the spring(s).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">While the spring(s) are compressed, roll the shift block into place on the shift
                        shaft (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13032a0">Figure 100</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The shift shaft and shift key may require repositioning to allow the shift block to fit into
                        place.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f13032a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032a0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Roll Shift Block Into Place</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Loctite 242 or equivalent to the bolt. Install the shift block bolts. Tighten the
                    bolt to 54 to 61 Nm (40 to 45 ft-lbs) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13032a1">Figure 101</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the reverse pin and switch, neutral pin and switch, breather, and air module.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f13032a1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G13032a1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 101. Install Shift Block Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_60.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
