<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - INSTALL -
        MAINSHAFT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="24">
        <title>MAINSHAFT</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are worn or
                    damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <note>
                <para>To install the mainshaft, the input shaft and the main countershafts must be installed in the
                    case.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>Apply Loctite #242 or equivalent on the threads of the fasteners.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate all parts with new oil that is used in the transmission. Refer to GROUP
                10-LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The rear bearing cone must be installed on the upper countershaft.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the upper countershaft toward the side of the case
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v4">(Figure 314).</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>Install a long bolt or T-Handle Tool in the hole in the front of the upper countershaft. The tool or
                the bolt makes the countershaft easier to move.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033v4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 314. Install T-Handle Tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the input shaft and move the lower countershaft assembly so that the timing marks are
                aligned
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v5">(Figure 315)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033v5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 315. Align Timing Marks</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the snap ring to remove the auxiliary drive gear assembly from the mainshaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the snap ring that fastens the reverse gear to the mainshaft. Slide the reverse gear
                forward until the gear touches the low gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v6">(Figure 316).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the sliding collar on the front of the mainshaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v6">(Figure 316).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033v6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 316. Slide Reverse Gear Forward and Install Sliding Collar</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the lifting hooks or a rope under the mainshaft assembly. Install the mainshaft assembly
                in the case. Make sure the front of the mainshaft is installed in the bushing in the input shaft.
                Temporarily install the auxiliary drive gear to support the rear of the mainshaft. Remove the lifting
                hooks or rope
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v7">(Figure 317)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033v7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 317. Put Lifting Hooks or a Rope Under Mainshaft Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The mainshaft must be supported when the countershaft is serviced. If not supported, the timing
                    marks fall out of alignment. The weight of the mainshaft will also damage the thrust washers between
                    the gears.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary drive gear and arrange the assembly so that the mainshaft is supported
                in the case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the timing marks on the main drive gear of the input shaft with the timing marks on
                the upper countershaft. Use the T-Handle Tool or the long bolt to move the countershafts
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v8">(Figure 318</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>Remove the T-Handle Tool or long bolts from the countershafts.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The bearing cone must be installed on the rear of the countershaft.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033v8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 318. Align Timing Marks</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 1 Transmissions:</emph>
                install the upper rear bearing cup and the upper front bearing cup and cone on the countershaft.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put the cup in the bore for the upper rear countershaft. Use a plastic hammer to install
                    the cup in the bore.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver tool to install the upper rear countershaft cup. The cup
                    is correctly installed when the cup is past the snap ring groove
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033v9">(Figure 319</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033v9" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033V9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 319. Install Upper Rear Countershaft Cup</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Use hand tools to rotate the forcing screw of the countershaft bearing pusher tool. If
                            power tools are used, the tool will be damaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install Countershaft Bearing Pusher Tool or equivalent on the front of the countershaft.
                    Rotate the forcing screw until the rear countershaft bearing cup is against the snap ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w0">Figure 320)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w0" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 320. Install Countershaft Bearing Pusher Tool</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver tool to install the upper front countershaft cone. The
                    cone is correctly installed when the cone touches the countershaft
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w1">(Figure 321</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w1" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 321. Install Upper Front Countershaft Cone</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are
                            worn or damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver tool to install the upper front countershaft cup. The
                    cup is correctly installed when the cup is past the snap ring groove
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w2">(Figure 322)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w2" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 322. Install Upper Front Countershaft Cup</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install a 1.73 mm (.068 inch) snap ring in the bore for the front countershaft. The snap
                    O-ring is used as a gauge
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w3">(Figure 323)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w3" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 323. Install Snap Ring in Bore for Front Countershaft</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install T-Handle Tool or a long bolt in the front of the countershaft
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w4">(Figure 324)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Pull the countershaft and front cone assembly into the cup until the front cup is
                    against the snap ring
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w4">(Figure 324</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w4" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 324. Install T-Handle Tool and Pull Countershaft and Front Cone Assembly into Cup
                    </caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the T-Handle Tool or the long bolt.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The bearing cone must be installed on the rear of the countershaft.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Design Level 2 Transmissions:</emph>install the upper rear bearing cup and the upper
                front bearing cup and cone on the countershaft.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put the cup in the bore for the upper rear countershaft. Use a plastic hammer to install
                    the cup in the bore.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are
                            worn or damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Install the cup so that the cup extends at least 3 mm (0.125 or 1/8 inch) above the
                            surface of the case. Make sure the Driver Tool does not touch any part of the bearing cone
                            or the cone will be damaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver to install the rear cup in the bore. The cup is
                    correctly installed when the cup extends 3 mm (0.125 or 1/8 inch) above the surface of the case
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w5">(Figure 325).</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w5" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 325. Install Rear Cup in Bore</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean three bolts that fasten the countershaft rear bearing retainer to the main case
                    Apply Loctite #242 or equivalent to the threads of the bolts.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Use a new hardened countershaft bearing retainer to install the rear countershaft cup. If
                            a retainer that is not hardened is used, the transmission will be damaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put a hardened countershaft rear bearing retainer in position of the main case. Install
                    the bolts. Alternately and evenly tighten the bolts 47 Nm (35 ft-lbs.) until the retainer touches
                    the main case
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w6">(Figure 326).</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 326. Alternately and Evenly Tighten Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are
                            worn or damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver tool to install the upper front countershaft cone. The
                    cone is correctly installed when the bottom of the cone is against the countershaft
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w7">(Figure 327</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 327. Install Upper Front Countershaft Cone</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put the cup in the bore for the upper front countershaft. Use a plastic hammer to start
                    installing the cup in the bore.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear safe eye protection and make sure the tools are in safe condition. If the tools are
                            worn or damaged (mushroomed), pieces can break and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver tool to install the upper front countershaft cup. The
                    cup is correctly installed when the cup touches the bearing cone (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w8">Figure 328)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w8" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 328. Install Upper Front Countershaft Cup</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and bearing driver to install the front cup in the bore. The cup is
                    correctly installed when the cup extends 3 mm (0.125 inch) above the surface of the case.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the shims in the bore for the upper front countershaft bearing. Replace any worn
                    or damaged shims. Make sure the slot for the oil passage on the shims is aligned with the oil
                    passage hole. Install a 0.127 mm (0.005 inch) shim or a 0.190 mm (0.0075 inch) shim (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033w9">Figure 329).</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033w9" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033W9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 329. Align Slot With Oil Passage Hole</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Make sure the retainer and the shims are correctly installed against the case. Make sure
                            the retainer does not push the shims against the cup or the end play will not be correct.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install a new retainer for the upper and lower front countershaft bearings. Install the
                    Allen-head bolts. Alternately and evenly tighten the bolts to 14 Nm (120 in-lbs.)
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x0">(Figure 330)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 330. Install New Retainer and Allen-Head Bolts</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the end play on the upper and lower main countershafts as described in
                <hotlnk document="s13033_68.xml" xrefid="x1303305">ADJUSTMENT, MAIN COUNTERSHAFT END PLAY</hotlnk>
                section. The end play is between 0.051 to 0.152 mm (0.002 to 0.006 inch).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the needle bearing assembly inside the upper reverse idler gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x1">(Figure 331)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the inner race inside the needle bearing assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x1">Figure 331)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a spacer washer on each side of the reverse idler gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x1">Figure 331</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 331. Install Needle Bearing Assembly, Inner Race, and Spacer Washers</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the reverse idler gear in position in the top of the case.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the shaft through the reverse idler gear assembly from the auxiliary cover side of
                the transmission case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nut and washer on the upper reverse idler gear assembly. Hold the end of the
                shaft with a screwdriver. Tighten the nut to 102 to 136 Nm (75 to 100 ft-lbs.)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x2">(Figure 332)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 332. Install Nut and Washer on Upper Reverse Idler Gear Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the reverse gear to the rear of the mainshaft. Remove the auxiliary drive gear
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x3">(Figure 333)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 333. Move Reverse Gear to Rear of Mainshaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new snap ring that fastens the reverse gear on the mainshaft. Make sure the snap
                ring is completely installed in the groove
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x4">(Figure 334).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 334. Install Snap Ring Fastening Reverse Gear on Mainshaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the thrust washer on the mainshaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x5">Figure 335)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033x5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 335. Install Thrust Washer on Mainshaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the auxiliary drive gear assembly on the mainshaft and in the rear of the case.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13033x6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 336. Round Retainer</caption>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Round Retainer, see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x6">Figure 336.</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install the retainer, bearing and gear assembly on the mainshaft. Make sure the groove for the
                        snap ring on the shaft is visible.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Rotate the retainer so that the holes in the retainer are aligned with the bores in the
                        case.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install and tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).</para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Two-Piece Retainer, see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x7">Figure 337</hotlnk>.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <figure id="f13033x7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033X7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 337. Two-Piece Retainer</caption>
                </figure>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install the bearing assembly in the case over the mainshaft.</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install the two-piece retainer on the case.</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install and tighten the bolts to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Install the auxiliary drive gear on the mainshaft. Make sure the groove for the snap ring on
                        the shaft is visible.
                    </para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new snap ring that fastens the auxiliary drive gear on the main shaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033x6">(Figure 336)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_58.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_60.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
