<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - INSTALL -
        OUTPUT YOKE AND OIL SEAL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="3">
        <title>OUTPUT YOKE AND OIL SEAL</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the bore for the seal in the output bearing retainer and the seal journal on the
                output yoke for wear or damage. Replace the retainer if worn or damaged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the outer surface of the output bearing retainer where the seal is installed with
                the oil that is used in the transmission. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Hold the seal only on the outer diameter. Do not touch the inner diameter of the seal. Touching
                    contaminates the inner diameter of the seal and causes a leak between the shaft and the seal.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the oil seal in the output bearing retainer.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only the specified seal driver tool. If a different driver tool is used, the seal will not be
                    installed at the correct depth and will leak.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use seal driver tool, ZTSE-4424, to install the seal. Clean and inspect the tool. Replace
                the tool if the area that touches the seal is worn or damaged
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033y7">(Figure 347).</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>On 115 and 125 Series transmission, use the sleeve inside the seal driver tool.</para>
            <para>On 135, 145 and 155 Series transmissions, remove the sleeve from the inside of the seal driver tool.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033y7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033y7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 347. Install Seal</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the seal driver tool. Put the oil seal on the seal driver tool so that the spring is
                away from the tool. Make sure the seal is flat against the surface of the tool
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033y8">(Figure 348)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033y8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033y8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 348. Put Oil Seal on Tool So Spring is Away From Tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drive the seal into the retainer until the flange on the tool touches the retainer. Make
                sure there are not gaps between the tool and the retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use a cleaning solvent to clean the yoke. Do not use a crocus cloth to polish the journal of the
                    yoke. If a crocus cloth is used, the seal will leak.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the yoke with a cleaning solvent. Lubricate the journal and splines in the yoke with
                the oil that is used in the transmission.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Make sure the speedometer drive gear or tone ring is correctly installed or the output shaft seal
                    may be damaged when the yoke is installed.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the speedometer drive gear or tone ring on the yoke.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the yoke on the output shaft. Put a holding tool on the yoke
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033y9">(Figure 349</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not tighten the yoke nut more than 678 Nm (500 ft-lbs) or the output bearing will be damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new nut that fastens the yoke on the output shaft. Tighten the nut to 610 to 678
                Nm (450 to 500 ft-lbs.)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033y9">(Figure 349).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033y9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/g13033y9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 349. Install New Nut Fastening Yoke on Output Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_60.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
