<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>9 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS INTERNATIONAL PS125-9A, PS140-9A, PSO125-9A, PSO140-9A AND PSO150-9A - TROUBLESHOOTING
        - HARD SHIFTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HARD SHIFTING</title>
        <para>An improperly operating clutch will interfere with the proper shifting of gears in any transmission. It is
            also important that the hydraulic, air or similar release mechanism is in proper working order. If full and
            complete clutch release is being made, the following could be a few of the possible causes for hard shifting
            complaints:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>No lubricant in remote control unit.
                    <emph type="bold">(NOTE: The forward remote is isolated and is often overlooked. Many remote
                        controls used on transmissions and auxiliaries require separate lubrication.)
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>No lubricant in, or grease fittings on, u-joints or swivels of remote controls.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Lack of lubricant or wrong lubricant used, causing buildup of sticky varnish and sludge deposits
                    on splines of shaft and gears.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Badly worn or bent shift forks.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Improper adjustment on shifter linkage.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sliding clutch gears tight on splines of shaft.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch teeth burred over, chipped or badly mutilated because of improper shifting.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Binding or interference of shift lever with other objects or rods inside the cab or near the
                    remote control island.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Driver not familiar with proper shifting procedure for the transmission.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch dragging.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch brake engaging too soon when clutch pedal is depressed.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Free running gears seized or galled on either the thrust face or diameters.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13005v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
