<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>9 SPEED AND 10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON 16709 AND 16710 SERIES - AIR SYSTEM - ROADRANGER VALVE A-5010
        (FIGURE 7)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ROADRANGER VALVE A-5010 (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1302107">FIGURE 7</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f1302107" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1302107" filename="../figg13/g1302107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Roadranger Valve Reassembly</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal and Disassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two screws holding the bottom cover to the valve and slide the cover down the
                    gear shift lever to expose the air line fittings. Disconnect air lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the jam nut and turn the control valve from the gear shift lever.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pry the medallion from the recess in the top cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two screws to separate the top cover from the valve housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two screws on the side of the valve housing to separate the housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the Range Preselection Lever from the left housing and the position balls and
                    guide from the lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, remove the spring and O-ring from the bores in the left housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, remove the springs, O-ring and sleeve from the bores in the right
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassembly and Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1302107">Figure 7</hotlnk>
                    for proper reassembly. Use a VERY SMALL amount of silicone lubricant on the O-rings to avoid
                    clogging the ports. A small amount of grease on the position springs and balls will help to hold
                    them in place during reassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install Roadranger valve on the gear shift lever and tighten the jam nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the air lines and install the bottom cover.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021_X1302103.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13021.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
