<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>6 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS INTERNATIONAL MODEL ES52-7A AND ESO65-7A 6-PLUS - TROUBLESHOOTING - DIRT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIRT</title>
        <para>More than 90% of all ball bearing failures are caused by dirt, which is always abrasive.</para>
        <para>Dirt may enter the bearings during assembly of unit or may be carried into the bearing by the lubricant
            while in service. Dirt also may enter bearings through seals, the breather or even dirty containers used for
            addition or change of lubricant.
        </para>
        <para>Softer material, such as dirt or dust, usually forms abrasive paste or lapping compounds within the
            bearings. The pressure between the balls and raceways makes a perfect pulverizer. The rolling motion tends
            to entrap and hold the abrasives. As the balls and raceways wear, the bearings become noisy. The lapping
            action tends to increase rapidly as the fine steel from the balls and rollway adds to the lapping material.
        </para>
        <para>Hard, coarse material, such as metal chips, may enter the bearings during assembly from tools such as
            hammers, drifts, and power chisels. It may also be manufactured within the unit during service from raking
            teeth. These chips produce small indentations in balls and races. When these hard particles jam between the
            balls and races, it may cause the inner race to turn on the shaft, or the outer race to turn in the housing.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13006h.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
