<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RT-6613 SERIES - AIR SYSTEM -
        SELECTOR VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SELECTOR VALVE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1303004">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1303004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1303004" filename="../figg13/G1303004.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Selector Valve</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1303004">
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>Porting - There are four ports in the bottom of the selector valve:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The port stamped "S" is the supply port and is the constant air line from the air valve.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The port stamped "E" is the exhaust port and is left open.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The port stamped "R" is the signal line to the slave air valve.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The port stamped "F" is the signal line to the intermediate shift cylinder.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the selector valve button in "LO" position, disconnect the two lines connected to
                    the port "R" and "F." There should be no air coming out of these ports.
                </para>
                <para>Move the selector valve button to "INT." There should now be a steady flow of air coming from the
                    "F" port, but still no air coming from the "R" port.
                </para>
                <para>Move the selector valve button to the "DIR" position. There should now be a steady flow of air
                    coming from both the "F" and "R" ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Maintenance and Assembly - The selector valve is easily disassembled by removing the
                    cover screws. Individual parts can be obtained in an "A" number kit. Critical assembly factors are:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the jam nut locking the selector valve to the shifting lever is secure.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure that when reassembled, the top plate screws are tightened securely. A
                        loose top plate screw can affect valve operation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When reassembling, lubricate the O-ring and O-ring carrier with a silicone
                        lubricant.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>If the above results are not obtained, disconnect the supply air line at the "S" port and make sure
                that a steady flow of air is coming through the line. If air is present, this would indicate a faulty
                selector valve. Cause can be defective parts, damaged O-ring or loose top plate screw.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Any steady flow of air from the selector valve exhaust port indicates a faulty selector
                    valve or incorrect hook-up. Cause can be damaged O-ring, defective parts, loose top plate screw or
                    reversed air lines on the selector.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
