<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Leakage Inspection</title>
        <para>The transmission has the following parts to prevent external fluid leakage:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Gaskets</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Lip-type seals</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>O-ring seals</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Seal rings</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Seal grommets</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Thread sealant</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sealing washers</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f0701021" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../fign00/n0029363.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. External Sealing</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Torque converter assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Front pump seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Front pump seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Pump gasket</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Front pump sealing bolt</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fluid level indicator</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fluid filler tube assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Filler tube O-ring</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Short fluid inlet tube assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Case</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Bulkhead connector O-ring seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Bulkhead connector and harness</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Turbine shaft speed (TSS) sensor (model-dependent)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">O-ring seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Extension housing gasket</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Extension assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Output shaft speed sensor</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">O-ring seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Extension housing seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission output shaft retainer</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">PTO - case cover (if equipped)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">PTO - cover gasket (if equipped)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Manual control lever seal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Plug - test port - 1/8-27 hex head</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid pan gasket</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Transmission fluid pan</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fluid pan drain plug</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Leakage at the transmission pan-to-case gasket often can be stopped by tightening the retaining bolts to
            specification. Refer to Torque Specifications in this section. If necessary, install a new pan-to-case
            gasket only if gasket is damaged.
        </para>
        <para>If leakage is found by the solenoid body connector, refer to Solenoid Body Assembly in this section.
        </para>
        <para>When fluid is found to be leaking between the case and the cooler tube fitting, tighten the fitting to
            maximum specification. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070260.xml" xrefid="x3070260">Transaxle/Transmission Cooling</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with power take-off (PTO), check the sealing gasket at the PTO unit for
            leaks.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not try to stop the fluid leak by increasing the torque beyond specification. This can cause
                    damage to the case threads and/or case fittings.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>If the leak continues, install new cooler tube fitting and tighten to specification. The same procedure
            should be followed for fluid leaks between the oil-to-air cooler transmission remote filter, and the cooler
            tube fittings.
        </para>
        <para>If leakage is found at the manual control lever shaft, install a new seal.</para>
        <para>Check for fluid leaking from the end of the extension housing. Leakage can result from a damaged seal,
            missing garter spring, worn extension bushing, damaged speed sensor plug or the output shaft retainer
            (vehicles equipped with a fixed yoke). Install a new seal assembly, bushing or both, as necessary.
        </para>
        <para>Inspect the line pressure plug for leakage. Make sure it is tightened to specification. Refer to Torque
            Specifications in this section. If tightening the plug does not stop the leak, the case threads and/or plug
            could be damaged. Remove the plug and inspect the plug and case thread for damage. Repair as necessary.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fluid Leakage in Torque Converter Area</emph>
        </para>
        <para>In diagnosing and correcting fluid leaks in the front pump assembly and torque converter area, use the
            following procedures to locate the exact cause of the leakage. Leakage at the front of the transmission, as
            evidenced by fluid around the torque converter housing, may have several sources. By careful observation it
            is possible, in many instances, to pinpoint the source of the leak before removing the transmission from the
            vehicle. The paths which the fluid takes to reach the bottom of the torque converter housing are shown in
            the illustration. The following 5 steps correspond with the numbers in the illustration.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0701021" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../fign00/n0018693.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fluid leaking by the front pump seal lip will tend to move along the impeller hub and onto
                the back of the impeller housing. Except in the case of a total seal failure, fluid leakage by the lip
                of the seal will be deposited on the inside of the torque converter housing only, near the outside
                diameter of the housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fluid leakage by the outside diameter of the front pump seal and front pump body will follow
                the same path as leaks by the inside diameter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fluid leakage from the converter seal weld or converter to flexplate stud weld will appear
                at the outside diameter of the torque converter, on the back face of the flexplate and in the converter
                housing only near the flexplate. Fluid leaks from the torque converter will leave a ring of fluid around
                the inside of the torque converter housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fluid that leaks by a front pump to case bolt or pump gasket will be deposited on the inside
                of the torque converter housing only. Fluid will not be deposited on the back of the torque converter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>White facial tissue may aid in determining the color (transmission fluid is red) and source of the
                    leaking fluid.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Engine oil leaks are sometimes incorrectly diagnosed as transmission pump gasket leaks. The
                following areas of possible leakage should also be checked to determine if engine oil leakage is causing
                the concern.
            </para>
            <para>&#8226; Leakage at the valve cover gasket may allow oil to flow over the torque converter housing or
                seep down between the torque converter housing and cylinder block, causing oil to be present in or at
                the bottom of the torque converter housing.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Oil galley plug leaks will allow oil to flow down the rear face of the cylinder block to
                    the bottom of the torque converter housing.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Leakage at the crankshaft rear oil seal will work back to the flexplate, and then into
                    the torque converter housing.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Leak Check Test with Black Light</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>An ultraviolet light must be used to detect the fluorescent dye solution.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Add UV Fluorescent Tracer dye for automatic transmission fluid. Use 1 ounce of dye solution for
                    every 4 quarts of ATF capacity. Add any transmission fluid, designated for the
                    transaxle/transmission, to bring the unit to its correct fluid level.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Start and run the engine. Shift the transmission through all the gears several times to make sure
                    the fluorescent dye has had enough time to circulate. Observe the back of the engine cylinder block
                    and the top of the converter housing part of the case for evidence of leakage. Turn off the engine.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Position the vehicle on a hoist. For additional information, refer to
                    <exhotlnk document="../S10/S10019.htm" bookname="S10019">Jacking and Lifting in S10019</exhotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: The leak source will probably be above and/or forward of the actual leak
                        indications due to airflow and/or gravity.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>Using an ultraviolet light, observe the transmission. Follow the leak back to its source point.
                    Repair as required.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <table id="t0701067" tblwidth="pg-wide">
            <title>External Fluid Leaks</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.84*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.16*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Leak Path</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Possible Source</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks at the fluid pan-to-case</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Pan bolts not tightened to specification.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Case pan rail damaged.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Pan gasket damaged.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fluid cooler lines of fittings leaking</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cooler line(s), cooler line fitting(s) damaged.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cooler line fittings-to-case union damaged.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Case damage at case fitting.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Fittings not tightened to specifications.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fluid cooler line nut-to-case fittings leaking</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Damaged or missing O-ring seals.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Fittings not tightened to specifications.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks at the fluid cooler</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Fluid cooler damage.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Fitting(s) damaged or not tightened to specifications.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks at the external sensors</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Damaged or missing O-ring seals.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Screw not tightened to specifications.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks at the manual control lever seal</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Damaged or missing lever seal.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks at the solenoid body harness connector</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Install a new solenoid body harness connector O-ring seal. Either on the
                                        harness end or the solenoid body.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fluid leakage in the torque converter area</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>For possible sources refer to Fluid Leakage In Torque Converter Area Chart.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
