<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>8.6.2. Standard and Forward Position "X" Bar</title>
        <figure id="f13033r4" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 274. Standard and Forward Position "X" Bar</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f13033r5" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 275. Lockwire Installation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r4">Figure 274</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r5">Figure 275</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The standard position "X" bar top cover assembly and the forward position "X" bar top cover
                    assembly use different covers. The forward cover also uses a plate and a gasket installed over the
                    detent balls and springs.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate all the parts of the top cover with the oil that is used in the transmission.
                Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the threads of the fasteners with Loctite Safety Solvent #755 or equivalent. Make sure
                all dirt is removed from the threads.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the specifications of the sealant manufacturer for "cure" time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite #242 or equivalent to the threads of the fasteners.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the low-reverse fork in a vise with brass jaws.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the ball and spring in the bore next to the plunger.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the plunger and spring in the bore of the fork
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r6">(Figure 276).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033r6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 276. Install Plunger and Spring</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the snap ring that holds the assembly in the fork.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the guide pin through the rocking lever
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r7">(Figure 277).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033r7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 277. Install Guide Pin Through Rocking Lever</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install spacer washer on the guide pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Install the O-ring on the guide pin after installing the rocking lever and spacer plate or the
                    O-ring will be damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new O-ring on the guide pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the assembly so that the long part of the spacer plate is toward the center of the
                housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new nut and new washer that fasten the guide pin to the housing. Tighten to 47 to
                61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the low-reverse shift shaft in the bottom bore in the rear of the housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r8">(Figure 278)</hotlnk>. Make sure the two detent grooves are toward the rear of
                the housing. Make sure the detent grooves in the shaft are aligned with the detent ball holes in the
                housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033r8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 278. Put Low-Reverse Shift Shaft in Bottom Bore</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the low-reverse shift fork assembly in the housing so that the lower lever slot is
                toward the center of the assembly. Make sure the bore of the fork is aligned with the bore in the
                housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the fork and sleeve assembly until the holes in the fork and
                shaft are aligned.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>After the set screws with the Loctite sealant are tightened to the specified torque, do not loosen
                    or tighten. If loosened or tightened, the set screws must be removed, cleaned and new sealant
                    applied or the bolts may loosen during operation.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the set screw with the Loctite sealant that fastens the fork in position on the
                shaft. Tighten the set screws to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lock wire in the holes in the set screw and the fork assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the neutral check shaft in the bore on the top of the housing. Make sure the round
                end of the shaft is installed toward the low-reverse shift rail. Make sure the end of the shaft touches
                the slot in the rail
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033r9">(Figure 279)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033r9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033R9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 279. Install Neutral Check Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the large interlock ball in the bottom of the middle bore of the first set of bores on
                the rear of the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s0">Figure 280</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 280. Put Large Interlock Ball in Bottom of Middle Bore</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The 1-2 shift shaft is the same size as the 3-4 shift shaft and has a hole drilled through the
                    shaft.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>Move the low-reverse shift shaft assembly so that the interlock ball is completely installed in
                    the bore. Move the low-reverse shaft assembly so that the 1-2 shaft can be installed.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 1-2 shift shaft in the middle bore of the housing. Make sure the part identification
                on the end of the shaft is toward the front of the housing. Make sure the detent grooves in the shaft
                are aligned with the detent ball holes (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s1">Figure 281</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 1-2 shift sleeve in the housing. Make sure the bore of the sleeve is aligned with
                the bore in the housing. Make sure the threaded hole in the sleeve is toward the rear of the housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s1">(Figure 281)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the 1-2 shift sleeve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s1">Figure 281</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 281. Push Shift Shaft Through 1-2 Shift Sleeve</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 1-2 shift fork in the housing. Make sure bend on the fork is installed toward the
                middle set of bores. Make sure the bore of the fork is aligned with the bore in the housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s1">(Figure 281)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the 1-2 fork until the holes in the fork and the sleeve are
                aligned with the holes in the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s1">Figure 281)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>After the set screws with Loctite sealant are tightened to the specified torque, do not loosen or
                    tighten. If loosened or tightened, the set screws must be removed, cleaned and new sealant applied
                    or the set screws may loosen during operation.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the set screws with the Loctite sealant that fastens the 1-2 fork and the sleeve to
                the rail. Tighten the set screws to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lock wire in the holes in the set screws and the fork and sleeve. Wrap the lock
                wire around the barrel of the shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the interlock pin in the hole drilled in the end of the 1-2 shift shaft
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s2">(Figure 282</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 282. Put Interlock Pin in Hole Drilled in End of 1-2 Shift Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the interlock ball in the bottom of the top bore of the first set of bores at the rear
                of the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s3">Figure 283</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 283. Put Interlock Ball in Bottom of Top Bore</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Makes sure the low-reverse sleeve and the 1-2 sleeve are in the NEUTRAL position. The slots
                in the sleeve must be aligned.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>On R-ratio transmissions, the bill of material refers to the 3-4 shift fork as the O/D (Overdrive)
                    shift fork and the 3-4 "X" bar sleeve as the O/D shift sleeve.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the 3-4 shift sleeve and the shaft assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The 3-4 shift sleeve shaft has a slot on one side.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Move the 1-2 shift shaft assembly so that the interlock ball is completely installed in the bore.
                    Move the 1-2 shaft assembly so that the 3-4 shift sleeve shaft can be installed.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 3-4 shift sleeve shaft in the top bore of the housing. Make sure the interlock slot
                on the end of the shaft is toward the rear of the housing. Make sure the detent grooves in the shaft are
                aligned with the detent ball holes in the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s4">Figure 284)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 3-4 shift sleeve in the housing. Make sure the bore of the sleeve is aligned with
                the bore in the housing. Make sure the slot in the 3-4 shift sleeve is aligned with the slot in the 1-2
                sleeve
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s4">(Figure 284)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 284. Push Shift Shaft Through 3-4 Shift Sleeve</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the 3-4 shift sleeve.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 3-4 "X" bar sleeve in the housing. Make sure the slot in the sleeve is aligned over
                the rocking lever assembly. Make sure the bore of the sleeve is aligned with the bore in the housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s4">(Figure 284</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the 3-4 "X" bar sleeve until the holes in the sleeves are
                aligned with the holes in the shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>After the set screws with Loctite sealant are tightened to the specified torque, do not loosen or
                    tighten. If loosened or tightened, the set screws must be removed, cleaned and new sealant applied
                    or the set screws may loosen during operation.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the set screws with the Loctite sealant that fastens the sleeves to the shaft.
                Tighten the set screws to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lock wire in the holes in the sleeves and set screws.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>On R-ratio transmissions, the bill of material refers to the 3-4 shift fork as the O/D (Overdrive)
                    shift fork and the 3-4 "X" bar sleeve as the O/D shift sleeve.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 3-4 shift fork shaft in the top bore at the front of the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s5">Figure 285</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the 3-4 shift fork in the housing. Make sure slot on the fork is aligned with the
                rocking lever assembly. Makes sure the bore of the fork and sleeve assembly is aligned with the bore of
                the housing
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s5">(Figure 285</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 285. Put 3-4 Shift Fork in Housing</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the shift shaft through the 3-4 fork.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>After the set screws with Loctite sealant are tightened to the specified torque, do not loosen or
                    tighten. If loosened or tightened, the set screws must be removed, cleaned and new sealant applied
                    or the set screws may loosen during operation.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the set screw with the Loctite sealant that fastens the 3-4 fork to the shaft.
                Tighten the set screw to 47 to 61 Nm (35 to 45 ft-lbs.).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lock wire in the holes in the set screws and fork</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, install the large and small oil scoops on the housing. Install and tighten the
                bolts with the Loctite sealant to 14 to 18 Nm (10 to 13 ft-lbs.) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s6">Figure 286)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 286. Install Oil Scoops</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>On standard position top cover assemblies, one or two reverse switches may be used. On forward
                    position top covers, one reverse switch is used.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the larger pin(s) in the bore(s) for the reverse lamp switch. Install the switches
                or plugs and tighten to 47 to 68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs.) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s7">Figure 287).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 287. Install Larger Pin in Bore</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the short pin in the bore for the neutral safety switch. Install the switch or plug
                and tighten to 47 to 68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s8">(Figure 288).</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the breather vent in the top cover. Tighten to 20 to 27 Nm (15 to 20 ft-lbs) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13033s8">Figure 288</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f13033s8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G13033S8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 288. Install Short Pin and Breather Vent</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_51.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
