<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 5 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER ES65-5 - REASSEMBLY -
        COUNTERSHAFT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>COUNTERSHAFT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press all gears onto the countershaft (
                <hotlnk document="s13013_10.xml" xrefid="f1301337">Figure 37</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">2nd Speed Gear:</emph>Assemble and securely seat a key to the countershaft.
                    Support hub of 2nd speed gear on a press (gear is symmetrical), align key in countershaft with
                    keyway in gear and press countershaft to gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">3rd Speed Gear:</emph>Slide spacer onto countershaft. Assemble and securely seat a
                    key to the countershaft. Support hub of 3rd speed gear on a press (long hub DOWN, or toward front of
                    countershaft). Align key in countershaft with keyway in gear and press countershaft to gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">4th Speed Gear:</emph>Assemble and securely seat a key to the countershaft.
                    Support hub of 4th speed gear on a press (long hub DOWN, or toward front of countershaft). Align key
                    in countershaft with keyway in gear and press countershaft to gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Countershaft Drive Gear: Slide spacer onto countershaft. Assemble and securely seat a
                    key to the countershaft. Support hub of drive gear on a press (long hub UP, or toward rear of
                    countershaft). Align key in countershaft with keyway in gear and press countershaft to gear. Firmly
                    seat drive gear snap ring in groove of countershaft. To avoid distortion, do not expand snap ring
                    excessively.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press front and rear bearings onto countershaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1301346">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1301346" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1301346" filename="../figg13/G1301346.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Press Front and Rear Bearings onto Countershaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13013_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13013_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
