<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER - LUBRICATION - LUBRICATION PUMP</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LUBRICATION PUMP</title>
        <para>An optional lubrication pump is available for this transmission. To properly install the unit, follow
            these instructions.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the range rear bearing cap and gasket from the right side of the transmission.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using purple Loctite 515 or the equivalent, install the countershaft pump bearing cap.
                Secure the gasket bearing cap with four bolts, and tighten them to 34 to 41 ft-lbs. (46 to 56 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Next, install the pump gasket and pump. The pump shaft inserts into the countershaft end
                groove. Secure the pump body onto the bearing cap with four bolts. Tighten them to 13 to 17 ft-lbs. (18
                to 23 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install an elbow in the pump lower port hole with the threads down, pointing to eight
                o'clock in the rear view. Install the 90&#176; elbow and nipple in the upper pump port hole, with the
                threads up.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the oil screen filter into the center drain hole on the rear of the transmission
                case. Connect the hose assembly between the oil screen filter and the elbow at the bottom of the pump.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the bushing reducer to the oil cooler at both the outlet and inlet (top and bottom)
                port holes. Use the adapter fitting to do this. Also install the oil cooler in the air flow.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the air control valve and lower tower assembly. Remove the pipe plug from the top
                right side of the transmission main case. Then install the elbow with the threads to the right.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Continue by attaching a hose and fitting to the pump outlet connector (upper port). Connect
                the opposite end of the hose to the cooler inlet adapter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the elbow on top of the main case to the cooler outlet with the correct Weatherhead
                hose and fittings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prime the oil cooler system and pump.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the transmission with the recommended lubricant. Start the vehicle and check for leaks
                and proper oil cooler system operation. After the initial start up, check the oil level. If needed, add
                lubricant until the oil level is even with the transmission filler hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13023x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
