<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER AUTOMATE-2 - TROUBLESHOOTING (ELECTRICAL) - EMERGENCY OVERRIDE TO DISABLE
        AUTOMATED SHIFTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1302212" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EMERGENCY OVERRIDE TO DISABLE AUTOMATED SHIFTS</title>
        <para>Use this procedure only if the transmission is stuck in 9th or 10th gear, and the driver is unable to use
            the lower eight manual gears.
        </para>
        <para>The emergency override procedure involves overriding the 9th, neutral and 10th shift solenoids. This
            override mode completely disables the 9th and 10th gears of the transmission and enables the driver to have
            manual control of the first eight gears and drive the vehicle to the nearest service facility for repairs.
        </para>
        <para>Again, this is to be used only if the transmission is stuck in 9th or 10th gear, and the driver is unable
            to use the lower eight manual gears.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before activating the override mode, turn off the engine and activate the parking brake. Failure
                    to do so would cause the vehicle to move and could result in serious injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the override valve from underneath the vehicle. The valve is located in the 9/10
                actuator housing, which is mounted on the right side of the transmission shift tower.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To activate the valve, remove the pin near the center and on top of the piston housing. This
                will return the transmission to neutral.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Upon completion of corrective maintenance, push the plunger in and replace the pin to
                reactivate the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302207.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_X1302214.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
