<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Output Shaft and Rear Bearing Assemblies</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the output shaft in a vise with the threaded end up and secure on the range mainshaft
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l4">Figure 214</hotlnk>). For models so equipped, install the stepped washer on
                the shaft, large diameter step down.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l4" filename="../figg13/G13018L4.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 213. Mount Output Shaft in Vise</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the splined spacer on the output shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l5">left, Figure 215</hotlnk>). For models equipped with stepped washer on shaft,
                install the spacer with the large diameter splines down (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l5">right, Figure 215</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l5" filename="../figg13/G13018L5.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 214. Install Splined Spacer on Output Shaft and Install Spacer With Large Diameter
                    Splines Down
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT: Mark any two adjacent teeth on deep reduction gear and repeat the procedure
                    for the two adjacent teeth directly opposite the first set marked (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l6">Figure 216</hotlnk>). A highly visible color of toolmaker's dye is
                    recommended.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l6" filename="../figg13/G13018L6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 215. Mark Teeth on Deep Reduction Gear</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, install the snap ring in the deep reduction gear of models so
                equipped (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l7">inset, Figure 217</hotlnk>). Install the gear on the output shaft, clutching
                teeth down and engaged with the splines of the spacer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l7" filename="../figg13/G13018L7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 216. Install Snap Ring in Deep Reduction Gear and Install Gear on Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the washer on the shaft against the deep reduction gear, small diameter step down (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l8">left, Figure 218</hotlnk>: 11608LL Models); or side with the large groove up (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l8">right, Figure 218:</hotlnk>
                14608LL Models).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l8" filename="../figg13/G13018L8.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 217. Install Washer on Shaft, Small Diameter Step Down or Side With Large Groove Up
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For models not equipped with the oil retention ring in the auxiliary housing, proceed to Step
                        8.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">14608LL Models only</emph>
                - Place the oil retention ring in the housing bore, cupped side up (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l9">left, Figure 219</hotlnk>). Use a soft bar and two rear bearing outer spacers
                stacked on top of each other to move the oil retention ring 2 inches deep into the bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018l9">right, Figure 219</hotlnk>). The ring will be at the proper depth when the top
                of the second spacer is flush with the housing bore. Remove the spacers when installation is completed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018l9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018l9" filename="../figg13/G13018L9.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 218. Place Oil Retention Ring in Housing Bore, and Move Oil Retention Ring into Bore
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place two mainshaft spacers or flat steel stock of equivalent thickness (.190 inch) on rear
                face of the deep reduction gear 180 degrees from each other (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m0">left, Figure 220</hotlnk>). Install the auxiliary housing over the end of the
                output shaft assembly, allowing the housing to rest on the spacers (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m0">right, Figure 220</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m0" filename="../figg13/G13018M0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 219. Place Mainshaft Spacers on Rear Face of Deep Reduction Gear, and Install Auxiliary
                    Housing Over End of Output Shaft Assembly
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Heat the front bearing cone and install on output shaft against oil retention ring, bearing
                taper up (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m1">left, Figure 221</hotlnk>). For models not equipped with the oil retention
                ring in the auxiliary housing, install the heated bearing cone on the shaft against the washer, taper up
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m1">right, Figure 221</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m1" filename="../figg13/G13018M1.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 220. Install Front Bearing Cone on Output Shaft Against Oil Retention Ring or Against
                    Washer
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not heat bearing above 275 degrees F (136 degrees C). If possible, use heat lamps as
                        source.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing inner spacer on the output shaft against the front bearing cone (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m2">Figure 222</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m2" filename="../figg13/G13018M2.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 221. Install Bearing Inner Spacer on Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the front bearing cup in housing bore, taper to the inside, and use a soft bar to
                start cup into the bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m3">Figure 223</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m3" filename="../figg13/G13018M3.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 222. Place Front Bearing Cup in Housing Bore and Start Cup in Bore</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stack the bearing outer spacer and rear bearing cup on the top of the front bearing cup in
                proper sequence (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m4">Figure 224</hotlnk>). Use a soft bar or a flanged driver to move all three
                parts evenly into the housing bore until the lip of the rear bearing cup seats on the housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m4" filename="../figg13/G13018M4.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 223. Stack Bearing Outer Spacer and Rear Bearing Cup on Top of Front Bearing Cup, and
                    Move All Three Parts Evenly into Housing Bore
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If not previously done, install the auxiliary housing over the end of the output shaft
                assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m5">Figure 225</hotlnk>). Heat the rear bearing cone and install on shaft, taper
                down and inside bearing cup.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m5" filename="../figg13/G13018M5.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 224. Install Auxiliary Housing Over End of Output Shaft Assembly, and Install Rear
                    Bearing Cone
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not heat bearing above 275 degrees F (136 degrees C).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For 14608LL Model, install the speedometer drive gear or replacement spacer on the output
                shaft and retain with snap ring installed in the groove of the shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m6">left, Figure 226</hotlnk>). Remove the blocking (two shaft spacers or flat
                steel stock) from between the deep reduction gear and auxiliary housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m6">right, Figure 226</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m6" filename="../figg13/G13018M6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 225. Install Speedometer Drive Gear or Replacement Spacer, and Remove Blocking From
                    Between Deep Reduction Gear and Auxiliary Housing
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount assembly upright in a vise and secure (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m7">Figure 227</hotlnk>). Install the deep reduction sliding clutch on the output
                shaft, internal splines toward the gear and engaged with the splines of the shaft.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m7" filename="../figg13/G13018M7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 226. Install Deep Reduction Sliding Clutch on Output Shaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the snap ring in the groove of the range mainshaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m8">Figure 228</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m8" filename="../figg13/G13018M8.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 227. Install Snap Ring in Groove of Range Mainshaft</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previously removed, install the oil seal in the rear bearing cover (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018m9">inset, Figure 229</hotlnk>). Seal should be installed so the spring is to the
                front of the cover.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018m9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018m9" filename="../figg13/G13018M9.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 228. Install Oil Seal in Rear Bearing Cover</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position gasket on the cover mounting surface and install the rear bearing cover on the
                auxiliary housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018n0">Figure 230</hotlnk>). Use the nylon collar and brass washer with the bolt at
                the chamfered hole which intersects speedometer bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018n0">inset, Figure 230</hotlnk>). Tighten bolts to secure cover to housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018n0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018n0" filename="../figg13/G13018N0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 229. Install Rear Bearing Cover on Auxiliary Housing, and Use Nylon Collar and Brass
                    Washer
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Because the collar becomes distorted when compressed, DO NOT REUSE OLD NYLON COLLAR.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_61.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_63.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
