<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Transmission - Transaxle / Transmission Cooling - Diagnosis and Testing</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Diagnosis and Testing</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Cooling Inspection and Verification</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When internal wear or damage occurs in the transmission, component material can travel into
                        the fluid cooler tubes and the in-tank transmission fluid cooler. Remove these contaminants from
                        the cooling system before placing the transmission back into use. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic Transaxle/ Transmission -
                            5R110.
                        </hotlnk>
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When internal wear or damage occurs in the transmission, metal particles, clutch plate
                        material and band material can travel into the torque converter, the fluid cooler tubes and the
                        in-tank transmission fluid cooler. These contaminants are a major cause of recurring
                        transmission concerns. To prevent future concerns, remove these contaminants from the cooling
                        system before placing the transmission back into use.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>1. Clean the contaminants from the transmission fluid cooling system. Carry out the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission fluid cooler-backflushing and cleaning.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque converter flushing.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque converter cleaning and inspection.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Also carry out the transmission fluid cooler flow test. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110.
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>2. Visually inspect for obvious signs of mechanical damage, incorrect component installation and
                system leaks. Repair as necessary.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Install a new or remanufactured radiator when fluid is found leaking from the in-tank
                        transmission fluid cooler. Refer to the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the fault is not visually evident, GO to Symptom Chart.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symptom Chart</title>
            <table id="t0702003" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Symptom Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.66*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.08*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.12*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Possible Sources</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Action</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Transmission overheating</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Excessive vehicle or towing loads, severe vehicle use.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Incorrect fluid level.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Fluid condition.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Incorrect fluid type.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Transmission cooling system damaged, blocked, restricted or installed
                                            incorrectly.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>System leaks.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Engine overheating.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Engine control system electrical inputs/outputs, vehicle wiring harnesses,
                                            engine control module (ECM), torque converter clutch (TCC) solenoid.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Internal transmission concerns.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to the vehicle specification manual for load and GVW/GCW
                                            information. REFER to the Owner's Guide.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK and, if necessary, ADJUST the fluid to the correct level. REFER to
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110.
                                            </hotlnk>
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Check fluid condition. REFER to
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110.
                                            </hotlnk>
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to Specifications in this section.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CARRY OUT the transmission fluid cooler flow test. REFER to
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110.
                                            </hotlnk>
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110
                                            </hotlnk>
                                            for leakage inspection procedures.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to the Engine Operation and Maintenance manual.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CARRY OUT on-board diagnostics. REFER to the engine manual EGES-305 and
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110
                                            </hotlnk>
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to
                                            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070159.xml" xrefid="x3070159">Automatic
                                                Transaxle/ Transmission - 5R110
                                            </hotlnk>
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fluid leak at transmission in-tank cooler</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Transmission fluid cooler to fluid cooler fitting.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>REFER to component test in this section.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Test</title>
            <para>
                <title>Transmission Fluid Cooler Leaks at Radiator</title>
            </para>
            <para>Transmission fluid may leak between the radiator transmission fluid cooler and the transmission fluid
                cooler fitting (not the cooler tube into the fitting), which may result in a residue of transmission
                fluid on the radiator tank around the fluid cooler fitting. Insufficient thread sealer on the
                transmission fluid cooler fitting may cause this.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area around the transmission fluid cooler fittings.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0702001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024560.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that transmission fluid is leaking between the transmission fluid cooler and the
                    transmission fluid cooler fitting (not the transmission fluid cooler tube fitting into the
                    transmission fluid cooler fitting).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the radiator from the vehicle and place it on a flat surface with the
                    transmission fluid cooler fittings facing upward. For additional information, refer to the Engine
                    Operation and Maintenance manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Oil-based solvents and cleaners should not be used when cleaning the radiator. Oil-based
                        solvents and cleaners can damage the radiator end tank seals and cause leaks.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area around the transmission fluid cooler fittings so that contaminants do not
                    enter the transmission fluid cooler when the transmission fluid cooler fittings are removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0702002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024560.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Remove only one transmission fluid cooler fitting at a time, otherwise the cooler may drop
                        into the radiator.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the upper transmission fluid cooler fitting.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the fitting is removed from the transmission fluid cooler, verify that there is a
                    gasket between the transmission fluid cooler and the inside of the radiator tank.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If there is no gasket, install a new radiator.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If there is a gasket, proceed to the next step.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the transmission fluid cooler fitting threads for damage.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the threads are damaged, install a new radiator.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the threads show no sign of damage, proceed to the next step.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0702003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0082149.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Thread sealant or tape should never be used on the threads of the transmission fluid cooler
                        fittings. The use of such materials will create a leak path.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring on the transmission fluid cooler fitting.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0702004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024560.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not use air tools to tighten the transmission fluid cooler fitting. Use a hand-operated
                        torque wrench only.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Making sure that the gasket between the transmission fluid cooler and the inside of the
                    radiator tank is still in place, install the transmission fluid cooler fitting.
                </para>
                <para>&#8226; Tighten to 60 Nm (44 lb-ft).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the procedure to install a new O-ring on the other transmission fluid cooler
                    fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure that no radiator coolant has entered the transmission fluid cooler. Install
                    the radiator in the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that both the transmission and the engine cooling system are at the correct fluid
                    levels.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_83.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_85.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
