<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON RTLO-14613 - PRECAUTIONS - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Make sure that interiors of case and housings are clean. It is important that dirt and other foreign
            materials be kept out of the transmission during reassembly. Dirt is an abrasive and can damage polished
            surfaces of bearings and washers. Use certain precautions, as listed below, during reassembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">GASKETS-Use new gaskets throughout the transmission as it is being rebuilt. Make sure all
                gaskets are installed. An omission of any gasket can result in oil leakage or misalignment of bearing
                covers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BOLTS-To prevent oil leakage, use Loctite 242 thread sealant on all bolts. For torque
                ratings, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s13027_76.xml" xrefid="t1302701">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">O-RlNGS-Lubricate all O-rings with silicone lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">ASSEMBLY-Refer to the illustrations provided in the detailed disassembly instructions as a
                guide to reassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">INITIAL LUBRICATION-Coat all limit washers and splines of shafts with Lubriplate during
                reassembly to prevent scoring and galling of such parts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">AXIAL CLEARANCES-Maintain original axial clearances of .005" to .012" for mainshaft gears.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">BEARINGS-Use of flanged-end bearing drivers is recommended for the installation of bearings.
                These special drivers apply equal force to both bearing races, preventing damage to balls/rollers and
                races while maintaining correct bearing alignment with bore and shaft. Avoid using a tubular or
                sleeve-type driver, whenever possible, as force is applied to only one of the bearing races.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">UNIVERSAL JOINT COMPANION FLANGE OR YOKE-Pull the companion flange or yoke tightly into
                place with the output shaft nut, using 450 to 500 ft-lbs. (610 to 678 N&#183;m) of torque. Make sure
                speedometer drive gear or a replacement spacer of the same width has been installed. Failure to pull the
                companion flange or yoke tightly into place will permit the output shaft to move axially with resultant
                damage to the rear bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Refer to the appropriate illustrated parts list (specified by model series) to ensure that proper
                    parts are used during reassembly of the transmission.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13027.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
