<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Meritor Transfer Cases MTC-4208, -4210, and -4213 -
        Assembly - MTC-4208 and -4210 Rear Output Shaft End Play Adjustment
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>MTC-4208 and -4210 Rear Output Shaft End Play Adjustment</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Determine rear output shaft bearing end play before final assembly. Seals should not be installed
                    until end plays are set.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the rear output shaft yoke. Tighten the yoke nut to 200 lb-ft (271 Nm).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the output shaft several times to seat the bearings.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a dial indicator to check output shaft bearing end play. Center the dial indicator over
                the shaft using a ball bearing for accuracy (Figure 50).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1303550" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg13/G1303550.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 50. Center Dial Indicator Over Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a pry bar to lift the yoke to obtain a measurement. To obtain a consistent and averaged
                reading, perform this operation two or three times. Record the reading for this shaft.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is greater than 0.001- to 0.005-inch (0.025-0.127
                            mm):
                        </emph>
                        Add shims to reduce end play.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If the end play reading is less than specification:</emph>
                        Remove shims to increase end play. Bearing shims come in 0.003-, 0.005- and 0.010-inch (0.08,
                        0.13 and 0.25 mm) thicknesses.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If rear output shaft bearing end play requires adjustment, remove the rear output shaft yoke
                so that the case and cover can be easily separated.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure end play on the remaining shafts before splitting the case to make adjustments.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After performing rear output shaft bearing end play measurement, separate the transfer case
                halves as necessary to adjust shims and achieve correct end play on the shaft requiring adjustment.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust shims to achieve the correct bearing end play on all shafts as required. Refer to
                Shim Assembly in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13035.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
