<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>8 SPEED, 9 SPEED, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS EATON SERIES - INSTALL - RIGHT COUNTERSHAFT ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>RIGHT COUNTERSHAFT ASSEMBLY</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The left countershaft assembly MUST remain in time with main drive gear when timing right
                    countershaft assembly.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove blocking from right countershaft assembly and place it parallel to the mainshaft
                assembly. Mesh the marked tooth of the right countershaft drive gear with the remaining set of two
                marked teeth on the main drive gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018bk">Figure 396</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018bk" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018bk" filename="../figg13/G13018BK.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 395. Mesh Marked Tooth of Right Countershaft Drive Gear With Marked Teeth on Main Drive
                    Gear
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the countershaft support tool or blocking in the rear bearing bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018bl">Figure 397</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018bl" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018bl" filename="../figg13/G13018BL.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 396. Insert Countershaft Support Tool or Blocking in Rear Bearing Bore</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the right countershaft bearings in the same manner described for left countershaft
                bearings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With bearing installation complete, install the snap ring in the right countershaft rear
                groove (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018bm">Figure 398</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018bm" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018bm" filename="../figg13/G13018BM.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 397. Install Snap Ring in Right Countershaft Rear Groove</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the reverse gear to the rear on the mainshaft and use a screwdriver to engage sliding
                clutches with all forward speed gears (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f13018bn">Figure 399</hotlnk>). A sliding clutch that will not engage with a gear
                indicates the gear set is not in proper mesh. The bearings of the right countershaft would then need to
                be removed and the drive gear set retimed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f13018bn" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g13018bn" filename="../figg13/G13018BN.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 398. Engage Sliding Clutches With All Forward Speed Gears</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not engage sliding clutches with more than one gear at the same time. This will lock the
                        gearing and prevent the mainshaft and countershaft assemblies from rotating.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_88.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018_90.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
