<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS FULLER RT-610 SERIES - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Eaton Fuller Transmissions are designed so that the internal parts operate in a bath of oil circulated
                by the motion of gears and shafts.
            </para>
            <para>Thus, all parts will be amply lubricated if these procedures are closely followed:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Maintain oil level. Inspect regularly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Change oil regularly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the correct grade and type of oil. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Buy from a reputable dealer.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>The use of mild EP gear oil or multi- purpose gear oil is not recommended, but if these gear oils are
                used, be sure to adhere to the following limitations:
            </para>
            <para>Do not use mild EP gear oil or multi-pur- pose gear oil when operating temperatures are above 230&#176;F
                (110&#176;C). Many of these gear oils, particularly 85W140, break down above 230&#176;F and coat seals,
                bearings and gears with deposits that may cause premature failures. If these deposits are observed
                (especially a coating on seal areas causing oil leakage), change to Eaton Roadranger CD50 transmission
                fluid, heavy duty engine oil or mineral gear oil to assure maximum component life and to maintain your
                warranty with Eaton.
            </para>
            <para>In addition, transmission oil coolers are not recommended with these gear oils since the oil cooler
                materials may be attacked by these gear oils. The lower temperature limit and oil cooler restriction
                with these gear oils generally limit their success to milder applications.
            </para>
            <para>Additives and friction modifiers are not recommended for use in Eaton Fuller transmissions.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_62.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024_64.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
