<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>10 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS SPICER AUTOMATE-2 - TROUBLESHOOTING (MECHANICAL)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING (MECHANICAL)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>NOISY OPERATION</title>
            <para>Noise is usually very elusive and generally not the fault of the transmission; therefore, mechanics
                should road test to determine if the driver's complaint of noise is actually in the transmission.
            </para>
            <para>In numerous instances, drivers have insisted that the noise was in the transmission, however,
                investigations revealed the noise to be caused by one of the following conditions:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fan out of balance or blades were bent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Defective vibration dampers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Crankshafts out of balance.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flywheels out of balance.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flywheel mounting bolts loose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine rough at idle, producing rattle in gear train.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clutch assembly out of balance.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine mounts loose or broken.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Power-take-off engaged.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Universal joints worn out.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Propeller shafts out of balance.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Universal joint angles out of place or at excessive angle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Center bearings in drive line dry, not mounted properly, etc.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wheels out of balance.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tire treads humming or vibrating at certain speeds.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Air leaks on suction side of induction system, especially with turbo-chargers.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Mechanics should try to locate and eliminate noise by means other than transmission removal, or
                overhaul. However, if the noise appears to be in the transmission, try to break it down into the
                following classifications. If possible, determine what position the gear shift lever is in when the
                noise occurs. If the noise is evident in only one gear position, the cause of the noise is generally
                traceable to the gears in operation.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Growl and humming</emph>
                    or, more serious, a grinding noise. These noises are caused by worn, chipped, rough or cracked
                    gears. As gears continue to wear, the grinding noise will be noticeable, particularly in the gear
                    position that throws the greatest load on the worn gear.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Hissing</emph>
                    or, more serious, a thumping or bumping-type noise. Hissing noises can be caused by bad bearings. As
                    bearings wear and retainers start to break up, etc., the noise could change to a thumping or
                    bumping.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Metallic rattles</emph>
                    within the transmission usually result from a variety of conditions. Engine torsional vibrations are
                    transmitted to the transmission through the clutch. In heavy duty equipment, clutch discs with
                    vibration dampers are not used, so a rattle, particularly in neutral, is common with diesel
                    equipment. In general, engine speeds should be 600 RPM or above to eliminate objectionable rattles
                    and vibration during the idle. A defective or faulty injector would cause a rough or lower idle
                    speed and a rattle in the transmission. Rattle could also be caused by excessive backlash in PTO
                    unit mounting.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13022x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
