<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Transmission Fluid Cooler</title>
        <table id="t0701068">
            <title>Special Tool</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.94*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <graphic filename="../figEZT/EZTECH.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                     scalefitheight="152px"/>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>EZ-Tech III</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Cleaning and backflushing the transmission fluid cooling system along with following all the
                    normal cleaning and inspection procedures during disassembly and reassembly will keep contamination
                    from entering the transmission, causing a repeat repair.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>When internal wear or damage has occurred in the transmission, metal particles or clutch plate material
            may have been carried into the torque converter and transmission fluid cooler. These contaminants are a
            major cause of recurring transmission troubles and must be removed from the system before the transmission
            is put back into use.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Transmission Fluid Cooler Flow Test</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The transmission linkage/cable adjustment, fluid level and line pressure must be within
                    specification before carrying out this test. Refer to Fluid Level Check under Verification of
                    Condition in this section. Refer to Line Pressure Test under Special Testing Procedures in this
                    section. For shift linkage/cable adjustment procedures, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070561.xml" xrefid="x3070561">Automatic Transaxle/Transmission External
                        Controls</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install EZ-Tech and monitor the transmission fluid temperature (TFT) sensor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the fluid level indicator from the fluid filler tube.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a funnel in the fluid filler tube.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the vehicle in NEUTRAL, position it on a hoist. For additional information, refer to
                Jacking and Lifting in S10019.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the cooler return tube (rear fitting) from the transmission case.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect one end of a hose to the cooler return tube and route the other end of the hose up
                to a point where it can be inserted into the funnel at the fluid filler tube.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the end of a hose into the funnel.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and run at idle with the transmission in the NEUTRAL range.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Once a steady flow of fluid (without air bubbles) is observed, remove the hose from the
                funnel and place the hose in a measuring container for 15 seconds. After 15 seconds, place the hose back
                into the funnel and turn the engine off. Measure the amount of fluid in the container.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <table id="t0701069">
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.94*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Temperature</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Flow</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>44&#176;C (112&#176;F)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>236.6 ml (8 oz) 15 sec</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>78&#176;C (172&#176;F)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>473.2 ml (16 oz) 15 sec</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>82&#176;C (180&#176;F) and up</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1893 ml (64 oz) 15 sec</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>There is a temperature valve in the pump. Cooler flow rates will vary according to automatic transmission
            fluid temperature. The use of a diagnostic tool will determine the actual fluid temperature. If adequate
            flow is observed into the container, the test is now complete.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If adequate flow is not observed, turn off the engine. Disconnect the hose from the cooler
                return line (transmission inlet).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the fluid cooler tube from the front case fitting and connect the hose to the
                case fitting (converter out) and repeat Steps 7, 8 and 9.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If adequate flow is not observed from the transmission, look for a plugged or crushed cooler
                tube, plugged remote filter manifold orifice, and/or fluid cooler. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070260.xml" xrefid="x3070260">Transaxle/Transmission Cooling</hotlnk>
                for diagnosis of the transmission fluid cooler.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If adequate flow is still not observed, repair or installation of a new pump and/or torque
                converter may be required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>For the installation of new transmission fluid cooler tubes, refer to
            <hotlnk document="s13036_X3070260.xml" xrefid="x3070260">Transaxle/Transmission Cooling</hotlnk>.
        </para>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
