<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL 9, 10, AND 13 SPEED TRANSMISSIONS - LUBRICATION
        AND MAINTENANCE - DRAINING AND REPLACING THE TRANSMISSION OIL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DRAINING AND REPLACING THE TRANSMISSION OIL</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Drain the oil when the transmission is hot.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the vehicle is parked on a level surface. Put a large container under the
                transmission. Put a screen on top of the container.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The magnetic drain plug can be re-used if, after cleaning, the plug has a minimum pick-up capacity
                    of 0.7 kilograms (1.5 pounds) of low carbon steel.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the drain plugs from the bottom of the transmission. Drain and discard the oil.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the O-rings on the drain plugs. Replace worn or damaged O-rings.</para>
            <para>Inspect the screen on top of the container for metal particles and damaged particles. Service the
                transmission as necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the transmission is disassembled or replaced and an oil cooler is used, remove the
                cooler. Remove and discard the oil from the cooler and the oil lines. Install the oil cooler and the
                lines. Tighten the fittings to the specified torque.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install and tighten the drain plug to 47 to 68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs.).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the area by the fill plug. Remove the fill plug from the side of the transmission.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only the specified type of single weight oils. Do not use multi-viscosity oils or EP (Extreme
                    Pressure) gear oils. Multi-viscosity oils and EP gear oils may damage components. The use of
                    multi-viscosity or EP gear oils voids the warranty.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add the specified transmission oil through the hole for the fill plug.</para>
            <para>Add the oil until the oil level is even with the bottom of the hole of the fill plug (
                <hotlnk document="s13033_77.xml" xrefid="f1393320">Figure 379</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install and tighten the fill plug to 47 to 68 Nm (35 to 50 ft-lbs.).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate the vehicle for five minutes. Check for correct operation.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_77.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033_79.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s13033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
