<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - VERIFICATION
        OF TIMING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VERIFICATION OF TIMING</title>
        <para>Verify Injection Pump to Engine Timing as Follows, if Gear Train was Disassembled:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the #1 piston is on the compression stroke by:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Removing the valve cover/intake manifold assembly.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check to see if the #1 cylinder intake and exhaust valve levers are loose by turning the
                    push rods by hand.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If loose, the #1 piston is on the compression stroke and the injection pump may be
                    removed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the #1 cylinder valve levers are
                    <emph type="bold">NOT</emph>
                    loose, set the pump to engine static timing as described in steps 2-4.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the engine one complete revolution. The engine should now be on the #1 compression
                stroke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Observe the engine front cover timing indicator and damper pulley degree alignment. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e105_231.xml" xrefid="ef1051106">11.6</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>The engine should now be positioned at specified static pump to engine timing. Refer to Specifications.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If timing is not within specifications, rotate engine to correct crankshaft position (specified
                    degrees before top dead center) before removing injection pump. If necessary to rotate engine in
                    opposite direction of normal rotation to achieve specified timing, rotate engine to 90&#176; before
                    top dead center and then rotate engine to specified timing. This procedure takes up gear backlash.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_229.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_231.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
