<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - INTRODUCTION - GENERAL FEATURES</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL FEATURES</title>
        <para>The DT 408, DT 466 and International&#174; 530 Diesel Engine Series are inline six cylinder, 4 cycle
            water-cooled, overhead valve, turbocharged and air-to-air intercooled, direct injection diesel engines (
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e105_8.xml" xrefid="f105IN06">6</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ).
        </para>
        <para>Proven premium features have been designed into this series of engines such as a GEROTOR type lube oil
            pump with cast water and oil passages in the crankcase and front cover. Replaceable wet type cylinder
            sleeves, one piece cylinder head, cast aluminum alloy pistons, forged tee pee connecting rods and a forged
            steel crankshaft with induction hardened journals and undercut fillets are used. A single spin-on type lube
            oil filter and one fuel filter and fuel strainer are engine mounted. All models of the engine come equipped
            with an oil cooler. The GEROTOR lube oil pump is mounted to the front cover and driven directly by the
            crankshaft at engine speed. With the exception of the air compressor, fuel injection pump and turbocharger
            oil supply, there is no external lube oil piping used.
        </para>
        <para>The crankshaft is supported on seven precision insert bearings and camshaft on four pre-reamed bushings.
            The rod and main bearing caps are mated parts and are stamped for identification and are not
            interchangeable.
        </para>
        <para>Each engine main bearing web has angled, drilled holes which are fitted with jet tubes that direct lube
            oil, under pressure, to the underside of each piston.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
