<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - NOZZLES - NOZZLES - CARE AND RECONDITIONING LAPPING
        BLOCKS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CARE AND RECONDITIONING LAPPING BLOCKS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>KEEP THE LAPPING BLOCKS COVERED WHEN NOT BEING USED, TO KEEP DUST OR OTHER FOREIGN MATTER FROM
                        THE SURFACE.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It will be necessary to perform a certain amount of maintenance on the lapping blocks to keep
                        them in top condition. The wear will be gradual but, by continued use, worn or low spots in the
                        block must be removed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>A short time spent each day in hand-lapping the blocks will be an effective way of maintaining the
                finish necessary for quality lapping.
            </para>
            <para>The lapping blocks must be thoroughly cleaned before any reconditioning is started. Use a stiff
                bristle brush (not a wire brush) and scrub the blocks in a good solvent and blow dry with filtered
                compressed air.
            </para>
            <para>All lapping blocks in a set are involved in the reconditioning procedure outlined below:</para>
            <para>Step 1: Spread a small amount of 1000 grit lapping compound (prepared in a paste) on block number 1,
                assuming the blocks to be numbered 1, 2 and 3.
            </para>
            <para>Step 2: Lap number 1 and 2 (face to face) together, using a figure eight pattern
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e105_244.xml" xrefid="ef1051213">12.13</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                . Then take 1 and 3; and finally 2 and 3.
            </para>
            <para>After working 1 and 3 together, wipe off number 2 on a clean sheet of paper placed on a flat surface.
                Low spots, if any, will appear as dark spots and high spots as bright spots. Continue the lapping
                procedure until the overall appearance is a uniform gray surface.
            </para>
            <para>Step 3: After the blocks have been refinished, clean them thoroughly in a good solvent using a bristle
                brush, then blow dry with filtered compressed air.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the valve stop spacer pins for deformity or breakage. Replace as
                    required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the nozzle cap nut for cracks, damaged threads or damaged copper gasket
                    seating face. Replace as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the stem and the body of the valve. When both parts are wet with fuel oil, no
                    sticking should be evident. Pull the valve out of the body about one-third of its length. When
                    released, the valve should slide freely back to the seat. Foreign matter or scratches on the valve
                    will cause it to stick. Carefully inspect before installing the valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">OPENING PRESSURE ADJUSTMENT</emph>: The nozzle opening pressure is increased or
                    decreased by the selection of the appropriate sized spacer.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_244.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_246.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
