<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - TURBOCHARGERS - GENERAL OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>GENERAL OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TURBOCHARGER</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">FIGURE
                    <hotlnk document="e105_31.xml" xrefid="ef1050205">2.5</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the part location of the turbocharger.
            </para>
            <para>The turbocharger assembly is an exhaust-driven centrifugal air compressor. Its purpose is to increase
                power output by supplying compressed air to the engine. The center housing is oil and air cooled. Engine
                oil is circulated through the center housing which acts as a heat barrier between the "hot" turbine and
                the "cold" compressor. Bearings are sleeve-type and are lubricated by engine oil. Oil is pumped directly
                from the clean-oil side of the oil filter, thru the turbocharger oil feed supply tube, then circulated
                in the center housing of the turbocharger and returned to the engine through an oil drain tube.
            </para>
            <para>High velocity engine exhaust gases drive the turbine shaft assembly to speeds over 100,000 revolutions
                per minute. Filtered air entering the compressor side of the turbocharger is compressed and delivered to
                the engine valve cover/intake manifold at a pressure higher than atmospheric pressure. Because more air
                is delivered to the intake manifold, the result is more power, fuel efficiency and the ability to
                maintain power at altitude.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
