<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - INTRODUCTION - COOLANT FLOW SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>COOLANT FLOW SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Coolant flows from the bottom of the radiator into the inlet tube of the front cover and onto the
                water pump. The coolant is pushed by the impeller of the water pump, through an internal passage in the
                front cover and out to the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>An internal passageway located in the crankcase directs coolant from front to rear, evenly
                distributing coolant to the lower sections of the cylinder sleeves. The coolant flow is directed toward
                each cylinder sleeve on a tangent causing a swirling motion upward towards the cylinder head. This
                swirling action improves heat dissipation.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant leaves the area around the cylinder sleeves in the following two ways:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The coolant is directed to the oil cooler via an exterior tube leading to the rear oil cooler
                        header. Coolant flows through passages in the oil cooler and exits at the water pump to be
                        re-mixed with incoming coolant from the radiator.
                    </para>
                    <para>Coolant is supplied to rear of air compressor from left side of crankcase. After coolant
                        exists at front of air compressor, it is returned via passage.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant exits from the crankcase through two cored holes at the top of each cylinder sleeve
                        bore.
                    </para>
                    <para>Coolant then flows through the cylinder head to the thermostat. The thermostat housing
                        incorporates two outlets to direct coolant either to the radiator when the engine is at
                        operating temperature, or directly back to the water pump when the engine has not yet reached
                        operating temperature.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
            <title>THERMOSTAT OPERATION</title>
            <para>When the engine coolant temperature is below specified thermostat opening temperature, the coolant
                flows through the bypass passage to the water pump because the radiator outlet port is blocked. As the
                engine reaches operating temperature, the thermostat opens, directing coolant towards the radiator; this
                also restricts the bypass opening (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f105IN09">9</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f105IN09" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g105IN09" filename="../figg10/G105IN09.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
