<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - INTRODUCTION - LUBRICATION SYSTEM - OIL FLOW</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OIL FLOW</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Unfiltered oil is drawn from the oil pan, through the oil pick-up tube and to the front cover assembly
                to the oil pump. Leaving the oil pump, the unfiltered oil travels (under pressure) back through the
                front cover assembly, passing the high pressure oil relief valve and into the crankcase unfiltered oil
                galley. Any excess oil is dumped by the relief valve back into the oil pan (
                <emph type="bold">Figures
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f105IN10">10</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f105IN11">11</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The high pressure oil relief controls unfiltered oil pressure at 80 psi (552 kPa) maximum.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>There are two oil galleries in the crankcase. The unfiltered oil travels down the unfiltered oil
                galley on the lower right hand side of the crankcase and the filtered oil galley runs above it.
                Unfiltered oil travels from the oil pump, through the front cover assembly and into the unfiltered oil
                galley. The oil pressure relief valve controls unfiltered oil pressure at 80 psi (552 kPa). When oil
                pressure exceeds 80 psi (552 kPa), the oil pressure relief valve opens and excess oil is dumped back to
                the oil sump. There are two exit ports in the unfiltered oil galley. One exits to the front header of
                the oil cooler and one exits to the rear header of the oil cooler. Depending upon the position of the
                oil thermostat, located in the rear header, unfiltered oil can by-pass the oil cooler core and go
                directly to the oil filter or can flow through the oil cooler core into the rear header.
            </para>
            <para>The oil cooler thermostat opens or closes by sensing oil temperature in the unfiltered galley. Oil is
                directed from the unfiltered galley to the filter, were it enters from the outside of the element and
                exits from the center. Oil by-pass valve is located within the filter can and operates at a pressure
                differential of psi. Oil filter element by-pass is effected from within the filter can. Clean engine oil
                flows out of the filter and goes back into the oil cooler header, then out the header and into the
                crankcase clean oil galley. The clean oil enters the crankcase, passes the oil cooler regulator valve
                and is directed through various ports of the crankcase. Excess oil is dumped back into the crankcase by
                the regulator valve.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The oil cooler pressure regulator valve controls filtered oil pressure at 50 psi (345 kpa).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Flow</title>
            <figure id="f105IN10" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g105IN10" filename="../figg10/g105IN10.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The turbocharger receives filtered oil through an external tube connected at the rear oil cooler
                header. The fuel injection pump and air compressor (if equipped) also receive oil through external lines
                which are connected at a common fitting on the right side of the crankcase main filtered oil gallery.
                This fitting is supplied with oil directly from the main gallery. The front gear train is splash
                lubricated by oil draining from the injection pump and air compressor (if equipped).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Cooler Header Oil Flow Schematic.</title>
            <figure id="f105IN11" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg2486" filename="../figeg2/eg2486.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Thermostat Cap</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Hot/Cold Oil Mixing Chamber</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Internal Passage To Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. Internal Passage Oil Filter To Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. Oil Filter Stud</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. Clean Oil Flow From Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. Pressure Regulator Valve Location</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. From Oil Cooler By-Pass Galley</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. Oil Cooler Header</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. Unfiltered Oil From Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. Oil Cooler Thermostat</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
