<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - NOZZLES - NOZZLES - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e105_E10512.xml" xrefid="ef1051201">12.1</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                touch lapped surfaces. To avoid interchanging of nozzle parts, reassemble one nozzle at a time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dip all parts in clean calibrating fluid.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clamp the nozzle holder body upright in a vise, using the flats on the holder body to clamp
                onto.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select an appropriate size spacer to achieve the correct opening pressure and insert it into
                the holder body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the pressure adjusting spring and spring seat guide into the nozzle holder body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the valve stop spacer with the dowel pin holes in the holder body and assemble to the
                nozzle holder body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dip the nozzle valve, located in the nozzle valve body, into clean calibrating fluid. Insert
                the nozzle valve into the valve body and move the valve up and down several times to insure free
                movement.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a thin, even coat of "Lubriplate 630-AAA" or equivalent to the nozzle valve body
                seating shoulder; align the nozzle valve body locating pin holes with the plate pins and assemble to the
                two components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the cap nut over the nozzle valve body and tighten the cap by hand to the holder.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Assemble nozzle holder assembly to injection nozzle holding fixture
                <emph type="bold">ZTSE2752</emph>
                as described under
                <emph type="bold">"DISASSEMBLY"</emph>
                in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Tighten the cap nut to the specified special torque.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Install a new copper gasket over the nozzle tip.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Cap the nozzles with plastic caps until retesting and adjusting is performed.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_245.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_247.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
