<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND
        CRANKCASE - INSPECTION AND REPAIR - CRANKSHAFT AND MAIN BEARINGS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CRANKSHAFT AND MAIN BEARINGS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the bearing inserts and caps thoroughly in solvent and dry with filtered compressed
                air.
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT SCRAPE GUM OR VARNISH DEPOSITS FROM BEARING SHELLS.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all the internal oil passages of the crankshaft using a stiff nylon brush. Loosen all
                dirt, sludge and deposits which may have accumulated. Flush the oil passages with a suitable non-caustic
                solvent.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Blow the passages dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the crankshaft journals (main and rod) for scratches, grooves and scoring.
                Use dye penetrant methods to check for cracks.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect all bearing inserts. Replace bearings that are scored, chipped or worn.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the diameter of each journal using a micrometer. (See "
                <emph type="bold">SPECIFICATIONS</emph>"). Measure each journal at two points, at right angles to each
                other. Move the micrometer over the entire width of the journal. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1050741">7.41</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the journals exceed the maximum out-of-round specification, the crankshaft must be
                        reground.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef1050740" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11359" filename="../figcg1/cg11359.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7.40.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1050741" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12180" filename="../figcg1/cg12180.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7.41.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The crankshaft can be ground 0.010 in., 0.020 in. or 0.030 in.(0.25mm, 0.51mm or 0.76 mm)
                undersize as follows:
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An induction hardened fillet and journal crankshaft can be reground similar to any precision
                        crankshaft. However, these shafts require special treatment when grinding. Before grinding all
                        crankshafts must be checked for hardness.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check crankshaft hardness before regrinding and on every journal which incurred a
                    bearing failure or shows evidence of overheating.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Bearing failures can cause overheating of crankshaft journals and reduction of hardness.
                            When this occurs, the crankshaft strength may be unacceptably reduced.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check crankshaft journal hardness using a Rockwell Hardness Tester as follows:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The hardness test is destructive and is only made prior to grinding the crankshaft. The
                            grinding process will correct the damage made by the Rockwell Hardness Tester. DO NOT TEST
                            FOR HARDNESS UNLESS THE CRANKSHAFT IS TO BE REGROUND.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>Check crankshaft rod and main journals at three locations: the top, bottom and one other
                    location.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The top and bottom is determined with the crankshaft journal at TDC.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Check as close to the fillet as possible.</para>
                <para>If any reading is below 50 RC hardness,
                    <emph type="bold">REPLACE</emph>
                    the crankshaft. If hardness is acceptable, grind the crankshaft.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Superior strength of the fillet-hardened shaft is due to the special process by which the
                            bearing surfaces and fillets are hardened. This localized hardening greatly increases the
                            bending strength of the crankshaft; in order to maintain this strength, special precautions
                            must be taken when regrinding the shaft. If special precautions are not taken, the crank.
                            shaft can be severely weakened. The metallurgical characteristics of the shaft demand
                            exacting standards and control when regrinding journals. However, it can be reground locally
                            where equipment and experience can produce quality standards outlined in the following
                            instructions.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Grind the crankshaft as any other precision crankshaft using the following guidelines:
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The crankshafts are reground similar to any precision crankshaft with the following
                precautions:
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A mechanical or an automatic wheel dresser is mandatory to prevent chatter, burning and poor
                surface finish. A hand stone should
                <emph type="bold">NEVER</emph>
                be used to rough or fine dress the face or radii of the wheel. The radii should blend evenly into the
                journal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The selection of the grinding wheel is important because too hard a wheel will increase the
                possibility of burning. An aluminum-oxide wheel with a grit size of approximately 50 and a maximum
                hardness of M will produce satisfactory results, with other conditions being suitable.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. The coolant must be such that it minimizes burning. This requires a fluid with high
                lubricity properties. The straight-cutting oils appear to be the best for grinding crankshafts and are
                strongly recommended.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>USE EVERY PRECAUTION TO AVOID BURNS ON THE SHAFT DURING THE GRINDING OPERATION.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. A grinding wheel speed of 6500 surface feet per minute with a work spindle speed of
                approximately 40 to 45 revolutions per minute is usually satisfactory.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Grind all journals with crankshaft rotating in a counterclockwise direction (viewed from
                front of crankshaft), lap all journals with crankshaft rotating in clockwise direction.
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT REFINISH REAR SEAL FLANGE.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Feed rates should be slower than normal to prevent any burning.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Maximum allowable taper on crankpins (rod journals) and main journals 0.015 per inch of
                length (.38 mm per 25.4 mm) of length. Crankpins and journals must be polished to 20 Micro-inch maximum
                - to 5 Micro-inch minimum, and must not be over 0.005 inch (0.12 mm) out of round.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not grind the crankshaft flange.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>AS A NORMAL PRECAUTION, IT IS RECOMMENDED THAT A CO2 FIRE EXTINGUISHER BE NEAR THE GRINDING
                        MACHINE, JUST IN CASE ANY EXCESSIVE HEAT SHOULD IGNITE THE OIL. IF A FIRE SHOULD START, IT CAN
                        BE RAPIDLY EXTINGUISHED WITHOUT CAUSING ANY DAMAGE TO THE MACHINE OR SURROUNDING AREA BY
                        FOLLOWING THE NORMAL FIRE-EXTINGUISHING PROCEDURE.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Inspection of the crankshaft for dimensional tolerances is the same as for conventionally
                hardened crankshafts, except that extra care must be taken to be sure the shaft is cool before
                inspecting. Scrap only those crankshafts which do not meet the specified tolerances.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. In addition to inspecting the dimensional tolerances, the crankshaft must also be
                carefully checked for surface defects, particularly for grinding cracks and burns. It is advisable to
                spray check the crankshaft (using dye penetrant methods) after grinding and lapping to insure that there
                is no surface cracking.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">.
                <emph type="bold">TARASOV ETCH:</emph>
                In order to establish the acceptability of a regrind procedure, crankshaft should be etched before
                lapping to determine whether the crankshaft was burned during the regrinding procedure. The best etch to
                use is the Tarasov etch, which will show both the rehardened and the overtempered areas. The etching
                procedure is as follows:
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>DUE TO THE SHARP ODOR AND FLAMMABILITY OF THE TARASOV ETCH, THE ETCHING SHOULD BE DONE IN A
                        WELL-VENTILATED AREA, AWAY FROM ANY OPEN FLAME.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean surface with a scouring powder and water or a good solvent.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wash thoroughly and rinse with alcohol.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply etchant No. 1 (4 parts nitric acid in 96 parts water) for approximately 16 seconds
                    with a cotton swab.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Rinse with water and dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply etchant No. 2 (2 parts hydrochloric acid in 98 parts acetone) for approximately 15
                    seconds with a cotton swab.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>ACETONE IS HIGHLY FLAMMABLE.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Rinse with alcohol and dry thoroughly with compressed air.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>IF THE CRANKSHAFT HAS BEEN BURNED, IT WILL SHOW UP AS A CHANGE OF COLOR AFTER THE ETCH.
                            AREAS REHARDENED BY EXCESSIVE HEAT APPEAR NEARLY WHITE, WHILE SOFTENED AREAS TURN DARK GRAY
                            OR BLACK. AREAS UNAFFECTED BY THE HEAT OF GRINDING ETCH A LIGHT GRAY.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>IF ANY BURNS SHOW UP AFTER THE ETCH IS USED, THE PHYSICAL PROPERTIES OF THE CRANKSHAFT
                            WILL HAVE BEEN SERIOUSLY REDUCED, AND THE CRANKSHAFT SHOULD NOT BE USED.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If burning becomes a serious problem, it can usually be eliminated by reducing the infeed
                            rate, using a softer grade of wheel, or increasing the work spindle speed. Sometimes, a
                            combination of these factors, along with the recommendations mentioned above, will be
                            necessary to overcome the problem.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">After the crankshaft passes the Tarasov etch test, it may be lapped.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>THOROUGHLY CLEAN CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES WITH NYLON BRISTLE BRUSH, SOAP AND WATER TO
                            REMOVE ALL DEBRIS WHICH MAY HAVE ACCUMULATED DURING REGRINDING PROCEDURE. ANY DEBRIS LEFT IN
                            CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES CANNOT BE REMOVED BY OIL FILTERS AND WILL DAMAGE BEARINGS
                            IMMEDIATELY UPON ENGINE START-UP. ONCE CLEANED, WRAP CRANKSHAFT, TO PROTECT IT FROM
                            CONTAMINATION, UNTIL IT IS INSTALLED.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">. Visually inspect the crankshaft gears for chipping or wear. Replacement as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_157.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_159.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
