<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Service (1994) - INTRODUCTION - AIR INDUCTION AND EXHAUST SYSTEMS - AIR
        FLOW
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>AIR FLOW</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The intake system consists of an air cleaner, air piping, the compressor side of the turbocharger,
                valve cover/intake manifold and intake valves. During start up, the air is forced through the air
                cleaner by the atmospheric pressure (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f105IN15">15</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <para>The turbocharger is used to increase engine power output by increasing air supply to the engine. It
                provides uniform performance at various operating altitudes. It is an exhaust driven centrifugal air
                compressor; that allows filtered air to enter at the center of the compressor housing and is forced
                under pressure to the combustion chamber. After combustion, hot and expanding exhaust gases move through
                the turbine housing causing the turbine wheel to spin. The turbine wheel drives the compressor wheel
                through a common shaft. The turbocharger responds directly to engine loads. During heavy load, increased
                flow of exhaust gases turn the turbine wheel faster causing the compressor impeller to turn faster and
                supply more air (greater boost) to the intake manifold. Conversely, with light engine load, flow of
                exhaust gases decrease and less air is pumped into the intake manifold.
            </para>
            <para>The exhaust system includes exhaust valves, exhaust manifold, muffler and exhaust piping. The
                turbocharger compressor side is part of the intake system and turbine side is part of the exhaust
                system.
            </para>
            <para>The air is cooled by a air-to-air intercooler prior to entering the intake manifold. Air then flows
                into the combustion chamber where it is mixed with the proper amount of fuel and burned. Exhaust gases
                leave the cylinders through exhaust ports and the exhaust manifold. From the exhaust manifold, the
                expansion of exhaust gases on the exhaust turbine drive the turbocharger and are released through the
                exhaust pipe to the atmosphere.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Induction And Exhaust Systems Turbocharged And Intercooled</title>
            <figure id="f105IN15" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3578" filename="../figeg3/EG3578.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 15.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e105.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
