<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS PROCEDURES
        FOR.. - ...LOW POWER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>...LOW POWER</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the problem:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Determine how power or performance is checked.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Compare to identical units in same type operation. (Refer to "PERFORMANCE DATA
                    GUIDELINES").
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Determine the cause of the problem:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check fuel type and grade. Refer to appropriate "OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE" manual.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Inspect shutoff cable or electric shutoff for proper adjustment.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Inspect the throttle cable for full travel from low idle stop to high idle stop under
                    all conditions of operation. Make certain the operation of the vehicle is not changing these
                    adjustments. Verify high idle.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Inspect throttle cable over-travel at wide open throttle with engine running. Refer to
                    Section 5 for procedure.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Throttle cable over-travel is the adjustment made on the throttle cable which compensates
                            for wear that occurs in the throttle linkage and for chassis movement. If throttle cable
                            over-travel is not maintained, full throttle and consequently, maximum performance will not
                            be available.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Measure transfer pump pressure.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Change filter if pressure is low</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check for fuel inlet restriction if new fuel filter did not correct the low transfer pump
                            pressure.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If fuel inlet is not being restricted and fuel pressure is still low replace fuel return
                            valve or transfer pump.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Measure air cleaner restriction.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Service air cleaner element(s) as necessary</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check injection pump timing and correct with injection pump on engine.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loss of one cylinder.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check for plugged injection line</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check nozzle operation</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Intake manifold pressure loss or aneroid diaphragm leakage.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Pressurize intake system and inspect for leaks at all (boost pressure) connections. Air
                            leakage may occur at line connectors or on the boost line to the aneroid. During engine
                            operation leaks at the connectors can cause manifold pressure to be reduced at the aneroid
                            which allows the injection pump to operate in "cut back" or reduced power level.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Test aneroid diaphragm by applying (20 psi max.) air pressure, using the D-200 Pressure
                            Test Kit, for 30 seconds. If leakage occurs, replace diaphragm. Low power and low manifold
                            pressure will result if diaphragm leaks because injection pump will stay in "cut back"
                            position.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
