<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS GUIDES</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection division="ENGINE" id="e11003" svcsectype="prodspec" date="04/10/1996">
        <title>ENGINE PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS GUIDES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
            <para>Accurate diagnosis assures customer satisfaction by avoiding unnecessary repairs and expense. No doubt
                almost any mechanical problem can be accurately diagnosed under ideal conditions. But what really
                matters is whether accurate diagnosis can become the norm under everyday conditions. Much of the long
                term success and acceptance of an engine is actually determined by the efficiency of thousands of shop
                foremen and mechanics. The Engine Performance Analysis Guides are useful to the mechanic. It is not a
                form that remains buried in a book in the shop foreman's service library. The Performance Analysis Guide
                comes in pads of 50 sheets. The mechanic takes it right to the job with him and he uses it as a check
                list. The Performance Analysis Guide begins with those items which are easiest to check, and progress
                through the items for which the procedure to check is more involved.
            </para>
            <para>Beginning with the basics, those items which are more common, and progressing to the less likely
                causes of a malfunction promotes RAPID as well as ACCURATE diagnosis when using the Performance Analysis
                Guide.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
