<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - EGED-115 DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS GUIDE FOR THE
        INTERNATIONAL(r) 530 and DT-408/466 DIESEL ENGINES WITH ROBERT BOSCH "P" INJECTION PUMP [FRONT SIDE] - INJECTION
        PUMP STATIC TIMING (ENGINE STOPPED) - (Static) Timing Check
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>(Static) Timing Check</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect battery cables.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove injection pump gear drive access cover from front of engine and discard O' ring.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Shut-off must be in the no-fuel position before proceeding.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the engine in the normal operating direction until the #1 piston is on the
                compression stroke and the mark on the damper pulley is aligned with the correct timing mark on the
                timing indicator for the particular engine application. (See Performance Data Guidlines this section)
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The kidney shaped hole in the injection pump drive gear should be approximately at the 11:00
                        o'clock position when the #1 piston is on the compression stroke. Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100507">5.7</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thread plunger pin (ZTSE-4373) into timing hole. If plunger pin enters the timing hole,
                injection timing is ok. If plunger pin does not enter timing hole, remove the plunger pin tool from
                gear.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>THE PLUNGER PIN TOOL MUST BE REMOVED TO AVOID DAMAGING THE TOOL.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the four cap-screws which secure the gear to the injection pump. Rotate injection
                pump with socket wrench to align the small hole in the drive gear hub with the lock plate hole behind
                the pump drive hub. Torque the four capscrews which secure the gear to the injection pump using the
                correct torque specification. Re-thread the timing plunger pin tool into the timing hole. If plunger pin
                enters timing hole, injection pump timing is correctly set.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">* - Form specified with latest revision.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the plunger timing pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install gear cover using a new O" ring seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Enter the observed pump to engine timing in the 1st check block of EGED-115 -
                <emph type="bold">*</emph>.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1100507" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6183" filename="../figeg6/eg6183.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.7 Static Pump to Engine Timing</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">* - Form specified with latest revision.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_49.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_51.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
