<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - DWYER SLACK TUBE MANOMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DWYER SLACK TUBE MANOMETER</title>
        <para>DESCRIPTION</para>
        <para>The manometer
            <emph type="bold">(Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100417">4.17</hotlnk>)
            </emph>
            is a "U" shaped tube with a scale mounted between the legs of the "U". Where the portability of the Model
            200 Pressure Test Kit is not required, this manometer can be used to measure either low pressure or vacuum
            and may be filled with water.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1100417" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg7725" filename="../figcg7/CG7725.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 4.17 Slack Tube manometer (Dwyer No. 1211-48)</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>"A" Dimension Indicates Total Fluid Column</para>
        <para>Order from:</para>
        <para>Dwyer Instruments, Inc.</para>
        <para>P.O. Box 373</para>
        <para>Michigan City, Indiana 46360</para>
        <para>Phone: (219) 872-9141</para>
        <para>FILLING</para>
        <para>The manometer may be filled with water, when checking very low pressures.</para>
        <para>When filling with water, use only good drinking water without additives except for some colored water
            vegetable dye which enables the tester to read the scale easier. With both legs of the manometer open to the
            atmosphere, fill the tube until the top of the fluid column is near the zero mark on the scale. Shake the
            tube to eliminate any air bubbles.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>NEVER USE AN ANTIFREEZE SOLUTION, SODA POP, TONIC, ETC. THE INCREASE IN DENSITY CAUSES FALSE
                    READINGS.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>INSTALLING AND READING</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the manometer in a vertical position. Be sure the fluid is at the zero mark on the
                scale.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect one leg of the manometer to the source of the pressure or vacuum. Be sure the other
                leg is open to atmosphere.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and when the engine is in the proper operating condition as specified in
                Performance Data Guideline pages, observe the manometer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After about two minutes, record the average position the fluid level is above and below the
                zero mark. Add the two figures together. The sum of the two is the total column of fluid.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>At times both columns of the manometer will not travel the same distance. This is of no
                        concern to the tester as long as the leg not connected to the pressure or vacuum source is open
                        to the atmosphere.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If it is necessary to convert from the column of fluid to psi of kPa, refer to the "Metric
                Conversion Factor Chart" in Section 6.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>CLEANING</para>
        <para>1. Wash the tube thoroughly with a little pure soap and water. Avoid liquid soaps and solvents.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
