<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - EGED-115 DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS GUIDE FOR THE
        INTERNATIONAL(r) 530 and DT-408/466 DIESEL ENGINES WITH ROBERT BOSCH "P" INJECTION PUMP [FRONT SIDE] - EXTERNAL
        LEAKAGE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EXTERNAL LEAKAGE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="t1100502">
                <title>FROM FORM NO. EGED - 115 -*</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="36p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="115p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="86p"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="58p"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="79p"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="58p"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="2" nameend="6" spanname="S2T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="3" nameend="4" spanname="S3T4"/>
                    <spanspec namest="5" nameend="6" spanname="S5T6"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>EXTERNAL LEAKAGE</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>FUEL</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>OIL</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>AIR</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para>COOLANT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="S2T6">
                                <para>RECORD LOCATION OF LEAKS IN "COMMENTS"</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>METHOD 1 st Check 2 nd Check</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>VISUAL CHECK</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>PRESSURE CHECK</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S3T4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S5T6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>EXTERNAL LEAKAGE</para>
            <para>Inspect for fuel, oil, air or coolant leaks. If no leaks are found, enter OK in 1st check box. Upon
                visual inspection, check all hoses and look for water stains, oil stains and wetness at the water pump.
                Record the location of leaks in the comments section.
            </para>
            <para>Leakage can be the reason for complaints of poor fuel economy, or high oil consumption. A leak in the
                air intake system can shorten engine life, especially under dusty conditions. A coolant leak can result
                in a complaint of engine overheating.
            </para>
            <para>If coolant and air leaks are observed, but the source not readily identified, the service technician
                may utilize the following test procedures to pin point the coolant or air leak:
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>I. ENGINE COOLANT LEAKAGE TEST</title>
            <para>General</para>
            <para>Too often attempts to correct complaints of external and/or internal water leakage reflects an
                arbitrary replacement of oil to water coolers and/or a complete engine teardown for a visual inspection.
                Components such as cylinder heads, coolers, etc., are either sent out for inspection and/or replaced as
                the result of a guess.
                <emph type="bold">THIS IS NOT A RECOMMENDED APPROACH AND IN MOST CASES LEAVES MUCH DOUBT IF ALL LEAKAGE
                    AREAS HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>THE PROCEDURE DESCRIBED IN SECTION 2, PAGE 5 IDENTIFIES THE MOST COMMON POINTS OF LEAKAGE and
                describes the step-by-step instructions required to properly test for leakage.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">* - Form specified with latest revision.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>II. AIR INDUCTION SYSTEM PRESSURE TEST</title>
            <para>General</para>
            <para>The most common cause of engine failure is dirt. Even though an air cleaner element itself is properly
                serviced there are other areas in the induction system which must be maintained. The importance of
                pressure testing the air induction system cannot be emphasized enough with present-day high speed diesel
                engines. An air induction leak on the suction side, no matter how small, can cause an engine failure and
                must not be tolerated.
            </para>
            <para>Test for leakage in the air induction system using a manually regulated compressed air supply, 0-15
                psi (0-103 kPa) pressure test gauge.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TEST PROCEDURE (REFER TO FIGURE
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100503">5.3</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mask off the outer diameter of air cleaner element air inlet with duct tape and plug air
                    cleaner canister drain.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air cleaner restriction indicator or tubing at the air cleaner. Install a
                    plug to seal opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate tap on cold air discharge pipe which may contain a plug or a line which supplies
                    ether to the intake system. Remove the plug or line and connect a manually regulated air supply with
                    pressure gauge to the tap opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 5-8 psi of air pressure with regulator to pressurize the air induction system. A
                    constant supply of air is needed to compensate for the air loss through opened intake valves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat the following areas with the soap solution and check for leaks. Leaks will cause
                    air bubbles to form.
                    <emph type="bold">(Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100503">5.3</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    )
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air cleaner body surface around the outlet pipe.</para>
                    <figure id="ef1100503" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg3119" filename="../figeg3/eg3119.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.3 Air Induction System Pressure Test</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air cleaner outlet pipe to air cleaner body junction.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All clamped hose and gasket connections between air cleaner outlet and intake
                        manifold/valve cover. This includes connections at turbocharger.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Surface of all air induction piping and hoses between air cleaner and intake
                        manifold/valve cover.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When applicable, the air compressor air inlet piping from the air cleaner tube to
                        and including the fitting and the gasket.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Piping to the air charge cooler.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No leakage is permitted between air cleaner and turbocharger (suction side). If leakage
                    at the joints is detected, tighten hose clamps. If leakage still persists, remove the parts to
                    determine the cause. Replace parts as necessary using the latest clamps and torques specified.
                    Retest the corrected area.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Any leaks found in the air induction system could have allowed dirt to enter the engine.
                            Dirt entering engine can cause piston rings to wear abnormally or break (which causes high
                            oil consumption), excessive blue smoke, turbocharger compressor wheel pitting and erosion.
                            If any leaks are found in the air intake system, you can check the internal condition of the
                            engine by running a crankcase pressure check.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Visually inspect the following:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner housing externally for damage or distortion which could allow
                    unfiltered air to enter the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner housing internally for end seal movement indicated by polishing
                    where end seal contacts the air cleaner housing. End seal movement indicates dirt may have passed
                    the air cleaner element and entered the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner element for holes, damaged seals, element sooting, end cap denting
                    because of overtightening or damage during servicing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect hoses and clamps for tightness and positioning over sealing beads.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the chassis mounted air charge cooler and piping.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_46.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
