<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>530 and DT-466/408 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - EGED-115 DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS GUIDE FOR THE
        INTERNATIONAL(r) 530 and DT-408/466 DIESEL ENGINES WITH ROBERT BOSCH "P" INJECTION PUMP [FRONT SIDE] - SHUTOFF
        CABLE/ELECTRIC SHUTOFF - ELECTRIC SHUTOFF (AUTOMATIC SHUTOFF)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>ELECTRIC SHUTOFF (AUTOMATIC SHUTOFF)</title>
        <para>12 OR 24 VOLT</para>
        <para>PROBLEM: ENGINE WILL CRANK, BUT WILL NOT START.</para>
        <para>SERVICE TIP</para>
        <para>Prior to ESO Solenoid diagnostic check, verify that the proper COLD START procedure has been followed.
        </para>
        <para>1. Set the parking brake, put the transmission in neutral and depress the clutch if applicable. DO NOT
            DEPRESS THE ACCELERATOR PEDAL AT THIS TIME!
        </para>
        <para>2. Turn the keyswitch to the "START" position to engage starter/pull in E.S.O.</para>
        <para>3. After the starter in engaged fully, depress the accelerator pedal to provide starting fuel quantity.
        </para>
        <para>4. Refer to vehicle Operator's Manual for additional starting instructions.</para>
        <para>5. If the engine still DOES NOT START begine ESO diagnostic routine.</para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>PLACE THE TRANSMISSION IN NEUTRAL WITH THE PARKING BRAKE ON.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>VERIFY THE ELECTRIC SHUTOFF IS INOPERABLE AS FOLLOWS: VISUALLY OBSERVE THE SHUTOFF LEVER (FIGURE
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100505">5.5</hotlnk>) AND TURN THE KEY SWITCH TO THE "START" POSITION (FOR
                    VEHICLES WITHOUT PUSHBUTTON START). FOR VEHICLES WITH PUSHBUTTON START, TURN KEY SWITCH TO THE "ON"
                    POSITION AND PUSH THE START PUSHBUTTON. THE SHUTOFF LEVER SHOULD ROTATE COUNTERCLOCKWISE (CCW) AS
                    THE SOLENOID PLUNGER "PULLS IN". IF THIS DOES NOT OCCUR, TURN THE KEY SWITCH TO THE "ON" POSITION.
                    DEPRESS THE PLUNGER, BY HAND, AND OBSERVE IF THE PLUNGER REMAINS "PULLED IN". IF THE PLUNGER REMAINS
                    PULLED IN, CHECK SOLENOID ADJUSTMENT (SEE FIGURE
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100505">5.5</hotlnk>) IF NOT, DETERMINE THE CAUSE AND CORRECT AS FOLLOWS:
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fuse - Inspect the electric shutoff fuse. If burned out, replace.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">12 or 24</emph>
                Volt Supply - This externally switched solenoid design incorporates a
                <emph type="bold">"pull"</emph>
                coil and a
                <emph type="bold">"hold"</emph>
                coil which are activated by separate circuits. There are three terminals in the Metri-Pack connector.
                The wires and the connector of the solenoid are labled to indicate
                <emph type="bold">"common"</emph>,
                <emph type="bold">"pull"</emph>
                or
                <emph type="bold">"hold"</emph>.
                <emph type="bold">(Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100506">5.6</hotlnk>).
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">"pull"</emph>
            coil is wired into the cranking motor circuit. Check for 12 or 24 volts between the
            <emph type="bold">"common"</emph>
            and
            <emph type="bold">"pull"</emph>
            terminals of the solenoid mating connector with the key switch in the
            <emph type="bold">"start"</emph>
            position [cranking engine].
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The minimum voltage required for the 12 volt solenoid to pull in is 9 volts.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The minimum voltage required for the 24 volt solenoid to pull in is 18 volts.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">"hold"</emph>
            coil is wired into the key switch.
            <emph type="bold"></emph>Check for 12 or 24 volts between the "common" and
            <emph type="bold">"hold"</emph>
            terminals of the solenoid mating connector while the key switch is in the
            <emph type="bold">"on"</emph>
            position.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>DO NOT "JUMP" OR BYPASS THE FUSE.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>If voltage available to the (12V or 24V) solenoid is under 12 or 24 VDC, check battery condition, wiring,
            connections and key switch.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rubber Boot - The rubber boot seals the core from dirt and moisture.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Verify that the boot is firmly attached to the solenoid body.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Replace any solenoid which has a torn boot.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Replace the solenoid if the boot becomes hard and inflexible in cold temperatures (-10
                    &#176;F or below). This condition may hinder "pull-in" of the solenoid.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef1100505" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg15237" filename="../figcg1/CG15237.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.5 Electric Shut-off Solenoid</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>ADJUSTMENT PROCEDURE</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>FOLLOW THESE STEP BY STEP INSTRUCTIONS TO PREVENT SOLENOID BURN OUT OR INTERNAL DAMAGE TO
                            INJECTION PUMP.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>1. Loosen jamnut.</para>
                <para>2. Apply the proper D.C. voltage from a power source (with an 8 amp fuse protection) across the
                    "HOLD" &#38; "COMMON" terminals of the solenoid connector.
                </para>
                <para>3. Depress solenoid plunger in to bottom of its travel. The plunger should hold the shut-off lever
                    in the Run Fuel On Position.
                </para>
                <para>4. Move the shut-off lever toward the RUN position and screw the solenoid swivel (using swivel
                    wrench flats) into the rod end until the shut-off lever stops its forward movement.
                </para>
                <para>5. Turn swivel two full turns in the opposite direction (moving shut-off lever back). Tighten
                    jamnut, then de-energize the solenoid.
                </para>
                <para>6. Cycle the solenoid 2-3 times to insure the shut-off lever travel is adequate to achieve the
                    "RUN" and "SHUT-OFF" positions. This is done by cranking the engine to activate the "PULL" coil
                    causing the plunger to depress and turn the ignition off allowing the plunger to return under spring
                    load. CAUTION ! DO NOT CYCLE more than 3 times. Additional cycling may cause pull-in coil
                    overheating resulting in burnout.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The boot should be free of paint which will cause the boot to become soft and catch
                            between the spring and plunger. This will prevent the plunger from seating properly.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Solenoid Worn - Inspect as follows:</para>
            <para>Inspect for evidence of dust, dirt, brass powder, or blackened deposits on the plunger or in the
                solenoid core.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If evidence of a worn solenoid is found, as described above, solenoid condition is marginal
                        and may not
                        <emph type="bold">"pull in"</emph>
                        quickly or consistently.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure resistance (ohms) across the terminals of the solenoid as follows:
                <emph type="bold">(Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100506">5.6</hotlnk>).
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Be sure the key switch is off. Disconnect the power supply to the solenoid. Connect an Ohm
                        meter to the
                        <emph type="bold">"Hold"</emph>
                        and
                        <emph type="bold">"Common"</emph>
                        terminals
                        <emph type="bold">(Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100506">5.6</hotlnk>).
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12.8 to 16.0 ohms (12V solenoid); 46.7 to 57.1 ohms (24V solenoid) resistance should be
                        observed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect an ohm meter to the
                        <emph type="bold">"Pull and Common"</emph>
                        terminals
                        <emph type="bold">(Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1100506">5.6</hotlnk>).
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>.16 to .24 ohms (12V solenoid); .55 to .68 (24V solenoid) ohms resistance should be
                        observed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>REPLACE SOLENOID IF RESISTANCE MEASUREMENTS EXCEED SPECIFICATIONS</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef1100506" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14480" filename="../figcg1/CG14480.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.6 Solenoid Connector Terminal Identification</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="t1100506">
                <title>RESISTANCE CHECK (NO POWER TO SOLENOID IGNITION SWITCH OFF)</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="120p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="120p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="120p"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>TERMINALS</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>12 VOLT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24 VOLT</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>HOLD TO COMMON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>12.8-16.0 OHMS</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>46.7-57.1 OHMS</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>PULL TO COMMON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>.16-.24 OHMS</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>.55-.68 OHMS</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e110.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
