<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - VEHICLE
        PERSONALITY MODULE - PROGRAMMING AND SOFTWARE FAULTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PROGRAMMING AND SOFTWARE FAULTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 613 - ATA CODE SID 252 FMI 1 - VPM: VPM/ECM SW MISMATCH - FLASH CODE 614 - ATA CODE SID
                252 FMI 13 - ECM: ECM/VPM SW MISMATCH
            </title>
            <para>Codes 613 and 614 will only occur when the VPM or ECM has been
                <emph type="bold">changed in the field</emph>. At start-up, the ECM compares software versions in the
                VPM and ECM. If the versions are not compatible, codes 613 or 614 and 622 will be set. Code 622
                indicates Field Defaults are being used and turns ON the Engine Warning Light.
            </para>
            <para>If codes 613 and 614 are active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The ECM and VPM must be software compatible. Whichever component (ECM or VPM) was
                    recently replaced is not the correct part number (has software version that is not compatible with
                    the component (ECM or VPM) that was not changed). Determine correct part number and install.
                </para>
                <para>The component having the most recent software configuration date sets the code (613 or 614).
                </para>
                <para>Example: If the VPM is replaced and the replacement VPM software version is of a later date than
                    the ECM software in the vehicle, the fault code (613) will indicate that the ECM software is not
                    compatible with the VPM.
                </para>
                <para>Example: If the replacement VPM installed had a software date older than the ECM software, the
                    fault code (614) would indicate that the VPM software is not compatible with the ECM.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 615 - ATA CODE SID 254 FMI 13 - ECM: PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETER KAM CORRUPT MEMORY</title>
            <para>At start-up, the ECM performs tests on the KAM memory, where programmable parameter information will
                be stored when retrieved from the VPM. If the KAM memory test fails (bad memory or corrupt data), then
                Flash code 615 will be set. The engine will operate on Field defaults turning ON the Engine Warning
                Light and setting code 622. If the condition causing code 615 to set is intermittent, and the condition
                is no longer present, the code will change to inactive status and the engine will operate normally.
            </para>
            <para>Flash Code 615 can also be caused by no or low power to KAM memory at ECM terminal 1 which could cause
                code 224 to be set.
            </para>
            <para>If code 615 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to SECTION 3: KEEP ALIVE MEMORY CIRCUIT.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If a defect is found in KAM Feed Circuit, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If KAM power is present to ECM terminal 1, and code 615 is active, attempt to clear
                        code 615. If code 615 continues to be set, replace the ECM.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 621 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 1 - ECM: ECM USING MANUFACTURING DEFAULTS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>Engine operates, but limited to 25 HP rating and Engine Warn Light is
                ON.
            </para>
            <para>If the VPM is not programmed at the factory OR an unprogrammed VPM is installed in the field, then the
                ECM will select parameter values from the Manufacturing Default list. This list will provide only
                limited engine horsepower (25 HP). If the condition that caused code 621 to set is intermittent, and the
                condition is no longer present, the code will change to inactive status and the engine will operate
                normally.
            </para>
            <para>If code 621 is active:</para>
            <para>A. Program the VPM using established programming procedures included in the Prolink Manual.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 622 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 0 - ECM: ECM USING FIELD DEFAULTS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>Engine Warning Light ON, customer options disabled (cruise control
                etc.) and the engine is limited to 175 HP.
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle is not operating under normal operating conditions, the ECM uses either partial or
                full field default values stored in ECM memory, instead of programmed values that are stored in VPM
                memory. When the ECM is using Full Field Default values, code 622 is set. If the condition causing the
                ECM to operate using field defaults is intermittent, and the condition is no longer present, code 622
                will become inactive and normal engine operation will resume.
            </para>
            <para>Code 622 is an indicator that field defaults are being used. Other codes cause code 622 to be set. The
                other codes identify the condition that caused the ECM to use field defaults.
            </para>
            <para>If, for any reason, the ECM is unable to down load parameter values from the VPM or the parameter
                values received from the VPM are not valid, then the ECM selects full or partial Field Default parameter
                values. The Field Default parameter values are stored in the ECM. If no data is available from the VPM,
                full field defaults are used. If only certain data is corrupt, then partial field defaults may be used.
            </para>
            <para>If code 622 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Review other logged codes. The specific values that the ECM is unable to download and/or
                    reason for the communication failure must be determined and corrected. When corrected, the ECM will
                    not use the field default mode of operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 623 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 13 - ECM: INVALID EFRC</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the ECM requested, and was unable to get valid Engine Family Rating codes
                from the VPM. If this occurs, the code 623 is set and the engine operates on Field Defaults causing code
                622 to be set. If the condition causing code 623 to set is intermittent, and the condition is no longer
                present, code 623 will become inactive and normal engine operation will resume.
            </para>
            <para>If code 623 is active, reprogram the VPM with the proper engine family data.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_423.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_425.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
