<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 5.2 PRO-LINK 9000 ELECTRONIC SERVICE TOOL OPERATION -
        DESCRIPTION - INJECTOR TEST (ENGINE OFF)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INJECTOR TEST (ENGINE OFF)</title>
        <para>Press the
            <emph type="bold">"FUNC"</emph>key to continue. The next option is
            <emph type="bold">"INJECTOR TEST"</emph>. By selecting this test the ECM will exercise (Buzz) the electronic
            injectors. During this test it will measure the circuits as well activate the injectors. This will allow the
            technician to listen to the operation of the injector without the engine running. At the completion of the
            test, if the electronic components detect any faults they will be recorded and displayed. Also by monitoring
            the noise made by the injector the technician can determine if an injector does not fire electronically.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This test can only be done after the Engine Off test has been completed.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Select the
            <emph type="bold">"INJECTOR TEST"</emph>
            then press the
            <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
            key (
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252211">5.28</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ).
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1252211" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="pl007" filename="../figpl0/pl007.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 5.28 - Pro-link Injector Test Screen</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Depressing the
            <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>key will start the test.
        </para>
        <para>At first all the injectors are energized, a loud buzzing noise can be heard.</para>
        <para>Next, each injector will be energized individually. This will proceed in sequence starting at number 1
            cylinder and proceeding through number 8 cylinder. All eight injectors should be heard as the injectors
            fire.
        </para>
        <para>After the injectors are fired individually the complete sequence will repeat several times.</para>
        <para>At the end of the test, the screen will indicate if any faults were found. If faults are indicated, press
            the
            <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
            key. This will display any faults that were recorded. If there are multiple faults the "&#8593;&#8595;"
            symbol will appear on the screen. Press the "&#8595;" key to display the other faults.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_541.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_543.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
