<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTOR DRIVE
        CIRCUIT OPERATION - INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUIT EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUIT EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FUNCTION</emph>
            </title>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_331.xml" xrefid="ef12518118">3.125</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes an ECM (Electronic Control Module) and an IDM (Injector
                Drive Module). The ECM provides the IDM with two important output signals which control fuel injector
                operation. The ECM uses the fuel quantity control strategy and input from the engine sensors to
                determine how long each fuel injector is actuated in order to provide the proper fuel quantity at any
                given engine operating condition. The ECM determines and provides a fuel output signal, FDCS (Fuel
                Demand Command Signal), by combining the desired length of each injection with the result of the
                injection timing control strategy which determines when each injection will occur. The second output
                signal, (CI) Cylinder Identification, enables the IDM to determine the correct injector firing order.
            </para>
            <para>The IDM processes the FDCS and CI signals sent by the ECM to control injector operation. It amplifies
                the FDCS signal to make it powerful enough to operate the injectors and distributes it to each injector
                according to the CI signal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The IDM contains two solid state high side drivers. Each driver supplies a continuous 115 volts DC.
                Right bank high side driver supplies cylinders 1,3,5 and 7 with 115 volts at terminal 24 of the IDM to
                terminals 3 and 20 of the valve cover connector. Left bank high side driver supplies cylinders 2,4,6 and
                8 with 115 volts at terminal 23 of the IDM to terminals 21 and 11 of the valve cover connector. The IDM
                turns each injector on by switching on a solid state device (Low Side Driver) to ground the injector
                solenoid return circuit. The IDM contains a low side driver for each of the injectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_328.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_330.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
