<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 4: SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - ROUGH IDLE
        DIAGNOSTICS (CONTINUED)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ROUGH IDLE DIAGNOSTICS (CONTINUED)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
            <title>PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTICS (CONTINUED)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform Injection Control Pressure Tests</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Oil Aeration Test with DVOM</para>
            <para>Aerated oil will cause the engine to idle rough and possibly die upon de-acceleration. The most likely
                causes for aeration is insufficient oil level, incorrect oil grade, extended oil drain intervals and low
                pressure suction leaks.
            </para>
            <para>Before performing oil aeration tests, verify that the ICP sensor is reading correctly by monitoring
                the ICP voltage signal with a DVOM or the injection control pressure using the EST with the key on and
                engine off. The value displayed will measure between .15 to .25 volts with a DVOM or display 0 PSI on
                the EST.
            </para>
            <para>Oil Quality</para>
            <para>If the oil is being aerated due to depletion of the anti-foaming agents in the oil, the problem will
                be most evident when the engine is hot and after prolonged operation at high engine speeds. During this
                test, oil aeration caused by engine oil will probably start at a low ICP signal level (1.4 to 1.5 volts
                or 1024 to 1060 PSI) and increase to a signal level above (1.75 volts or 1270 PSI) after 60 seconds of
                WOT engine operation.
            </para>
            <para>Change oil (CG-4) and re-test if this test is failed</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Low pressure suction leaks</emph>
            </para>
            <para>If a leak on the suction side is present, engine temperature will most likely have little effect on
                oil aeration. The ICP signal during this test will most likely immediately measure above 1.9 volts or
                1400 PSI during the WOT test and the engine may not achieve a engine speed above 2000 RPM during this
                test. (It is important that all KOER and cylinder contribution tests have been performed prior to this
                test. A cylinder or injector not functioning will give similar test results.)
            </para>
            <para>To confirm that a low side suction leak is occurring, over fill the engine crankcase with 3 quarts of
                engine oil, raise the rear wheels 10" off the ground and rerun this test, If a suction leak is present,
                (oil pickup tube or gasket leak) the added oil will seal the leak and the ICP signal should be in
                specification.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Low Idle Stability Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This test will help discern if erratic rail pressure and an associated low idle concern is caused by
                the ICP sensor or IPR valve. Disconnect engine harness connector at ICP sensor while engine is at idle.
                If engine rough idle smooths out, replace ICP sensor. If engine continues to idle rough with harness
                connector removed, refer to IPR and Injection Control Pressure system diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform Crankcase Pressure Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The crankcase pressure test will determine the condition of the power cylinders and base engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Injection Control Pressure Balance</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Compare ICP Pressure of Right and Left Cylinder Head. Pressure differences between the right and left
                cylinder head have been found to cause poor idle and performance complaints. Install an additional ICP
                sensor in the right cylinder head, connect the EBP sensor connector (if vehicle is equipped with) to the
                additional sensor, install a breakout box and monitor the ICP signal on the left head and right head.
                (Use EBP signal pin) with two DVOM's installed. Compare the measured signal of the right and left
                cylinder head at low idle, high idle and under a load. The difference between each head should not
                exceed .2 volts.
            </para>
            <para>To isolate if the pressure difference is caused by internal leakage in the cylinder head or by the
                high pressure pump, block the line feeding the right cylinder head and operate the on the left bank
                only. Then route the line feeding the left cylinder head to the right cylinder head. (The left high
                pressure line will reach the right head).
            </para>
            <para>If there are pressure differences between the cylinder heads, leakage is occurring in the lower
                pressure head (e.g. loose or cross threaded oil gallery drains, injector "O" rings, bad injector).
            </para>
            <para>If the pressure is the same on each cylinder head, the initial pressure difference is caused by the
                high pressure pump.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Compression Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Perform compression test to verify base engine condition (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252020">4.20</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3684" filename="../figeg3/EG3684.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.20 Compression Test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no other faults found replace injectors.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_514.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_516.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
