<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - APS/IVS PEDAL
        POSITION SENSOR/IDLE VALIDATION SWITCH - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>When the key is ON, the ECM continuously monitors the APS/IVS circuits for expected voltages. It also
                compares the APS and IVS signals for conflict. If the signals are not what the ECM expects to see, Fault
                codes will be set.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 131 - ATA CODE PID 91 FMI 4 - - ECM: APS OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            <para>The ORL (out of range low) code 131 is set if the ECM detects a voltage lower than 0.146 volts at
                terminal 47. Possible causes include: a short to ground or an open in circuit 99B. This code is
                displayed by either the Prolink EST or using the Engine Warn Light to flash codes.
            </para>
            <para>When code 131 is active, the ECM restricts engine speed to idle and turns the Engine Warning Light ON.
                If the condition causing code 131 is intermittent and the condition is no longer present, the code will
                become inactive and normal engine operation will resume. If code 131 is active, perform Testing APS
                Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_132.xml" xrefid="ef1251805">3.12</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 132 - ATA CODE PID 91 FMI 3 - - ECM: APS OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            <para>The ORH (out of range high) code 132 is set if the ECM detects a voltage greater than 4.56 volts at
                terminal 47. Possible cause: short to VREF or 12 volts in circuit 99B. This code is displayed by either
                the Prolink EST or using the Engine Warn Light to flash codes.
            </para>
            <para>When code 132 is active, the ECM restricts engine speed to idle and turns the Engine Warn Light ON. If
                the condition causing code 132 is intermittent and the condition is no longer present, the code will
                become inactive and normal engine operation will resume. If code 132 is active, perform Testing APS
                Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_132.xml" xrefid="ef1251805">3.12</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODES 133, 134 AND 135 - APS IN-RANGE FAULTS</title>
            <para>The ECM checks the voltage output of the APS by comparing the APS signal with the IVS signal. APS and
                IVS signals can disagree in two cases:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The APS signal indicates the pedal is pressed down to accelerate, but the IVS signal indicates
                        idle position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The APS signal indicates the pedal has been released to allow the engine to return to idle,
                        but the IVS signal indicates off-idle position of the pedal.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the ECM detects either of the above conditions, the ECM attempts to isolate the source of conflict.
                If code(s) 133, 134 and/or 135 are active, perform Testing IVS Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_131.xml" xrefid="ef1251804">3.11</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) and Testing APS Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_132.xml" xrefid="ef1251805">3.12</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 133 - ATA CODE PID 91 FMI 2 - - ECM: APS IN RANGE FAULT</title>
            <para>If the IVS signal is changing and the APS signal is constant, the ECM assumes APS is the conflict
                source and sets code 133. Engine rpm is restricted to idle and the Engine Warn Light is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 134 - ATA Code PID 91 FMI 7- - ECM: APS/IVS DISAGREE</title>
            <para>If neither the APS or IVS is changing, or both are changing or the ECM cannot determine the faulty
                code in specified time, then code 134 is set, engine rpm is restricted to idle and the Engine Warn Light
                is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 135 - ATA CODE SID 230 FMI 11- - ECM: IVS CIRCUIT FAULT</title>
            <para>If the APS is changing and IVS is constant, the ECM assumes IVS is the conflict source and sets flash
                code 135. In this case the ECM limits the APS signal to a lower value, which provides less than full
                rpm, but does not limit engine rpm to idle. The Engine Warn Light is not turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>Note that codes 133, 134 and 135 are caused by an intermittent condition, the codes remain ACTIVE
                until the vehicle has been shutdown and restarted. They do not recover without cycling the key switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_125.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_127.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
