<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 4: SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - ROUGH IDLE
        DIAGNOSTICS - PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PROCEDURES</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify Complaint</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Confirm conditions when complaint is present, for example does the engine rough idle only
                when hot, cold, after high speed operation, does it misfire over whole speed range, is there chassis
                vibration are there any other conditions or observations present when the engine idles rough.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect Exhaust System For Contact With Cab Or Bed</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Many vehicles inspected have had contact between the flat exhaust pipe that comes off of the
                engine to the cab. This will transmit engine vibrations to the cab, especially on acceleration when the
                engine twists on it's mounts. It may be improperly diagnosed as a rough idle complaint. The other
                exhaust ground out area observed has been in the center of the box area if a fifth wheel has been
                installed, the underside bracket may sometimes rub on the driveline.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Complete all tests on the
                <emph type="bold">Performance Diagnostic Sheet</emph>. Conditions are described below that can
                contribute to rough idle and why each test is being performed is listed below.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Check Engine Oil Level</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Verify Correct Grade</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Must meet CG-4 / SJ specification.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform EST TOOL - Engine off Tests</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Intermittent CMP, IDM, ICP, Injector or wiring harness faults can affect engine idle conditions the
                ECM may have detected and recorded these conditions.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform EST Injector Buzz Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This test will verify that the injectors are working electronically.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Measure Transfer Pump Pressure</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Low fuel pressure will cause the engine to misfire and will cause a loss of power.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If pressure is low, remove canister mounted on fuel regulator and remove any debris on fuel
                screen. Remove fuel regulator from side of fuel filter and remove any material from screen protecting
                the fuel de-aeration orifice.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Measure Transfer Pump Inlet Restriction</emph>
            </para>
            <para>If fuel pressure is low, this test will determine if the cause is a restricted fuel inlet from the
                fuel tank.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform Air in Fuel and Fuel Return Flow Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This test consists of installing a clear line on the return fuel line. Observing the clear line will
                indicate if return fuel is present and/or if air is present in the return fuel.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform EST - engine running Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This test will test the functionality of the ICP control system, the exhaust back pressure system. The
                engine must be up to operating temperature to perform this test.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Perform Cylinder Contribution Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This test will test the contributions of the individual power cylinders. It will only detect a
                cylinder that is contributing very little. It's primary function is to detect a bad injector, but it is
                possible it could detect a base engine problem such as broken rocker arm bolts, bent push tube, broken
                rings or bent connecting rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_513.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_515.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
