<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - ECM - IDM
        COMMUNICATIONS - SIGNAL FUNCTIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Cylinder Identification -</emph>Cylinder Identification (CI) signal is a 0 to12 volt wave
            form signal that communicates from the ECM to the IDM the position of cylinder 1. This signal is used by the
            IDM to synchronize the injector firing sequence. This signal is calculated from the signal generated from
            the Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP). The CI signal is generated by the ECM by "pulling down" (switching to
            grd.) a12 volt communication circuit in the IDM.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fuel Demand Command Signal -</emph>Fuel Demand Command Signal is a 0 to12 volt wave form
            signal that communicates from the ECM to the IDM the required engine timing and duration of injector firing.
            The timing and duration of the signal is determined by ECM calibration and the signals of various sensor
            inputs. The FDCS signal is generated by the ECM by "pulling down" (switching to ground) a 12 volt
            communication circuit in the IDM.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Injector Driver Module Feedback -</emph>Injector Driver Module Feedback signal is a 0 to12
            volt wave form signal that communicates from the IDM to the ECM a mirror image of the FDCS signal.
            Extensions of the EF (Electronic Feedback) signal can indicate to the ECM possible problems with the
            injectors by the IDM as the engine is running. An EF toggle (100 hz. signal) generated when the key is first
            turned "ON" and before the engine starts, communicates to the ECM that the IDM is powered up. In an engine
            off or engine running diagnostic mode, the EF signal is also used to communicate diagnostic information from
            the IDM to the ECM. The EF signal is generated by the IDM by "pulling down" (switching to grd) a12 volt
            communications circuit in the ECM.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_HL1251810.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_247.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
