<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - EXHAUST BACK
        PRESSURE (EBP) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ECM continuously monitors the signal from the EBP sensor to ensure the signal is within the
                correct operating range. If the signal is lower or higher than required, the ECM will set a fault code.
                This fault code is retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the flash code using
                the STI diagnostic switch. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will be stored as an inactive code.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>341 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 20</emph>
                - EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE LOW
            </title>
            <para>Code 341 indicates the ECM has detected a EBP signal voltage less than .039 volts for more than 0.1
                seconds. If this fault code is set, the ECM will ignore the EBP signal and continue to operate normally,
                however, if the fault is active the ECM will disable exhaust back pressure valve operation
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for code 341: Open Vref signal circuit or a defective EBP sensor.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>342
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 19</emph>
                - EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH
            </title>
            <para>An out of range high code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage more than 4.9 volts for more than
                0.1 seconds. If this fault code is set, the ECM will ignore the EBP signal and continue to operate
                normally. If this fault is active, the ECM will disable exhaust back pressure operation.
            </para>
            <para>Code 342 may be caused by an open signal return circuit, a short to a voltage source or a defective
                EBP sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>344 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 29</emph>
                - EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE BELOW WARNING LEVEL
            </title>
            <para>Code 344 indicates the exhaust back pressure was greater than 19 psi (130 Kpa) with the key "ON" and
                engine "OFF"
            </para>
            <para>Code 344 may be caused by a defective or plugged EBP sensor or a restriction in the tube leading to
                the sensor. To confirm this, remove sensor and/or tube and inspect for carbon deposits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_187.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_HL1251807.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
