<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - CRUISE CONTROL,
        PTO, HAND THROTTLE SYSTEM - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <para>Before troubleshooting the Cruise/PTO control system, use the Prolink EST to:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Review any logged Flash Codes.</para>
            <para>Code 221 relates directly to Cruise or Remote SCCS switches circuits. Codes 213 and 214 relate to
                operation of the remote PTO pedal.
                <emph type="bold">First resolve any other codes that may be present, because they may cause the ECM to
                    disable the cruise control.
                </emph>
                Flash code 622 indicates the ECM is using Field Defaults that disable cruise and PTO operation. The
                cause for code 622 must be corrected.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the Prolink EST to monitor clutch switch operation. There is no diagnostic code for the
                DDS, Drive Line Disengagement Switch (clutch switch) operation.
            </para>
            <para>If the clutch switch circuit is open, indicating that the switch is depressed, then cruise and PTO
                controls won't operate. If the clutch switch circuit is defective (shorted high), depressing the clutch
                pedal may not disengage the cruise or PTO, causing the engine to go to rated rpm when the clutch pedal
                is depressed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Flash code 222 is a Brake Switch fault which will disable cruise and PTO operation. Use
                Prolink to check brake switch operation. The BNO and BNC switches must be working properly for cruise
                control to operate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Flash codes 141 and 142 are Vehicle Speed Sensor faults which will disable the cruise and
                PTO controls. A speed sensor that is not properly adjusted will affect speedometer and cruise control
                operation, and no codes will set. Correct any speedometer problems before troubleshooting the PTO
                system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A severe INTERMITTENT connection or NOISE in the CMP SIGNAL can cause the engine to surge
                and the cruise control cannot properly maintain vehicle speed or PTO engine rpm will fluctuate.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_373.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_375.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
