<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 1: ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SECTION 1.7: SENSOR
        OPERATION - TYPES OF SENSORS - HALL EFFECT SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>HALL EFFECT SENSOR</title>
        <para>The Hall Effect sensor is an electronic device which generates a voltage signal controlled by the
            presence, absence or strength of a magnetic field.
        </para>
        <para>The Camshaft Position sensor is an example of a Hall Effect device. It contains a transducer, permanent
            magnet, signal conditioner and a switching transistor. The sensor's permanent magnet applies a magnetic
            field around the transducer as shown in
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1250705">1.27</hotlnk>.
            </emph>
            The sensor's transducer senses the strength of the magnetic field which is controlled by the vanes and
            windows (located on the rotating timing sensor disk) as they pass the sensor.
        </para>
        <para>A voltage signal is generated by the Hall Effect device each time a window passes the device. The signal
            is filtered and conditioned by the signal conditioner. The conditioned signal is applied to the switching
            transistor's base which causes the transistor to switch on and ground the 12 volt line from the ECM. The ECM
            no longer senses the 12 volt reference signal.
        </para>
        <para>Each time a vane passes the Hall Effect device no signal is generated. This action causes the transistor
            to shut off and causes the ECM to see its 12 volt reference signal.
        </para>
        <para>This switching action allows the ECM to determine crankshaft position and engine speed which is required
            by the ECM to control engine operating parameters such as injector timing and injection duration.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1250705" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1111" filename="../figeg1/EG1111.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.27 - Hall Effect Sensor (Camshaft Position Sensor)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
