<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 4: SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - NO START - DRY
        RESERVOIR - PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>PROCEDURES</title>
        <para>"STARTED RAN APPROXIMATELY 15 SECONDS AND STALLED"</para>
        <para>This condition assumes that the reservoir was full when the engine start was attempted, the engine started
            normally and would die after 15 seconds of running.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refill the reservoir and verify the start and stall condition.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove, inspect and measure clearances in the engine lube oil pump (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252016">4.16</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). Upon removal of the lube oil pump inspect the mating front cover surface for gouging or deep
                scratching, inspect the oil pump for damage or wear. Measure the "G" rotor to oil pump housing
                clearance. Specification is 0.028" - 0.032" (0.72 - 0.81 mm). Measure from surface of housing to
                "G"rotor dimension. Specification is 0.001" - 0.003" (0..2 - 0.08 mm.)
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg7145" filename="../figeg7/eg7145.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.16 Lube Oil Pump Inspection and Measurements</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <para>"DID NOT START AND RESERVOIR WAS FOUND DRY"</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refill the reservoir and attempt to start the engine.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the engine does not start, perform the procedures on the Hard Start/No Start Diagnostic
                form. The tests on this form will discern if the essential elements required to start are present. (e.g.
                CMP camshaft position signal, battery voltage, fuel &#38; fuel pressure, ICP injection control pressure,
                etc.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the engine starts, the low reservoir problem may be caused by reservoir leak down after a
                prolonged period of not running.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Road test the vehicle for a minimum of 10 miles to assure that all air is purged from the
                injection control pressure system. Check oil level in reservoir to assure that it is full and let sit
                over night.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect oil level (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252017">4.17</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
                <emph type="bold"></emph>the next morning (prior to starting engine) to determine if leak down has
                occurred.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The only paths for leakage is past a check ball internal to the high pressure oil pump or
                through a porous reservoir or front cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Leakage past the check valve in the high pressure pump may be intermittent, the check valve
                internal to the pump is not serviceable. If the high pressure pump is suspect, replace it (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252018">4.18</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The IPR injection pressure regulator valve which is mounted in the pump will not cause a leak
                        down problem and does not require replacement when a high pressure pump is replaced.)
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Porosity through a reservoir or front cover casting is highly unlikely and if it does occur
                will probably be detected at very low miles. Leakage through a porous casting will also be diagnosed as
                a consistent problem and should not be a case of intermittent leak down. If porosity is suspected it is
                recommended to replace the reservoir first since it is far easier to replace than a front cover.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3179" filename="../figeg3/eg3179.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.17 Checking Oil Level in Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1252018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg7146" filename="../figeg7/eg7146.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.18 High Pressure Oil System (600 to 3000 PSI)</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_509.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_511.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
