<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 1: ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SECTION 1.9:
        DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION - OPERATOR ON DEMAND TESTS ENGINE OFF
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATOR ON DEMAND TESTS ENGINE OFF</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>STANDARD TEST (ENGINE OFF)</title>
            <para>"Engine Off Tests" are "Standard Tests" performed by the ECM. These tests are commanded by the
                operator using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or using the Self Test Input (STI) push-button switch.
                Since Injector Driver Module (IDM) faults are not stored in the ECM, it will be necessary to perform a
                self test to transmit faults from the IDM to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>To use the EST access the Engine menu and select Diagnostic Tests. Then select Engine Off Tests.
                Depressing the Enter key will initiate the test.
            </para>
            <para>To use the STI diagnostic push-button switch, depress the switch and hold in, while turning the
                ignition switch to the "ON" position. Release the STI button after the key is in the "ON" position.
                <emph type="bold">Do not start the engine.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the operator signals the test to begin, the ECM will perform internal tests of its processing
                components and internal memory.
            </para>
            <para>It will automatically proceed to Output Circuit Check (OCC). This will operate the ECM output
                circuits. It will measure each individual circuit's response. The following circuits are checked by the
                ECM during the test:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Cylinder identification</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Pressure Regulator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Crank Inhibit (relay)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Glow Plug Control (relay)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injector Driver Module (relay)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Glow Plug Light</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel Demand Command Signal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine to Transmission Data Line (EDL relay).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>The ECM will monitor the outputs and test the operation of the output signals and actuators. If a
                circuit fails the test, a fault code will be logged.
            </para>
            <para>When the test is complete, the EST will display any faults that were found during the test. If the STI
                diagnostic switch was used, the faults will be transmitted as "Flash Codes," using the Oil Warning and
                Engine Warning lights.
            </para>
            <para>The fault codes are read by counting the number of light flashes. The following sequence occurs:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The
                        <emph type="bold">"Oil/Water"</emph>light will flash one time. This indicates the beginning of
                        Active fault codes.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The
                        <emph type="bold">"WARN ENGINE"</emph>light will flash repeatedly signaling the active fault
                        codes. All codes are three digits. The number of flashes should be counted in sequence.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>At the end of each digit of the code there will be a short pause. Three flashes and a pause
                        indicates the number 3. The code 232 will be sent as two flashes, (a pause), three flashes, (a
                        pause), and two flashes.
                    </para>
                    <para>If there is more than one code being sent, the
                        <emph type="bold">"OIL/WATER"</emph>light will flash once indicating the beginning of another
                        active fault code. The code 111 indicates "NO FAULTS".
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>If no further Active fault codes exist, the
                <emph type="bold">"OIL/WATER"</emph>light will flash twice, indicating the beginning of "INACTIVE
                CODES". The
                <emph type="bold">"WARN ENGINE "</emph>light will then flash the "INACTIVE CODE"(s) present. If several
                "INACTIVE CODES" are present, the
                <emph type="bold">"OIL/WATER"</emph>light will flash once between each of the fault codes.
            </para>
            <para>When all of the stored fault codes have been sent, the
                <emph type="bold">"OIL/WATER"</emph>light will flash three times indicating "END OF MESSAGE".
            </para>
            <para>If it is necessary to repeat transmission of fault codes, press the STI button and all stored codes
                will be retransmitted as described previously.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_52.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_54.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
