<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTION CONTROL
        PRESSURE (ICP) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_316.xml" xrefid="ef12518108">3.115</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="e125_316.xml" xrefid="ef12518109">3.116</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM continuously monitors the signal of the ICP sensor to determine if the signal is within an
                expected range. If the signal voltage is higher or lower than expected, the ECM will set a fault code.
                The ECM will then ignore the ICP sensor signal and will use a preset value determined by engine
                operating conditions. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will become an Inactive code.
            </para>
            <para>ICP faults can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or by reading the flash codes from the
                warning light using the STI diagnostic switch located on the vehicle dash.
            </para>
            <para>If the ignition key is shut off, the code will become an Inactive code. ICP codes will cause the
                Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 124 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 4 - ICP SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            <para>An out of range low code 124 will be set by the ECM if the signal voltage is less than .039 volts for
                more than 1.0 seconds.
            </para>
            <para>Code 124 may be set due to an open or short to ground on the signal circuit, a defective sensor or an
                open VREF circuit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 125 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 3 - ICP SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            <para>An out of range high code 125 will be set by the ECM if the signal voltage is greater than 4.9 volts
                for more than 1.0 seconds.
            </para>
            <para>Code 125 may be set by an open return circuit, short to a voltage source on the ICP signal circuit or
                a defective sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 332 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 13 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE ABOVE SPECIFICATION WITH ENGINE
                OFF
            </title>
            <para>Code 332 will be set by the ECM, if the signal from the ICP sensor is higher than expected with the
                engine not running. If the ECM detects this fault, the ECM will ignore the ICP signal and will operate
                the IPR with fixed values determined from engine operating conditions.
            </para>
            <para>Code 332 may be caused by a defective sensor or a biased circuit.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_313.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_315.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
