<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - SPEEDOMETER SIGNAL
        - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Signal (VSS) from the VPM is sent over the DCL data link to the ECM. The VSS
                information is used by the ECM to control features such as: Cruise Control, PTO, Torque Level Tailoring
                and Road Speed Limiting.
            </para>
            <para>The VPM also provides VSS input to the vehicle speedometer, tachometer and odometer unit located in
                the instrument panel.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_435.xml" xrefid="ef12518174">3.181</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk document="e125_437.xml" xrefid="ef12518177">3.184</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="e125_438.xml" xrefid="ef12518178">3.185</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) for the following discussion.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VEHICLE SPEED SENSOR (303)</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) is located on the transmission and sends an AC signal to the VPM. The
                VSS sensor contains a permanent magnet which creates a magnetic field. The AC signal is created when the
                16-tooth transmission speedometer gear rotates breaking the magnetic field created by the sensor. The
                VSS signal is sent through the engine and cab harness to the VPM.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, Navistar installs the speed sensor at the rear of the transmission. With
                an Allison AT/MT transmission, Allison installs the sensor at the lower right side of the transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VPM (VEHICLE PERSONALITY MODULE)</title>
            <para>The VPM (381) receives the AC signal from the vehicle speed sensor. The VPM programming includes the
                rear axle ratio and tire size. It uses this programmed information and the speed sensor input to create
                the vehicle speed signal sent to the Speedometer Unit.
            </para>
            <para>From VPM connector (381), terminal 18, an analog AC signal is input on circuit 47B to the vehicle
                speedometer unit through connector (27). Speedometer ground circuit 47-G from connector (27) is grounded
                at the cab ground stud.
            </para>
            <para>The VSS signal is also formatted so that it can be sent over the Digital Communications Link (DCL) to
                the ECM (379).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_430.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_432.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
