<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 5.2 PRO-LINK 9000 ELECTRONIC SERVICE TOOL OPERATION -
        SERVICE TOOL FUNCTIONS - SNAPSHOT
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>SNAPSHOT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Snapshot allows the technician to record data from the Data List, for review. This can be helpful for
                collecting data while driving the truck or for searching for an intermittent problem.
            </para>
            <para>The following functions are available for Snapshot:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Quick Trigger</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trigger Setup</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Data Update Rate</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Review Snapshot</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Quick Trigger</title>
            <para>The Quick Trigger function enables the technician to take a second Snapshot quickly, using the
                previous setting established during Trigger Setup for the first Snapshot. It is not necessary to reset
                the setup values for each Snapshot. Press the
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                key and the data is displayed on the Pro-Link screen.
            </para>
            <para>The Quick Trigger default trigger is Any Numeric Key. Press any numeric key on the Pro-Link keypad to
                start recording data. Press any numeric key again to stop recording data.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Trigger Setup</title>
            <para>Trigger Setup allows the technician to configure how and when Snapshot triggers. Selecting this option
                displays the screen in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252227">5.44</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252227" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl032" filename="../figpl0/pl032.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.44 - Pro-link Trigger Setup Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Four choices are available for Snapshot triggering.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Any Numeric Key</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Any Code</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Specific PID</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Specific SID</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Any Numeric Key</title>
            <para>Choosing this option requires the technician to press any numeric key on the Pro-Link keypad to
                activate the trigger.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Specific Code, PID and SID</title>
            <para>When selecting a Specific Code, PID or SID a screen is displayed which enables the technician to
                choose the Code, PID or SID to trigger on from a list of those choices.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Setting Memory Trigger Point</title>
            <para>Selecting any of the Trigger Setup options presents the display in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252228">5.45</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252228" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl033" filename="../figpl0/pl033.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.45 - Pro-link Trigger Setup Option Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NO</emph>
                is the default. To adjust the trigger point, use the "&#8592;" key to select
                <emph type="bold">YES</emph>, then press
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>. Selecting YES present the screen in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252229">5.46</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252229" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl034" filename="../figpl0/pl034.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.46 - Pro-link Adjust Trigger Point Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Use the &#8592; &#8594; keys on the Pro-Link keypad to adjust the location of "T" along the line, then
                press
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>to accept this position . When the trigger occurs, all data to the right
                of "T" was received after the trigger occurred or towards the end of the Snapshot, Data to the left of
                "T" was received before the trigger occurred or towards the beginning of the Snapshot.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Processing the Trigger</title>
            <para>After defining all the setup functions, pressing the
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                key presents the prompt on the screen,
                <emph type="bold">"WAITING FOR TRIGGER"</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>The Pro-Link is now storing data from the ECM and waiting for the trigger condition to occur. When the
                trigger occurs, the prompt is displayed
                <emph type="bold">"PROCESSING TRIGGER"</emph>. The Pro-Link will record data in its memory buffer until
                full. When complete refer to
                <emph type="bold">"Review Snapshot"</emph>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Review Snapshot</title>
            <para>This function will only be displayed when there is Snapshot data in memory to view. The Snapshot
                should have been triggered previously and the data stored in memory (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252230">5.47</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252230" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl035" filename="../figpl0/pl035.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.47 - Pro-link Review Snapshot Data Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The "&#8593; &#8595;" keys are active and scroll the data up and down. The "&#8592; &#8594;" keys
                scroll the current frame number (C). Pressing any numeric key followed by pressing the
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                key reverts to that frame number. Entering a GOTO_ _ _ frame number greater than the number of frames in
                memory, reverts to the highest frame in memory. Pressing the
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                key without having pressed any other key presents the codes for that frame. Arrows appear on line four
                if there is more than one code. Pressing
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>again reverts back to the Review Snapshot Data List mode. Data Update
                Rate
            </para>
            <para>This selection gives the technician the ability to determine how often Snapshot data is updated in
                memory. As the time is increased, the delay between sampling frames is increased (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252231">5.48</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1252231" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl036" filename="../figpl0/pl036.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.48 - Pro-link Update Snapshot Data Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>On the numeric keypad of the Pro-link, type in the desired delay time from within the range of 0.1 to
                9.9 seconds, then press
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>. The screen automatically returns to the Snapshot Function Menu screen.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_556.xml" xrefid="ef1252232">5.49</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for an overview of the MPSI Pro-link service tool.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_554.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_556.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
