<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 4: SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - EXCESSIVE FUEL
        CONSUMPTION - PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PROCEDURES</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Review customer records and fueling procedures. Measurement errors are common. Fuel
                consumption taken only from one tank of use is susceptible to significant error because of filling
                procedures and vehicle application differences during operation. Accurate fuel consumption must be
                measured over time, preferably over four tanks of fuel with a record of what the vehicle was towing or
                doing during that time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loss of fuel economy is normal if winter fuels, kerosene or #1 diesel is being used.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Review vehicle specifications to determine if fuel consumption is normal for type of
                application and use of vehicle. (Compare consumption with similar vehicles in same application)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Conduct all tests on the Performance Diagnostic Sheet. These tests will test the following
                engine/chassis systems and determine if the following systems are functioning or if particular
                conditions are present. Intake and exhaust system, fuel delivery and filtration system, high pressure
                fuel system and injector operation, turbocharger and exhaust back pressure operation, oil aeration, base
                engine condition and electronic control system condition. If all tests are passed, the engine is
                operating normally.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_501.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_503.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
