<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 2.2: HARD START/NO START DIAGNOSTICS - T 444E ENGINE -
        HIGH PRESSURE LEAKAGE TESTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>HIGH PRESSURE LEAKAGE TESTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Isolate Right Cylinder Head</title>
            <para>Remove high pressure hose from the right cylinder head (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251124">2.24</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). Use an Aero Equip size 6 flare plug and install into the high pressure hose to block it off. Crank
                the engine and monitor the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) signal.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>THE ENGINE MAY START!</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the engine fails to start, refer to procedure on Isolating Left Cylinder Head. If the engine starts
                or the ICP pressure is now within specifications, the injection control pressure leak has been isolated
                to the right cylinder head.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove flare plug from the high pressure supply hose and reconnect hose to right
                    cylinder head.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve cover on right cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Crank the engine and inspect the injector body and bore area for leakage. If no leakage
                    is detected, perform ICP Leakage Test.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>oil is under high pressure</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <figure id="ef1251124" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3551" filename="../figeg3/eg3551.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.24 - Isolating Right Cylinder Head</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Isolate Left Cylinder Head</title>
            <para>Remove the plug (used to isolate the right cylinder head high pressure hose) and reconnect hose to
                cylinder head. Remove the high pressure hose from the left cylinder head. Remove the ICP sensor and
                assemble it to the ICP adapter. Install the ICP sensor/adapter onto the high pressure hose (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251125">2.25</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). Crank the engine and monitor the ICP signal.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the ICP pressure is not within specification proceed to IPR and High Pressure Pump Test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the engine starts, or the ICP pressure is now within specifications, the injection control pressure
                leak has been isolated to the left cylinder head. Reattach the left side high pressure hose. Remove left
                valve cover and crank the engine. Inspect the injector body and bore area for oil leakage. If no leakage
                is detected, perform ICP Leakage Test.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251125" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3552" filename="../figeg3/eg3552.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.25 - Isolating Left Cylinder Head</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IPR And High Press Pump Test</title>
            <para>If injection control pressure is still low after isolating both cylinder heads, leave the ICP sensor
                adapter in the left hose and reinstall the flare plug to block the right high pressure hose (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251126">2.26</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) and crank the engine. This has effectively deadheaded the high pressure pump. If pressure is still not
                developed, inspect the IPR (Injection Pressure Regulator) valve for debris and/or replace with a known
                good valve and retest. If pressure is still low, check the high pressure pump and drive gear. The gear
                may be loose or the pump may be defective.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251126" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3550" filename="../figeg3/eg3550.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.26 - IPR and High Pressure Pump Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_78.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_80.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
