<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE COOLANT
        TEMPERATURE (ECT) SENSOR - ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE SENSOR EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE SENSOR EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>Refer to the Sensor Circuit Diagram (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_269.xml" xrefid="ef1251879">3.86</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes an Engine Coolant Temperature sensor. The ECM measures the
                Engine Coolant Temperature signal and uses this information for Coolant Temperature Compensation and
                optional high temperature warning and shut down systems.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant temperature Compensation is used to protect the engine if the coolant temperature is too high.
                The ECM monitors the ECT signal to determine the coolant temperature. If the coolant reaches 214&#176;
                F(101&#176;C ), the ECM will reduce the fuel delivery by 6% for each Celsius degree of temperature
                increase. If the coolant temperature increases to 218&#176;F(104&#176;C), fuel quantity will be reduced
                3% for each Celsius degree of temperature increase. Coolant Temperature Compensation can be programmed
                to be inoperative in certain applications where full engine performance is required over the protection
                of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>On engines equipped with an engine warning system, the ECM will activate the audible warning alarm and
                illuminate the red Oil/Water warning light when the engine coolant temperature reaches 225&#176;F (107&#176;C).
            </para>
            <para>On engines equipped with an engine shut down system, the ECM will shut the engine off when the coolant
                temperature reaches 235&#176;F (112.5&#176;C). The vehicle operator may restart the engine by turning
                the ignition key "OFF" and then restarting it. Upon restart, the ECM will allow the engine to run for an
                additional 30 seconds, before shutting off the engine again.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Engine Coolant temperature sensor is a thermistor type sensor which changes resistance when
                exposed to different temperatures (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_270.xml" xrefid="ef1251880">3.87</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature of the coolant is decreased, the resistance of the thermistor increases which
                causes the signal voltage to increase. As the temperature of the coolant is increased the resistance of
                the thermistor decreases, which causes the signal voltage to decrease.
            </para>
            <para>The ECT sensor is supplied a regulated 5 volt reference voltage from ECM terminal 7. The sensor is
                grounded at terminal A through the signal return, terminal 46, at the ECM. As the coolant temperature
                increases or decreases, the sensor changes resistance and provides the ECM with the coolant temperature
                signal voltage at terminal 7 of the ECM. This signal voltage is then read by the ECM to determine the
                temperature of the coolant.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_266.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_268.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
