<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - CRUISE CONTROL,
        PTO, HAND THROTTLE SYSTEM - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>Cruise control and PTO operation (including remote PTO) share many circuits and components, so both
            systems are included in this description.
        </para>
        <para>The Cruise/PTO system is controlled by the ECM in response to driver input on the Speed Control Command
            Switches (SCCS), which are the Cruise ON/OFF and SET/ RESUME switches. With a remote PTO operation, the body
            builder installed controls include a remote SET/RESUME switch and a PTO DISABLE switch that are also SCCS
            switches.
        </para>
        <para>The body builder also installs a Remote pedal sensor and switches to enable the remote PTO at a preset
            speed or enable in the variable mode, with engine speed controlled by the remote pedal sensor. These
            circuits will be discussed in Remote Pedal Sensor Circuits.
        </para>
        <para>The Clutch Pedal Switch supplies the Driveline Disengaged Signal (DDS) to the ECM and the Service Brake
            Switches supply a Brake Normally Open (BNO) and Brake Normally Closed (BNC) signal to the ECM. These signals
            indicate pedal positions and are used by the ECM in operating the Cruise/PTO Control System.
        </para>
        <para>The Vehicle Speed Signal (VSS) and CMP signal provide vehicle speed and engine rpm information that the
            ECM uses in controlling the Cruise/PTO system.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_359.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_361.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
