<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - VPM COMMUNICATIONS
        (DATA COMMUNICATIONS LINK, ATA LINK) - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM/VPM COMMUNICATION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes the Electronic Control Module (ECM), Vehicle Personality
                Module (VPM), and Injector Driver Module (IDM). Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251829">3.36</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The engine control system "communicates" with the Electronic Service Tool through connector (384) as
                shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251829">3.36</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                The EST communicates with the VPM using the American Trucking Association (ATA) data link lines(1).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM communicates with the VPM through a proprietary data link channel (DCL). The Data
                Communications Link (DCL) channel connects the ECM and the VPM.
            </para>
            <para>Both the ATA and DCL circuits use twisted wire pairs. All repairs to these pairs must maintain one
                complete twist per inch along the entire length of the circuits. These circuits are polarized (one
                positive and one negative) and reversing the polarity of these circuits will disrupt communications.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">(1)</emph>
                - The ATA data link is defined by SAE recommended practices J1708 and J1587. This link and connector
                (384) were adopted by the Recommended Practices 1201 and 1202.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATA COMMUNICATIONS</title>
            <para>Refer to the circuit diagram (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_178.xml" xrefid="ef1251830">3.37</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) for the following discussion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATA DATA LINK CONNECTOR (384)</title>
            <para>All communications between the EST (Prolink 9000TM using the Navistar cartridge) and the engine
                control system is done through the EST connector (384). This communications link supports:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Displaying fault codes and operating conditions on the EST.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Performing proprietary diagnostic tests programmed into the cartridge.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clearing fault codes.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Programming performance parameter values.</para>
                    <para>EST connector (384) has six pins, labeled A through F,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251829">3.36</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        that provide the following:
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>Fused BATTERY power is provided to Pin "C" to provide battery power for electronic service
                        tools. Pin "E" provides a battery ground for the EST.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connector (384) terminal A is connected by circuit 98B(+) to the positive RED ATA bus and EST
                        connector (384) terminal B is connected by circuit 98D(-) to the negative BLUE (428) bus. These
                        two connections allow communication with all components connected to the data link at these same
                        two busses.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="ef1251829" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg7031" filename="../figeg7/EG7031.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.36 - ATA and DCL Communication</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE ATA DATA LINKS</title>
            <para>The RED Positive and BLUE Negative Data Link Busses connect the EST connector (384) and the VPM (381).
                They are also the connection point for other electronic components that require access to the engine
                control system through the ATA communications link.
            </para>
            <para>The RED positive bus (427) is connected by circuit 98A(+) to the VPM at connector (381), terminal 11.
                The BLUE negative bus (428) is connected by circuit 98C(-) to the VPM at connector (381), terminal 12.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DCL COMMUNICATION LINKS</title>
            <para>The VPM is connected to the ECM through the DCL. The DCL connection between the ECM and the VPM serves
                as a conduit for data sent on the ATA to be shared with the ECM. Communications between the ECM and the
                EST connector go through the VPM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VPM - ECM COMMUNICATIONS</title>
            <para>The positive (+) DCL link is circuit 97AS, which connects ECM connector (379) terminal 28, to the VPM
                through connector (381), terminal 13. The negative (-) DCL link is circuit 97AT, which connects ECM
                connector (379), terminal 9 to the VPM through connector (381), terminal 14. These two circuits (97AS
                and 97AT) are a twisted wire pair and pass through dash connector (3) at terminals 8 and 1.
            </para>
            <para>Both the ATA and DCL circuits use twisted wire pairs. All repairs to these wire pairs must maintain
                one complete twist per inch along the entire length of the circuits. Both circuits are polarized (one
                positive and one negative) and reversing the polarity of the circuit will disrupt communications.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_175.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_177.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
