<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 2.2: HARD START/NO START DIAGNOSTICS - T 444E ENGINE - ICP
        LEAKAGE TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>ICP LEAKAGE TEST</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title></title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect all high pressure oil lines disconnected in the process of isolating the
                    cylinder head which is causing a loss of ICP pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the high pressure supply line of the suspect leaking cylinder head at the high
                    pressure pump
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251127">2.27</hotlnk>.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a regulated air supply
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251128">2.28</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    to the high pressure supply oil line removed in the previous step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 100 psi of pressure from the regulated air source and inspect for leakage around
                    the injectors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the fuel lines removed from the fuel regulator block, inspect for oil leakage out
                    of each of the disconnected fuel lines. If oil is seeping out of the disconnected fuel lines remove
                    all injectors in the cylinder head being tested and inspect injectors for worn "O" rings or obvious
                    damage.
                </para>
                <para>If leakage is observed at an injector, remove and inspect injector for obvious damage or worn
                    "O"rings.
                </para>
                <para>If no leakage is present, perform Injector "Buzz" test with air pressure still applied. Observe
                    oil discharge from each of the injectors. Oil discharge should be equal from all injectors. If
                    excess oil is discharged from an injector(s), the injector(s) may be defective.
                </para>
                <para>If it is difficult to determine which injector(s) are leaking remove air supply and regulator from
                    the high pressure oil supply hose and:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">a. Connect an
                        <emph type="bold">automotive cylinder leak tester</emph>to the high pressure supply hose and
                        apply air pressure via the cylinder leak tester.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">b. Conduct an Injector "Buzz" test and observe the percent cylinder leakage while
                        each injector is activated. Remove and inspect injectors which exhibit a greater amount of
                        leakage compared to the others.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">c. If none of the injectors indicate an excessive amount of leakage, remove all
                        injectors. Inspect all "O" rings for wear and damage. All "O" rings should be replaced.
                    </para>
                    <para>If oil was entering the fuel system, drain fuel tanks and dispose of the contaminated fuel
                        properly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="ef1251127" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3735" filename="../figeg3/EG3735.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.27 - High Pressure Pump Oil Outlet Locations</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1251128" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg3733" filename="../figeg3/EG3733.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.28 - ICP Leakage Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes:</title>
            <para>Low injection pressure (voltage) indicates the injectors are not receiving sufficient oil pressure to
                properly operate the fuel injectors. This may be caused by:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>No oil in engine.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil reservoir leak down (possibly through high pressure pump check valve.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective high pressure pump</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injector "O" ring leak.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injector body leak.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IPR valve stuck open.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pump drive gear loose or damaged.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required:</title>
            <para>DVOM, ICP sensor breakout "T" (ZTSE-4347), ICP adapter and an Aero Equip size 6 flare plug.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supplemental Diagnostics</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor diagnostics, in Electronic Control System Diagnostics, Section
                        3.5.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_79.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_81.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
