<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - CAMSHAFT POSITION
        (CMP) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to CMP Circuit Diagnostics (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_172.xml" xrefid="ef1251826">3.33</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) for the following paragraphs.
            </para>
            <para>Once the ECM has recognized the narrow vane (wide window) it will synchronize the engine firing order
                to the timing of the CMP signal. Every 2 crankshaft revolutions it will verify that synchronization. If
                the ECM receives too many or too few pulses for the number of engine revolutions, it will set a fault
                code.
            </para>
            <para>The engine will not operate without a functioning CMP signal. However, the ECM will attempt to
                determine the cause of an invalid signal and identify it with a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>CMP codes that are set will become inactive codes if the key is turned off. These codes can be
                retrieved using the Self Test Input (STI) switch/(Engine Diagnostics switch) located on the vehicle
                dashboard or the Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>143 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</emph>
                - WRONG # OF CMP SIGNAL TRANSITIONS PER CAM REVOLUTION
            </title>
            <para>Code 143 indicates the ECM has received CMP signals with the wrong number of transitions. This
                indicates that the ECM has counted the voltage transitions and found less than the specified number of
                pulses from the sensor. When this problem is continuous, the engine will stop running and the ECM will
                log an active code. If the key is shut off, the code will become an inactive code. This code will not
                turn the warning light on.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for code 143: Intermittent CMP signal caused by an intermittent circuit, defective
                Camshaft Position Sensor, or incorrect CMP sensor to timing disk clearance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>144
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</emph>
                - CMP SIGNAL NOISE DETECTED
            </title>
            <para>Code 144 indicates that the ECM has detected voltage spikes or transitions other than the CMP signal.
                If this problem is continuous the engine could stop running and the ECM will log an active code. If the
                key is shut off, the code will become an inactive code. This code will not cause the warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
            <para>Code 144 may be due to: Poor ground connections for CMP or other electronic components. Wire harness
                shielding missing or incorrectly installed on the engine harness. Outside components that could induce
                voltage signals.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>145 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 12</emph>
                - CMP SIGNAL INACTIVE WHILE ICP HAS INCREASED
            </title>
            <para>Flash code 145 indicates that the ECM does not detect a CMP signal. This code would be set if the
                engine was rotating and the ECM detected a rise in ICP pressure, but did not detect a CMP signal. To set
                this code the engine must be rotated long enough for the ICP to increase. When this code is set the
                engine will not operate. This code will not cause the warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for flash code 145: Defective CMP sensor, faulty sensor circuitry, or improper air gap
                between sensor and camshaft timing disk.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>612 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 7</emph>
                - INCORRECT ECM INSTALLED FOR CMP TIMING DISK
            </title>
            <para>Flash code 612 indicates that the ECM has monitored the CMP signal and the signal is incorrect for the
                programming in the ECM. This means that the ECM does not recognize the signal generated from the timing
                disk and CMP sensor.
            </para>
            <para>When this condition exists, the ECM does not send a Fuel Demand Command Signal (FCDS) to the Injector
                Drive Module (IDM). The engine cannot operate without a FDCS signal from the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: ECM has been accidently replaced with an incorrect ECM for the particular engine
                application. (For example, the timing disk for the V-8 (T444E) and the I-6 are different and generate a
                different signal. An ECM from an I-6 engine will not run a V-8 (T444E) engine). Incorrect signal due to
                a defective CMP sensor or incorrect air gap between the CMP sensor and the timing disk.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_169.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_171.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
