<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 1: ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SECTION 1.5:
        ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE - OPERATION AND FUNCTION - III. MICROPROCESSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>III. MICROPROCESSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ECM contains an internal microprocessor. The processor stores operating instructions (control
                strategies) and tables of values (calibration parameters). It compares these stored instructions and
                values to sensed input values to determine the correct operating strategy for any given engine
                condition. Calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds referred to as the foreground
                and the background calculations. These calculations are performed on a continuous closed loop basis.
            </para>
            <para>The foreground calculations occur at a much faster rate than the background calculations. These are
                normally the more critical functions to engine operation or they occur at a faster rate. Such as engine
                speed control. Background calculations are normally things that occur at a slower pace such as engine
                temperature.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic strategies (instructions) are also programmed into the ECM. Some instructions cause inputs
                or outputs to be monitored on a continuous basis and will flag a code that will be set, other strategies
                will instruct the ECM to perform certain tests upon operator demand.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM's microprocessor is equipped with three types of memory Random Access Memory (RAM), Read Only
                Memory (ROM) and Keep Alive Memory (KAM) (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1250504">1.17</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). They allow the processor to store the necessary instructions, calibration tables and input values to
                control the engine.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="underscr">ROM</emph>:
            </title>
            <para>Read Only Memory is the memory where calibration tables and operating strategies are stored.
                Information in the ROM is permanent. It can not be changed or lost by turning the engine off or
                disconnecting the batteries.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="underscr">RAM</emph>:
            </title>
            <para>Random Access Memory is a temporary storage memory for current events such as current engine
                temperature or current speed, pedal position etc. It is the memory to which information is temporarily
                stored so that it can be compared to the information in the ROM. Unlike the Rom memory, the RAM is lost
                every time the key is turned off or when power is interrupted to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="underscr">KAM</emph>:
            </title>
            <para>Keep Alive Memory is a permanent memory. It is used to store diagnostic faults (codes). Adaptive
                strategies (temporary operating instructions) can also be written to it in event of a system failure or
                as a compensation for component wear. Uninterrupted power must be supplied from the battery to the ECM
                on a continuous basis to keep KAM memory alive. All information in KAM is lost if the ECM has a total
                power loss such as when the batteries are disconnected.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1250504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1101" filename="../figeg1/EG1101.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.17 - Electronic Control Module Microprocessor Memory</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
