<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 5.3: MULTIMETER USE - 12-VOLT TEST LIGHTS</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>12-VOLT TEST LIGHTS</title>
        <para>The 12-volt test light tests for voltage in a circuit between the point being tested and ground
            <emph type="bold">(Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252314">5.63</hotlnk>).
            </emph>
            If there is no glow in the bulb, the circuit is open and no current is flowing.
        </para>
        <para>Once a technician becomes familiar with the test light and the brilliance of the bulb in a normal circuit,
            high-resistance circuits can be recognized by the dimming effect that they have on the test light bulb. As
            the current drops in a high-resistance circuit, the bulb will glow less brightly. Although using a 12-volt
            test light cannot be used as a fool-proof test for high resistance, a less than normal brilliance of the
            test light is an indication of circuit high resistance. Further testing will verify the condition and locate
            the cause.
        </para>
        <para>The 12-volt test light continuity tester depends on the vehicle battery to power the circuit under test.
            Twelve-volt testers are available with a variety of tips to permit touching them to connectors, bare wires,
            insulated wires or even wires within wiring harnesses
            <emph type="bold">(Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252315">5.64</hotlnk>)
            </emph>
            . To check the tester before use, briefly touch the clip to one post of the battery and the other to the
            opposite post. Twelve-volt testers are not sensitive to polarity and can be connected either way.
        </para>
        <para>The 12-volt test light generally has a sharp probe tip so it can be inserted into connector terminals or
            through wire insulation for testing. It is important to keep the probe tip sharp to minimize damage to wire
            insulation. When the test is complete at a particular point, make sure to tape any holes made in wire
            insulation.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1252314" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg6136" filename="../figeg6/EG6136.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 5.63 - Troubleshooting Using 12-Volt Test Light</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="ef1252315" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg6137" filename="../figeg6/EG6137.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 5.64 - Typical 12-Volt Test Lights</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_573.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_575.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
