<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 1: ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SECTION 1.9:
        DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION - CONTINUOUS SELF TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CONTINUOUS SELF TEST</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CONTINUOUS MONITOR</title>
            <para>Diagnostics are performed by the Electronic Control Module (ECM) continuously to detect out of range,
                rationality and system faults.
            </para>
            <para>During the time that the key is "ON", if an input signal is "Out of Range" meaning the signal is
                either greater or lesser than what the signal range should be during normal operation, the ECM will
                record a "Fault". It will also monitor the operation of systems and will determine if the system is
                working within a normal range. If the ECM detects that a system falls outside a predetermined range, it
                will record and flag a fault.
            </para>
            <para>During normal engine operation, the ECM automatically performs several tests to detect faults. When it
                has detected a fault, the ECM often invokes a fault management strategy to allow continued, though
                sometimes degraded, vehicle operation.
            </para>
            <para>A "Fault" is an indication of a malfunction measured or monitored electronically. Sometimes "Faults"
                are referred to as "Codes."
            </para>
            <para>"Codes" are three digit numbers assigned to Faults to indicate the source of the malfunction. Most
                Codes will indicate the source and the "Mode" of failure. The "Failure Mode" will indicate the signal
                reading, IE.; "Out of Range High", "Out of Range Low" or in Range fault.
            </para>
            <para>During operation of the truck with the engine running, the Vehicle Personality Module (VPM) memory
                will record "EVENT ENGINE HOURS". This is the monitoring of engine operation exceeding programmed
                parameters. The standard Engine Event is Overspeed of the engine, referred to as Over RPM and excess
                coolant temperature. To retrieve information on Engine Events, it will be necessary to access them with
                the Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
            <para>If the engine is equipped with the optional engine warning/shutdown system, low oil pressure, and low
                coolant level operation, will also be monitored and recorded as "EVENT ENGINE HOURS".
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_51.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
