<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - CAMSHAFT POSITION
        (CMP) SENSOR - CAMSHAFT POSITION SENSOR (CMP) EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAMSHAFT POSITION SENSOR (CMP) EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to circuit diagram (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_171.xml" xrefid="ef1251825">3.32</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) for the following discussion.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP). This sensor provides the
                Electronic Control Module (ECM) with a signal that indicates camshaft position and engine speed.
            </para>
            <para>The CMP sensor signal is used by the ECM to synchronize piston position to injector firing sequence.
                The injector firing order sequence begins when the ECM detects the narrow vane on the timing disk
                indicating #1 cylinder. Engine position for each cylinder is then continuously calculated as each vane
                on the timing disk passes by the CMP sensor. This information is processed by the ECM and used for
                injection timing and fuel delivery control. The ECM can then initiate the beginning of firing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Camshaft Position Sensor is a Hall Effect type sensor that generates a digital frequency as
                windows on the timing disk pass through the magnetic field. The frequency of the windows passing by the
                sensor as well as the width of selected windows allows the ECM to detect engine speed and position. When
                the narrow vane passes the CMP sensor the signal on time is less than when the other vanes pass the
                sensor. This produces a signal that the ECM uses to indicate engine position.
            </para>
            <para>Engine speed is detected by the ECM by counting the frequency of the 24 signal pulses for each
                camshaft revolution.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_168.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_170.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
