<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE COOLANT
        TEMPERATURE (ECT) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to ECT Sensor Diagnostics (Figure ) for the following discussion.</para>
            <para>With the ignition key "ON", the ECM continuously monitors the ECT circuit for expected voltages. If
                the signal voltage is less than or more than expected the ECM will set a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>If the ECM detects a fault in the ECT signal, the ECM will disregard the signal and default to a
                temperature of 180&#176;F (82&#176;C) for engine running operation and -4&#176;F (-20&#176;C) for
                starting the engine. If the fault is no longer present, the ECM will once again return to normal
                operation using the ECT signal for processing.
            </para>
            <para>Faults in the ECT signal can be retrieved using the Self Test Input Switch (STI) or the Electronic
                Service Tool. If the fault is no longer present, it will be stored as an Inactive Code.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 114 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 4 - ECT: OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            <para>An out of range low code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage less than .127 volts for more than
                0.1 seconds. If this fault is Active, the ECM will use the default value of 180&#176;F (82&#176;C).
            </para>
            <para>Code 114 may be caused by a short to ground or a shorted or biased sensor.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 115 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 3 - ECT: OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            <para>An out of range high code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage greater than 4.6 volts for more
                than 0.1 seconds. If this fault is Active, the ECM will use the a default value of 180&#176;F (82&#176;C).
            </para>
            <para>Code 115 may be caused by an open circuit, an open sensor, or a short to another voltage source.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 316 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 1 - ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE UNABLE TO REACH COMMANDED
                SETPOINT
            </title>
            <para>Code 316 will only be set with engines that have the Cold Ambient Protection (CAP) System enabled.
                This code will be set after the engine has run for greater than 120 minutes and has not exceeded 147&#176;F
                (75&#176;C) for vehicles with manual transmissions and 140&#176;F (60&#176;C) for vehicles with
                automatic transmissions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This code only indicates that the engine has not been able to reach operating temperature. It
                        does not indicate an electronic fault.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Possible causes of code 316: Extended idle time, cold ambient temperatures, (may require use of winter
                front), thermostat stuck open, mis-plumbed cooling system (thermostat bypass bypassed), auxiliary heater
                cores cooling off engine (school bus applications or fan clutch locked on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 321 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 0 - ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE - ABOVE WARNING LEVEL</title>
            <para>Code 321 will be set if the ECM detects engine coolant temperature above 225&#176;F (107&#176;C). When
                this occurs, the ECM illuminates the OIL/WATER warning light and sounds the audible alarm (if equipped),
                alerting the operator that a potential for engine damage exists.
            </para>
            <para>If the temperature drops below 225&#176;F(107&#176;C), the code will become inactive and the ECM will
                return to normal operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 322 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 7 - ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE ABOVE - CRITICAL LEVEL</title>
            <para>Code 322 will be set if the ECM detects engine coolant temperature above 235&#176;F (112.5&#176;C).
                When this occurs, the OIL/WATER warning light illuminates and the audible alarm sounds (if equipped)
                will alert the operator that the temperature is increasing (having set code 321) indicating a potential
                for engine damage. With code 322 active, the engine will shut down. At the same time the code and
                current engine hours will be recorded in the VPM as an Engine Event.
            </para>
            <para>If the temperature drops below 235&#176;F (112.5&#176;C), the code will become inactive and the ECM
                will return to normal operation. Should the engine shut down, it can be restarted to move the vehicle to
                a safe place.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 325 - ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 14 - POWER REDUCED, MATCHED TO COOLING - SYSTEM PERFORMANCE
            </title>
            <para>Code 325 will be set if the cooling system temperature exceeds 214&#176;F (101&#176;C ). At this
                temperature the ECM will reduce the fuel delivered to the engine at or near the maximum demand level.
                For each one Celsius degree of temperature the fuel will be reduced 6%. This reduces the heat produced
                by the engine thereby reducing the burden on the engine cooling system. It will also slow the vehicle
                speed encouraging the operator to downshift, thus increasing the efficiency of the cooling system.
            </para>
            <para>As the temperature is reduced the compensation level is reduced until the temperature drops below 214&#176;F
                (101&#176;C ) at which normal operation is resumed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_267.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_269.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
