<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - KEEP ALIVE MEMORY
        POWER AND VPM BATTERY POWER CIRCUIT - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>During normal vehicle operation, the ECM performs certain tests. When the key is turned ON, the ECM
                performs the Start-Up KAM Test to test its Keep-Alive Memory. The test is performed once each time the
                key is turned on or when the ECM resets.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM performs a test to determine if the memory is working properly, but a lack of battery power to
                ECM terminal 1 can cause fault code(s) 224 and 653 to be set.
            </para>
            <para>When power to KAM has been disrupted, there will be no inactive faults.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE 224</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">SID 254 FMI 2</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">ECM:</emph>KAM CORRUPT
            </title>
            <para>Flash Code 224 can be caused by:</para>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>Short or open in KAM circuit. High or low voltage to ECM terminal 1 from the KAM battery
                        supply circuits will cause code 224.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note that if the battery cable has been disconnected, on the next key ON cycle, code 224 will
                        be present, indicating that the KAM memory has lost power. The code will change to inactive
                        status on the next key cycle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Faulty KAM memory in the ECM.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Conditions causing Flash Code 224 can also cause Flash Code 615 to occur.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE 615</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">SID 254 FMI 13</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">ECM:</emph>PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETER KAM CORRUPT FAULT
            </title>
            <para>If flash code 615 occurs when the KAM power supply to the ECM is good, then the KAM memory is
                defective. Refer to Electronic Control Module Diagnostics (ECM) in this manual section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_343.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_345.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
