<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTION PRESSURE
        REGULATOR (IPR) - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_339.xml" xrefid="ef12518124">3.131</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="e125_339.xml" xrefid="ef12518125">3.132</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the Injection Control Pressure while the engine is in operation. If the actual
                pressure is greater or less than the desired pressure, the ECM will set a fault code. When this occurs,
                the ECM will ignore the ICP sensor and control the engine using pre programmed values for the IPR.
            </para>
            <para>The Electronic Service Tool is used to Perform the Engine Running Standard Test which enables the ECM
                to vary the command signal to the IPR and monitor the performance of the Injection Control Pressure
                system. If the system does not respond within the specified parameters, the ECM will set a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>Fault codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or the Self Test Input diagnostic
                switch located on the vehicle dash. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will be stored as an
                Inactive code.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 241 - ATA CODE SID 42 FMI 11 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE REG. OCC SELF TEST FAILED
            </title>
            <para>Code 241 is set only during the Engine Off Standard Output Circuit Check. This test indicates the ECM
                has performed an output circuit test, measured voltage drop across the IPR circuit and determined it is
                below or above specification.
            </para>
            <para>If this fault is present, the engine will not run. The ECM will not illuminate the Engine Warning
                light if this code is active, however, this code will be transmitted at the completion of the Output
                Circuit Check, using the STI switch or the Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Open feed circuit or fuse to the IPR, open IPR solenoid, or an open or shorted IPR
                signal circuit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 331 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 0 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE - ABOVE SYSTEM WORKING RANGE
            </title>
            <para>Code 331 indicates the ECM has detected injection control pressure greater than 3675 PSI (25 MPA)
                which is greater than the maximum allowable working pressure.
            </para>
            <para>When this code is active, the ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light.</para>
            <para>Possible causes: Incorrect ICP signal due to faulty circuits or sensor, grounded IPR signal circuit, a
                malfunction in the injection control pressure system or a sticking or blocked IPR valve. Refer to
                Injection Control Pressure system diagnostics in Section 2.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 333 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 10 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE ABOVE/BELOW DESIRED LEVEL
            </title>
            <para>Code 333 may be set during normal engine operation through the continuous monitor function or during
                the Engine Running Standard Test. It indicates the measured pressure does not match the expected value.
                The ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>When this code is active, the ECM will ignore the ICP sensor signal and will control the IPR from
                programmed values to keep the engine operating. Perform ICP sensor diagnostics to determine if the
                problem exists in the ICP sensor/circuit. If diagnostic testing indicates the ICP sensor/circuit is
                functioning properly, perform additional diagnostic tests on the injection control pressure system.
                Refer to Injection Control Pressure system diagnostics in Section 2.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Incorrect ICP signal due to circuit or sensor malfunctions. IPR signal circuit may be
                grounded or contain excessive resistance. The IPR valve may be sticking or blocked. Injection control
                pressure system may not be functioning properly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 334 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 7 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE UNABLE TO REACH SETPOINT-POOR
                PERFORMANCE
            </title>
            <para>Code 334 indicates an injection control system response time fault and may be set during normal engine
                operation through the continuous monitor function or during the Engine Running Standard Test.
            </para>
            <para>While the driver of the vehicle rapidly presses his foot down on the accelerator pedal, the ECM
                compares the actual vs the desired injection control pressure and looks for a large pressure difference
                (1300 PSI/9MPA) for a short period of time (3 seconds). If the injection control system does not respond
                quick enough Code 334 will be set and the Engine Warning Lamp will be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible Causes: Low oil level, contaminated engine oil or aerated oil. Trapped air in the injection
                control pressure system (particularly after an injector or high pressure pump replacement). Defective or
                stuck Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR). Intermittent IPR valve wiring connection-spread IPR harness
                terminals at IPR valve, poorly crimped terminals or pulled back pin. Leaking injector "O" rings. Problem
                with ICP sensor and sensor circuit, system biased high or low. Refer to Injection Control Pressure
                system diagnostics in Section 2.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 335 - ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 1 - INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE UNABLE TO BUILD PRESSURE DURING
                CRANKING
            </title>
            <para>Code 335 indicates the ECM has determined that the injection control pressure system has failed to
                build a pressure of at least 725 PSI/5 MPA during a programmed period of engine cranking time which will
                vary with engine temperature.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Engine cranking speed must be greater than 130 RPM before fault detection begins.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Possible Causes: No oil in engine. Air in the injection control pressure system (particularly after an
                injector or high pressure pump replacement). Defective or stuck IPR regulator. Leaking injector "O"
                rings. Loose high pressure pump gear. Defective high pressure oil pump.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_336.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_338.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
