<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 2.2: HARD START/NO START DIAGNOSTICS - T 444E ENGINE - EST
        TOOL-DATA LIST
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>EST TOOL-DATA LIST</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Table
                    <hotlnk xrefid="et1251109">2.11</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the EST Tool-Data List of the diagnostic form.
            </para>
            <table id="et1251109">
                <title>Table 2.11 - EST Tool - Data List</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="144p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="144p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="144p"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="3" spanname="S1T3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">FROM FORM EGED - 130 - 1</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">8. EST TOOL - DATA LIST</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>&#8226; Select and enter the following data as the first three lines in a custom
                                    data list
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>&#8226; Monitor the data while cranking the engine for 20 seconds minimum</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Data</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Bat. voltage</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>7 volts min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Eng. RPM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>100 RPM min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>ICP pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>800 PSI min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>&#x25A1; If voltage is low, proceed to Test 9a.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>&#x25A1; If no RPM is noted, recheck fault codes and proceed to Test 9b.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S1T3">
                                <para>&#x25A1; If ICP pressure is low, refer to diagnostic manual EGES - 125 - 1 for
                                    system leakage tests
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if the components needed for starting are operating within specifications.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>TEST MUST BE PERFORMED WITH
                        <emph type="underscr">FULLY CHARGED BATTERIES.</emph>
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>To measure engine cranking speed, battery voltage, and Injection Control Pressure (ICP), it may be
                possible to read the data on the Electronic Service Tool (EST), "DATA LIST", while the engine is
                cranking. If the voltage drops below 7 volts while cranking, the EST tool will "RESET" back to start-up.
                If this happens, the tool cannot be used to perform this test.
                <emph type="bold">Refer to Test 9</emph>, "Testing Voltage, RPM and ICP individually"
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Turn all accessories and the ignition off, before connecting EST tool to ATA diagnostic
                        connector.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Connect the EST tool to the American Trucking Association (ATA) diagnostic connector. The connector is
                located on the lower left kick panel inside the cab. The screen of the reader should light up as soon as
                the tool is plugged in.
            </para>
            <para>Turn the ignition switch to the "ON" position.
                <emph type="bold">Do not start the engine.</emph>
                This will allow the EST to receive data from the electronic control components on the truck. If no data
                is received press
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                to retry. The information received will be data indicating the current status of the engine (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251117">2.17</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl008" filename="../figpl0/pl008.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.17- Pro-link Engine Status Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Press the "&#8595;" key until "BATT VOLTS" appears on the screen. Continue to press the "&#8595;" key
                until "BATT VOLTS", is at the top of the screen. Pressing the number
                <emph type="bold">"1"</emph>
                key, a block dot will appear on line number one.(&#x2043; ) (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251118">2.18</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl009" filename="../figpl0/pl009.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.18- Pro-link Battery Volts Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This will "Freeze the "BATT VOLTS" on line one. Now press the "&#8595;" key until "ENGINE RPM" appears
                on the second line of the screen. Press the number
                <emph type="bold">"2"</emph>
                key to freeze "ENGINE RPM" on line two of the screen (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251119">2.19</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251119" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl010" filename="../figpl0/pl010.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.19- Pro-link Engine RPM Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Continue to press the"&#8595;" key until "INJ CNTL PSI" is on the third line. Then press the number
                <emph type="bold">"3"</emph>
                key to freeze "INJ CNTL PSI" on line three (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1251120">2.20</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1251120" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="pl011" filename="../figpl0/pl011.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.20- Pro-link Injection Control PSI Screen</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The EST is now ready to read the data needed. Crank the engine while observing the data on the screen.
                If the EST recycles to the entry screen or shuts down, it will be necessary to measure the values
                separately. If this is required continue on to steps 9A through 9C. Record the data on the diagnostic
                form.
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage must be 7 or more volts. If the voltage to the Electronic Control Module (ECM)
                drops below 7 volts, the ECM will not remain powered up. If the ECM is not receiving power via the ECM
                relay, the engine cannot be started.
            </para>
            <para>Engine cranking RPM must be sufficient to generate the required Injection Control Pressure to operate
                the fuel injectors and to create enough compression heat to ignite the fuel.
            </para>
            <para>A "0" RPM indication on the Electronic Service Tool (EST) during engine cranking, indicates the ECM
                may not be receiving a signal from the Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor. Refer to CMP sensor diagnostics
                in Section 3.5 Electronic Control System Diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>If the CMP sensor is inoperative, it must be repaired before continuing. The ECM will not allow the
                Injector Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve to fully activate without a CMP signal.
            </para>
            <para>If injection control pressure is low, remove the inspection plug in top of the oil reservoir and
                recheck the oil level. (If the engine has not been operated for some time, the oil may have drained into
                the crankcase.) If oil level is low, fill the reservoir. If the oil level in the reservoir continues to
                decline, the engine may not be pumping oil to the reservoir.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TEST MUST BE PERFORMED WITH</emph>
                <emph type="underscr">FULLY CHARGED BATTERIES.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Low battery voltage. Due to "faulty" batteries, high resistance at battery cable connections
                        or in the wiring to the ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective ECM power relay.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blown 15A inline fuse (located in battery box) which supplies battery power (voltage) to
                        ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blown fuse F5 at ECM power relay control terminal 86.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low cranking RPM. May be caused by electrical system malfunctions, incorrect oil or extended
                        oil change intervals in cold ambient temperatures.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No engine RPM indication on EST while cranking the engine. CMP sensor or faulty circuitry to
                        the ECM may cause this condition. Recheck for fault codes after cranking engine. (Refer to Test
                        5 or 7).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A defective high pressure oil pump or pump drive will prevent proper injection control
                        pressure. A defective Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR), or electronic controls for the
                        regulator will cause low injection control pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <para>PRO-LINK 9000 (ZTSE-43661)</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supplemental Diagnostics</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Starting system diagnostics. Refer to Electrical section CTS-5110 of the Truck Service
                        Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low voltage at ECM. Refer to Electronic Control Module Power Supply (ECM PWR) in (Section 3.5)
                        Electronic Control System Diagnostics.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No Engine RPM indication during engine cranking. Refer to CMP sensor diagnostics in Electronic
                        Control System Diagnostics Section 3.5.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No Injection Control Pressure. Refer to Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor, IPR valve
                        diagnostics in Electronic Control System Diagnostics Section 3.5.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No injection control pressure and no electronic faults. - Refer to Test 9C.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If ICP pressure is low, refer to High Pressure Leakage Tests.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_74.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_76.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
