<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - VEHICLE
        PERSONALITY MODULE - VPM FUEL/HOURMETER AND ODOMETER FAULTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>VPM FUEL/HOURMETER AND ODOMETER FAULTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef12518171">3.178</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef12518171" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6091" filename="../figeg6/EG6091.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.178 - VPM Fuel/Hourmeter and Odometer</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The VPM (Vehicle Personality Module) records total engine hours (to 999,999 hours), total vehicle
                miles (to 9,999,999 miles) and total fuel used (to 9,999,999 gallons). While the vehicle is operating,
                the information is temporarily stored and every 30 minutes the information (new total hours, miles and
                gallons) is written to EEPROM memory locations in the VPM as new totals.
            </para>
            <para>The accumulator totals (engine hours, vehicle miles and total fuel used) can be read using the Prolink
                EST. Accumulator information may be useful for maintenance purposes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VPM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>If the VPM attempts to write the latest total (for any of the three totals) to one of eight EEPROM
                locations in the VPM and the memory location is defective, then the VPM sets Flash Code (634, 635 or
                641) and selects another memory location to store the information. Flash Code 645 may also be set.
            </para>
            <para>If the VPM can't find a serviceable memory location to write the data, then Flash Code 642, 643 or 644
                will be set.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 634 - ATA CODE PID 250 FMI 2 - VPM: FUEL METER MEMORY - LOCATION ERROR</title>
            <para>Flash code 634 indicates the first attempt to write the fuel totals encountered a defective memory
                location. The fuel totals logged may be inaccurate although the error will not be more than 1/2 hour use
                of fuel.
            </para>
            <para>If the fuel meter totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
                <emph type="bold">The next read/write error will result in all of the fuel meter data being lost</emph>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 635 - ATA CODE PID 247 FMI 2 - VPM: HOUR METER MEMORY LOCATION - ERROR</title>
            <para>Flash code 635 indicates the first attempt to write the engine hour totals encountered a defective
                memory location. The engine totals logged may be inaccurate although the error will not be more than one
                half an hour.
            </para>
            <para>If the hour meter totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
                <emph type="bold">The next read/write error will result in the hour meter data being lost</emph>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 641 - ATA CODE PID 245 FMI 2 - VPM: ODOMETER MEMORY LOCATION - ERROR</title>
            <para>Flash code 641 indicates the first attempt to write the vehicle total miles encountered a defective
                memory location. The total vehicle miles logged may be inaccurate, although the error will not be more
                than 30 miles.
            </para>
            <para>If the odometer totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
                <emph type="bold">The next read/write error will result in the odometer data being lost</emph>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 642 - ATA CODE PID 250 FMI 12 - VPM: FAULTY FUEL METER</title>
            <para>Flash code 642 indicates the write cycle of the EEPROM memory locations in the VPM have been exceeded.
                The fuel meter totals have been lost.
            </para>
            <para>If the fuel meter totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 643 - ATA CODE PID 247 FMI 12 - VPM: FAULTY HOUR METER</title>
            <para>Flash code 643 indicates the write cycle of the EEPROM memory locations in the VPM have been exceeded.
                The hour meter totals have been lost.
            </para>
            <para>If the hour meter totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 644 - ATA CODE PID 245 FMI 12 - VPM: FAULTY ODOMETER</title>
            <para>Flash code 644 indicates the write cycle of the EEPROM memory locations in the VPM have been exceeded.
                The Odometer totals have been lost.
            </para>
            <para>If the odometer totals are used for vehicle maintenance or otherwise essential to vehicle operation,
                the VPM should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_424.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_426.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
