<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - VEHICLE
        PERSONALITY MODULE - VPM MEMORY FAULTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VPM MEMORY FAULTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 645 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 7 - VPM: RAW EEPROM MEMORY LOCATION - ERROR</title>
            <para>Code 645 requires no action. Flash code 645 indicates an error was detected during a read or write
                attempt at one of the EEPROM memory locations in the VPM. The code is informational and will be logged
                as an inactive code. Code 645 will be logged along with another code which specifies what system or
                feature is affected.
            </para>
            <para>If the error was in the VPM accumulators (total miles, fuel used or engine hour totals) a 634, 635,
                641, 642, 643 or 645 will be logged.
                <emph type="bold">Refer to VPM Fuel Meter, Hour Meter and Odometer in this section for a discussion of
                    these codes.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If the EEPROM memory location failure was storing information from one of the data lists stored in the
                VPM (Short List, High Priority List or Low Priority List), one of several fault codes (223, 235, 623,
                624, 633, 651, 652, or 653) discussed in this section would be set because corrupt data would be read by
                the ECM. If for example, the ECM attempted to read the Short List and the data was bad, Flash Code 653
                would be set.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 651 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 10 - VPM: FEATURE MEMORY LIST CORRUPTED</title>
            <para>If the VPM detects an error with the Feature List, code 651 will be set.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOMS:</emph>Engine runs on partial defaults, but Engine Warning Light is not
                turned on. Vehicle features such as cruise control, remote PTO and optional engine protection system are
                disabled.
            </para>
            <para>If code 651 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recycle the VPM. With the key ON, pull fuse F4 (H1 with FBC) and then reinstall the
                    fuse.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 651 is inactive, end the test.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 651 still is active after resetting the VPM, reprogram the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 651 still is active after reprogramming the VPM, replace the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 652 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 2 - VPM: ENGINE/FUEL MEMORY LIST CORRUPTED</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOMS:</emph>Engine runs on field defaults, setting code 622 and Engine Warning
                Light is turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>This code can be set if the VPM detects an error in the engine-fuel list.</para>
            <para>If code 652 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recycle the VPM. With the key ON, pull fuse F4 (H1 with FBC) and then reinstall the
                    fuse.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 652 is inactive, end test.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 652 is still active, replace the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 653 - ATA CODE SID 253 FMI 12 - VPM: ENGINE RATING MEMORY LIST CORRUPTED</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOMS:</emph>Engine runs on field defaults, with Engine Warning Light turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>This code can be set if the VPM detects an error in the engine rating list.</para>
            <para>If code 653 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recycle the VPM. With the key ON pull fuse F4 (H1 with FBC) and then reinstall the
                    fuse.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 653 is inactive, end test.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If code 653 is still active, replace the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FLASH CODE 654 - ATA CODE SID 252 FMI 12 - VPM: WATCHDOG TIME-OUT FAULT</title>
            <para>If a VPM software fault is detected, code 654 will be set, then the VPM will reset. The driver will
                likely not notice the reset, but the code will be logged as an inactive code following the reset for
                informational purposes.
            </para>
            <para>If code 621 is active:</para>
            <para>A. Program the VPM using established programming procedures included in the Prolink Manual.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_425.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_HL1251831.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
