<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - GLOW PLUG CONTROL
        - GLOW PLUG SYSTEM EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GLOW PLUG SYSTEM EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Glow Plug Control System that controls the current flow
                to the glow plugs. Glow plug relay "ON" time is controlled by the ECM and is a function of Engine
                Coolant Temperature, Barometric Pressure, and Battery Voltage. Glow plug "ON" time varies between 10-120
                seconds. Glow plugs are self limiting glow plugs and do not require to be cycled on and off. The glow
                plug relay will cycle on and off repeatedly, if battery voltage is greater than 13.0 volts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="e125_300.xml" xrefid="ef12518100">Figure 3.107 - Glow Plug Control Circuit Diagram
                </hotlnk>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>Glow Plug System operation is dependent upon engine coolant temperature, barometric pressure and
                battery voltage. When the ignition switch is placed in the "ON" position,Terminal B (coil side) of the
                glow plug relay is supplied with battery voltage. Terminal A (coil side) of the relay is connected to
                Terminal 58 of the ECM. The ECM supplies battery ground to the glow plug relay coil via an internal
                driver transistor when coolant temperature, barometric pressure and battery voltage conditions require
                the glow plug system to warm the engine for starting.
            </para>
            <para>Applying ground (B-) to terminal A causes the relay to switch and apply battery voltage (present at
                the large terminal containing a single wire leading to and connected to the B+ terminal of the starter
                solenoid) to the other large terminal which contains two wires. These wires now supply battery power to
                the glow plugs in the right and left cylinder heads.
            </para>
            <para>The Glow Plug Wait Lamp is also turned on by the ECM when the glow plug relay is enabled.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Wait light on time is independent from glow plug relay on time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_300.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_302.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
