<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 4: SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - ECM RESET - GLOW
        PLUG LAMP CYCLES ON/GLOW PLUGS RECYCLE/ENGINE STUMBLE DIE/NO ACCELERATOR PEDAL AUTHORITY UNTIL RETURN TO IDLE
        POSITION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>GLOW PLUG LAMP CYCLES ON/GLOW PLUGS RECYCLE/ENGINE STUMBLE DIE/NO ACCELERATOR PEDAL AUTHORITY UNTIL
            RETURN TO IDLE POSITION
        </title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>A Electronic Control Module (ECM) reset occurs when the ECM momentarily "reboots" or is turned off and
                on while the engine is operating. If the condition occurs a single time, the engine will momentarily
                stumble and the ECM will go through a normal key on cycle, including turning the glow plug lamp and glow
                plugs on and will also attempt to validate the accelerator pedal position. If the pedal is not at the
                idle position when this fault occurs, pedal authority will not be allowed by the ECM until the APS is
                released and the engine will idle only.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Probable Causes</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Momentary loss of power to the ECM or IDM: Defective power relays, shorted or open
                    harness, intermittent connectors, poor grounds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Momentary short to ground of V ref: Shorted harness or connector, defective sensor
                    (sensors that use Vref include - EBP exhaust back pressure, ICP injection control pressure, CMP
                    camshaft position sensor, MAP manifold absolute pressure sensor, BARO barometric pressure sensor,
                    APS accelerator pedal sensor.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Momentary short to ground of injector high side voltage: Under valve cover harness,
                    valve cover gasket, engine harness, chassis harness are all possible sources of short to ground
                    conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Procedures</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete tests #3, #4a and #4b on the Performance Diagnostic Form, this will determine
                    if the ECM has detected any fault conditions that can cause a ECM reset. If the EST does not operate
                    or is unavailable, perform Test 5 (STI Flash Codes).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the ECM is unable to perform a KOEO Injector Electrical Self Test (Buzz Test) this will
                            sometimes indicate an injector circuit high side short to ground condition. Disconnect pairs
                            of injectors by removing the connector at the valve cover and attempt to perform the Buzz
                            Test. If the Buzz test can be accomplished with an injector pair disconnected, the high side
                            short to ground has most likely been isolated to the under valve cover harness corresponding
                            to the disconnected injectors.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check all power and ground connections for the ECM and IDM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monitor V ref (pin #26) and V Power (pins #37 &#38; #57) with the breakout box installed
                    when the fault occurs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the CMP sensor harness connector and the harness (particularly around the idler
                    pulley) for a V ref or signal short to ground condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and inspect the CMP camshaft position sensor for possible timing disk to CMP
                    sensor contact
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the ECM reset condition is repeatable, disconnect the following sensors one at a time
                    and operate the engine to determine if the reset will reoccur. EBP exhaust back pressure, ICP
                    injection control pressure, MAP manifold absolute pressure sensor, BARO barometric pressure sensor,
                    APS accelerator pedal sensor, and EOP engine oil pressure sensor. Inspect each harness and connector
                    upon removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the valve covers and inspect the under valve cover connectors (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1252019">4.19</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    )
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>for possible pinching under the valve cover gasket or rub through against
                    the push tubes.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef1252019" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg7147" filename="../figeg7/eg7147.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.19 Under Valve Cover Harness Inspection</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_511.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_513.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
