<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTOR DRIVE
        MODULE (IDM) POWER SUPPLY - INJECTOR DRIVER MODULE POWER CIRCUITS EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INJECTOR DRIVER MODULE POWER CIRCUITS EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The Injector Driver Module (IDM) Power Relay acts as an ON/OFF switch that the ECM uses to turn the IDM on
            and off.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM uses sensors to monitor Injection Control Pressure and Exhaust Back Pressure parameters. When
            starting the engine, if the ECM determines that any of these parameters are out of safe operating range, the
            ECM does not enable the IDM Power Relay, which prevents the engine from starting.
        </para>
        <para>If the engine is started, and parameters are detected out of the safe operating range, the engine will
            derate, then disable the IDM Power Relay, which turns the IDM off, causing the engine to shut down.
        </para>
        <para>With the optional Engine Protection System, the ECM also monitors Engine Oil Pressure, Coolant Level and
            Temperature sensor information. If these parameters are out of prescribed limits, the ECM will first derate
            the engine and then turn off the IDM, shutting down the engine.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to the circuit diagram (
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e125_325.xml" xrefid="ef12518112">3.119</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ) for the following discussion.
        </para>
        <para>The IDM PWR relay (396) controls battery power to the Injector Driver Module (IDM) through connector (380)
            terminal 14. Battery power is available at all times to relay connector (396) at terminal 30. The feed
            circuit is protected by 15A, #2 ECM PWR fuse.
        </para>
        <para>When the key switch is turned ON, power from ECM PWR relay (395) is applied to the IDM PWR relay control
            coil at terminal 85. The IDM relay control coil ground circuit (97AH) is connected to ECM connector (379)
            terminal 33. The ECM switches ECM terminal 33 between 0 and 12 volts to enable or disable the IDM relay.
            When terminal 33 is at 0 volts, the IDM relay energizes.
        </para>
        <para>When the IDM PWR relay is energized, battery power passes through the normally open relay contacts (30 to
            87) and on circuit 97AG to connector (380) terminal 14 (IDM VIGN). The IDM power ground is from IDM terminal
            26, through circuits 97-GM/97-GMA/ 97-GMC/97-GMD/11-G to the negative battery terminal.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">If the IDM is not powered, the engine will not run.</emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_320.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_322.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
