<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 3.5: CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - VPM COMMUNICATIONS
        (DATA COMMUNICATIONS LINK, ATA LINK) - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Flash codes that can be caused by defects occurring in the ATA or DCL circuits are discussed in this
                section. There are also Flash Codes related to or caused by faulty communication (corrupt or invalid
                data transmitted between the ECM and VPM), that are discussed in this section.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EST CONNECTOR (384)</title>
            <para>The engine control system
                <emph type="underscr">does not detect</emph>
                faults in the power or ground circuits to EST connector (384). If the service tool does not power up
                when connected, try the service tool on another vehicle if one is available to determine if the service
                tool is working properly. If the service tool is OK, then perform Testing EST Connector (384) Power and
                Ground Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_181.xml" xrefid="ef1251831">3.38</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EST DISPLAYS</title>
            <para>Should the EST display NO DATA, the ATA data link circuit from the EST connector to the VPM may be
                disrupted. Verify that the key is ON and then perform Testing The ATA Data Link Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251832">3.39</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251833">3.40</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251834">3.41</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT CODES -
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>223 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 252 FMI 7</emph>
                - VPM NOT COMMUNICATING WITH ECM
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom:</emph>Flash code 223 causes the engine to operate in Field Defaults, which
                turns the Engine Warning Light ON. When Field Defaults are being used by the ECM, Flash Code 622 also is
                set. If the condition causing code 223 is intermittent, and the condition is no longer present, the code
                will change to an inactive code, and the engine will resume normal operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Wiring Causes:</emph>
                DCL circuits 97AS and/or 97AT between the ECM and VPM: shorted Low or High or Open.
            </para>
            <para>If code 223 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TESTING DCL CIRCUITS (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251835">3.42</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251836">3.43</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defect is found in DCL circuit, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the DCL circuits (97AT and 97AS) check good, replace the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>231 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 250 FMI 2</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">VPM:</emph>ATA COMMON FAULT
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>Code 231
                <emph type="bold">does not</emph>
                turn Engine Warning light ON. This code can occur when the VPM can't access the ATA data link. If this
                occurs, there will not be any ATA data available at the electronic service tool (EST). The code can be
                "flashed" using the STI switch located on the instrument panel.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WIRING CAUSES:</emph>ATA positive or negative circuits between EST and VPM and any
                other electronic devices (transmissions, brakes etc.) using the ATA bus: Shorted (high or low), open, or
                busy (too many devices).
            </para>
            <para>If code 231 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform Testing the ATA Data Link Circuits (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251832">3.39</hotlnk>,
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251833">3.40</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251834">3.41</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defect is found in ATA circuits, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defect is not found in ATA circuits, investigate SYSTEM CAUSES.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">SYSTEM CAUSES:</emph>System causes can include:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>A defective ATA device (such as transmission controller or antilock brake controller)
                                connected to the ATA bus is pulling the signal to ground.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Too many ATA devices, although this would be rare.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If no system causes are present, replace the VPM.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>232 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 250 FMI 9</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">VPM:</emph>UNABLE TO FORWARD ECM MESSAGE TO ATA DCL
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>There are no ECM replies to requests from the EST or VPM. Flash Code
                232
                <emph type="bold">does not</emph>
                turn the Engine Warn Light ON.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WIRING CAUSES:</emph>The positive and/or negative ATA data link circuits between the
                EST and VPM (or other devices installed using the ATA link): Shorted High or Low or Open.
            </para>
            <para>If code 232 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform Testing the ATA Data Link Circuits (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251832">3.39</hotlnk>,
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251833">3.40</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="e125_182.xml" xrefid="ef1251834">3.41</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A. If wiring defect is found, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">B. If no wiring defects are found, investigate System Causes.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">SYSTEM CAUSES:</emph>Code 232 can occur when the ECM is sending more messages
                        than the VPM can transmit on the ATA bus. This can be caused by:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>A defective ATA device (such as transmission controller or antilock brake controller)
                                connected to the ATA bus pulling the signal to ground.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Too many ATA devices or an incompatible ATA device has been connected to the ATA
                                bus.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>May be caused by code 231 occurring.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If none of the system causes are present, replace the VPM.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>234 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 248 FMI 9</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">VPM:</emph>UNABLE TO FORWARD ATA MESSAGE TO ECM.
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>There are no ECM replies to requests from the EST or VPM. There is NO
                Engine Warning Light. Code 223 may also be present.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Code 234 can be set by connecting the EST when the key is OFF. If the key was recently turned
                        off, the VPM may still be powered. The VPM can stay on for up to 30 minutes after turning the
                        key off. If the prolink is connected (key off), the VPM will unsuccessfully request data from
                        the ECM, which is not powered with the key off. If this occurs, turn the key on and clear the
                        codes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WIRING CAUSES:</emph>DCL positive or negative circuits (97AT and/or 97AS): Shorted
                High or Low or open between ECM and VPM.
            </para>
            <para>If code 234 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that ignition key is ON.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform Testing DCL Data Link Circuits (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251835">3.42</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251836">3.43</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defect is found in DCL, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If no defects are in DCL, replace the ECM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>235 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 248 FMI 2</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">VPM:</emph>VPM/ECM DCL FAULT
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>There are no ECM diagnostic replies to requests from the EST or VPM.
                Engine Warning Light OFF. If the condition causing code 235 to set is intermittent and the condition is
                no longer present, the code will go to inactive status.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WIRING CAUSES:</emph>
                DCL circuits 97AT and/or 97AS are: shorted High or Low or Open between VPM and ECM.
            </para>
            <para>If code 235 is active, Perform Testing DCL Data Link Circuits (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251835">3.42</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251836">3.43</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If wiring defect is found, correct defect.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If wiring defect is not found, replace the ECM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FLASH CODE</emph>633 -
                <emph type="bold">ATA CODE SID 252 FMI 2</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold">ECM:</emph>ECM/VPM COMMON FAULT
            </title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>The engine operates on Field Defaults turning the Engine Warning Light
                ON and setting code 622.
            </para>
            <para>This code indicates that the ECM and VPM are communicating incorrectly. The message from the VPM
                contains bad data, or the VPM takes too long to respond to ECM requests for data. If this code is caused
                by an intermittent condition, and the condition is no longer present, the code will become inactive and
                normal engine operation will resume.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WIRING CAUSES:</emph>DCL circuits 97AT or 97AS between ECM and VPM are: shorted Low,
                High or Open.
            </para>
            <para>If code 633 is active:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform Testing DCL Data Link Circuits (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251835">3.42</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="e125_183.xml" xrefid="ef1251836">3.43</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defect is found in DCL, correct.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there are no defects in the DCL, refer to codes 613 and 614 and verify that the
                        ECM and VPM have the correct software versions. If the software versions are correct, replace
                        the VPM.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_176.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_178.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
