<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1997) - SECTION 1: ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SECTION 1.4: EXHAUST
        BACK PRESSURE DEVICE - EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE DEVICE (OPTIONAL) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>The exhaust back pressure device is located on the turbocharger pedestal and consists of the following
            components:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Exhaust Back Pressure Regulator (EPR).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Actuator Piston</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Butterfly valve.</para>
            <para>The Exhaust Back Pressure device is controlled by the Electronic Control Module (ECM). The ECM senses
                Engine Coolant Temperature and Intake Air Temperature (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1250402">1.13</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) to determine when the exhaust back pressure (butterfly valve closure) is required.
            </para>
            <para>Engine oil pressure is present on one side of the regulator valve while the engine is running. When
                coolant and intake air temperatures are low, the ECM signals the regulator valve to open which allows
                engine oil pressure to push on the actuator piston causing the butterfly valve to close. The ECM
                receives exhaust back pressure information from the exhaust back pressure sensor and controls the
                position of the butterfly valve.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine reaches operating temperature, the ECM will signal the regulator valve to fully close,
                cutting off engine oil pressure to the actuator piston. The actuator piston will retract due to spring
                pressure causing the butterfly valve to fully open and remove the exhaust restriction.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="ef1250401" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1096" filename="../figeg1/EG1096.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.12 - Exhaust Back Pressure Device</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="ef1250402" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg7009" filename="../figeg7/EG7009.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.13 - Exhaust Back Pressure Device Location and Function</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e125.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
