<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS - DIAGNOSTIC ANALYIS
        PROCEDURES FOR LUBE OIL IN FUEL
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC ANALYIS PROCEDURES FOR LUBE OIL IN FUEL</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title></title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If lube oil is suspected to be in the fuel, drain some fuel from the filter and observe
                    its color. If the fuel appears darker than it should, it is recommended a small amount of fuel to be
                    purchased from the supplier for comparison to confirm contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If comparing fuels is impossible or inconclusive, remove the fuel filter and cut the
                    housing open using a filter cutter. If the filter element appears black, oil may have entered the
                    fuel system. The point of entry is most likely past an injector "O" ring or a missing "O" ring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>PERFORM ICP LEAKAGE TEST</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove intake manifold/valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the high pressure lube oil hose at the high pressure lube oil pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a regulated air supply to the disconnected high pressure lube oil hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 100 PSI air pressure with the regulated air supply. This will pressurrize the
                    entire oil manifold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for air leakage around each injector assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel lines from the fuel manifold and check for air leakage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If leakage is observed at an injector, remove and inspect the injector for obvious
                    damage or worn O-rings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no leakage is present, perform Injector "Buzz" Test while the air pressure is still
                    being applied to the oil manifold. Oil discharge from each injector should be equal. If an injector
                    or injectors show excessive oil discharge in comparison to others it is suspect. If it is not
                    possible to determine which injector(s) are suspect, apply air pressure using a cylinder leak tester
                    and observe leakage during an Injector "Buzz" Test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no leakage is evident, remove all injectors and inspect all "O" rings on each
                    injector.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <seqlist style="arabic">
                            <item>
                                <para>Discard all "O" rings after inspection. Always use new "O" rings when reinstalling
                                    injectors.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>After reassembly, drain fuel tanks and dispose of contaminated fuel properly.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>POSSIBLE CAUSES:</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Leaking injector O-rings</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or porous cylinder head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or porous fuel/oil manifold</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Internal leakage of HEUI injector</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_184.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_186.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
