<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - CRUISE CONTROL, PTO, HAND THROTTLE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450332" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="14">
        <title>CRUISE CONTROL, PTO, HAND THROTTLE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e3">Figure 3.118 Cruise Control, PTO, Hand Throttle System</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503e3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6058" filename="../figeg6/EG6058.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.118 Cruise Control, PTO, Hand Throttle System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control</title>
            <para>ECM terminal 50 outputs a 6.58 volt signal to the resistor block. Activating the cruise command
                switches causes the signal to pass through different resistance levels in the resistor block, altering
                the signal which is grounded at ECM terminal 39. There are five expected signals to the ECM: OFF, ON,
                SET, RESUME and open (no switches have been used). Refer to Extended Description for additional detail.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote PTO Controls</title>
            <para>To use the remote controls, cruise control must be turned on using the cab cruise ON/OFF switch. The
                remote Set/Resume switch and disable switch are wired parallel to cab switches and operate in the same
                manner.
            </para>
            <para>With cruise control ON:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Placing the remote PTO Preset switch in the ON position (closed) causes the PTO to
                        operate at a preset engine speed (customer selected) programmed into the VPM.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Placing the remote PTO Variable switch in the ON position (closed) causes the PTO to
                        operate using remote pedal.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>IF both of the above switches are ON, the remote pedal is deactivated.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the
                <emph type="bold">SCCS signal</emph>for the five expected signals. If an incorrect signal is detected,
                Flash Code 221 is logged. The ECM also monitors the
                <emph type="bold">R-APS signal</emph>
                input at ECM terminal 30 from the remote pedal sensor for out-of-range signals, high or low.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e4">Figure 3.119 Cruise Control, PTO, Hand Throttle System Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503e4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6059" filename="../figeg6/EG6059.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.119 Cruise Control, PTO, Hand Throttle System Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Operational Voltage Checks</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Connector (379) with breakout box installed and key ON</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="et1450324">
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="86p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="72p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="65p"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="252p"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>SCCS Sw. Positions</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Breakout Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>All switches in neutral position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>#50 to #39</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>6.2V-7.1V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>&#60; than 6.2V check connections, battery condition. Greater than 7.1V check for
                                    short to VBAT
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Hold switch in OFF position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>#50 to #39</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>0V-100mV</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>> than 100mV check connections, switch, resistor block and circuits for correct
                                    resistance or short to VBAT or grd
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Hold switch in ON position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>#50 to #39</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>4.4V-5.0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>&#60;> than specified voltage drop, check connections, switch, resistor block and
                                    related circuits for correct resistance or short to VBAT or grd
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Hold Set switch in SET position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>#50 to #39</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>2.2V-3.0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>&#60;> than specified voltage drop, check connections, switch, resistor block and
                                    related circuits for correct resistance or short to VBAT or VREF or grd
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Hold Res switch in RES position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>#50 to #39</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>700mV-800mV</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>&#60;> than specified voltage drop, check connections, switch, resistor block and
                                    related circuits for correct resistance or short to VREF or VBAT or grd
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="et1450325">
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="432p"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Fault Code Descriptions</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>213 = RPS signal was less than 0.146 volts for more than 0.5 seconds</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>214 = RPS signal was greater than 4.56 volts for more than 0.5 seconds</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>221 = SCCS voltage signal does not match expected levels (5 assigned levels for
                                    different conditions)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>Cruise control and PTO operation (including remote PTO) share many circuits and components, so both
                systems are included in this section.
            </para>
            <para>The Cruise/PTO system is controlled by the ECM in response to driver input on the Speed Control
                Command Switches (SCCS), which are the Cruise ON/OFF and SET/ RESUME switches. With a remote PTO
                operation, the body builder installed controls include a remote SET/RESUME switch and a PTO DISABLE
                switch that are also SCCS switches.
            </para>
            <para>The body builder also installs a Remote pedal sensor and switches to enable the remote PTO at a preset
                speed or enable in the variable mode, with engine speed controlled by the remote pedal sensor. These
                circuits will be discussed in Remote Pedal Sensor Circuits later in this section.
            </para>
            <para>The Clutch Pedal Switch supplies the Driveline Disengaged Signal (DDS) to the ECM and the Service
                Brake Switches supply a Brake Normally Open (BNO) and Brake Normally Closed (BNC) signal to the ECM.
                These signals indicate pedal positions and are used by the ECM in operating the Cruise/PTO Control
                System.
            </para>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Signal (VSS) and CMP signal provide vehicle speed and engine rpm information that
                the ECM uses in controlling the Cruise/PTO system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Control</title>
            <para>Refer to the circuit diagram
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e5">3.120</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussions on circuit operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SCCS CIRCUITS</title>
            <para>The ECM sends a 6.58 volt signal from ECM terminal 50 to the SCCS system. The signal goes through the
                SC Resistor Block Assembly to the SCCS switches (see note 1) and returns to the ECM at terminal 39.
                Depending on SCCS switch position (ON, OFF, SET, RESUME or when no switch is active), one of five
                different signals is expected when the signal returns to ECM signal ground terminal 39. These five
                signals are discussed in the following paragraphs.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE 1:</emph>The SC Resistor Block is permanently attached to the cab harness and
                contains a printed circuit board, that includes three resistors. The printed circuit board can be
                removed by opening the end of the resistor block assembly and pulling the board out.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>No SCCS Switches Active</title>
            <para>Note in circuit diagram that the ON/OFF, SET/RESUME (including the remote SET/RESUME) and the remote
                DISABLE PTO switch are normally open, momentary switches. With the key switch ON, voltage is being
                applied from ECM terminal 50, but the ECM expects to see an open circuit. With no switch depressed,
                voltage measured between ECM terminals 39 and 50 is expected to be between 6.2 and 7.1 volts.
                <emph type="bold">An OPEN circuit (6.2 to 7.1 volts between terminals 39 and 50) is the signal that the
                    ECM expects to see with no switch depressed.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise ON/OFF Switch In ON Position</title>
            <para>Momentarily placing this switch in the ON position causes the signal from ECM terminal 50 to go
                through the 2.2K ohm resistor located in the Resistor Block (390) through the ON terminal of the ON/OFF
                switch and returns to ECM terminal 39. With the ON switch depressed, the voltage drop in this circuit
                (measured between ECM terminals 39 and 50) is expected to be between 4.4 and 5.0 volts.
                <emph type="bold">A voltage between 4.4 and 5.0 volts is the signal the ECM expects to see with the ON
                    switch depressed.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise ON/OFF Switch In OFF Position</title>
            <para>Momentarily placing this switch in the OFF position causes the signal from ECM terminal 50 to go
                through the Resistor Block (390), terminals F to E, where there is no resistor, then through the OFF
                terminal of the ON/OFF switch returning to ECM terminal 39. With the OFF switch depressed, the expected
                voltage drop in this circuit (measured between ECM terminals 39 and 50) is expected to be between 0 and
                100mV.
                <emph type="bold">A voltage between 0 and 100mV is the signal the ECM expects to see with the OFF switch
                    depressed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Remote DISENGAGE PTO Switch is a normally open (NO) momentary switch that is wired parallel to the
                OFF side of the ON/ OFF switch. The PTO can only be turned on from the cab switch, but can be turned OFF
                from the remote location. When this switch is closed, the ECM expects to see the same signal as when the
                ON/OFF switch is in the OFF position (0 to 100mV voltage drop).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise SET/RESUME in SET Position</title>
            <para>Momentarily placing this switch in the SET position causes the signal from ECM terminal 50 to go
                through the 680 ohm resistor located in the Resistor Block (390) through the SET terminal of the
                SET/RESUME switch returning to ECM terminal 39. With the SET switch depressed, the voltage drop in this
                circuit (measured between ECM terminals 39 and 50) is expected to be between 2.2 and 3.0 volts.
                <emph type="bold">A voltage between 2.2 and 3.0 volts is the signal the ECM expects to see with the SET
                    switch depressed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Remote PTO SET/RESUME Switch is a normally open (NO) momentary switch that is wired parallel to
                the cab SET/RESUME switch. When the remote SET switch is in the SET position, the ECM expects to see the
                same signal as when the cab SET switch is in the SET position (2.2 to 3.0 volts).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise SET/RESUME in RESUME Position</title>
            <para>Momentarily placing this switch in the RESUME position causes the signal from ECM terminal 50 to go
                through the 121 ohm resistor located in the Resistor Block (390) through the RESUME terminal of the
                SET/RESUME switch returning to ECM terminal 39. With the RESUME switch depressed, the voltage drop in
                this circuit (measured between ECM terminals 39 and 50) is expected to be between 700 mV and 810 mV.
                <emph type="bold">A voltage between 700mV and 810mV is the signal the ECM expects to see with the RESUME
                    switch depressed.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Remote PTO SET/RESUME Switch is a normally open (NO) momentary switch that is wired parallel to
                the cab SET/RESUME switch. When the remote SET/RESUME switch is in the RESUME position, the ECM expects
                to see the same signal as when the cab SET/RESUME switch is in the RESUME position (700mV to 810mV).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>REMOTE PEDAL SENSOR (RPS) SWITCHES</title>
            <para>To enable the remote PTO, first the cab ON/OFF switch must be set to the ON position. With PTO
                enabled, the Enable PRESET switch or Enable VARIABLE switch must be turned ON. These are toggle
                switches, not momentary on switches.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Preset Switch</title>
            <para>The remote Preset Switch receives ignition voltage from 5A fuse, F6 through the body builder connector
                429, terminal 8. Closing this switch applies ignition voltage to ECM terminal 2. When ECM terminal 2
                sees 12 volts, it turns on the PTO to the preset speed. Opening the switch turns off the remote PTO. If
                both the PRESET switch and the VARIABLE switch are on, the ECM interprets this as an off signal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Variable Switch</title>
            <para>The remote Variable Switch receives ignition voltage from 5A fuse, F6 through the body builder
                connector 429, terminal 7. Closing this switch applies ignition voltage to ECM terminal 12. When ECM
                terminal 12 sees 12 volts, it turns on the PTO in the variable mode, where engine speed is controlled by
                the remote pedal. Opening the switch turns off the remote PTO. If both the PRESET switch and the
                VARIABLE switch are on, the ECM interprets this as an off signal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS)</title>
            <para>The RPS receives R-VREF (5V) from ECM terminal 44, through body builder connector (429), terminal 12.
                As the pedal position is changed, the wiper sends the variable RPS signal through body builder connector
                (429), terminal 11 to ECM terminal 30. The ECM expects to see a signal between 152 mV and 4.55 volts.
                This signal is interpreted by the ECM as percent of throttle, from 0 to 100 percent. The RPS sensor is
                grounded through body builder connector (429), terminal 10 to ECM terminal 51 (SIG RTN).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SCCS Diagnostics</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the signal on SCCS circuit 97AC for the expected five signals discussed earlier. If a
                signal is detected by the ECM that does not match any one of the five expected signals, then Flash Code
                221 is set and the PTO or Cruise is disabled.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 221</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 244 FMI 2</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: SCCS Switch or Circuit Fault</title>
            </para>
            <para>CAUSES: Open, short (HIGH or LOW), or bias high or low in SCCS circuits or components.</para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the R-APS signal input at ECM terminal 30 from the remote pedal sensor for
                out-of-range signals, high or low.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Biased High Or Low - A wiring or component defect that changes the circuit resistance
                        (corroded switch contacts, poor connections, dirty or corroded terminals etc.) will alter the
                        signal, causing the code to be set.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A short to a 12V or 5V circuit will change the expected signal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A short to ground changes the expected signal.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>CORRECTIVE ACTION: Perform Testing SCCS Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e8">3.123</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RPS DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the R-APS signal input at ECM terminal 30 from the remote pedal sensor for
                out-of-range signals, high or low.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 213</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 29 Fmi 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: RPS ORL</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the ECM detects an RPS signal lower than 152 mV, this code is set and the remote pedal is
                disabled.
            </para>
            <para>CORRECTIVE ACTION: Perform Testing RPS Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f5">3.130</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 214</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 29 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: RPS ORH</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the ECM detects an RPS signal greater than 4.55 volts, this code is set and the remote pedal is
                disabled.
            </para>
            <para>CORRECTIVE ACTION: Perform Testing RPS Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f5">3.130</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>Before troubleshooting the Cruise/PTO control system, use the Prolink EST to:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Review any logged Flash Codes.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Code 221 relates directly to Cruise or Remote SCCS switches circuits. Codes 213 and
                        214 relate to operation of the remote PTO pedal.
                        <emph type="bold">First resolve any other codes that may be present, because they may cause the
                            ECM to disable the cruise control.
                        </emph>
                        Flash code 622 indicates the ECM is using Field Defaults that disable cruise and PTO operation.
                        The cause for code 622 must be corrected.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the Prolink EST to monitor clutch switch operation. There is no diagnostic code for
                    the DDS, Drive Line Disengagement Switch (clutch switch) operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the clutch switch circuit is open, indicating that the switch is depressed, then
                    cruise and PTO controls won't operate. If the clutch switch circuit is defective (shorted high),
                    depressing the clutch pedal may not disengage the cruise or PTO, causing the engine to go to rated
                    rpm when the clutch pedal is depressed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flash code 222 is a Brake Switch fault which will disable cruise and PTO operation. Use
                    Prolink to check brake switch operation. The BNO and BNC switches must be working properly for
                    cruise control to operate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flash codes 141 and 142 are Vehicle Speed Sensor faults which will disable the cruise
                    and PTO controls. A speed sensor that is not properly adjusted will affect speedometer and cruise
                    control operation, and no codes will set. Correct any speedometer problems before troubleshooting
                    the PTO system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A severe INTERMITTENT connection or NOISE in the CMP SIGNAL can cause the engine to
                    surge and the cruise control cannot properly maintain vehicle speed or PTO engine rpm will
                    fluctuate.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the batteries are fully charged! Check battery
                    connections and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage. Voltage tests will give
                    misleading results if the batteries are not fully charged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose, or damaged
                    (spread or bent) terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. Wires and connections must be free of
                    damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must
                    be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections
                    free of damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Prolink EST can be used to monitor cruise switches, but if code 221 is active, the
                    switches do not operate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If Flash code 221 is active or if no flash code is present, perform Testing SCCS
                    Circuits
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e8">3.123</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503e5" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6060" filename="../figeg6/EG6060.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.120 Circuit Diagram Cruise Control and PTO</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>** - Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e6">3.121</hotlnk>
                            for typical PTO installation.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef14503e6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6119" filename="../figeg6/EG6119.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.121 Typical Remote PTO Connections</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e7">Figure 3.122 Cruise Control (Without Remote Controls)</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503e7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6061" filename="../figeg6/EG6061.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.122 Cruise Control (Without Remote Controls)</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef14503e8" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6062" filename="../figeg6/EG6062.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.123 Testing Speed Control Command Switch (SCCS) Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e5">3.120</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e9">Figure 3.124 Testing Speed Control Command Switch (SCCS) Circuits
                    </hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503e9" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6063" filename="../figeg6/EG6063.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.124 Testing Speed Control Command Switch (SCCS) Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f0">Figure 3.125 Testing (SCCS) Circuits</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503f0" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6064" filename="../figeg6/EG6064.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.125 Testing (SCCS) Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f2">3.127</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f1">Figure 3.126 Testing (SCCS) Circuits</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503f1" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6065" filename="../figeg6/EG6065.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.126 Testing (SCCS) Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef14503f2" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6066" filename="../figeg6/EG6066.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.127 Testing SCCS On/Off and Set/Resume Switches</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e5">3.120</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>REMOTE PTO ONLY DOES NOT OPERATE (OR OPERATES INCORRECTLY)</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before diagnosing any problem with the remote PTO, be sure that the vehicle cruise control
                        system operates correctly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Preset PTO Mode Does Not Operate Properly</title>
            <para>Turning the cruise control on using the cab Cruise ON/OFF switch, then turning the remote Enable
                Preset switch ON will cause the PTO to operate at the customer selected preset rpm. The ECM does not
                diagnose the Enable Preset switch circuit, therefore there are no fault codes to indicate the circuit is
                defective.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle cruise control works properly, but the remote Enable Preset switch does not work,
                perform Testing Remote PTO Preset And Variable Enable Circuits (below).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Variable PTO Mode Does Not Operate Properly</title>
            <para>Flash codes 213 and 214 indicate the ECM detected an out-of-range signal (high or low) from the remote
                pedal sensor (RPS). Note that the ECM
                <emph type="bold">does not</emph>
                diagnose the
                <emph type="underscr">Enable Variable switch circuit</emph>, therefore there are no fault codes to
                indicate a defect in that circuit.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle cruise control works properly, but the remote PTO does not work in the variable mode,
                check for flash codes. If Flash Code 213 or 214 is present
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
                if no Flash Codes are present, perform Testing Remote PTO Preset And Variable Enable Circuits (below)
                and Testing Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS) Circuits on page
                <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450334.xml" xrefid="ef14503g6">249</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing Remote PTO Preset And Variable Enable Circuits</title>
            <para>This test checks the Navistar installed circuits, but not the body builder switches and circuits. The
                circuit diagram in this section shows a typical installation of the body builder switches.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f3">Figure 3.128 Testing Remote PTO Preset and Variable Enable Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503f3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6067" filename="../figeg6/EG6067.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.128 Testing Remote PTO Preset and Variable Enable Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e5">3.120</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f4">Figure 3.129 Testing Remote PTO Preset and Variable Enable Circuits
                    (Continued)
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503f4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6068" filename="../figeg6/EG6068.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.129 Testing Remote PTO Preset and Variable Enable Circuits (Continued)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS) Circuits</title>
            <para>This test checks the Navistar installed circuits, but not the body builder installed remote pedal
                sensor (RPS) or connecting circuits. The circuit diagram shows a typical installation of the body
                builder installed RPS.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503f5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6069" filename="../figeg6/EG6069.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.130 Testing Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS) Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e5">3.120</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503f6">Figure 3.131 Testing Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS) Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503f6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6070" filename="../figeg6/EG6070.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.131 Testing Remote Pedal Sensor (RPS) Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450331.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450333.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
