<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - TWO SPEED AXLE SPEEDOMETER CIRCUIT
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450335" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>TWO SPEED AXLE SPEEDOMETER CIRCUIT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503g9">Figure 3.144 Two Speed Axle Speedometer Circuit</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503g9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6083" filename="../figeg6/EG6083.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.144 Two Speed Axle Speedometer Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The VPM is programmed with the high and low rear axle ratios. The ratios are used to calculate the
                speedometer signal, depending on which mode the switch is in. The VPM uses the high ratio unless voltage
                is applied to VPM terminal 9 indicating the two speed selector switch is in the low range.
            </para>
            <para>The two speed switch applies 12 volts to the VPM at terminal 9 ( and to the shifter) when the switch
                is in the LO position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>There are no ECM diagnostics for the two speed circuits.</para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503h0">Figure 3.145 Two Speed Axle Speedometer Circuit Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503h0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6084" filename="../figeg6/EG6084.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.145 Two Speed Axle Speedometer Circuit Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>USE PROLINK EST TO PERFORM THE FOLLOWING TEST</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use Prolink EST to verify correct VPM programming including correct rear axle ratios
                    (high and low)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If programmed correctly go to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If programming is not correct, make necessary programming corrections.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use EST to monitor two speed switch while changing switch position several times.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If switch does not function, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If switch functions properly go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect connector (381) from VPM. With key ON and switch in LOW position, measure
                    voltage to ground at circuit 93A. Battery voltage (12 1.5 volts) should be present.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If less than 10.5 v check connections, if 0 volts check for open/short to ground.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, replace the VPM.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to Service Manual Group 08 Instruments, and perform Speedometer Self Diagnostic
                    Test.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If self test is not OK, follow the recommendations of the service manual.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If self test is OK, roadtest the vehicle and have a passenger monitor vehicle speed
                        using the Prolink. If the Prolink displays the correct speed replace the speedometer/tachometer
                        unit. If the Prolink does not display the correct speed, replace the VPM.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The purpose of this section is to diagnose the two speed interface with the speedometer. This
                        section does not diagnose two speed axle operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The vehicle speed sensor reads the revolutions of the transmission speedometer gear and sends a signal
                to the VPM. VPM programming includes the high and low rear axle ratios. The VPM uses the sensor input
                and rear axle rations to calculate the speedometer signal, depending on which range the vehicle is
                operating in. When voltage is applied to VPM terminal 9 from the two speed circuit, the VPM uses the low
                ratio.
            </para>
            <para>The Two Speed Axle switch receives ACC power from 10A fuse F14. This is a normally open switch with
                "High" as the normal operating position. With the Two-Speed switch in the "Low" position, 12V accessory
                power is applied through VPM connector (381) at VPM terminal 9.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>There are no ECM/VPM diagnostics for this circuit.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>If the speedometer/odometer does not correctly show vehicle speed when changing from the high to low
                range, or low to high range, perform Testing Two-Speed Speedometer Circuit
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503h3">3.148</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the batteries are fully charged! Check battery
                    connections and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage. Voltage tests will give
                    misleading results if the batteries are not fully charged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose, or damaged
                    (spread or bent) terminals, or wires with cut strands etc. Wires and connections must be free of
                    damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must
                    be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections
                    free of damage.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503h1" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6085" filename="../figeg6/EG6085.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.146 Circuit Diagram Two Speed Electric (Air)</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef14503h2" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg14503h2" filename="../figeg1/EG14503H2.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.147 Circuit Diagram Two Speed Electric (Hydraulic)</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef14503h3" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6086" filename="../figeg6/EG6086.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.148 Testing Two Speed Speedometer Circuit</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503h1">3.146</hotlnk>
                            or
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503h2">3.147</hotlnk>
                            .
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450334.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450336.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
