<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTION PRESSURE REGULATOR (IPR)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450329" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>INJECTION PRESSURE REGULATOR (IPR)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c8">Figure 3.103 Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1140" filename="../figeg1/EG1140.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.103 Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OUTPUT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Pressure Regulator -</emph>Is a variable position valve that controls
                injection control pressure. The ECM uses many input variables to determine the desired injection control
                pressure.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is supplied to the IPR when the ignition key is in the on position. Valve position is
                controlled by switching the output signal circuit to ground inside the Electronic Control Module (ECM).
                On off time is modulated from 0-50% dependent upon the desired injection control pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>An open or a short to ground control circuit can be detected by an on demand output circuit check
                performed during the engine off test.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM is capable of detecting, while the engine is running, if desired injection control pressure is
                equal to measured injection control pressure. If the measured injection control pressure does not
                reasonably compare to the desired injection control pressure, the ECM ignores the measured ICP signal
                and attempts to control the engine with the desired value. (If the problem was in the sensor circuit,
                this strategy causes little performance deterioration, if the problem is in the control circuit, engine
                performance will probably still be unsatisfactory).
            </para>
            <para>A faulty IPR or problem with the high pressure oil system can be detected by the engine running test
                during the injection control pressure step test. During this test, the ECM commands and measures two
                specific preprogrammed pressures. A fault code is set, if the pressures can not be maintained.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>THE ENGINE WILL NOT OPERATE WITH AN IPR CIRCUIT THAT IS NOT FUNCTIONING.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c9">Figure 3.104 Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6045" filename="../figeg6/EG6045.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.104 Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve that controls
                oil pressure in the high pressure injection control system which is used to actuate the injectors. The
                IPR valve consists of a solenoid, poppet and spool valve assembly and is mounted in the high pressure
                oil pump. The ECM regulates injection control pressure by controlling the duty cycle or (on/off time) of
                the injection control pressure solenoid. this increase or decrease of 'on/off" time positions a poppet
                valve and spool valve internal to the IPR, which in turn either maintains pressure in the injection
                control pressure system or vents pressure to the oil sump via the front cover. (Refer to Engine Control
                system Overview for a more complete description of the IPR operation and function.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The IPR valve is supplied with voltage at terminal A of the IPR conector when the ignition key is
                turned on thru fuse F5. Control of the injection control system is accomplished by the ECM grounding the
                IPR circuit from terminal B of the IPR valve thru pin #21 of the ECM. Precise control is accomplished by
                varying the pulse width or percentage of "on/off" time of the IPR solenoid. The frequency of the pulse
                width to the IPR is 400 Hz, normal "on/off" times varies from 8% to 50%. A high duty cycle indicates a
                high amount of injection control pressure being commanded, a low duty cycle is an indication of less
                pressure being commanded.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the Injection Control Pressure while the engine is in operation. If the actual
                pressure is greater or less than the desired pressure, the ECM will set a fault code. When this occurs,
                the ECM will ignore the ICP sensor and control the engine using preprogrammed values for the IPR.
            </para>
            <para>The Electronic Service Tool is used to Perform the Engine Running Standard Test which enables the ECM
                to vary the comand signal to the IPR and monitor the performance of the Injection Control Pressure
                system. If the system does not respond within the specified parameters, the ECM will set a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>Fault codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or the Self Test Input diagnostic
                switch located on the vehicle dash. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will be stored as an
                Inactive code.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 241</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 42 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INJECTION CONTRL PRESSURE REG. OCC SELF TEST FAILED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 241 is set only during the Engine Off Standard Output Circuit Check. This test indicates the ECM
                has performed an output circuit test, measured voltage drop across the IPR circuit and determined it is
                below or above specification.
            </para>
            <para>If this fault is present, the engine will not run. The ECM will not illuminate the Engine Warning
                light if this code is active, however, this code will be transmitted at the completion of the Output
                Circuit Check, using the STI switch or the Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Open feed circuit or fuse to the IPR, open IPR solenoid, or an open or shorted IPR
                signal circuit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 331</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 0</title>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE ABOVE SYSTEM WORKING RANGE</title>
            <para>Code 331 indicates the ECM has detected injection control pressure greater than 3675 PSI (25 MPA)
                which is greater than the maximum allowable working pressure.
            </para>
            <para>When this code is active, the ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light.</para>
            <para>Possible causes: Incorrect ICP signal due to faulty circuits or sensor, grounded IPR signal circuit, a
                malfunction in the injection control pressure system or a sticking or blocked IPR valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 333</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 164 FMI 10</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INJECTION CONTROL PRESsure ABOVE/BELOW DESIRED LEVEL</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 333 may be set during normal engine operation through the continuous monitor function or during
                the Engine Running Standard Test. It indicates the measured pressure does not match the expected value.
                The ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>When this code is active, the ECM will ignore the ICP sensor signal and will control the IPR from
                programmed values to keep the engine operating. Perform ICP sensor diagnostics to determine if the
                problem exists in the ICP sensor/circuit. If diagnostic testing indicates the ICP sensor/circuit is
                functioning properly, perform additional diagnostic tests on the injection control pressure system.
                Refer to Injection Control Pressure system diagnostics..
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Incorrect ICP signal due to circuit or sensor malfunctions. IPR signal circuit may be
                grounded or contain excessive resistance. The IPR valve may be sticking or blocked. Injection control
                pressure system may not be functioning properly.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503d0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6046" filename="../figeg6/EG6046.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.105 Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503d1">Figure 3.106 Injection Control Pressure Regulator</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503d1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6047" filename="../figeg6/EG6047.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.106 Injection Control Pressure Regulator</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503d0">3.105</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503d2">Figure 3.107 Injection Control Pressure Regulator</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503d2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6048" filename="../figeg6/EG6048.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.107 Injection Control Pressure Regulator</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450328.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450330.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
