<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE
        SELF TEST OPERATION - INJECTOR "BUZZ" TEST (ENGINE OFF)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INJECTOR "BUZZ" TEST (ENGINE OFF)</title>
        <para>The purpose of the Engine Off Injector "BUZZ" Test is to diagnose electrical problems with the fuel
            delivery components. This test can only be accessed with the EST and only after an "Engine Off Test" or
            Standard Test has been performed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before running this test, fault codes should be accessed, noted and erased. This will allow the
                    faults found in this test to be displayed as "Active Codes".
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>During the test, the ECM will signal the IDM to activate the injectors in numerical order 1 thru 6. The
            IDM will monitor each injector's electrical circuit operation. The IDM will send feedback signals to the ECM
            which indicate the status of injector performance and electrical circuit operation. If a electronic
            component in the fuel system fails the parameters of the test, a inactive fault code will be logged and
            transmitted to the EST at the end of the test.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The technician can monitor injector operation by listening to the sound each injector produces as
                    it is activated by the IDM, however, in a Hard/Start No Start condition where oil may be very
                    cold/thick injectors may not be audible.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>If the faults were not erased before this test, the faults found during this test will be displayed as
            "INACTIVE CODES".
        </para>
        <para>To read these fault codes, access the "Diagnostic Codes" menu and read both Active and Inactive codes.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_43.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_45.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
