<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE OIL PRESSURE (EOP) SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450322" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>ENGINE OIL PRESSURE (EOP) SENSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a0">Figure 3.75 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1126" filename="../figeg1/eg1126.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.75 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) sensor is a variable capacitance sensor, that, when supplied with a 5
                volt reference signal from the ECM produces a linear analog voltage signal that indicates engine oil
                pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Warning and Protection -</emph>An optional feature which, when enabled, will
                warn driver of low engine oil pressure condition and can be programmed to shut the engine down.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>An EOP signal that is detected out of range high or low by the ECM will cause the engine to ignore the
                EOP signal and disable Engine Warning and Protection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a1">Figure 3.76 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6020" filename="../figeg6/eg6020.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.76 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Engine Oil Pressure sensor (EOP) is included in Navistar engine control system only when a vehicle
                is equipped with either the engine warning or optional Engine Shutdown engine monitoring system.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM measures the EOP signal to monitor the oil pressure during engine operation. If the oil
                pressure drops below 5.0 PSI (34kPa) @ 700 RPM or 10.0 PSI (69 kPa) @ 1400 RPM or 20.0 PSI (138 kPa) @
                2000 RPM, the ECM will illuminate the OIL/WATER WARN light and sound the audible warning alarm. If the
                vehicle is equipped with the Engine Shut down system and the oil pressure drops to 2.0 PSI (14kPa) @ 700
                RPM or 5.0 PSI (34 kPa) @ 1400 RPM or 12.0 PSI (152 kPa) @ 2000 RPM, the ECM will shut the engine off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Engine Oil Pressure sensor is a variable capacitance sensor. When pressure is applied to the
                sensor, the capacitance changes in relation to the pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM supplies a regulated 5 volt signal to terminal B of the EOP sensor from terminal 26 of the
                ECM. The EOP sensor is supplied a signal return (ground) at terminal A to terminal 46 of the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>During engine operation, oil pressure acting on the sensor causes the sensor's capacitance to vary
                which changes the incoming 5 volt reference signal in relation to pressure. The sensor's oil pressure
                signal at terminal C is sent to terminal 42 of the ECM. This signal increases equally in proportion to
                an increase in pressure up to a maximum of 38 PSI (262 kPa).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM continuously monitors the signal from the EOP sensor to ensure the signal is within the
                correct operating range. If the signal is lower or higher than required, the ECM will set a fault code.
                This fault code is retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the flash code using
                the STI diagnostic switch. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will be stored as an inactive code.
            </para>
            <para>During engine operation, the ECM also monitors the engine speed signal. It compares the expected oil
                pressure specification versus engine speed. If the ECM detects that the oil pressure is lower for a
                given engine speed, the ECM will set a fault code. If the pressure is lower than the "critical" level,
                the ECM will record a fault code. The VPM will automatically record this as a low oil pressure "Event"
                which is stored in the VPM memory and cannot be erased using the EST. This becomes a record of operation
                of the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 211</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 100 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL PRESS SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            </para>
            <para>An out of range low code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage less than .039 volts for more than
                0.1 seconds. If this fault code is set the ECM will ignore the EOP signal and continue to operate
                normally. However, if the fault is Active, the ECM will turn on the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>Code 211 may be caused by an open Vref feed, open signal circuit or a defective sensor.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 212</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 100 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL PRESSURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            </para>
            <para>An out of range high code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage more than 4.9 volts for more than
                0.1 seconds. If this fault code is set, the ECM will ignore the EOP signal and continue to operate
                normally. If this fault is active, the ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>Code 212 may be caused by an open signal return circuit, a short to a voltage source or a defective
                sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 313</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 100 FMI 1</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL PRESSURE BELOW WARNING LEVEL</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 313 indicates that the oil pressure has dropped below the warning level. The specification for
                the warning level is 5.0 PSI (34kPa) @ 700 RPM or 10.0 PSI (69 kPa) @ 1400 RPM or 20.0 PSI (138 kPa) @
                2000 RPM.
            </para>
            <para>Code 313 may be caused by a defective sensor sending an incorrect signal. To confirm this, compare
                actual oil pressure to the reading on the data list of the EST. Low oil pressure due to defective
                mechanical components will also set this code.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It may be possible to set this code at start-up, especially if the oil was just changed, or
                        after a rebuild until the oil system is primed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 314</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE 100 FMI 7</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL PRESSURE BELOW CRITICAL LEVEL</title>
            </para>
            <para>If flash code 314 is set, this indicates that the oil pressure has dropped below the critical level.
                The specification for the critical level is 2.0 PSI (14kPa) @ 700 RPM or 5.0 PSI (34 kPa) @ 1400 RPM or
                12.0 PSI (152 kPa) @ 2000 RPM.
            </para>
            <para>Code 314 may be caused by a defective sensor sending an incorrect signal. To confirm this, compare
                actual oil pressure to the reading on the data list of the EST. Low oil pressure due to defective
                mechanical components will also set this code.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6021" filename="../figeg6/eg6021.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.77 Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef14503a3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6022" filename="../figeg6/eg6022.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.78 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a2">3.77</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a4">Figure 3.79 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6023" filename="../figeg6/eg6023.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.79 Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450321.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450323.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
