<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - ECM-IDM COMMUNICATIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450318" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>ECM-IDM COMMUNICATIONS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450377">Figure 3.56 ECM/IDM Communications</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450377" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5997" filename="../figeg5/EG5997.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.56 ECM/IDM Communications</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cylinder Identification -</emph>Cylinder Identification (CI) signal is a 0 to12 volt
                wave form signal that communicates from the ECM to the IDM the position of cylinder 1. This signal is
                used by the IDM to synchronize the injector firing sequence. This signal is calculated from the signal
                generated from the Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP). The CI signal is generated by the ECM by "pulling
                down" (switching to grd.) a12 volt communication circuit in the IDM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Demand Command Signal -</emph>Fuel Demand Command signal is a 0 to12 volt wave
                form signal that communicates from the ECM to the IDM the required engine timing and duration of
                injector firing. The timing and duration of the signal is determined by ECM calibration and the signals
                of various sensor inputs. The FDCS signal is generated by the ECM by "pulling down" (switching to
                ground) a 12 volt communication circuit in the IDM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injector Driver Module Feedback -</emph>Injector Driver Module Feedback signal is a 0
                to12 volt wave form signal that communicates from the IDM to the ECM a mirror image of the FDCS signal.
                Extensions of the EF (Electronic Feedback) signal can indicate to the ECM possible problems with the
                injectors by the IDM as the engine is running. A EF toggle (100 hz. signal) generated when the key is
                first turned "ON" and before the engine starts, communicates to the ECM that the IDM is powered up. In
                an engine off or engine running diagnostic mode, the EF signal is also used to communicate diagnostic
                information from the IDM to the ECM. The EF signal is generated by the IDM by "pulling down" (switching
                to grd) a12 volt communications circuit in the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cylinder Identification -</emph>Intermittent open or short to ground conditions can be
                detected by the IDM through IDM stuck high or low codes (532 &#38; 531). Active faults can be detected
                by an on demand output circuit check performed during engine off tests.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>THE ENGINE WILL NOT OPERATE WITHOUT A FUNCTIONING CI CIRCUIT</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Demand Command Signal -</emph>Active faults can be detected by an on demand
                output circuit check performed during engine off tests.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>THE ENGINE WILL NOT OPERATE WITHOUT A FUNCTIONING FDCS CIRCUIT</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injector Driver Module Feedback -</emph>Active faults can be detected by a toggle
                sequence that the ECM looks for on start up. The WARN lamp will be illuminated if this is detected.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>IDM DIAGNOSTIC FAULT CODES WILL NOT BE TRANSMITTED IF THE EF LINE IS NOT FUNCTIONING, HOWEVER,
                        THE ENGINE WILL OPERATE NORMALLY.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450378">Figure 3.57 ECM/IDM Communication Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450378" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5998" filename="../figeg5/EG5998.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.57 ECM/IDM Communication Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">FUNCTION</emph>
            </title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes an Electronic Control Module (ECM) and an Injector Drive
                Module (IDM). The IDM's primary functions are to supply high current and voltage to power the injectors
                and to electrically "turn on" individual injectors upon command by the ECM. The ECM communicates and
                controls injector timing and fuel quantity and communicates engine position to the IDM to insure correct
                fueling timing, quantity and firing sequence. The IDM is also capable of feeding back or handshaking
                information received from the ECM and of communicating diagnostic information pertinent to injector or
                IDM operation to the ECM. Information is transmitted between the IDM and ECM on three circuits; (CI)
                Cylinder Identification, (FDCS) Fuel Demand Command Signal and (EF) Electronic Feedback.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Cylinder Identification (CI)</emph>
                is the signal from the ECM to the IDM to indicate the beginning of the firing order. This signal is
                generated by the ECM to indicate to the IDM the position of #1 cylinder and synchronize injector firing
                order to engine position. Engine position is detected by the Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor by
                identifying the sync window in the timing disk. (Refer to CMP sensor for complete function)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Fuel Demand Command Signal (FDCS)</emph>
                is the signal sent by the ECM to the IDM to indicate the beginning and ending of each injection cycle.
                This precise "On/Off" signal controls the fuel timing and rate by varying the beginning and ending of
                injection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Electronic Feedback (EF)</emph>
                signal is sent from the IDM to the ECM to verify IDM operation and communicate diagnostic information.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>On initial power up, the IDM will signal the ECM with a constant 100 Hz signal that it has
                        successfully initialized.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>During engine operation, the EF signal mirrors the FDCS signal to the ECM to verify FDCS
                        reception by the IDM and will modify the EF signal if certain injector faults are detected
                        during engine operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After a "Engine Off Standard Test" is performed, the EF signal will communicate diagnostic
                        information stored in the IDM pertaining to IDM function or injector operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CYLINDER IDENTIFICATION (CI)</title>
            <para>When the IDM is powered up, 12 volts is supplied from pin 16 of the IDM to pin 34 of the ECM. The ECM
                will "pull down" this 12 volts low to approximately .6 volts (the voltage drop across an internal
                transistor in the ECM). After the ECM has received a sync signal from the CMP sensor and can identify
                the position of cylinder #1, it will toggle CI and allow it to go high (12 volts), 180of camshaft
                rotation later or 360of crankshaft rotation the ECM will again pull the CI signal low (.6 volts). This
                indicates to the IDM to initiate the firing sequence 1 - 5 - 3 when it receives the high signal and 6 -
                2 - 4 when it receives the low signal. This signal will be repeated every camshaft revolution.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL DEMAND COMMAND SIGNAL (FDCS)</title>
            <para>When the IDM is powered up,12 volts is also supplied from pin 12 of the IDM to pin 22 of the ECM, the
                ECM will "pull down" this 12 volts low to approximately .6 volts (the voltage drop across an internal
                transistor in the ECM). After the IDM has received the CI signal, the ECM will toggle the FDCS signal
                high and low to indicate to the IDM the beginning and ending of injector operation for each cylinder.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>THE ENGINE REQUIRES A FUNCTIONING CI AND FDCS SIGNAL TO OPERATE.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ELECTRONIC FEEDBACK (EF)</title>
            <para>After the ignition key is turned "ON" and the ECM and IDM relays are enabled, the IDM is powered up
                and performs it's internal self checks. To signal that the IDM is initialized, a 100 Hz signal is
                transmitted on the EF circuit to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>During engine operation, the EF signal mirrors the FDCS signal to the ECM to verify FDCS reception by
                the IDM and will modify the EF signal if certain injector faults are detected during engine operation.
            </para>
            <para>After a "Engine Off Standard Test" is performed, the EF signal will communicate diagnostic information
                stored in the IDM pertaining to IDM function or injector operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IDM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The IDM monitors operation of output circuits during engine operation. Output circuits that are
                shorted or open are detected by the IDM and are subsequently disabled if necessary to prevent damage to
                the output drivers. This will set a fault code. When a fault is detected during operation an EF
                "extension", transfers fault information to the ECM. Not all faults can be transfered during engine
                operation. However, faults are stored in the IDM when they are detected. These faults are transmitted
                during the "Engine Off Tests", as inactive faults.
            </para>
            <para>At start up, the IDM performs a Self Test of internal components to determine if they are operating
                satisfactorily. The IDM compares the signal inputs to determine if the signal voltages are within
                specification, if not a fault code will be set. These faults are also transferred to the ECM on command
                as inactive faults.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the timing of the EF signal while the engine is running. When it detects a fault sent
                from the IDM, it will log the transfer. However, it will be necessary to perform an Engine Off Standard
                Test to determine most fault codes stored in the IDM. The Engine Off Test may be initiated by the
                Electronic Service Tool or the STI Self Test Input switch located on the vehicle dash.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM continually measures the communication signal voltage levels. If the voltage levels are lower
                or higher than expected, a fault code will be set to identify the circuit or component. The fault will
                be automatically recorded as an active code. If the ignition key is turned off, the fault will be stored
                as an inactive code.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 242</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 154 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>FDCS CIRCUIT TO IDM OCC SELF TEST FAILED</title>
            </para>
            <para>During the Engine Off Standard Output Circuit Check test, Code 242 will be set by the ECM, if the ECM
                did not detect a voltage transition on the FDCS circuit. This code will not cause the Engine Warning
                light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Code 242 may be caused by a shorted high or low or open FDCS circuit. If accompanied by other
                communication codes could indicate the IDM is not powered up. This fault must be repaired for the engine
                to operate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 253</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 153 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>FUEL INJ SYNC CIRCUIT OCC SELF TEST FAILED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 253 will be set during the Engine Off Standard Output Circuit Check test. This code is set
                by the ECM and indicates no voltage transition detected on the Cylinder Identification circuit. This
                fault will not cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes are a shorted (high or low) or open CI circuit. If accompanied by other communication
                codes could indicate the IDM is not powered up. This fault must be repaired for the engine to run.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 531</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 153 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>FUEL INJ. SYNC SIGNAL LOW</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 531 is set by the IDM and is transmitted to the ECM on command from the ECM during the
                Engine Off Standard Test. This code indicates the IDM has detected an FDCS signal and the CI signal has
                remained at 0 volts. This code will cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible cause may be a short to ground in the CI circuit. This code must be repaired for the engine
                to run.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 532</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 153 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>FUEL INJ. SYNC SIGNAL HIGH</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 532 is set by the IDM and is transmitting to the ECM on command from the ECM during the
                Engine Off Standard Test. This code indicates the IDM has detected and FDCS signal and CI signal has
                remained at 12 volts. This code will cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes are a short to a voltage source or an open CI circuit.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 541</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 155 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>IDM FEEDBACK TOGGLE NOT DETECTED BY ECM</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 541 is set by the ECM. The ECM monitors the CI, FDCS and EF signals for voltage levels. If
                the ECM detects that the CI or FDCS is open or if the EF signal is not sending a 100 Hz signal, this
                code will be set. This code will cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes are a short or open on the EF circuit if this code is the only code present. If
                accompanied by other IDM circuit faults the IDM may not be powered or operational. If displayed during a
                Engine Off Standard Test it will be accompanied by code 543. This code may be set due to other faults in
                the ECM due to a reset condition. If other codes are present repair them first in the order of
                importance for engine operation. This code should not prevent engine operation by itself.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 543</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 155 FMI 7</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>IDM FAULTS NOT RECEIVED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 543 is set by the ECM during a Engine Off Standard Output Circuit Check test. This
                indicates that the ECM has commanded the transmission of fault codes from the IDM and has not received
                the codes. If this code occurs, first record any active or inactive codes. Then clear the codes and
                rerun the Engine Off Standard test. This code will cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for this code would be opens or shorts in the IDM / ECM communications circuits or an
                IDM not powered. If accompanied by other faults repair the other faults first in the order of importance
                for engine operation. This code should not prevent engine operation by itself.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450379" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5999" filename="../figeg5/EG5999.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.58 Injector Drive Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450380">Figure 3.59 ECM IDM Communications</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450380" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6000" filename="../figeg6/EG6000.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.59 ECM IDM Communications</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450379">3.58</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450381">Figure 3.59a ECM IDM Communications</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450381" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6001" filename="../figeg6/EG6001.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.59a ECM IDM Communications</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450316.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450319.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
