<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - SPEEDOMETER SIGNAL
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450338" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="9">
        <title>SPEEDOMETER SIGNAL</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i0">Figure 3.155 Speedometer Signal</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503i0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6092" filename="../figeg6/eg6092.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.155 Speedometer Signal</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The vehicle speed signal from the speed sensor is input to the VPM. VPM programming includes number of
                teeth on the sensor wheel, tire size and axle ratios. Using this information, the VPM creates a signal
                which is sent to the speedometer/tachometer cluster as input for the speedometer function.
            </para>
            <para>The VPM also outputs a DCL formatted vehicle speed signal over the DCL data link circuit to the ECM.
                The ECM uses the input for controlling vehicle functions including cruise control, engine brake, etc.
            </para>
            <para>Additionally the VPM outputs an ATA formatted signal over the ATA data link to the diagnostic
                connector where vehicle speed can be read using the Prolink EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>The vehicle speed sensor signal is monitored continuously by the VPM to see that the signal is within
                certain range. If the VSS signal is out-of-range, the VPM sends an out-of-range high signal to the ECM,
                telling the ECM that the VPM detected a fault in the VSS.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM sees the out-of-range high signal, VPM Flash code 141 or 142 is set, but the Engine
                Warning light is NOT turned on. The ECM disables operation of the Cruise Control or PTO. If Road Speed
                Limiting is enabled, the ECM will limit engine speed in all gears. Torque level tailoring will use a
                prescribed torque curve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Codes</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the vehicle speedometer does not operate properly, but no fault codes are present, use the
                        Prolink to attempt to read vehicle speed from the ATA data link connector. If vehicle speed can
                        be read using the Prolink, troubleshoot circuit 47B and the instrument cluster.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i1">Figure 3.156 Speedometer Signal Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503i1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6093" filename="../figeg6/eg6093.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.156 Speedometer Signal Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VPM Harness Connector Checks to Chassis Ground</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Connector (381) with VPM disconnected and connector (27) disconnected and key OFF
                </emph>
            </para>
            <table id="et1450326">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="72p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="90p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="306p"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>cir 47 to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>>100K ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>&#60; less than 100K ohms check for short to grd or defective sensor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>cir 47A to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>> 100K ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>&#60;less than 100K ohms check for short to grd or defective sensor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>cir 47 to 47A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>600 - 800 ohms</para>
                                <para>(manual xmsn)</para>
                                <para>1200-1450 ohms</para>
                                <para>(auto xmsn)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>> than specified ohms, check for open circuit or sensor</para>
                                <para>&#60; than specified ohms, check for short between circuits or defective sensor.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>47B to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>>100 K ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>&#60; less than 100K ohms check for short to ground</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>47B to (27) 47B</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>&#60; 5 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>> than 5 ohms check for open in circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>VPM Harness Voltage Checks</para>
            <para>Voltage check at Connector (381) with VPM disconnected and connector (27) disconnected and key ON
            </para>
            <table id="et1450327">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="72p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="90p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="306p"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>47 to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>&#60; 1.0 volt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>> than 1.0 volt check for short to VREF or Batt circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>47A to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>&#60; 1.0 volt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>> than 1.0 volt check for short to VREF or Batt circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>47B to grd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>&#60; 1.0 volt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>> than 1.0 volt check for short to VREF or Batt circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Operational Voltage Checks</para>
            <para>Connect (381) to VPM and (27) to cluster. Disconnect sensor pigtail at (303). Place rear axles on
                stands (front wheels blocked) and with engine at idle and transmission in high gear, measure AC voltage
                from sensor.
            </para>
            <table id="et1450328">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="72p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="90p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="306p"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>white to black</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>> 2.0 A.C. volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>&#60; less than 2.0 volts check sensor adjustment or defective sensor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>extended description</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Signal (VSS) from the VPM is sent over the DCL data link to the ECM. The VSS
                information is used by the ECM to control features such as: Cruise Control, PTO, Torque Level Tailoring
                and Road Speed Limiting.
            </para>
            <para>The VPM also provides VSS input to the vehicle speedometer, tachometer and odometer unit located in
                the instrument panel.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to circuit diagram
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i2">3.157</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor (303)</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) is located on the transmission and sends an AC signal to the VPM. The
                VSS sensor contains a permanent magnet which creates a magnetic field. The AC signal is created when the
                16-tooth transmission speedometer gear rotates breaking the magnetic field created by the sensor. The
                VSS signal is sent through the engine and cab harness to the VPM.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, Navistar installs the speed sensor at the rear of the transmission. With
                an Allison AT/MT transmission, Allison installs the sensor at the lower right side of the transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VPM (Vehicle Personality Module)</title>
            <para>The VPM (381) receives the AC signal from the vehicle speed sensor. The VPM programming includes the
                rear axle ratio and tire size. It uses this programmed information and the speed sensor input to create
                the vehicle speed signal sent to the Speedometer Unit.
            </para>
            <para>From VPM connector (381), terminal 18, an analog AC signal is input on circuit 47B to the vehicle
                speedometer unit through connector (27). Speedometer ground circuit 47-G from connector (27) is grounded
                at the cab ground stud.
            </para>
            <para>The VSS signal is also formatted so that it can be sent over the Digital Communications Link (DCL) to
                the ECM (379).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Diagnostics</title>
            <para>
                <title>Flash Codes</title>
            </para>
            <para>During vehicle operation, the vehicle speed signal (VSS) is monitored continuously by the VPM to see
                that the signal is within certain range. If the VSS signal is out-of-range, the VPM sends an
                out-of-range high signal to the ECM, telling the ECM that the VPM detected a fault in the VSS.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM sees the out-of-range high signal, VPM Flash code 141 or 142 is set, but the Engine
                Warning light is NOT turned on. The ECM disables operation of the Cruise Control or PTO. If Road Speed
                Limiting is enabled, the ECM will limit engine speed in all gears. Torque level tailoring will use a
                prescribed torque curve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 141</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 84 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VPM: VSS ORL</title>
            </para>
            <para>This code is set when the VPM detects an out-of-range low (ORL) signal from the vehicle speed
                sensor.
            </para>
            <para>WIRING CAUSE: VSS Sensor circuit between the VPM and Sensor, shorted to ground or open.</para>
            <para>If this code is active, perform Testing VPM to Sensor Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i3">3.158</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 142</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 84 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VPM: VSS ORH</title>
            </para>
            <para>This code is set when the VPM detects an out-of-range high (ORH) signal from the vehicle speed
                sensor.
            </para>
            <para>WIRING CAUSE: VSS Sensor circuit shorted to VREF or VBAT circuit.</para>
            <para>If this code is active, perform Testing VPM to Sensor Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i3">3.158</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedometer Does Not Function Properly</title>
            <para>The ECM/VPM diagnostics DO NOT check for VSS sensor adjustment, so it is possible with a mis-adjusted
                vehicle speed sensor to get a faulty vehicle speed signal
                <emph type="bold">without fault code 141 or 142</emph>. The speedometer and/or odometer will operate
                erratically or not at all. The odometer may not function correctly.
            </para>
            <para>If Flash code 141 or 142 IS NOT PRESENT, but the speedometer and/or odometer does not function
                properly, perform Testing Speedometer
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i7">3.162</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If Flash code 141 or 142 is present and the speedometer does not function properly, correct the cause
                of the Flash Codes before troubleshooting the speedometer.
            </para>
            <para>If the speedometer/odometer does not function properly when the Two-Speed Axle is shifted (HIGH or
                LOW), refer to Two Speed Axle in this section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the batteries are fully charged! Check
                        battery connections and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage. Voltage tests will
                        give misleading results if the batteries are not fully charged.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose, or
                        damaged (spread or bent) terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. Wires and connections must
                        be free of damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be
                        present that must be removed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections
                        free of damage.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef14503i2" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg6094" filename="../figeg6/eg6094.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3.157 Circuit Diagram</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef14503i3" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg6095" filename="../figeg6/eg6095.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3.158 Testing VPM To Sensor Circuits</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>* - Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i2">3.157</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>** - Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i5">3.160</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>*** - Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i6">3.161</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i4">Figure 3.159 Testing VPM To Sensor Circuits</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503i4" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6096" filename="../figeg6/eg6096.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.159 Testing VPM To Sensor Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef14503i5" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6097" filename="../figeg6/eg6097.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.160 Vehicle Speed Sensor Test With Manual Transmission</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>* - Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i2">3.157</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>** - Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i3">3.158</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef14503i6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6098" filename="../figeg6/eg6098.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.161 Vehicle Speed Sensor Test With Allison AT or MT Transmission</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>* - Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i2">3.157</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>** - Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i3">3.158</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If Flash Codes are not present indicating that a VSS signal problem has been detected by
                    the VPM or ECM, but the speedometer and/or odometer are not functioning properly, perform this test.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503i7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6099" filename="../figeg6/eg6099.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.162 Testing Speedometer</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>* - Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i2">3.157</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503i8">Figure 3.163 Testing Speedometer</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <figure id="ef14503i8" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg6100" filename="../figeg6/eg6100.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.163 Testing Speedometer</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450337.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_129.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
