<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE (EOT) SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450323" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE (EOT) SENSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a5">Figure 3.80 Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1128" filename="../figeg1/EG1128.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.80 Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) sensor is a thermistor type sensor that has a variable resistance
                which changes when exposed to different temperatures. When interfaced with the ECM, it produces a 0 to 5
                volt analog signal that indicates temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cranking Fuel Quantity/Timing Control -</emph>The EOT signal is used to determine the
                timing and quantity of fuel required to optimize starting over all temperature conditions.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Temperature Compensation -</emph>Fuel quantity and timing is controlled throughout the
                total operating range to compensate for oil viscosity changes due to temperature variations and insure
                that adequate torque and power is available.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>An EOT signal that is detected out of range high or low by the ECM will cause the ECM to ignore the
                EOT signal and default to the engine coolant temperature (ECT) sensor. The WARN engine lamp will also be
                illuminated as long as the fault condition exists. If both the EOT and ECT sensors are not functioning,
                the ECM will assume a 212F (100C) value for engine oil temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a6">Figure 3.81 Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6024" filename="../figeg6/EG6024.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.81 Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) sensor. The ECM monitors
                engine oil temperature via the EOT sensor signal to control fuel quantity and timing throughout the
                operating range of the engine. The EOT signal allows the ECM to compensate for oil viscosity variations
                due to temperature changes in the operating environment. This insures that adequate power and torque are
                available under all operating conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Engine Oil Temperature Sensor is a thermistor type sensor which changes resistance when exposed to
                different oil temperatures.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature of the oil is decreased the resistance of the thermistor increases which causes
                the signal voltage to increase. As the temperature of the oil is increased, the resistance of the
                thermistor decreases, causing the signal voltage to decrease.
            </para>
            <para>The EOT sensor is supplied a regulated 5 volt reference signal at terminal B from ECM terminal 14. A
                return circuit (ground) is supplied at terminal A from ECM terminal 46. As the oil temperature increases
                or decreases, the sensor changes resistance and provides the ECM with the oil temperature signal voltage
                at terminal 14. This signal voltage is then read by the ECM to determine the temperature of the oil.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>With the ignition key "ON", the ECM continuously monitors the EOT signal to determine if it is within
                expected values. If the signal voltage is above or below the expected levels, the ECM will set a fault
                code.
            </para>
            <para>If the ECM detects a fault, it will use the value of the Engine Coolant Temperature signal, in place
                of the EOT signal. If the ECT sensor is not sending a correct signal, the ECM will default to 29F
                (-1.7C) for starting or 212F (100C) for engine running operation.
            </para>
            <para>EOT sensor faults can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or by reading the flash codes
                from the warning light using the STI diagnostic switch located on the vehicle dash. If the ignition key
                is shut off, the code will become an Inactive code. EOT codes will cause the Engine Warning light to be
                illuminated.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 311</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 175 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 311 out of range low, will be set if the signal voltage was less than 0.2 volts for more than 0.1
                seconds. If this code is set, the ECM will default to ECT temperature or a default value of -4F (-20C)
                for starting or 212F (100C) for engine running operation. This code will cause the ECM to illuminate the
                Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>Code 311 may be set due to a short to ground in the signal circuit or a defective sensor.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 312</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 175 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 312 out of range high,will be set if the signal voltage is more than 4.8 volts for more than 0.1
                seconds. If this code is set, the ECM will default to ECT temperature or a default value of -4F (-20C)
                for starting or 212F (100C) for engine running operation. This code will cause the ECM to illuminate the
                Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>Code 312 may be set due to an open signal circuit between the ECM and the sensor or a short to a
                voltage source. A defective sensor may also cause code 312 to be set.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6025" filename="../figeg6/EG6025.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.82 Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a8">Figure 3.83 Engine OIl Temperature (EOT) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503a8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6026" filename="../figeg6/EG6026.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.83 Engine OIl Temperature (EOT) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503a7">3.82</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450322.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450324.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
