<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUIT OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450328" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUIT OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c3">Figure 3.98 Injector Drive Circuit Operation</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6040" filename="../figeg6/EG6040.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.98 Injector Drive Circuit Operation</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High Side Drive Outputs -</emph>The high side drive output function is to supply to
                the injectors a power supply of 115 volt DC at a maximum of 10 amps. There are two separate high side
                drivers. One for the front three injectors (cylinders 1,2 and 3) and one for the rear three injectors
                (cylinders 4,5 and 6).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low Side Drive Outputs -</emph>The low side drive outputs control the injector on time
                (fuel quantity), timing (in relation to TDC) and sequencing (firing order). The IDM controls (fires)
                each individual injector by completing the ground circuit to each injector solenoid. A valid Cylinder
                Identification (CI) and Fuel Demand Command Signal (FDCS) must be sent from the ECM to the IDM before an
                injector will be allowed to fire.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>The Injector Driver Module (IDM) is capable of detecting, while the engine is running individual
                injector open and shorts to either ground or battery. It is also capable of detecting high side opens or
                shorts to ground. A special On-Demand Buzz test will also allow the operator to enable all injector
                solenoids while the engine is off to verify circuit operation.
                <emph type="bold">IDM detected diagnostic fault codes will not be transmitted if the EF line is not
                    functioning, however, the engine will function normally.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If a short to ground condition is detected on an individual injector, (low side), the IDM will
                discontinue the power to the bank with the shorted injector, enable the WARN engine lamp and operate the
                engine on three cylinders.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c4">Figure 3.99 Injector Drive Circuit Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6041" filename="../figeg6/EG6041.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.99 Injector Drive Circuit Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes an ECM (Electronic Control Module) and an IDM (Injector
                Drive Module). The ECM provides the IDM with two important output signals which control fuel injector
                operation. The ECM uses the fuel quantity control strategy and input from the engine sensors to
                determine how long each fuel injector is actuated in order to provide the proper fuel quantity at any
                given engine operating condition. The ECM determines and provides a fuel output signal, FDCS (Fuel
                Demand Command Signal), by combining the desired length of each injection with the result of the
                injection timing control strategy which determines when each injection will occur. The second output
                signal, (CI) Cylinder Identification, enables the IDM to determine the correct injector firing order.
            </para>
            <para>The IDM processes the FDCS and CI signals sent by the ECM to control injector operation. It amplifies
                the FDCS signal to make it powerful enough to operate the injectors and distributes it to each injector
                according to the CI signal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The IDM contains two solid state high side drivers. Each driver supplies a continuous 115 volts DC.
                Bank 1 driver supplies cylinders 1 through 3 with 115 volts at terminal 24 of the IDM to terminal A of
                the valve cover connector. Bank 2 driver supplies cylinders 4 through 6 at terminal 23 of the IDM to
                terminal L of the valve cover connector. The IDM turns each injector on by switching on a solid state
                device (Low Side Driver) to ground the injector solenoid return circuit. The IDM contains a low side
                driver for each of the injectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IDM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The IDM monitors the voltage on the driver circuits and is capable of detecting an open or shorted
                circuit. If the IDM detects a short to ground or a multiple fault in a driver, the IDM will discontinue
                operation of that driver which would cause the engine to operate on the remaining bank of 3 cylinders.
                The IDM will transmit a message to the ECM that a fault has been detected. The ECM will respond by
                illuminating the Engine Warning Light and compensating for inoperative cylinders to keep the engine
                running if mechanically possible.
            </para>
            <para>Faults detected by the IDM will be stored in the IDM and transmitted to the ECM during an "Engine Off
                Standard Test". These faults will be transmitted as Inactive faults. Faults can be retrieved using the
                Electronic Service Tool or the STI Self Test Input Diagnostic Switch located on the vehicle dash.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>the last digit of the flash code indicates the affected cylinder number. For example, code 421
                        indicates cylinder no. 1 has an open circuit between the IDM high side driver and the low side
                        (signal return) to the idm. The SID no.s 1-6, indicate cylinder no.s in a similar manner.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Flash Code 421 THROUGH 426</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 6 FMI 5</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>LOW SIDE TO HIGH SIDE OPEN</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash Codes for Low Side to High Side Open indicate an open circuit between the IDM high side driver
                and the low side (Signal return) to the IDM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating. The ECM will not illuminate
                the Engine Warning light when this situation occurs.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Open wire in injector harness, open injector return circuit or injector solenoid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 431 THROUGH 436</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 6 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>LOW SIDE SHORTED TO HIGH SIDE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash codes for Low Side Shorted to High Side indicate the return voltage is too high due to a short
                circuit between the high side driver and return circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating. The ECM will not illuminate
                the Engine Warning light when this situation occurs.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Shorted injector solenoid or wiring harness.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 441 THROUGH 446</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 6 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>LOW SIDE SHORTED TO B+</title>
            </para>
            <para>Low Side Shorted to B+ indicates the IDM has detected continuous battery voltage on the signal return
                circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating. The ECM will not illuminate
                the Engine Warning light when this situation occurs.
            </para>
            <para>A short circuit in the injector wiring harness will set these codes.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 451 THROUGH 456</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 6 FMI 6</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>LOW SIDE SHORTED TO GROUND</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash codes for Low Side Shorted to Ground indicate the return circuit shorted to ground.</para>
            <para>If the IDM detects this fault, it will disable the entire bank of cylinders associated with the
                cylinder indicated.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Shorted injector solenoid or wiring harness to ground.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 511</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BANK 1 HAS MULTIPLE FAULTS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Multiple Faults indicates more than one fault was detected by the IDM, such as an open and a short
                circuit in cylinders 1 through 3.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 511 active, the IDM will disable the drivers for cylinders 1 through 3. The ECM will
                compensate for misfire to keep the engine operatiing and will illuminate the Engine Warning Light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 512</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BANK 2 HAS MULTIPLE FAULTS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Multiple Faults indicates more than one fault was detected by the IDM, such as an open and a short
                circuit in cylinders 4 through 6.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 512 active, the IDM will disable the drivers for cylinders 4 through 6. The ECM will
                compensate for misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning Light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 513</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 5</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>HIGH SIDE TO BANK 1 OPEN</title>
            </para>
            <para>With the High Side to Bank 1 Open, the IDM has detected an open circuit to the injectors on cylinders
                1 through 3.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 513 active, the drivers for cylinders 1 through 3 are inoperative . The ECM will
                compensate for misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 514</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 5</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>HIGH SIDE TO BANK 2 OPEN</title>
            </para>
            <para>With the High Side to Bank 2 Open, the IDM has detected an open circuit to the injectors on cylinders
                4 through 6.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 513 active, the drivers for cylinders 4 through 6 are inoperative . The ECM will
                compensate for misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 515</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 6</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BANK 1 HIGH SIDE SHORT TO GROUND OR B+</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 515 indicates the IDM has detected the high side driver for cylinders 1 through 3 has
                excessive current draw.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 515 active, the driver for cylinders 1 through 3 will be disabled. The ECM will
                compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine running. This code will cause the Engine Warning light
                to be illuminated.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 521</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 6</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BANK 2 HIGH SIDE SHORT TO GROUND OR B+</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 521 indicates the IDM has detected excessive current draw on high side driver for cylinders
                4 through 6.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 521 active, the driver for cylinders 4 through 6 will be disabled. The ECM will
                compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 524</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BOTH HIGH SIDE SWITCHES SHORTED TOGETHER</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 524 indicates a short circuit between the two high side drivers.</para>
            <para>With this code active, the Engine Warning light will be illuminated.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 544</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 14</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INJECTOR FAULT BANK #2</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 544 indicates ECM has detected more than one injector in Bank #2 with low voltage.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 545</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 14</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INJECTOR FAULT BANK #1</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 545 indicates ECM has detected more than one injector in Bank #1 with low voltage.</para>
            <figure id="ef14503c5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6042" filename="../figeg6/EG6042.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.100 Injector Drive Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c6">Figure 3.101 Injector Drive Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6043" filename="../figeg6/EG6043.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.101 Injector Drive Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c5">3.100</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503c7">Figure 3.102 Injector Drive Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503c7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6044" filename="../figeg6/EG6044.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.102 Injector Drive Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450327.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450329.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
