<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450320" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE SENSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450388">Figure 3.64 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450388" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6008" filename="../figeg6/eg6008.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.64 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor is a thermister type sensor that has a variable resistance
                that changes when exposed to different temperatures. When interfaced with the ECM it produces a 0 to 5
                volt analog signal that will measure temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Coolant Temperature Compenstion</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold"></emph>At coolant temperatures greater than 214F (101C) fuel quantity is reduced by 6%
                for each degree of temperature (C), until engine temperature reaches 218F (103C) . Above 218F (103C)
                fuel is reduced by 3% for each C increase in temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Idle Speed</emph>
                -
                <emph type="bold"></emph>At temperatures below 158F, (70C) low idle is incremently increased to a
                maximum of 875 RPM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Warning and Protection -</emph>
                Optional feature when enabled will warn driver of overheat condition and can be programmed to shut the
                engine down.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault detection/management</title>
            <para>An ECT signal that is detected out of range high or low by the ECM will cause the ECM to ignore the
                ECT signal and assume an engine coolant temperature of -29F (-20C) for starting and a temperature of
                180F (82C) for engine running conditions. The WARN lamp will also be illuminated as long as the fault
                condition exists.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450389">Figure 3.65 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450389" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6009" filename="../figeg6/eg6009.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.65 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE SENSOR EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>
                <title>FUNCTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Engine Coolant Temperature sensor. The ECM measures the
                Engine Coolant Temperature signal and uses this information for Coolant Temperature Compensation and
                optional high temperature warning and shut down systems.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant temperature Compensation is used to protect the engine if the coolant temperature is too high.
                The ECM monitors the ECT signal to determine the coolant temperature. If the coolant reaches 214F(101C
                ), the ECM will reduce the fuel delivery by 6% for each Celsius degree of temperature increase. If the
                coolant temperature increases to 218F(104C), fuel quantity will be reduced 3% for each Celsius degree of
                temperature increase. Coolant Temperature Compensation can be programmed to be inoperative in certain
                applications where full engine performance is required over the protection of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>On engines equipped with an engine warning system, the ECM will activate the audible warning alarm and
                illuminate the yellow Oil/Water warning light when the engine coolant temperature reaches 225F (107C).
            </para>
            <para>On engines equipped with an engine shut down system, the ECM will shut the engine off when the coolant
                temperature reaches 235F (112.5C). The vehicle operator may restart the engine by turning the ignition
                key "OFF" and then restarting it. Upon restart, the ECM will allow the engine to run for an additional
                30 seconds, before shutting off the engine again.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Engine Coolant temperature sensor is a thermistor type sensor which changes resistance when
                exposed to different temperatures.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature of the coolant is decreased, the resistance of the thermistor increases which
                causes the signal voltage to increase. As the temperature of the coolant is increased the resistance of
                the thermistor decreases, which causes the signal voltage to decrease.
            </para>
            <para>The ECT sensor is supplied a regulated 5 volt reference voltage from ECM terminal 7. The sensor is
                grounded at terminal A through the signal return, terminal 46, at the ECM. As the coolant temperature
                increases or decreases, the sensor changes resistance and provides the ECM with the coolant temperature
                signal voltage at terminal 7 of the ECM. This signal voltage is then read by the ECM to determine the
                temperature of the coolant.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>With the ignition key "ON", the ECM continuously monitors the ECT circuit for expected voltages. If
                the signal voltage is less than or more than expected the ECM will set a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>If the ECM detects a fault in the ECT signal, the ECM will disregard the signal and default to a
                temperature of 180F (82C) for engine running operation and -29F (-33.9C) for starting the engine. If the
                fault is no longer present, the ECM will once again return to normal operation using the ECT signal for
                processing.
            </para>
            <para>Faults in the ECT signal can be retrieved using the Self Test Input Switch (STI) or the Electronic
                Service Tool. If the fault is no longer present, it will be stored as an Inactive Code.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 114</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 4</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECT: OUT OF RANGE LOW</title>
            </para>
            <para>An out of range low code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage less than .127 volts for more than
                0.1 seconds. If this fault is Active, the ECM will use the default value of 180F (82C).
            </para>
            <para>Code 114 may be caused by a short to ground or a shorted or biased sensor.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 115</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 3</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECT: OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            </para>
            <para>An out of range high code will be set if the ECM detects a voltage greater than 4.6 volts for more
                than 0.1 seconds. If this fault is Active, the ECM will use the a default value of 180F (82C).
            </para>
            <para>Code 115 may be caused by an open circuit, an open sensor, or a short to another voltage source.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 321</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 0</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE ABOVE WARNING LEVEL</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 321 will be set if the ECM detects engine coolant temperature above 225F (107C). When this
                occurs, the ECM illuminates the OIL/WATER warning light and sounds the audible alarm (if equipped),
                alerting the operator that a potential for engine damage exists.
            </para>
            <para>If the temperature drops below 225F(107C), the code will become inactive and the ECM will return to
                normal operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 322</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 7</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ENGINE COOLANT TEMPERATURE ABOVE CRITICAL LEVEL</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 322 will be set if the ECM detects engine coolant temperature above 235F (112.5C). When this
                occurs, the OIL/WATER warning light illuminates and the audible alarm sounds (if equipped) will alert
                the operator that the temperature is increasing (having set code 321) indicating a potential for engine
                damage. With code 322 active, the engine will shut down. At the same time the code and current engine
                hours will be recorded in the VPM as an Engine Event.
            </para>
            <para>If the temperature drops below 235F (112.5C), the code will become inactive and the ECM will return to
                normal operation. Should the engine shut down, it can be restarted to move the vehicle to a safe place.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 325</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 110 FMI 14</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>POWER REDUCED, MATCHED TO COOLING SYSTEM PERFORMANCE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 325 will be set if the cooling system temperature exceeds 214F (101C ). At this temperature the
                ECM will reduce the fuel delivered to the engine at or near the maximum demand level. For each one
                Celsius degree of temperature the fuel will be reduced 6%. This reduces the heat produced by the engine
                thereby reducing the burden on the engine cooling system. It will also slow the vehicle speed
                encouraging the operator to downshift, thus increasing the efficiency of the cooling system.
            </para>
            <para>As the temperature is reduced the compensation level is reduced until the temperature drops below 214F
                (101C ) at which normal operation is resumed.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450390" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6010" filename="../figeg6/eg6010.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.66 Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450391">Figure 3.67 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450391" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6011" filename="../figeg6/eg6011.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.67 Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450390">3.66</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450319.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450321.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
