<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - INJECTION CONTROL
        PRESSURE SYSTEM - IPR VALVE OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>IPR VALVE OPERATION</title>
        <para>The Injection Pressure Regulator valve is a pulse width modulated valve operating at 400 Hz. The pulse
            width is modulated from a duty cycle of 8 to 60% to control ICP pressure from 500 to 3000 psi (3.4 to 20
            mPa). The regulator valve is mounted in the high pressure pump and achieves injection control pressure
            regulation by dumping excess oil through a (shuttle) spool valve into the front cover and back to sump.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450105">1.5</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            illustrates the IPR valve in the Engine Off state. The spool valve is held closed (to the right) by the
            return spring and the drain ports are closed.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1450105" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1092" filename="../figeg1/eg1092.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.5 - Engine Off</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450106">1.6</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            illustrates the IPR valve in the Engine Cranking state. The ECM signals the IPR valve to close which directs
            all the oil to flow into the oil supply galleries to build oil pressure as quickly as possible to start the
            engine.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1450106" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1093" filename="../figeg1/eg1093.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.6 - Engine Cranking</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450107">1.7</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            illustrates the IPR valve in the Engine Running state. The ECM pressure regulating signal determines the
            magnetic field strength of the IPR valve solenoid. The magnetic field pulls the poppet to the left as shown
            in
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450107">1.7</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            . This action allows the pump outlet pressure that is on the spool valve to move the spool valve to the new
            position of the poppet. Poppet movement allows a small amount of oil to enter the spool chamber through the
            spool valve control orifice and filter.
        </para>
        <para>Spool chamber oil pressure is regulated by the ECM by controlling the poppet position. The spool responds
            to pressure changes in the spool chamber by changing position to maintain a balance of pressure on each side
            of the spool. Spool valve position determines the desired injection control pressure by bleeding off oil
            from the pump outlet to the drain port.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef1450107" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1094" filename="../figeg1/eg1094.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.7 - Engine Running</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
