<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection division="ENGINE" id="e14508" svcsectype="prodspec" date="04/29/96">
        <title>GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>GLOSSARY</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Actuator -</emph>
                A device which performs work in response to an electrical signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Address -</emph>
                A specific memory location in the RAM, ROM, or KAM of the ECM. The ECM can either read information from
                an address or send information (write) to an address (RAM or KAM only).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog -</emph>
                A continuously variable voltage.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog to Digital Converter (A/D) -</emph>
                A circuit within the processing section of the ECM that takes an analog signal (either DC or AC) and
                converts it into a usable digital signal for the microprocessor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog Multimeter -</emph>
                A meter that uses a needle to point to a number on a scale of numbers to indicate a measured value
                (volts, ohms, amperes). Not recommended for use on microprocessor systems because of the possibility of
                excessive current due to the low impedance of the meter.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">APS, Accelerator Position Sensor -</emph>
                A potentiometer style sensor that indicates the operator's pedal position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Data Link -</emph>
                A serial data link specified by the American Trucking Association and the SAE.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Background Manager -</emph>
                The portion of the computer that performs "housekeeping duties". Typically the Background Manager
                controls low priority items or items that occur at a slower rate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">BARO Barometric Pressure Sensor -</emph>
                A variable capacitance sensor which, when supplied with a 5 volt reference signal from the ECM, produces
                a linear analog voltage signal indicating pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">BNC, Brake Normally Closed -</emph>
                A on/off switch style sensor used to indicate if the brake is applied. Normal primary function is to
                disengage cruise control. (normally closed).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">BNO, Brake Normally Open -</emph>
                A on/off switch style sensor used to indicate if the brake is applied. Normal primary function is to
                disengage cruise control. (normally open).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Calibration -</emph>
                The data values used by the strategy to solve equations and make decisions. Calibration values are
                stored in the ROM as scalars, functions and tables. Calibration values are input into the processor
                during programming to allow for the engine to operate within certain parameters.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CI, Cylinder Identification -</emph>
                A signal from the ECM to the IDM that identifies the position of the cylinders of the engine
                <emph type="bold">.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CLS, Coolant Level Switch -</emph>
                A switch style sensor used to indicate low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CMP, Camshaft Position Sensor -</emph>
                A Hall effect sensor used to indicate engine speed and camshaft position. Speed is indicated by the
                number of vanes counted per revolution. Camshaft position is indicated by a single narrow vane which
                indicates #1 cylinder position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Continuous Test -</emph>
                A function of the ECM in which the inputs and outputs of the ECM are continuously monitored to assure
                that the readings are within set limits.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DCL, Data Communication Link -</emph>
                A serial communication link between the ECM and the VPM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DDS, Driveline Disengagement Switch -</emph>
                A switch indicating when the transmission is going out of gear.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Disable -</emph>
                A type of computer decision which results in an system being deactivated and not allowed to operate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Driver -</emph>
                A transistor in the output section of the ECM that is used to turn on or off various actuators in the
                system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Duty Cycle Signal -</emph>
                A type of wave signal that has a controlled on/off time measure from 0% to 100%. Normally used to
                control solenoids.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DVOM Digital Volt Ohm Meter -</emph>
                A meter that uses a digital display to indicate a measured value. Preferred for use on microprocessor
                systems, because a DVOM has a very high internal impedance and will not load down the circuit being
                measured.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECI, Engine Crank Inhibit -</emph>
                An output on the ECM that controls the ECI relay and controls when the starter motor is allowed to
                operate and crank the engine over.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM, Electronic Control Module -</emph>
                The housing which contains the micro computer, Vref regulator, input conditioners and output drivers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM Power Relay -</emph>
                Relay which supplies or removes power to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECT, Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor -</emph>
                A thermistor type sensor which indicates engine temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EF IDM Feedback -</emph>
                A communication line from the IDM to the ECM. In run mode, the signal on EF mirrors the FDCS signal
                received by the ECM from the IDM. EF extensions will be used to identity detected problems with
                individual injectors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EFRC, Engine Family Rating Code -</emph>
                A code readable in the calibration list of the VPM with the EST service tool that identifies the
                horsepower and emission calibration of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Off Test -</emph>
                A self test operation that is performed with the ignition switch in the "ON" position with the engine
                off.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Running Test -</emph>
                Self test operation that is performed with the engine running.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP, Engine Oil Pressure sensor -</emph>
                A switch type sensor used to indicate low oil pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOT, Engine Oil Temperature sensor -</emph>
                A thermistor type sensor which senses engine oil temperature. This sensor is used to provide engine
                temperature signal to the ECM which uses the information for fuel rate and timing adjustment.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EST Electronic Service Tool -</emph>
                The scan tool used for accessing diagnostics and programing the electronic control system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EWL - Engine Warning Light Circuit</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FDCS, Fuel Demand Command Signal -</emph>
                Command signal generated by the ECM and sent to the IDM which controls when an injector is energized
                (opened) and how long the injector remains energized (open). This signal determines when and how much
                fuel the injector delivers to the combustion chamber.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FMEM, Failure Modes Effects Management -</emph>
                An alternate control strategy devised to reduce the adverse effects that can be caused by a system
                failure. Should a sensor fail, the ECM substitutes a good sensor signal or assumed sensor value in its
                place. The WARN ENGINE Lamp is then lit to alert the driver to take the vehicle in for service.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Foreground Manager -</emph>
                That portion of the computer that controls the primary engine control functions. The foreground manager
                responds to external events quickly to maintain correct engine performance under a variety of
                conditions. Typically the foreground manager controls high priority items.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Function -</emph>
                An input value to a computer which the computer solves for an output.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fusible Link -</emph>
                A wire designed to melt if more than a specified amount of electrical current flows through it. Often
                used as a main fuse or backup fuse for large sections of the vehicle's wiring harness.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Hall Effect Sensor -</emph>
                A Hall Effect sensor generates a digital on/off signal that indicates speed and also engine timing. The
                signal is created by a switching action caused by the passing of a vanes thru a positive and negative
                voltage potential. When the vane is between this potential a signal is created. When the gap is between
                this potential is open, no signal is generated. The wider the vane the longer the duty cycle of the
                signal, the narrower the vane the shorter the duty cycle of the signal. A narrow vane is used to
                indicate the position of #1 cylinder. A Hall Effect sensor has three connections ground, Vref, and
                signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">HEUI Hydraulically Actuated, Electronically Controlled, Unit Injectors</emph>
                - Description for injectors used in the electronically controlled engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High Speed Digital Inputs -</emph>
                Inputs to the ECM that are from a sensor that generates varying frequencies. Examples of high speed
                digital input sensors are engine speed, vehicle speed and Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IAT, Intake Air Temperature sensor -</emph>
                A thermistor style sensor used to indicate intake air temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ICP, Injector Control Pressure Sensor -</emph>
                A transducer style sensor used to indicate Injection Control Pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IDM, Injection Driver Module-</emph>
                Is an electronic unit which has the primary function of an electronic distributor for the injectors. It
                also is the power supply for the injectors. It supplies 115 volts dc @ 7 amps to the injectors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Impedance -</emph>
                A form of opposition to AC current flow measured in Ohms.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure -</emph>
                High lube oil pressure generated by a high pressure pump/pressure regulator used to hydraulically
                actuate the fuel injectors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Input Conditioner -</emph>
                A device or circuit that conditions or prepares an input signal for use by the microprocessor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IPR, Injection Control Pressure Regulator -</emph>
                An ECM controlled pulse width modulated regulator valve which regulates injection control oil pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IVS, Idle Validation Switch -</emph>
                A on/off switch sensor that indicates when the accelerator pedal is in the idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KAM, Keep Alive Memory -</emph>
                Is a memory location in the microprocessor which allows the ECM to store information on input failures,
                identified in normal operations for use in diagnostic routines. Keep Alive Memory can also store
                alternate calibration parameters generated by the FMEM strategy in event of sensor failure or wear. KAM
                memory is volatile and will be lost if power is disconnected.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KAMPWR -</emph>
                The circuit that continuously supplies KAM memory with 12 volts to prevent the loss of KAM memory.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low Speed Digital Inputs -</emph>
                Are switched sensor inputs that generate an on/off (high/low) signal to the ECM. The input supplied to
                the ECM from the sensor could be from a high input source switch (usually 12 or 5 volts) or could be
                from a grounding type switch which grounds the signal from a current limiting resistor internal to the
                ECM and creates a low signal. (0 volts)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">MAP, Manifold Absolute Pressure -</emph>
                A MAP sensor is a sensor that generates a digital frequency that indicates manifold boost pressure or
                vacuum. The signal is created by switching action caused by manifold pressure on a diaphragm connected
                to a capacitor circuit in the sensor. The digital frequency increases as pressure increases. A MAP
                sensor has three connections, signal return (grd), MAP signal and Vref.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Microprocessor -</emph>
                An integrated circuit within a micro computer which controls information flow within the computer.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normally Closed -</emph>
                Refers to a switch or a solenoid that is closed when no control force is acting on it.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normally Open -</emph>
                Refers to a switch or solenoid that is open when no control force is acting on it.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">On Demand Test -</emph>
                A self test which the technician initiates, and is run from a program in the processor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OCC, Output Circuit Check -</emph>
                An "On Demand" test performed during an "Engine Off" self test that tests the continuity of selected
                actuators.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Output State Check -</emph>
                A "On Demand" test selected by the technician which forces the processor to activate actuators "High or
                Low" for additional diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OWL - Oil/Water Light and Alarm</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Potentiometer -</emph>
                Is an electro-mechanical device (variable voltage divider) which senses the position of a mechanical
                component. Mechanical motion connected to the wiper causes it to move along the resistance material in a
                rotary fashion. The voltage on the wiper changes at each point along the resistive material and is
                proportional to the amount of mechanical movement. Potentiometers have three connections. Vref, Signal
                out (wiper) and ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PROM -</emph>
                Programmable Read Only Memory
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO, Power Takeoff Unit -</emph>
                Accessory output, usually from the transmission that is used to power a hydraulic pump for garbage
                packing, lift equipment, etc.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Pulse Width -</emph>
                The length of time an actuator, such as an injector remains energized.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RAM, Random Access Memory -</emph>
                A type of memory that is used to store information. Information can be written to and read from the RAM.
                Input information such as current engine speed or temperature would be stored here to be compared to
                values stored in the ROM. All memory in the RAM is lost when the ignition switch is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Read -</emph>
                A computer operation where information is retrieved from the memory.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RFI -</emph>
                Radio Frequency Interference
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ROM, Read Only Memory -</emph>
                A type of memory that is used to store information permanently. Information can not be written to the
                ROM memory. Operating strategies and calibration tables are the type of information most commonly stored
                in the ROM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Sampling -</emph>
                The act of periodically collecting information, as from a sensor. A microprocessor samples inputs from
                various sensors in the process of controlling a system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Scalar -</emph>
                A single numerical value that is assigned a label and is used as a calibration parameter. This value can
                be multiplied, divided, added or subtracted to a given input.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SCCS, Speed Control Command Switches -</emph>
                A set of switches used for cruise control, PTO and remote hand throttle system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SIG GRD, Signal Ground -</emph>
                The common ground wire to the ECM in wire harness for the sensor inputs.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">STI, Self Test Input "Engine Diagnostics" Switch -</emph>
                Diagnostic switch located on vehicle dash used to activate Self Test Input engine diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Strategy -</emph>
                A plan or set of operating instructions that the microprocessor follows in order to achieve a desired
                goal. Strategy is the computer program itself, including all equations and decision making logic.
                Strategy is always stored in the RAM an thus cannot be changed during calibration.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">STOP -</emph>
                Stop Engine Lamp
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Switch Sensors -</emph>
                Switch sensors are used to indicate position, levels or pressures. The signal of a switch sensor is a
                digital signal created by either the opening or closing a switch. The on or off signal can indicate
                position as in the case of a clutch switch, level as in the case of a coolant level switch, or pressure
                as in the case of a low oil pressure switch. A switch sensor normally has two connectors signal return
                (Grd) and the signal. A switch sensor is considered a low speed digital signal input.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TAC, Tachometer Output Signal -</emph>
                Engine speed signal from the ECM to the VPM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Table -</emph>
                Devices that a computer uses to take two different inputs and solve for an output.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Thermistor -</emph>
                Sensor used to determine temperature. A thermistor changes it's resistance value in relation to
                temperature change. Increasing temperature results in decreasing resistance, decreasing temperature
                results in increasing resistance. The thermistor in conjunction with a current limiting resistor in the
                ECM forms a voltage divider that provides a voltage signal that indicates temperature. Since the top
                half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor and is internal to the ECM a thermistor
                sensor only has two connections, signal return and ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Threshold Value -</emph>
                A value stored in the ROM portion of the ECM. This value is compared to the value of a particular sensor
                provided to the ECM during the continuous self-test. If the value is not within the parameters of the
                threshold value, a service code is entered into the KAM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Transducers (load cells)</emph>
                - Transducers are used to sense pressure. Their function is very similar to potentiometers. The 5 volt
                reference signal is changed by the internal circuitry of the sensor into an analog voltage that
                indicates pressure. A transducer sensor has three connections Vref, signal and ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Transition -</emph>
                Changing from one value or condition to another, such as from positive to negative in an electronic
                circuit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TTS -</emph>
                Transmission Tailshaft Speed
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VEPS Vehicle Electronic System Programming System -</emph>
                The computer system used to program electronically controlled vehicles.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VIGN, Voltage Ignition -</emph>
                Voltage supplied by the ignition switch when the key is in the "ON" position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VIT, Vendor Interface Tool -</emph>
                A vendor (engine supplier) tool used to translate programming information between Navistar's truck VEPS
                system format to the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VPM, Vehicle Personality Module -</emph>
                A module which identifies to the ECM the individual vehicle parameters for the system being used. This
                module allows for resetting of road speed, PTO set points, cruise control set points, speedometer
                calibrations and other vehicle features.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VRE Vehicle Retarder Enable -</emph>
                Output from ECM to a vehicle retarder.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">V Ref Reference Voltage -</emph>
                A five volt reference supplied by the ECM to operate the engine sensors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VBAT -</emph>
                Battery voltage. (See VPWR)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VPWR -</emph>
                Battery voltage. (See VBAT)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VSS Vehicle Speed Sensor -</emph>
                Normally a magnetic pickup style sensor that is mounted on the tailshaft of the transmission to indicate
                ground speed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WARN ENGINE Lamp -</emph>
                Lamp in the dash that comes on when selected fault codes are set or when the ECM is utilizing FMEM
                strategy. Fault codes in some vehicles can be read as flash codes through the WARN ENGINE lamp. To
                access the flash codes, the STI (Self Test Input "Engine Diagnostics") switch is depressed and held
                momentarily while the ignition switch is placed in the "ON" position. This will cause the WARN ENGINE
                lamp to flash any fault codes which were stored while operating the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Write -</emph>
                A computer operation where information is sent to and stored in memory.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_256.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
