<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - CAMSHAFT POSITION (CMP) SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450312" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>CAMSHAFT POSITION (CMP) SENSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450337">Figure 3.26 Camshaft Position (CMP) Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450337" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1197" filename="../figeg1/eg1197.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.26 Camshaft Position (CMP) Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The CMP (Camshaft Position) sensor is a Hall Effect type sensor that generates a digital frequency as
                windows on the timing disk pass through its magnetic field. The frequency of the windows passing by the
                sensor as well as the width of selected windows allows the ECM to detect engine speed and position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Speed -</emph>
                Is determined by counting 24 windows on the timing sensor disk each camshaft revolution.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Timing Control -</emph>
                The position of cylinder #1 is determined by distinguishing a narrow vane on the camshaft timing sensor
                disk.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Mode Selection -</emph>
                Allows the ECM to discern when the engine is in the off, crank or run mode.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure -</emph>
                Engine speed is one of the controlling variables in the calculation of desired injection control
                pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Quantity Control/Torque Limiting -</emph>
                Engine torque and fuel is controlled and is dependent on engine speed. Fuel quantity is determined by
                engine speed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault detection/management</title>
            <para>An inactive CMP signal during cranking is detectable by the ECM. An inactive CMP signal will cause a
                no start condition. Electrical noise can also be detected by the ECM, if the level is sufficient to
                effect engine operation a corresponding fault code will be set. T
                <emph type="underscr">he engine will not operate without a functioning CMP signal.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450338">Figure 3.27 Camshaft Position Sensor Circuit Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450338" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5960" filename="../figeg5/eg5960.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.27 Camshaft Position Sensor Circuit Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Function</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP). This sensor provides the
                Electronic Control Module (ECM) with a signal that indicates camshaft position and engine speed.
            </para>
            <para>The CMP sensor signal is used by the ECM to syncronize piston position to injector firing sequence.
                The injector firing order sequence begins when the ECM detects the narrow vane on the timing disk
                indicating #1 cylinder. Engine position for each cylinder is then continuously calculated as each vane
                on the timing disk passes by the CMP sensor. This information is processed by the ECM and used for
                injection timing and fuel delivery control. The ECM can then initiate the beginning of firing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Camshaft Position Sensor is a Hall Effect type sensor that generates a digital frequency as
                windows on the timing disk pass through the magnetic field. The frequency of the windows passing by the
                sensor as well as the width of selected windows allows the ECM to detect engine speed and position. When
                the narrow vane passes the CMP sensor the signal on time is less than when the other vanes pass the
                sensor. This produces a signal that the ECM uses to indicate engine position.
            </para>
            <para>Engine speed is detected by the ECM by counting the frequency of the 24 signal pulses for each
                camshaft revolution.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>Once the ECM has recognized the narrow vane (wide window) it will synchronize the engine firing order
                to the timing of the CMP signal. Every 2 crankshaft revolutions it will verify that synchronization. If
                the ECM receives too many or too few pulses for the number of engine revolutions, it will set a fault
                code.
            </para>
            <para>The engine will not operate without a functioning CMP signal. However, the ECM will attempt to
                determine the cause of an invalid signal and identify it with a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>CMP codes that are set will become inactive codes if the key is turned off. These codes can be
                retrieved using the Self Test Input (STI) switch/(Engine Diagnostics switch) located on the vehicle
                dashboard or the Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 143</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>WRONG # OF CMP SIGNAL TRANSITIONS PER CAM REVOLUTION</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 143 indicates the ECM has received CMP signals with the wrong number of transitions. This
                indicates that the ECM has counted the voltage transitions and found less than the specified number of
                pulses from the sensor. When this problem is continuous, the engine will stop running and the ECM will
                log an active code. If the key is shut off, the code will become an inactive code. This code will not
                turn the warning light on.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for code 143: Intermittent CMP signal caused by a intermittent circuit, defective
                Camshaft Position Sensor, or incorrect CMP sensor to timing disk clearance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 144</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>CMP SIGNAL NOISE DETECTED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 144 indicates that the ECM has detected voltage spikes or transitions other than the CMP signal.
                If this problem is continuous the engine could stop running and the ECM will log an active code. If the
                key is shut off, the code will become an inactive. This code will not cause the warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
            <para>Code 144 may be due to: Poor ground connections for CMP or other electronic components. Wire harness
                shielding missing or incorrectly installed on the engine harness. Outside components that could induce
                voltage signals.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 145</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 12</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>CMP SIGNAL INACTIVE WHILE ICP HAS INCREASED</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 145 indicates that the ECM does not detect a CMP signal. This code would be set if the
                engine was rotating and the ECM detected a rise in ICP pressure, but did not detect a CMP signal. To set
                this code the engine must be rotated long enough for the ICP to increase. When this code is set the
                engine will not operate. This code will not cause the warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for flash code 145: Defective CMP sensor, faulty sensor circuitry, or improper air gap
                between sensor and camshaft timing disk.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 612</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 7</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>INCORRECT ECM INSTALLED FOR CMP TIMING DISK</title>
            </para>
            <para>Flash code 612 indicates that the ECM has monitored the CMP signal and the signal is incorrect for the
                programming in the ECM. This means that the ECM does not recognize the signal generated from the timing
                disk and CMP sensor.
            </para>
            <para>When this condition exists, the ECM does not send a Fuel Demand Command Signal (FCDS) to the Injector
                Drive Module (IDM). The engine cannot operate without a FDCS signal from the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: ECM has been accidently replaced with an incorrect ECM for the particular engine
                application. (For example, the timing disk for the I-6 and V-8 (T444E) are different and generate a
                different signal. An ECM from the V-8 (T444E) engine will not run an I-6 engine.) Incorrect signal due
                to a defective CMP sensor or incorrect air gap between the CMP sensor and the timing disk.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450339" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5961" filename="../figeg5/eg5961.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.28 Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450340">Figure 3.29 Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP) Circuit Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450340" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5962" filename="../figeg5/eg5962.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.29 Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP) Circuit Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450339">3.28</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450311.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450313.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
