<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - MULTIMETER USE - OHMMETER</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>OHMMETER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ohmmeter is used to measure resistance (ohms) in a circuit. Like the ammeter and voltmeter, there
                are both analog and digital meters available. It is recommended that the digital meter (Fluke 88 DVOM)
                be used. See ELECTRONIC CIRCUIT TESTING in this section.
            </para>
            <para>Ohmmeters use a small battery to supply the voltage and current which flow through the circuit being
                tested. The voltage of the meter battery and the amount of current flow in the circuit are used with
                Ohms Law and the meter calculates the circuit resistance which is displayed by the meter. With the Fluke
                88 DVOM, range selection and meter adjustment are not necessary.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measuring Resistance</title>
            <para>Resistance measurements determine:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Resistance of a load</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Resistance of conductors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Value of resistors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Operation of variable resistors</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>To measure the resistance of a component or a circuit, power must first be removed from the circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The component or circuit that is to be measured must be isolated from all other components or circuits
                so that meter current (from probe to probe) only flows through the desired circuit or component or the
                reading will not be accurate. Notice in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450530">5.30</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                that if we wanted to measure the resistance of the load, most of the current flow from the meter would
                flow through the indicator lamp because it has less resistance. To measure the load, one connector to
                the load should be removed. It is not always apparent when a component must be isolated in such a
                manner, so it is usually a good practice to isolate the circuit or component by physically disconnecting
                one circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The ohmmeter leads are then placed across the component or circuit and the resistance will be
                displayed in ohms
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450531">5.31</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). When checking a sensor or variable resistor such as fuel level gauge, heating the element or moving
                the arm should move the meter through a range of resistance that can be compared to a specification.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450530" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6129" filename="../figeg6/eg6129.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.30 Improperly Isolating Component For Resistance Check</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1450531" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6130" filename="../figeg6/eg6130.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.31 Measuring Resistance</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <emph type="bold">CHECKING FOR OPEN CIRCUITS</emph>
            </title>
            <para>Electrical circuits can be checked for opens using an ohmmeter. The circuit must first be disconnected
                from the power supply. The circuit to be checked must also be isolated from other circuits. Connect the
                meter to the open ends of the circuit as shown in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450532">5.32</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                . A high reading (infinity) indicates there is an open in the circuit. A near zero reading is an
                indication of a continuous circuit. Notice also in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450532">5.32</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                that we disconnected the circuit between the light and the ground. This precaution prevents reading a
                circuit as complete that may be shorted to ground ahead of the load device.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450532" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6131" filename="../figeg6/eg6131.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.32 Open Circuit Check Using An Ohmeter</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECKING FOR SHORT CIRCUITS</title>
            <para>Checks for short circuits are made in a similar manner to that used to check for open circuits, except
                that the circuit to be checked must be isolated from both the power source and the ground point.
            </para>
            <para>Connecting the ohmmeter as shown in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450533">5.33</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                between an isolated circuit and a good ground point will allow checking the circuit for a short to
                ground. A short to ground will be indicated by a near zero reading, while a circuit not shorted to
                ground will cause the meter to read very high (near infinity). With the Fluke 88 DVOM, an open circuit
                will read "OL" on the meter display.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450533" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6132" filename="../figeg6/eg6132.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.33 Short Circuit Check Using An Ohmeter</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_218.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_220.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
