<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - ENGINE CRANK INHIBIT SYSTEM (ECI)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450314" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="16">
        <title>ENGINE CRANK INHIBIT SYSTEM (ECI)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450350">Figure 3.37 Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI)</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450350" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5971" filename="../figeg5/EG5971.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.37 Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The ECM uses the enable circuit to control engine cranking. The ECM prevents cranking motor operation:
                whenever the engine is running or whenever a vehicle with an automatic transmission is not in neutral.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With the key ON, the ECM enables the crank relay if the engine is not running and if 12 volts is
                present at terminal 10 with an automatic transmission.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">MANUAL TRANSMISSION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, the ECM programming doesn't look at terminal 10 in enabling the crank
                inhibit relay.
            </para>
            <para>To enable the crank inhibit relay, the ECM sets terminal 35 LOW (ground state). To disable the crank
                relay, terminal 35 is HIGH (12 volts).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crank Inhibit Relay</title>
            <para>Turning the key to the start position applies power to the crank inhibit relay at pin 2. If the relay
                is enabled by the ECM, the relay is energized and applies ignition voltage to the cranking motor
                magnetic switch control coil.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor Magnetic Switch</title>
            <para>The crank motor magnetic switch is used to switch battery power to the crank motor solenoid when the
                crank inhibit relay is energized. With thermo overcrank protection installed the magnetic switch is
                grounded through the overcrank thermo couple.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>The ECM does not monitor the cranking system circuits. There are no fault codes for this system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450351">Figure 3.38 Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450351" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5972" filename="../figeg5/EG5972.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.38 Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* - Refer to Figures
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450352">3.39</hotlnk>
                        or
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450353">3.40</hotlnk>
                        for complete circuit diagram.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To bench test the Start Magnetic Relay, refer to Figure 3.42a.</para>
                    <para>To bench test the Crank Inhibit Relay, refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450360">3.44</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The engine starting system is controlled by the Electronic Control Module (ECM). While cranking the
                engine, vehicle battery voltage may momentarily drop below 6 volts, causing the ECM to shut down. When
                voltage comes back up, the ECM will resume operation. The Crank Inhibit Relay (385) has a 2-second delay
                feature that allows the engine to continue to crank (for up to 2 seconds) while the ECM is OFF, so the
                engine starts properly.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM disables the cranking system when:</para>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>The engine is running.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The automatic transmission is not in neutral.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Components include:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Start Switch (key or push button)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crank Inhibit Relay (385)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start Relay (387)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crank Motor and Solenoid</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (379)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Neutral Position Switch with automatic transmission</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Switch (386)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SYSTEM OPERATION</title>
            <para>Refer to the circuit diagram
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450352">3.39</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                (manual xmsn)
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450353">3.40</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                (automatic xmsn) for the following discussion. Energizing the engine starting system requires a series
                of events by the cranking system components. The Engine Crank Inhibit Relay (385) receives inputs from
                several sources and if all conditions are present, the Start Relay (387) is energized.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crank Inhibit Relay (385)</title>
            <para>The Crank Inhibit Relay has two major functions.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The ECM signal must "enable" the Crank Inhibit Relay for the cranking system to
                    operate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The relay must keep the engine cranking if vehicle battery voltage drops below 6 volts
                    during cranking, causing the ECM to go off line momentarily.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The Crank Inhibit Relay has 5 pins. To energize the Start Relay, the Engine Crank Inhibit relay
                interacts with the other cranking system components.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Crank Inhibit Relay PIN numbers shown in the circuit diagram are different than the relay
                        harness connector cavity numbers.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Crank Inhibit Relay Pin 5</emph>
                    is connected by circuit 97DE/97H to ECM terminal 35. For the relay to enable the cranking system,
                    ECM terminal 35 must be LOW (0 volts). Note that the ECM switches terminal 35 between LOW ( 0v) and
                    HIGH (12v), to either "enable" or "disable" the Crank Inhibit Relay. The circuit diagrams shows
                    terminal states (HIGH or LOW) for various conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Example 1: With the engine running, ECM terminal 35 will be HIGH, preventing the crank system from
                engaging.
            </para>
            <para>Example 2: With an automatic transmission, if the shift selector is NOT in neutral when preparing to
                start the engine, ECM terminal 35, would be HIGH and the crank system would not engage. Placing the
                transmission in neutral would cause ECM terminal 35 to switch LOW and enable the cranking system.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Crank Inhibit Relay Pin 1</emph>
                    receives power from 10A fuse F4 (H1 fuse w/FBC) when the key is ON. With an automatic transmission,
                    the power must first pass through the Neutral Position Switch (closed when in neutral). With a
                    manual transmission, the power from F4 (or H1 w/FBC) is present whenever the key is ON.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Crank Inhibit Relay Pin 2</emph>
                    receives ignition voltage when the start switch is engaged (push button or key switch). This
                    energizes the Crank Inhibit Relay (if steps 1, 2 and 3 occurred) causing voltage from terminal 3 to
                    energize the Start Relay (387).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Crank Inhibit Relay Pin 3</emph>
                    delivers output voltage on circuit 17A to the Start Relay when the Crank Inhibit Relay is energized.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Crank Inhibit Relay Pin 4</emph>
                    is grounded by circuit 97-GD at the relay bracket.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef1450352" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5973" filename="../figeg5/EG5973.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.39 Engine Cranking System with Manual Transmission</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef1450353" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5974" filename="../figeg5/EG5974.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.40 Engine Cranking System with Allison AT/MT Automatic Transmission</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Start Relay (387)</title>
            <para>The Start Relay (387) is energized by voltage on circuit 17A from the energized Crank Inhibit Relay
                (385). When the Start Relay is energized, battery voltage from "B" terminal of cranking motor solenoid
                is applied through the Start Relay contacts (E to A) to the "S" terminal of crank motor to energize the
                cranking motor. The Start Relay is a suppressed relay. The Start Relay has an internal diode to prevent
                voltage spikes from damaging electronic components in the vehicle system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermo Overcrank Protection (OCP)</title>
            <para>On vehicles equipped with Thermo Overcrank Protection cranking motors, the ground circuit for the
                Start Relay is through the Thermo Overcrank thermocouple. If the cranking motor temperature reaches a
                specified limit, the thermocouple opens, preventing further engine cranking until the cranking motor
                cools.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Neutral Position Switch</title>
            <para>With an Allison AT/MT automatic transmission, a normally open (NO) Neutral Position Switch is used to
                turn power ON or OFF in circuit 97AU.
            </para>
            <para>With the transmission in neutral, the switch is closed applying power to Crank Inhibit Relay pin 1 and
                to ECM terminal 10. On the circuit diagrams, ECM terminal 10 is labeled DDS (Driveline Disengagement
                Status). The 12 volts at ECM terminal 10 tells the ECM that the Neutral Position switch is closed and
                that the transmission is in neutral.
            </para>
            <para>With an Allison WT (electronic transmission controls), the neutral position switch is not used as the
                Allison WT Electronic Control Module determines shifter position. With the transmission in neutral,
                ignition power from the transmission Vehicle Interface Module (VIM) Neutral Start Relay is delivered on
                circuit 97AU to the Crank Inhibit Relay at pin 1. From pin 1, circuit 97L/97A applies the ignition
                voltage to ECM DDS terminal 10.
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle has an automatic transmission (AT or MT), the clutch switch connector (paragraph 2.4)
                has a jumper connecting circuits 97L and 97A, completing the circuit between Crank Inhibit Relay (385)
                pin 1 and ECM terminal 10.
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, ECM terminal 10 is programmed to expect 12 volts on circuit 97A when
                the shifter is in neutral and 0 volts when the shifter is not in neutral. The circuit diagram shows
                terminal states for various conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The Prolink 9000 can be used to monitor the Neutral Position Switch. When the switch is closed
                (transmission in neutral), the Prolink (using PTO/Clutch Switch Status) indicates clutch ON, meaning the
                driveline is disengaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Pedal Switch (386)</title>
            <para>The clutch pedal switch is used for cruise control, engine brakes etc. The ECM is programmed so that
                the input from the DDS terminal 10 has no effect on enabling or disabling the cranking system.
            </para>
            <para>The Prolink 9000 EST can be used to monitor the Clutch Switch position. When the clutch switch is open
                (clutch depressed), the Prolink indicates clutch ON, meaning the driveline is disengaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>Electronic Control Module terminals 10 (only with automatic xmsn) and 35 are directly involved with
                enabling the Crank Inhibit Relay. The ECM and VPM (VPM stores information for the ECM) are programmed
                differently for automatic or manual transmissions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Terminal 10 (DDS)</title>
            <para>ECM terminal 10 receives input (12 volts or 0 volts) from either the clutch switch with a manual
                transmission or neutral position indication with an automatic transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, the ECM uses the input to determine the voltage signal on ECM terminal
                35. If the transmission is in neutral, terminal 10 will be HIGH (12v) and terminal 35 will LOW (0v). If
                the transmission is not in neutral, terminal 10 will be LOW (0v) and terminal 35 will be HIGH (12v).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Manual Transmission</title>
            <para>With a manual transmission, the ECM does not use input from terminal 10 to set terminal 35.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Terminal 35 (ECI)</title>
            <para>ECM terminal 35 is connected by circuit 97H to Crank Inhibit Relay pin 5. Based on inputs to ECM
                terminal 10 and engine operating conditions, the ECM either sets terminal 35 LOW (0v) or HIGH (12v).
                With ECM terminal 35 LOW, the Crank Inhibit Relay is "enabled." If the ECM terminal 35 is HIGH, then the
                Crank Inhibit Relay is NOT "enabled."
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Programming</title>
            <para>The ECM "enables" the Crank Inhibit Relay if:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The engine is not running.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The transmission is in neutral (with automatic transmission).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>If these conditions do not exist, the Crank Inhibit Relay is not enabled and the engine will not
                crank.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>The ECM "enables" or "disables" the engine cranking system with the Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) relay.
                <emph type="underscr">There are no ECM diagnostics for this system.</emph>
                Perform the following tests to find the cause of a No Crank condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the batteries are fully charged! Check battery
                    cables and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage. Voltage tests will give misleading
                    readings if the batteries are not fully charged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting a particular circuit, inspect connectors for pushed back, loose
                    or damaged (spread or bent) terminals, or wires with cut strands etc. The wires and connections must
                    be free of damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present
                    that must be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Start Motor And Start Relay</title>
            <para>The tests for "Engine Does Not Crank" condition are divided into two parts. With manual or automatic
                transmission perform this test first.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450354" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5975" filename="../figeg5/EG5975.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.41 Start Magnetic Switch Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Part 1 troubleshooting chart is to be used with either a manual transmission (with and without
                clutch switch) or an Allison automatic transmission (AT or MT). Refer to circuit diagram
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450354">3.41</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>For Part 2, select the appropriate troubleshooting chart for vehicle being tested: Manual Transmission
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450357">3.43</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                or Automatic Transmission
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450361">3.45</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450355" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5976" filename="../figeg5/EG5976.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.42 Engine Start Motor and Start Relay Test</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450356">Figure 3.42a Engine Start Motor and Start Relay Test</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450356" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5977" filename="../figeg5/EG5977.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.42a Engine Start Motor and Start Relay Test</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* - Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450357">3.43</hotlnk>
                        diagnostics.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>** - Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450361">3.45</hotlnk>
                        diagnostics.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Perform Engine Start Motor and Start Relay Test Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450355">3.42</hotlnk>
                    before performing this test.
                </emph>
                Use this test with manual transmission equipped with a clutch switch.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450357" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5978" filename="../figeg5/EG5978.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.43 Engine Does Not Crank with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* - Refer to Circuit Diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450364">3.46</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>** - Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450355">3.42</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450358">Figure 3.43a Engine Does Not Crank with Manual Transmission</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450358" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5979" filename="../figeg5/EG5979.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.43a Engine Does Not Crank with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450359">Figure 3.43b Engine Does Not Crank with Manual Transmission</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450359" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5980" filename="../figeg5/EG5980.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.43b Engine Does Not Crank with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1450360" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6141" filename="../figeg6/EG6141.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.44 Procedure To Bench Test The Crank Inhibit Relay</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Use this test with automatic transmission.</para>
            <figure id="ef1450361" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5981" filename="../figeg5/EG5981.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.45 Engine Does Not Crank with Allison AT Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* - Refer to Circuit Diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450365">3.47</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>** - Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450355">3.42</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450362">Figure 3.45a Engine Does Not Crank with Allison AT Transmission</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450362" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5982" filename="../figeg5/EG5982.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.45a Engine Does Not Crank with Allison AT Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450363">Figure 3.45b Engine Does Not Crank with Allison AT Transmission (Continued)
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450363" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5983" filename="../figeg5/EG5983.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.45b Engine Does Not Crank with Allison AT Transmission (Continued)</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* - See Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450360">3.44</hotlnk>
                        for relay test method.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef1450364" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5984" filename="../figeg5/EG5984.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.46 Cranking System with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1450365" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5985" filename="../figeg5/EG5985.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.47 Cranking System with Allison AT/MT Automatic Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450313.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450315.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
