<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - MULTIMETER USE - Ohms Law Review
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Ohms Law Review</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Ohms Law describes the relationship of voltage, current and resistance, and provides us with a formula
                to make calculations as is shown in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450524">5.24</hotlnk>).
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450524" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6123" filename="../figeg6/EG6123.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.24 Ohms Law</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If any two of the values are known for a given circuit, the missing one can be found by substituting
                the values in amperes, volts, or ohms and solving for the missing value.
            </para>
            <para>In a typical circuit, battery voltage is applied to a bulb through a 10-amp fuse and a switch
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450525">5.25</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                . Closing the switch turns on the bulb.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450525" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6124" filename="../figeg6/EG6124.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.25 Simple Electrical Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To find the current flow use the formula:</para>
            <para>I = E / R</para>
            <para>Filling in the numbers for the circuit in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450525">5.25</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                , we have:
            </para>
            <para>I = 12V/2 ohms or I= 12 divided by 2 = 6 amperes of current flow.</para>
            <para>The bulb in this circuit operates at 6 amps and is rated to operate at this level. With 12 volts
                applied, the bulb will glow at the rated output level (candlepower rating). However:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the voltage applied is low (low battery), then (the value of E is lower) and current flow
                        will be less and the bulb will glow less brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Or if the connections are loose, or the switch corroded, the circuit resistance will be
                        greater (value of R will be larger) and the current flow will be reduced and the bulb will glow
                        less brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Being able to determine voltage drops is important because it provides the following information:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Too high a voltage drop indicates excessive resistance. If, for instance, a blower motor runs
                        too slowly or a light glows too dimly, one can be sure that there is excessive resistance in the
                        circuit. By taking voltage drop readings in various parts of the circuit, the problem can be
                        isolated (corroded or loose terminals for example).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Too low of a voltage drop, likewise, indicates low resistance. If for instance, a blower motor
                        ran too fast, the problem could be isolated to a low resistance in a resistor pack by taking
                        voltage drop readings.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maximum allowable voltage drop under load is critical, especially if there is more than one
                        high resistance problem in a circuit. It is important because all voltage drops in a circuit are
                        cumulative. Corroded terminals, loose connections, damaged wires or other similar conditions
                        create undesirable voltage drops that decrease the voltage available across the key circuit
                        components. Remember our earlier discussion, the increased resistance from the undesirable
                        conditions will also decrease the current flow in the circuit and all the affected components
                        will operate at less than peak efficiency. A small drop across wires (conductors), connectors,
                        switches, etc. is normal. This is because all conductors have some resistance, but the total
                        should be less than 10 percent of the total voltage drop in the circuit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>USING THE VOLTMETER</title>
            <para>In electrical diagnosis, the voltmeter is used to answer:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Is voltage present?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage reading?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage drop across a load device?</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When using a voltmeter to determine if voltage is present to power a device, connect the positive
                meter lead to input connection of the device (positive side) and connect the negative meter lead to good
                vehicle ground
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450526">5.26</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                . This shows how much of the source voltage is available to the device. Note that the meter is connected
                in parallel to the device.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450526" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6125" filename="../figeg6/EG6125.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.26 Checking Power To A Load Device</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Should we need to determine if voltage is available at a connector where we can't readily connect to
                the device, we can connect the meter in parallel as shown in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450527">5.27</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                . The meter internal resistance is very high so little current will flow in the circuit, and the voltage
                can be read accurately.
            </para>
            <para>To check the voltage drop across a load device
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450528">5.28</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                , connect the positive lead of the voltmeter to the positive side of the device and the negative meter
                lead to the negative side of the device.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450527" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6126" filename="../figeg6/EG6126.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.27 Checking Power To A Connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1450528" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6127" filename="../figeg6/EG6127.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.28 Checking Voltage Loss</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>With the device operating, this will measure the voltage drop across the device. Notice in
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450528">5.28</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                that since we only have one device, all of the voltage should be dropped at the device. In any circuit,
                the voltage applied will equal the voltage dropped in the circuit. If in this circuit we only dropped 9V
                across the load, that would indicate that our wires, connections, etc. were dropping the other 3V, which
                would indicate excessive circuit resistance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_216.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_218.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
