<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - APS/IVS PEDAL POSITION SENSOR / IDLE VALIDATION SWITCH
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450309" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="7">
        <title>APS/IVS PEDAL POSITION SENSOR / IDLE VALIDATION SWITCH</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="ef1450311" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1114" filename="../figeg1/EG1114.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.7 APS/IVS</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS (FIGURE
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450311">3.7</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>The Accelerator Pedal Position Sensor (APS) is a potentiometer type sensor which, when supplied with a
                5 volt reference signal from the Electronic Control Module (ECM), provides a linear analog voltage
                signal that indicates the driver's demand for power.
            </para>
            <para>The Idle Validation Switch (IVS) is a 0/12 volt switch that provides the ECM with a redundant signal
                to verify when the pedal is in the idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Quantity and Timing Control -</emph>The APS signal is used in calculating desired
                fuel quantity and injector timing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure -</emph>Accelerator pedal position is one of the
                controlling variables in the calculation of desired injection control pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>Any detected malfunction of the APS or IVS sensor circuit will illuminate the WARN ENGINE lamp.</para>
            <para>An APS signal that is detected out of range high or low by the ECM will cause the engine to ignore the
                APS signal and will only allow the engine to operate at low idle.
            </para>
            <para>If a disagreement in the state of IVS and APS is detected by the ECM and the ECM determines that it is
                an IVS fault, the ECM will only allow a maximum of 50% APS to be commanded.
            </para>
            <para>If a disagreement in the state of IVS and APS is detected by the ECM and the ECM can not discern if it
                is an APS or IVS fault or if it is an APS fault, the engine will be allowed to operate at low idle only.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450312">Figure 3.8 APS/IVS Circuit Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450312" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6140" filename="../figeg6/EG6140.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.8 APS/IVS Circuit Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>APS/IVS EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>Navistar electronic engines use an electronic accelerator pedal assembly that includes a
                <emph type="bold"></emph>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS). These two
                functions are integrated into one component mounted on the pedal. The accelerator pedal assembly is
                serviceable to the extent that the APS/IVS switch can be replaced without replacing the complete
                assembly.
            </para>
            <para>The engine Electronic Control Module (ECM) determines the position of the accelerator pedal by
                processing the input signals from the Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch
                (IVS).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (Aps)</title>
            <para>Refer to circuit diagram
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450313">3.9</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends a regulated 5 volt signal through ECM connector (379) terminal 26 to APS connector (382)
                terminal C. The APS then returns a variable voltage signal (depending on pedal position) from APS
                connector (382) terminal A to the ECM at terminal 47. The APS is grounded from connector (382) terminal
                B to the ECM signal ground terminal 46.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>APS AUTO-CALIBRATION</title>
            <para>The ECM learns the lowest and highest pedal positions by reading and storing the minimum and maximum
                voltage levels from the APS. In this manner the ECM "auto- calibrates" the system to allow maximum pedal
                sensitivity. The ECM auto-calibrates as the key is ON, but when the key is turned OFF, these values are
                lost. When the key is turned on again, this process starts over. When the pedal is disconnected (or new
                one installed), the pedal does not need to be calibrated, as the calibration happens when the key is
                turned on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IDLE VALIDATION SWITCH (IVS)</title>
            <para>The ECM expects to receive one of two signals through ECM connector (379) terminal 8 from APS/IVS
                connector (382) terminal D:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>0 volts when the pedal is at the idle posItion.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12 volts when the pedal is depressed.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The Idle Validation Switch receives 12 volt ignition voltage from 10A fuse F4 (H1 with FBC). When the
                pedal is NOT in the idle position (throttle applied), the IVS sends a 12 volt signal to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM compares the inputs it receives at terminals 47 and 8 from the APS/IVS to verify when the
                pedal is in the idle position. If the APS signal at terminal 47 indicates throttle is being applied,
                then the ECM expects to see 12 volts at IVS terminal 8. If the APS signal at terminal 47 indicates
                throttle is not applied, then the ECM expects to see 0 volts at the IVS terminal 8. The timing process
                is critical between the APS and the IVS sensors. For this reason, it is very difficult to determine if
                the APS/IVS assembly is working properly using a volt-ohmmeter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>When the key is ON, the ECM continuously monitors the APS/IVS circuits for expected voltages. It also
                compares the APS and IVS signals for conflict. If the signals are not what the ECM expects to see, Fault
                codes will be set.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 131</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA Code PID 91 FMI 4 -</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: APS Out of Range Low</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ORL (out of range low) code 131 is set if the ECM detects a voltage lower than 0.146 volts at
                terminal 47. Possible causes include: a short to ground or an open in circuit 99B. This code is
                displayed by either the Prolink EST or using the Engine Warn Light to flash codes.
            </para>
            <para>When code 131 is active, the ECM restricts engine speed to idle and turns the Engine Warning Light ON.
                If the condition causing code 131 is intermittent and the condition is no longer present, the code will
                become inactive and normal engine operation will resume. If code 131 is active, perform Testing APS/IVS
                Switch and Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450314">3.10</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 132</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA Code PID 91 FMI 3 -</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: APS Out Of Range High</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ORH (out of range high) code 132 is set if the ECM detects a voltage greater than 4.56 volts at
                terminal 47. Possible cause: short to VREF or 12 volts in circuit 99B. This code is displayed by either
                the Prolink EST or using the Engine Warn Light to flash codes.
            </para>
            <para>When code 132 is active, the ECM restricts engine speed to idle and turns the Engine Warn Light ON. If
                the condition causing code 132 is intermittent and the condition is no longer present, the code will
                become inactive and normal engine operation will resume. If code 132 is active, perform Testing APS/IVS
                Switch and Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450314">3.10</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Codes 133, 134 And 135</title>
            <para>
                <title>APS IN-RANGE Faults</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM checks the voltage output of the APS by comparing the APS signal with the IVS signal. APS and
                IVS signals can disagree in two cases:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The APS signal indicates the pedal is pressed down to accelerate, but the IVS signal indicates
                        idle position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The APS signal indicates the pedal has been released to allow the engine to return to idle,
                        but the IVS signal indicates off-idle position of the pedal.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the ECM detects either of the above conditions, the ECM attempts to isolate the source of conflict.
                If code(s) 133, 134 and/or 135 are active, perform Testing APS/IVS Switch and Circuits
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450314">3.10</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 133</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA Code PID 91 FMI 2 -</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: APS In Range Fault</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the IVS signal is changing and the APS signal is constant, the ECM assumes APS is the conflict
                source and sets code 133. Engine rpm is restricted to idle and the Engine Warn Light is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 134</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA Code PID 91 FMI 7-</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: APS/IVS Disagree</title>
            </para>
            <para>If neither the APS or IVS is changing, or both are changing or the ECM cannot determine the faulty
                code in specified time, then code 134 is set, engine rpm is restricted to idle and the Engine Warn Light
                is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 135</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA Code SID 230 FMI 11-</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM: IVS Circuit Fault</title>
            </para>
            <para>If the APS is changing and IVS is constant, the ECM assumes IVS is the conflict source and sets flash
                code 135. In this case the ECM limits the APS signal to a lower value, which provides less than full
                rpm, but does not limit engine rpm to idle. The Engine Warn Light is not turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>Note that codes 133, 134 and 135 are caused by an intermittent condition, the codes remain ACTIVE
                until the vehicle has been shutdown and restarted. They do not recover without cycling the key switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>The APS and IVS circuits operate with low current levels. When troubleshooting, pay special attention
                to the connectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Performing Any Test</title>
            <para>Inspect connectors for pushed back, damaged, corroded or dirty terminals, as well as making sure that
                the terminals and wires are properly crimped. Make sure the connectors are properly joined together.
                Also check for any damage to the wiring and make sure system grounds are clean and tight.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TESTING APS/IVS CIRCUITS</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If flash codes 131, 132, 133, 134 or 135 are present, perform Testing APS/IVS Switch and
                        Circuits
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450314">3.10</hotlnk>.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>These tests systematically check the APS and IVS circuits for:</para>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>Short circuits to ground.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Short circuits to unwanted voltage sources.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Open circuits or excessive circuit resistance.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Proper feeds and grounds.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The tests performed on the accelerator pedal assembly check for shorts, opens and correct
                        resistance values, but do not check for proper timing between the two functions. If all of the
                        circuits between the ECM and the accelerator pedal assembly check good (Testing APS/IVS Switch
                        and Circuits
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450314">3.10</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ), then the APS/IVS accelerator switch should be replaced.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef1450313" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5936" filename="../figeg5/EG5936.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.9 Circuit Diagram APS/IVS System</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">COMPONENT LOCATIONS:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>F4 FUSE . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
                . . . . . . MAIN FUSE PANEL W/TRUCK
            </para>
            <para>H1 FUSE . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
                . . . . . . . . .MAIN FUSE PANEL W/FBC
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450313">3.9</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                while performing this test.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450314" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6938" filename="../figeg6/EG6938.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.10 Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450315">Figure 3.10a Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450315" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5939" filename="../figeg5/EG5939.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.10a Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450316">Figure 3.10b Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450316" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5940" filename="../figeg5/EG5940.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.10b Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450317">Figure 3.10c Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450317" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg5941" filename="../figeg5/EG5941.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.10c Testing APS/IVS Switch And Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_100.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450310.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
