<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE
        SELF TEST OPERATION - STANDARD TEST (ENGINE RUNNING)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>STANDARD TEST (ENGINE RUNNING)</title>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>During the test, the ECM commands the IPR actuator through a pre-programmed testing sequence to determine
            if the actuator is performing as expected. The ECM monitors the feedback signal values from the injection
            control pressure sensor and compares those values to the expected values. At the end of the test, the ECM
            will return the engine to the normal operating mode and transmit any fault codes which may have been set
            during the test.
        </para>
        <para>This test can only be performed by using the Electronic Service Tool.</para>
        <para>
            <title>PROCEDURE</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Engine coolant temperature must be 160 F, battery voltage must be higher than 12.5 volts and no
                    vehicle speed sensor (VSS) signal should be present during this test. If active fault codes are
                    present, they must be repaired and cleared prior to running this test.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select "Engine Running Test" from the
                <emph type="bold">"Diagnostic Test"</emph>
                menu in the EST.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press
                <emph type="bold">"ENTER"</emph>
                to begin test. The ECM will begin to raise the engine idle speed to a pre-determined value. It will then
                command the IPR valve to set the injection control pressure to rated speed pressure. If the performance
                of the IPR is acceptable,the ECM will control the IPR valve to reduce the pressure in steps while
                continuing to monitor the performance of the injection control pressure system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>At the completion of the IPR test, normal engine operation is restored and fault codes will be transmitted
            as described previously.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_45.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_47.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
