<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - ELECTRONIC CONTROL
        MODULE - III. MICROPROCESSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>III. MICROPROCESSOR</title>
        <para>The ECM contains an internal microprocessor. The processor stores operating instructions (control
            strategies) and tables of values (calibration parameters). It compares these stored instructions and values
            to sensed input values to determine the correct operating strategy for any given engine condition.
            Calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds referred to as the foreground and the
            background calculations. These calculations are performed on a continuous loop basis.
        </para>
        <para>The foreground calculations occur at a much faster rate than the background calculations. These are
            normally the more critical functions to engine operation or they occur at an faster rate. Such as engine
            speed control. Background calculations are normally things that occur at a slower pace such as engine
            temperature.
        </para>
        <para>Diagnostic strategies (instructions) are also programmed into the ECM. Some instructions cause inputs or
            outputs to be monitored on a continuous basis and will flag a code that will be set, other strategies will
            instruct the ECM to perform certain tests upon operator demand.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM's microprocessor is equipped with three types of memory Random Access Memory (RAM), Read Only
            Memory (ROM) and Keep Alive Memory (KAM)
            <emph type="bold">(Figure
                <hotlnk document="e145_18.xml" xrefid="ef1450112">1.12</hotlnk>)
            </emph>
            . They allow the processor to store the necessary instructions, calibration tables and input values to
            control the engine.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
