<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - SENSOR OPERATION -
        TYPES OF SENSORS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="6">
        <title>TYPES OF SENSORS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>THERMISTOR</title>
            <para>A thermistor is a type of sensor which changes it's electrical resistance with temperature. The
                electrical resistance of the thermistor decreases as temperature increases and increases as temperature
                decreases. The thermistor in conjunction with a current limiting resistor in the ECM
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450119">1.19</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                forms a voltage divider network that provides a voltage signal that indicates temperature. The top half
                of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor internal to the ECM. A thermistor sensor has two
                electrical connections, signal return and ground. The output of a thermistor sensor is not linear.
            </para>
            <para>Examples: EOT Engine Oil Temperature, ECT Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor, IAT Intake Temperature
                Sensor
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450119" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1108" filename="../figeg1/eg1108.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.19 - Thermistor Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>POTENTIOMETER</title>
            <para>A potentiometer
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450120">1.20</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                is a variable voltage divider used to sense the position of a mechanical component. A reference voltage
                is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical motion connected to the wiper causes it to move
                along the resistance material in a rotary fashion. The voltage on the wiper changes at each point along
                the resistive material. This voltage is proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
            </para>
            <para>Example: APS Accelerator Position Sensor</para>
            <figure id="ef1450120" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1109" filename="../figeg1/eg1109.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.20 - Potentiometer (Variable Resistance Voltage Divider)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VARIABLE CAPACITANCE SENSOR</title>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors are used to measure pressure. The pressure which is to be measured is
                applied to a ceramic material. The pressure forces the ceramic to move closer to a thin metal disk. This
                action causes the capacitance of the sensor to change which creates a frequency that corresponds to a
                pressure. The internal circuitry of the sensor converts that frequency into a linear analog voltage that
                indicates pressure. The thicker the ceramic disk the more pressure that sensor can measure. A variable
                capacitance sensor has three connections: Vref, signal and ground.
                <emph type="bold">Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450121">1.21</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Examples: EOP Engine Oil Pressure Sensor, ICP Injection Control Pressure Sensor</para>
            <figure id="ef1450121" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1110" filename="../figeg1/eg1110.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.21 - Variable Capacitance Sensor (Engine Oil Pressure Sensor)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HALL EFFECT SENSOR</title>
            <para>The Hall Effect sensor is an electronic device which generates a voltage signal controlled by the
                presence, absence or strength of a magnetic field.
            </para>
            <para>The Camshaft Position sensor is an example of a Hall Effect device. It contains a transducer,
                permanent magnet, signal conditioner and a switching transistor. The sensor's permanent magnet applies a
                magnetic field around the transducer as shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450122">1.22</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
                The sensor's transducer senses the strength of the magnetic field which is controlled by the teeth and
                windows (located on the rotating timing sensor disk) as they pass the sensor.
            </para>
            <para>A voltage signal is generated by the Hall Effect device each time a window passes the device. The
                signal is filtered and conditioned by the signal conditioner. The conditioned signal is applied to the
                switching transistor's base which causes the transistor to switch on and ground the 12 volt line from
                the ECM. The ECM no longer senses the 12 volt reference signal.
            </para>
            <para>Each time a vane passes the Hall Effect device no signal is generated. This action causes the
                transistor to shut off and causes the ECM to see it's 12 volt reference signal.
            </para>
            <para>This switching action allows the ECM to determine crankshaft position and engine speed which is
                required by the ECM to control engine operating parameters such as injector timing and firing duration.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450122" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1196" filename="../figeg1/eg1196.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.22 - Hall Effect Sensor (Camshaft Position Sensor)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SWITCH SENSORS</title>
            <para>Switch sensors are used to indicate position, levels or pressures. The signal of a switch sensor is a
                digital signal created by either opening or closing a switch. The on or off signal can indicate position
                as in the case of a clutch switch, level as in the case of a coolant level switch or pressure as in the
                case of a low oil pressure switch. A switch sensor can be either a voltage input type switch or a
                grounding type switch. A voltage input style switch will supply the ECM with a voltage when closed. A
                grounding type switch is wired in series with a current limiting resistor in the ECM and will cause a
                zero voltage signal when closed (grounding the circuit). A switch sensor normally has two connectors
                signal return (Grd) and the signal. A switch sensor is considered a low speed digital input.
                <emph type="bold">Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450123">1.23</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Examples: IVS: Idle Validation Switch, BNO: Brake Normally Open, BNC: Brake Normally Closed, CLS:
                Coolant Level Switch, DDS: Driveline Disengagement Switch
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1450123" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1112" filename="../figeg1/eg1112.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.23 - Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MAGNETIC PICKUP</title>
            <para>A magnetic pickup is a sensor used to generate a alternating frequency that indicates speed. Magnetic
                pickups normally have a two wire connection for signal and ground. A magnetic pickup is constructed with
                a permanent magnetic core surrounded by a wire coil. The signal frequency is generated by the rotation
                of gear teeth which make and break the magnetic field created by the magnet.
                <emph type="bold">Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef1450124">1.24</hotlnk>.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Example: VSS Vehicle Speed Sensor</para>
            <figure id="ef1450124" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg2606" filename="../figeg2/eg2606.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.24 - Magnetic Pickup (Vehicle Speed Sensor)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Magnetic Pickup Sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Transmission Case</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 16 Tooth Speedometer Gear</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. Permanent Magnet Field</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. Output Signal</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
