<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - TOOLS - BEYERS MODEL 200 PRESSURE
        TEST KIT (ZTSE-2239)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BEYERS MODEL 200 PRESSURE TEST KIT (ZTSE-2239)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Pressure Test Kit
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
                (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e145_187.xml" xrefid="ef1450502">5.12</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                can be used to measure intake manifold (Boost) pressure, fuel pressure, air cleaner intake restriction,
                fuel restriction, exhaust restriction and crankcase pressure. It may also be used to test the accuracy
                of the gauges within the kit.
            </para>
            <para>The 0-30 psi gauge may be used to measure fuel pressure or intake manifold (Boost) pressure.</para>
            <para>The 0-30 in. Hg. vacuum gauge (0-14.7 psi), is used to measure fuel system inlet restriction.</para>
            <para>The 0-60 inches of water (magnehelic) gauge (0-2.16 psi), may be used to measure air cleaner
                restriction or crankcase pressure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The quick disconnects have shut-off valves in the panel connectors not in the plug. DO NOT
                        connect or disconnect lines while under pressure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the magnehelic gauge, be sure to plug the test line into the proper ("Pressure" or
                        "Vacuum") port. Use the "Pressure" port to read exhaust back pressure and crankcase pressure.
                        Use "Vacuum" port to read air cleaner restriction. In both cases, THE OPPOSITE CONNECTOR
                        <emph type="underscr">MUST BE VENTED TO THE ATMOSPHERE</emph>
                        BY INSTALLING A QUICK CONNECTIVE PLUG IN THE PORT.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The 0-160 psi gauge may be used to check fuel pressure.</para>
            <para>The 0-300 psi gauge is not normally used for any engine diagnostic check on Navistar International&#174;
                engines.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATING INSTRUCTIONS</title>
            <para>Connect tubes between the test ports on the panel and the test points shown on the (REAR SIDE) of HARD
                START NO START AND PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTIC FORM EGED-150.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_188.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_190.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
