<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1995) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS - MANIFOLD ABSOLUTE PRESSURE (MAP) SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl1450331" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>MANIFOLD ABSOLUTE PRESSURE (MAP) SENSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503d8">Figure 3.113 Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503d8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1142" filename="../figeg1/EG1142.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.113 Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SIGNAL FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>The Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor is a variable capacitance sensor which operates on a 5
                volt reference signal from the ECM to produce a digital frequency signal that indicates pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Smoke Control -</emph>The MAP signal is used to control smoke by limiting fuel
                quantity during acceleration until a specified boost pressure is obtained.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Dynamic Injection Timing -</emph>Optimizes injection timing for boost pressure
                measured.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>A MAP signal that is detected by the ECM to be out of range or at an incorrect value for specific
                conditions will cause the ECM to ignore the MAP signal and will operate the engine with the values from
                estimated MAP. (Operate from a calculated boost pressure signal)
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503d9">Figure 3.114 Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) Sensor Diagnostics</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503d9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6054" filename="../figeg6/EG6054.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.114 Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) Sensor Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes a Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor. The ECM
                measures the signal from the MAP sensor to determine intake manifold (Boost) pressure. From this
                information, the ECM can optimize control of fuel rate and injection timing for all engine operating
                conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>The Manifold Absolute Pressure sensor is a variable capacitance sensor that produces a digital
                frequency signal output. The MAP sensor is supplied 5 volts from the ECM at terminal 26 to terminal B of
                the sensor. A return circuit (ground) is supplied from ECM terminal 46 to terminal A of the sensor. The
                sensor receives intake manifold boost pressure via a hose which connects to a tap on the intake manifold
                to the map sensor. Pressure applied to the MAP sensor changes the capacitance of the sensor which varies
                the digital frequency of the signal sent to the ECM. As boost pressure increases the frequency
                increases.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the MAP sensor output signal for expected values. If the ECM detects the MAP signal
                is greater than or less than the desired value, the ECM will set a fault code.
            </para>
            <para>If an active MAP sensor fault code is set, the ECM will ignore the MAP signal. It will operate the
                engine using programmed default values. Active faults for the MAP sensor will cause the ECM to
                illuminate the Engine Warning light. These faults can be retrieved using the Self Test Input diagnostic
                switch located on the vehicle dash or the Electronic Service Tool. If the ignition key is turned off,
                the fault code will be stored as an Inactive code.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 121</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 102 FMI 8</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MAP FREQuency OUT OF RANGE HIGH</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 121 will be set, if the ECM detects a frequency greater than 256 Hz for more than 0.1 seconds in
                the MAP signal.
            </para>
            <para>If code 121 is active, the ECM will ignore the MAP signal and operate the engine using programmed
                default values. The ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light when this code is active.
            </para>
            <para>Excessive high frequency noise in the MAP signal will cause this code to be set.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 122</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 102 FMI 11</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MAP SIGNAL IS INACTIVE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 122 will be set, if the ECM detects a frequency less than 90 Hz or an inactive MAP signal for
                more than 0.25 seconds.
            </para>
            <para>When code 122 is active, the ECM will ignore the MAP signal and operate the engine using programmed
                default values. The ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light when this code is set.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: A defective MAP sensor or MAP sensor signal circuits may be open or shorted to
                ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flash Code 123</title>
            <para>
                <title>ATA CODE PID 102 FMI 2</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MAP signal ABOVE SPECified LEVEL AT LOW IDLE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Code 123 is set when the MAP signal is greater than 16.7 PSI (115 kPa) Absolute at low idle.</para>
            <para>When code 123 is active, the ECM will ignore the MAP signal and operate the engine using programmed
                default values. The ECM will illuminate the Engine Warning light when this code is set.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Restricted or plugged hose which supplies intake manifold boost pressure to the MAP
                sensor or a defective MAP sensor.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503e0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6055" filename="../figeg6/EG6055.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.115 Accelerator, BARO &#38; MAP Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e1">Figure 3.116 MAP Manifold Absolute Pressure Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503e1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6056" filename="../figeg6/EG6056.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.116 MAP Manifold Absolute Pressure Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e0">3.115</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef14503e2">Figure 3.117 MAP Manifold Absolute Pressure Sensor</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="ef14503e2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg6057" filename="../figeg6/EG6057.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.117 MAP Manifold Absolute Pressure Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450330.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145_HL1450332.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
