<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION: INTRODUCTION - FUEL INJECTOR OPERATION
        - END OF INJECTION - DRAIN CYCLE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>END OF INJECTION - DRAIN CYCLE</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef160in23">i.22</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef160in23">i.22</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Engines equipped with chassis mounted ECM and IDM units:</emph>The end of the injection
            cycle begins when the ECM terminates the fuel delivery command signal to the IDM. The IDM then terminates
            the electric pulse to the solenoid. The following events occur:
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Engines equipped with engine mounted ECM unit:</emph>The end of the injection cycle begins
            when the ECM terminates the fuel delivery command signal to the IDM solenoid. The following events occur:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The magnetic field of the solenoid collapses and is no longer able to overcome poppet spring
                tension to hold the poppet off its seat.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The poppet closes, shutting off high pressure oil from entering the injector.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the poppet is seated, the upper land of the poppet opens the poppet cavity to drain.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Pressurized oil in the intensifier chamber and poppet chamber flows upward around the poppet
                seat, through the vent holes in the poppet sleeve and out the adapter drain hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The pressure of the fuel and spring in the plunger cavity exerts an upward force on the
                plunger and intensifier. As the pressure of the pressurized oil above the intensifier drops, so does the
                downward force on the intensifier.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The upward force from the pressurized fuel almost instantly becomes greater than the
                downward force on the intensifier so the downward motion of the intensifier and plunger stops.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the plunger stops, fuel flow also stops.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the check still open, the remaining pressure on the fuel pushes a tiny amount of
                additional fuel out the orifice holes. This causes a large pressure drop and fuel nozzle pressure dorps
                below the VOP. Spring tension on the nozzle valve now reseats and injection stops.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef160in23" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1077" filename="../figeg1/eg1077.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure i.22 Fuel Injector Drain Cycle</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
