<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION 6: CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS, RINGS AND
        SLEEVES - CONNECTING RODS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CONNECTING RODS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the connecting rod bolts for nicks or damage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the rod and cap mating surfaces for fretting. Replace as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the connecting rod piston pin bushing for wear as follows:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>WHEN LUBRICATED WITH CLEAN ENGINE OIL, THE BOLTS MUST SCREW INTO THE ROD BY HAND. IF
                            RESISTANCE IS MET, CLEAN THE ROD THREADS AND TRY A NEW BOLT. IF A NEW BOLT DOES NOT SCREW IN
                            FREELY, THE ROD MUST BE DISCARDED. ROD THREADS CANNOT BE RETAPPED.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using a telescoping gauge (
                        <emph type="bold">OEM1022</emph>) and an outside micrometer, measure the pin bore at two (2)
                        locations 90&#176; from one another and record the readings. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600616">6.16</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>. If piston pin bushing I.D. exceeds minimum
                        specification, it is worn and must be replaced.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef1600615" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg5336" filename="../figeg5/eg5336.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.15 Measuring Ring Gap</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef1600616" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg5234" filename="../figeg5/eg5234.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.16 Measuring Connecting Rod Piston Pin Bore</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any worn bushing using a press and a driver.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the connecting rod piston pin bushing bore throughly and visually inspect for
                    defects. Using a telescoping gauge and a micrometer, measure the connecting rod piston pin bushing
                    bore diameter at two (2) locations. If out of specifications, replace the connecting rod.
                </para>
                <para>OUT-OF-ROUND CHECK</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check connecting rod bearing bore for "out-of-round" as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate connecting rod bolts with clean engine oil and assemble the cap to rod
                        with out bearing insert. Tighten bolts to the special torque value.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use an inside micrometer and measure connecting rod in three locations as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600617">6.17</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the difference between point "B" and average of points "A" and "C" ([A+C] &#247;
                        2), exceeds
                        <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>
                        rod must be replaced.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef1600617" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg5238" filename="../figeg5/eg5238.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.17 Checking Connecting Rod For Out-Of -Round</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure connecting rod bearing bore taper (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600618">6.18</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ), by measuring bore I.D. on each side of bearing bore. Record the readings. The difference between
                    the two readings is the bore taper (See
                    <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>). Replace rod as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With connecting rod cap removed, visually inspect surface finish of connecting rod
                    bearing bore. The bore must be smooth and free of scoring, nicks or burrs. Replace as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">CONNECTING ROD BEND AND TWIST:</emph>
                    Often engine component wear patterns can be identified and used to diagnose a problem. Some common
                    examples of connecting rod wear patterns include:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A shiny surface on edge of piston pin bushing usually indicates that a connecting
                        rod is bent or piston pin hole is not in proper relation to piston skirt and ring grooves.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Abnormal connecting rod bearing wear can be caused by either a bent connecting rod
                        or a tapered connecting rod bore.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Twisted connecting rods will not create an easily identifiable wear pattern but
                        badly twisted rods will disturb action of entire piston, rings and connecting rod assembly and
                        may be the cause of excessive oil consumption.
                    </para>
                    <para>If any of these conditions exist, check the connecting rods for bends or twists using a
                        suitable alignment fixture. Follow the instructions of the fixture manufacturer. If bend or
                        twist exceeds
                        <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>, replace the connecting rod.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>IF THE CONNECTING RODS
                                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                                MEET THE REQUIREMENTS SET FORTH IN "CONNECTING ROD INSPECTION", PARAGRAPHS 1-9. REPLACE
                                THE ENTIRE CONNECTING ROD ASSEMBLY.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef1600618" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg5237" filename="../figeg5/eg5237.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.18 Measuring Connecting Rod Bearing Bore Taper</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_143.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_145.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
