<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION: INTRODUCTION - LUBRICATION SYSTEM -
        OIL FLOW
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OIL FLOW</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figures
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef160in08">i.8</hotlnk>
                And
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef160in09">i.9</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <para>Lube oil is drawn from the oil sump through the pick-up screen and tube into the oil pump. The oil pump is
            of the gerotor type with the inner rotor portion driven directly by the crankshaft. The pump housing is
            bolted to the front cover. The pump inlet and outlet passages are through ports in the pump plate and front
            cover ports. Leaving the oil pump, the unfiltered oil travels (under pressure) back through the front cover
            assembly, passing the high pressure oil relief valve and into the crankcase unfiltered oil galley. The high
            oil pressure relief valve controls unfiltered oil pressure at 552 kPa (80 psi). When oil pressure exceeds
            552 kPa (80 psi), the oil pressure relief valve opens and excess oil is dumped back to the oil sump.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The high pressure oil relief controls unfiltered oil pressure at 552 kPa (80 psi) maximum.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>There are two oil galleries in the crankcase. The unfiltered oil travels down the unfiltered oil galley on
            the lower right hand side of the crankcase and the filtered oil galley runs above it. There are two exit
            ports in the unfiltered oil galley. One exits to the front header of the oil cooler and one exits to the
            rear header of the oil cooler. The oil cooler thermostat, located in the rear header, opens or closes by
            sensing oil temperature in the unfiltered galley. Depending upon the position of the oil thermostat, hot oil
            flows through the oil cooler core into the rear header and cold unfiltered oil by-passes the oil cooler core
            and goes directly to the oil filter.
        </para>
        <para>Oil directed from the unfiltered galley to the filter, enters from the outside of the element and exits
            from the center. The oil filter by-pass valve is located within the filter can and operates at a pressure
            differential of 124-138 kPa (18-20 psi). The oil filter element by-pass is effected from within the filter
            can. Clean engine oil flows out of the filter and goes back into the oil cooler header, then out the header
            and into the crankcase clean oil galley. The clean oil enters the crankcase, passes the oil pressure
            regulator valve and is directed through various ports of the crankcase. Excess oil is dumped back into the
            crankcase by the regulator valve.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The oil pressure regulator valve controls filtered oil pressure at 345 kpa (50 psi).</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Connecting rod bearings are individually fed through drilled passages in the crankshaft from main to rod
            journals. The camshaft journals are fed through passages drilled vertically through the main bearing webs.
        </para>
        <para>Oil is fed from the main bearing webs, through angled drillings, providing pressurized lube oil to the
            piston cooling jets. The valve lever rocker arms are lubricated through an anulus on the inside of the rear
            camshaft bushing bore of the crankcase. Oil then travels up through the vertical galley in the rear of the
            engine, through the banana slot in the head gasket and up the cylinder head bolt bore into the rocker arm
            shaft. Oil continues flowing through drillings located in the shaft of each rocker arm. Oil drains back to
            sump through push tube openings in the cylinderhead.
        </para>
        <para>Oil from the front of the main galley is routed through a cast-in passage located in the front of the
            crankcase, to the passage in the top of the high pressure pump reservoir. Oil then flows to the oil
            reservoir cast into the front cover, located in front of the high pressure pump. Oil, as needed, is then
            drawn by the high pressure pump through a passage found in the pump housing. High pressure oil is delivered
            to the high pressure supply manifold via an external hose from the high pressure pump. The high pressure oil
            reaches the fuel injectors through drillings in the supply manifold which intersect with the injector bores.
        </para>
        <para>The turbocharger receives filtered oil through an external tube connected at the rear oil cooler header.
            The air compressor (if equipped) also receive oil through external lines which are connected on the left
            side of the crankcase main filtered oil gallery. This fitting is supplied with oil directly from the main
            gallery. The front gear train is splash lubricated by oil draining from the high pressure reservoir and air
            compressor (if equipped) and from a small bleed slot at the top of the high pressure oil pump reservoir on
            the outer front cover.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef160in08" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg5889" filename="../figeg5/EG5889.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure i.8 Oil Flow</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="ef160in09" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg5891" filename="../figeg5/EG5891.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure i.9 Oil Cooler Oil Flow</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
