<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION 7: VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN
        BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - INSTALLATION - BEARING FITTING PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>BEARING FITTING PROCEDURE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new bearing in the bearing cap, as required. Be sure the locking tangs on the
                bearing inserts are snapped into the bearing cap notch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check bearing clearance as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the bearing surface and the exposed half of the crankshaft journal. Be sure these
                    surfaces are free of oil.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the bearing caps and lower inserts and tighten to the specified torque.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove one bearing cap with insert one at a time. Remaining caps are left tight while
                    checking the fit of the bearing with the cap removed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wipe the oil from all contact surfaces of the exposed journal and bearing insert and cap
                    removed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place a piece of Plastigage(r) across the full width of the bearing surface on the
                    crankshaft journal (or bearing cap insert) approximately 6 mm (1/4 in.) off center. Install bearing
                    cap and tighten cap bolt to specified torque.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not turn crankshaft while making check with Plastigage(r).</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>IN CHASSIS SERVICE ONLY - When bearing clearance is checked, the crankshaft will have to
                            be supported and held against the upper main bearing halves to get a correct Plastigage(r)
                            reading. Use a jack at counterweight next to each main bearing being checked to support the
                            crankshaft. Failure to support the crankshaft will result in inaccurate readings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef1600780" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5363" filename="../figeg5/EG5363.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7.80 Lubricating Upper Main Bearing Insert</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef1600781" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5359" filename="../figeg5/EG5359.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7.81 Installing Crankshaft</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove bearing cap with insert.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">g.
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>
                    <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                    disturb Plastigage(r). Using the Plastigage(r) envelope, measure the widest point of the
                    Plastigage(r),
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e160_204.xml" xrefid="ef1600782">7.82</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . This reading indicates the bearing clearance in thousandths of an inch or millimeters.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the bearing clearance is not within specifications, the crankshaft must be replaced
                    or reground and undersize bearings installed (as described earlier in this section).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_202.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_204.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
