<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION: INTRODUCTION - INJECTION CONTROL
        PRESSURE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e160_20.xml" xrefid="ef160in15">i.15</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                or
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e160_20.xml" xrefid="ef160in16">i.16</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <para>The system utilizes hydraulically actuated, electronically controlled unit injectors to deliver fuel
                to each cylinder. The hydraulic fluid used to actuate the injectors is engine oil.
            </para>
            <para>Oil is drawn from the oil pan thru the pickup tube by the engine oil pump. The engine oil pump is a
                gerotor type pump driven by the crankshaft. Oil is fed through passages in the front cover to the oil
                reservoir.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir makes available a constant supply of oil to a high pressure hydraulic pump mounted to
                the front cover. The high pressure pump is a gear driven swash plate pump. High pressure oil is
                delivered by the high pressure pump to the supply manifold and into oil passages machined into the
                cylinder head.
            </para>
            <para>When an injector is energized, a poppet valve is opened by an electronic solenoid mounted on the
                injector. Oil pressure is allowed to flow into the injector and act on the amplifier piston. When the
                solenoid is denergized the oil pressure on top of the amplifier piston is vented by the poppet valve
                thru the top portion of the injector.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
