<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION: INTRODUCTION - FUEL INJECTOR OPERATION
        - INJECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INJECTION</title>
        <para>When the ECM determines that the injector should be fired, the following sequence of events occurs:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Engines equipped with chassis mounted ECM and IDM units:</emph>ECM sends a Fuel
                Delivery Command Signal (FCDS) to IDM, which controls an electric current pulse sent to the injector
                solenoid bank. At the correct time, the IDM grounds the solenoid through a low-side driver within the
                IDM. When the injector has delivered the proper amount of fuel, the low-side driver is opened and the
                solenoid is denergized.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engines equipped with engine mounted ECM unit:</emph>The ECM sends a FCDS signal to
                the injector solenoid.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Solenoid is fully energized almost instantly creating a strong magnetic pull on the
                armature.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Magnetic pull of solenoid overcomes spring tension holding the poppet closed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Poppet is quickly raised off its seat.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Upper poppet land closes off path to drain.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower land opens poppet chamber to incoming high pressure oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">High pressure oil flows around poppet to the top of intensifier piston.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>Pressure on top of intensifier forces it down along with plunger. Downward movement of plunger pressurizes
            fuel in the plunger cavity and nozzle. When the fuel pressure reaches Valve Opening Pressure (VOP) the
            nozzle valve lifts off its seat and injection begins.
        </para>
        <para>Injection pressures may be as high as 12,411 kPa (18,000 psi) depending on engine requirements.</para>
        <figure id="ef160in22" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1076" filename="../figeg1/eg1076.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure i.21 Fuel Injector Operation</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
