<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION: INTRODUCTION - COOLING SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>COOLING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef160in06">i.6</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <para>The function of the cooling system is to keep the engine within a designated temperature range. Major
                components of most cooling systems include a radiator and fan combination with a coolant (water) pump,
                thermostat, oil cooler, and coolant filter. On these engines, the water pump is a belt-driven
                centrifugal type, which is set into the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>This front cover incorporates two separate passages. One passage to channel coolant to the crankcase
                from the water pump, the other is a bypass to route coolant back to the water pump when the thermostat
                is closed. The thermostat starts to open at 82&#176; C (180&#176; F) and is fully open at 94&#176; C
                (202&#176; F).
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows from the bottom of the radiator into the inlet tube of the front cover and onto the
                water pump. The coolant is pushed by the impeller of the water pump, through an internal passage in the
                front cover and out to the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>An internal passageway located in the crankcase directs coolant from front to rear, evenly
                distributing coolant to the lower sections of the cylinder sleeves. The coolant flow is directed toward
                each cylinder sleeve on a tangent causing a swirling motion upward towards the cylinder head. This
                swirling action improves heat dissipation.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant leaves the area around the cylinder sleeves in the following two ways:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The coolant is directed to the oil cooler via an exterior tube leading to the rear of
                    the oil cooler header. Coolant flows through passages in the oil cooler and exits at the water pump
                    to be re-mixed with incoming coolant from the radiator. Coolant is supplied to the rear of the air
                    compressor from the left side of the crankcase. After the coolant exits at the front of the air
                    compressor, it is returned to the crankcase on the left side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coolant exits from the crankcase, through two cored holes at the top of each side of the
                    cylinder sleeve bore and is metered for even distribution by holes in the head gasket. Coolant then
                    flows through the cylinder head to the thermostat. The thermostat incorporates two outlets to direct
                    coolant either to the radiator when the engine is at operating temperature, or directly back to the
                    water pump when the engine has not yet reached operating temperature.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef160in06" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5886" filename="../figeg5/eg5886.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure i.6 Coolant Flow</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
