<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION 6: CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS, RINGS AND
        SLEEVES - BEARING FITTING PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>BEARING FITTING PROCEDURE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
            <title>BEARING FITTING</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If bearing-to-crankshaft running clearances exceed specifications because of wear on the
                    crankshaft, replace or regrind the crankshaft and install undersize precision type bearing shells.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                            ATTEMPT TO REDUCE JOURNAL-TO-BEARING RUNNING CLEARANCES BY REWORKING BEARING CAP, BEARINGS
                            OR BOTH. REGRIND OR REPLACE THE CRANKSHAFT ONLY. REFER TO SECTION 7.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>REWORKING THE BEARING CAP WILL DESTROY THE ENGINEERED FIT OF THE BEARING SHELLS IN THEIR
                            BORES.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the connecting rod bolts alternately and evenly to the special torque value.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>ABOUT BEARING CRUSH AND SPREAD! Bearing shells must fit tightly in the bore. When bearing
                            shells are inserted into the connecting rod and cap, they protrude above the parting line.
                            This protrusion is required to achieve "BEARING CRUSH". Bearing shells are designed with
                            "SPREAD". That is, the width across the open ends are slightly larger than the diameter of
                            the connecting rod bore into which they are assembled, as shown in Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600626">6.26</hotlnk>. This condition is designed into the bearing shell
                            causing it to spread outward at the parting line when "CRUSH" load is applied by tightening
                            the bolts. Some
                            <emph type="underscr">snap</emph>
                            may be lost in normal use but bearing replacement is not required because of a nominal loss
                            of
                            <emph type="underscr">snap</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef1600626" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5756" filename="../figeg5/eg5756.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.26 Bearing Fitting Procedure</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>When the assembly is drawn up tight, the bearing is compressed, assuring a positive contact
                    between the bearing back and the bore as shown in
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600627">6.27</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit connecting rod bearings and measure bearing running clearance as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With bearing cap removed, wipe oil from the face of the bearing insert and exposed
                        portion of the crankshaft journal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place a piece of
                        <emph type="bold">"Plastigage</emph>(r)
                        <emph type="bold">"</emph>
                        across the full width of the bearing about 6 mm (1/4 in.) off center.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the cap and tighten bolts evenly and alternately to special torque value.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                                turn the crankshaft during running clearance check.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef1600627" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11569" filename="../figcg1/cg11569.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.27 Checking Bearing Running Clearance</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove main bearing cap. The
                        <emph type="bold">"Plastigage</emph>(r)
                        <emph type="bold">"</emph>
                        material will be found adhering to either the bearing shell or the crankshaft.
                        <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                        <emph type="bold">REMOVE "PLASTICGAGE</emph>(r)
                        <emph type="bold">"</emph>. Use
                        <emph type="bold">"Plasticgage</emph>(r)
                        <emph type="bold">"</emph>
                        scale to measure widest point of flattened plastic material (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600628">6.28</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ). The number within the graduated marks on the scale indicates the clearance in thousandths of
                        an inch or millimeters (See
                        <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the test material and the repeat test for each connecting rod bearing.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>With the precision bearings used, no problem should be encountered. If proper
                                clearance is
                                <emph type="underscr">NOT</emph>
                                achieved, a problem with the crankshaft may exist which requires regrinding and the use
                                of undersize bearings. (Refer to Section 7 for Crankshaft Rework Information.) Bearing
                                cap torque is very important. Repeat running clearance check procedure before condemning
                                the crankshaft.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check clearance of connecting rod by placing a feeler gauge between the connecting rod
                    and the crankshaft journal (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1600629">6.29</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check connecting rod side clearance using a dial indicator as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the tip of the dial indicator on the connecting rod cap.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pry the connecting rod towards the rear of the engine and "zero" the dial
                        indicator.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pry the connecting rod toward the front of the engine and read the indicator. Refer
                        to
                        <emph type="bold">"SPECIFICATIONS"</emph>
                        and repeat for all connecting rods.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The connecting rod side clearance must be checked to be certain that the specified
                                clearance exists.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Lack of clearance could indicate a damaged rod or a rod bearing out of position. Excessive
                        clearance may require replacement of the rods or crankshaft. Correct as required.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef1600628" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg6904" filename="../figeg6/eg6904.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.28 Placing Plasticgage(r) For Main Bearing Cap Clearance Check</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef1600629" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="eg7006" filename="../figeg7/eg7006.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.29 Checking Clearance Between Connecting Rod And Crankshaft Journal</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_149.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_151.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
