<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Service (1995 through 1999) - SECTION 11: ENGINE ELECTRICAL - VERIFYING CMP
        SENSOR CLEARANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>VERIFYING CMP SENSOR CLEARANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
            <title>REMOVING</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove CMP sensor mounting bolt from engine front cover and pull CMP sensor out. Clean
                    sensor mounting surface (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1601149">11.49</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Manually rotate the crankshaft at least two (2) complete revolutions in a clockwise
                    direction when viewing the engine from the front. This insures the CMP sensor air gap is at its
                    maximum with the camshaft gear in contact with its rear thrust face.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Be sure, when making the following measurement, to measure up to the tooth on the trigger
                            wheel. do not measure into the window between the teeth.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a depth micrometer or a precision caliper, carefully measure the distance to the
                    nearest one thousandth of an inch from the CMP sensor mounting surface to the camshaft gear trigger
                    wheel tooth (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1601150">11.50</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). Record this measurement in the appropriate box on worksheet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Manually rotate crankshaft 180&#176; in a clockwise direction, when viewed from the
                    front of the engine, and repeat step 3. Continue this process two (2) more times so that the
                    distance from the cover to the trigger wheel is measured at four (4) locations. Variations in these
                    measurements determine run out of the trigger wheel. Variation should not exceed 0.005 inches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a depth micrometer or precision caliper carefully measure CMP sensor from the tip
                    to its mounting flange (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef1601151">11.51</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). Record this dimension in the appropriate box on work sheet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the math as directed on the work sheet then select appropriate combination of
                    shims from shim kit, if required. Refer to the DT 466E and 530E Parts Manual for the proper kit part
                    number.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use the proper combination of shims to achieve a measurement as close to 0.30 inch as
                            possible.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef1601149" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5073" filename="../figeg5/eg5073.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.49 Remove CMP Sensor</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef1601150" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5894" filename="../figeg5/eg5894.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.50 Measuring CMP Sensor Clearance</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef1601151" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="eg5896" filename="../figeg5/eg5896.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.51 Measuring Depth Micrometer</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the CMP sensors with the shims required. Insure that the shims are centered on
                    the CMP sensor flange. Use a small amount of grease to hold then if necessary. Reconnect sensor
                    wiring harness and test engine.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use the following work sheet to complete the CMP sensor air gap analysis, as described in
                            steps 1 thru 7. Enter the measurements in the boxes on the work sheet.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_270.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160_272.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e160.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
