<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - CAMSHAFT POSITION (CMP) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>Once the ECM has recognized the narrow vane (wide window) it will synchronize the engine firing order to
            the timing of the CMP signal. Every 2 crankshaft revolutions it will verify that synchronization. If the ECM
            receives too many or too few pulses for the number of engine revolutions, it will set a fault code.
        </para>
        <para>The engine will not operate without a functioning CMP signal. However, the ECM will attempt to determine
            the cause of an invalid signal and identify it with a fault code.
        </para>
        <para>CMP codes that are set will become inactive codes if the key is turned off. These codes can be retrieved
            using the Self Test Input (STI) switch/(Engine DIAGNOSTICS switch) located on the vehicle dashboard or the
            Electronic Service Tool.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">143</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">WRONG # OF CMP SIGNAL TRANSITIONS PER CAM REVOLUTION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 143 indicates the ECM has received CMP signals with the wrong number of transitions. This indicates
            that the ECM has counted the voltage transitions and found less than the specified number of pulses from the
            sensor. When this problem is continuous, the engine will stop running and the ECM will log an active code.
            If the key is shut off, the code will become an inactive code. This code will not turn the warning light on.
        </para>
        <para>Possible causes for code 143: Intermittent CMP signal caused by a intermittent circuit, defective Camshaft
            Position Sensor, or incorrect CMP sensor to timing disk clearance.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">144</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 2</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">CMP SIGNAL NOISE DETECTED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 144 indicates that the ECM has detected voltage spikes or transitions other than the CMP signal. If
            this problem is continuous the engine could stop running and the ECM will log an active code. If the key is
            shut off, the code will become an inactive. This code will not cause the warning light to illuminate.
        </para>
        <para>Code 144 may be due to: Poor ground connections for CMP or other electronic components. Wire harness
            shielding missing or incorrectly installed on the engine harness. Outside components that could induce
            voltage signals.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">145</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 12</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">CMP SIGNAL INACTIVE WHILE ICP HAS</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">INCREASED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Flash code 145 indicates that the ECM does not detect a CMP signal. This code would be set if the engine
            was rotating and the ECM detected a rise in ICP pressure, but did not detect a CMP signal. To set this code
            the engine must be rotated long enough for the ICP to increase. When this code is set the engine will not
            operate. This code will not cause the warning light to illuminate.
        </para>
        <para>Possible causes for flash code 145: Defective CMP sensor, faulty sensor circuitry, or improper air gap
            between sensor and camshaft timing disk.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">612</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 21 FMI 7</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">INCORRECT ECM INSTALLED FOR CMP TIMING DISK</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Flash code 612 indicates that the ECM has monitored the CMP signal and the signal is incorrect for the
            programming in the ECM. This means that the ECM does not recognize the signal generated from the timing disk
            and CMP sensor.
        </para>
        <para>Possible causes: ECM has been accidently replaced with an incorrect ECM for the particular engine
            application. (For example, the timing disk for the I-6 and V-8 (T444E) are different and generate a
            different signal. An ECM from the V-8 (T444E) engine will not run an I-6 engine.) Incorrect signal due to a
            defective CMP sensor or incorrect air gap between the CMP sensor and the timing disk.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">315</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 190 FMI 0</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ENGINE SPEED ABOVE WARNING LEVEL</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Flash code 315 indicates that the ECM has detected an engine speed above 3000 RPM. The most likely cause
            of the excessive engine speed is an unintended down shift, steep acceleration down a hill without correct
            brake application or an external fuel source being ingested into the air intake system. The engine hours and
            miles of the last two over speed occurrences will be recorded in the Engine Event Log. Code 315 will cause
            the WARN lamp to illuminate.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_163.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_HL1901706.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
