<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ENGINE CRANK INHIBIT SYSTEM (ECI) - SYSTEM OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SYSTEM OPERATION</title>
        <para>Refer to circuit diagram
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>for the following description (
            <emph type="BOLD">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e190_189.xml" xrefid="f1901738">3.40</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ).
        </para>
        <para>When the ignition switch is turned to the start position, with the ignition switch on and the push button
            start switch depressed, current flows to the Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) relay. The relay is then enabled if
            the ECM supplies the ground circuit for the relay control windings.
        </para>
        <para>Closing this relay allows current to pass from the ignition switch through fuse F17 through the neutral
            safety switch (jumped if manual trans) and through the clutch switch normally closed (jumped if auto trans).
            With the relay closed current then passes through the relay and will energize the start relay, the ground
            circuit for the start relay is through the overcrank protection fuse in the crank motor or directly to
            ground if not equipped with overcrank protection. When the relay is closed the current can then pass from
            the crank motor Battery terminal through the relay and to the crank motor solenoid, start terminal. This
            closes the crank solenoid to engage the starter.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_184.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_186.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
