<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.8: DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION -
        OPERATOR ON DEMAND TESTS ENGINE OFF - INJECTOR "BUZZ" TEST (ENGINE OFF)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="f1900802" svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INJECTOR "BUZZ" TEST (ENGINE OFF)</title>
        <para>The purpose of the Engine Off Injector "BUZZ" Test is to diagnose electrical problems with the fuel
            delivery components. This test can only be accessed with the EST and only after an "Engine Off Test" or
            Standard Test has been performed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before running this test, fault codes should be accessed, noted and erased. This will allow the
                    faults found in this test to be displayed as "Active Codes".
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>During the test, the ECM will actuate the injectors in numerical order 1 through 8,
            <emph type="underscr">not in firing order</emph>. The ECM will monitor each injector's electrical circuit
            operation and evaluate the performance of the injector's solenoid and the electrical circuit operation. If
            an electronic component in the fuel system fails the expected parameters, an inactive fault code will be
            logged and transmitted to the EST at the end of the test.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The technician can monitor injector operation by listening to the sound each injector produces as
                    it is activated by the ECM, however, in a Hard Start/No Start condition where the oil may be very
                    cold/thick injectors may not be audible.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>If the faults were not erased before this test, the faults found during this test will be displayed as
            "INACTIVE CODES".
        </para>
        <para>To read these fault codes after the test has been completed, access the "Diagnostic Codes" menu and read
            both Active and Inactive codes.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900803.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
