<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE (EPR) REGULATOR - EXHAUST BACK
        PRESSURE REGULATOR VALVE EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE REGULATOR VALVE EXTENDED SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Function</title>
            <para>The Navistar engine control system includes an Exhaust Back Pressure Regulator (EPR) Valve. The valve
                controls exhaust back pressure in cold ambient temperatures to increase cab heat and decrease the amount
                of time required to defrost the windshield. The EPR valve consists of a solenoid, poppet and spool valve
                assembly and is mounted on the turbocharger pedestal. The ECM regulates exhaust back pressure by
                controlling the duty cycle of ON/OFF time of the exhaust pressure regulator solenoid. The increase or
                decrease of ON/OFF time positions a spool valve internal to the EPR which in turn either increases or
                decreases the amount of exhaust back pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>The EPR valve is supplied with voltage at Terminal A of the EPR connector from Terminal 29 of the ECM.
                The ECM controls the exhaust pressure regulator by varying the pulse width or percentage of ON/OFF time
                of the EPR solenoid. Normal ON/OFF time varies from 0% to 95%. A high duty cycle indicates that the
                exhaust back pressure valve is being closed to raise the amount of exhaust back pressure based on
                (ambient) intake air temperature, engine oil temperature, engine load and exhaust back pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the exhaust back pressure while the engine is in operation. If actual pressure is
                greater or less than the desired pressure, the ECM will set a fault code. When this occurs the ECM will
                discontinue exhaust pressure regulator operation leaving the exhaust back pressure valve open, creating
                no exhaust restriction to aid in warm up of vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Fault codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or the Self Test Input diagnostic
                switch located on the vehicle dash. If the ignition key is shut off, the code will be sent as an
                Inactive code.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
                <emph type="BOLD">245</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 35 FMI 11</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">EPR: OCC SELF TEST FAILED</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 245 is set only during the Engine Off Standard Output Circuit check. This test indicates the ECM
                has performed an output circuit test, measure voltage drop across the EPR circuit and determined it is
                above or below specification. If the fault is present, the exhaust pressure regulator will be disabled.
            </para>
            <para>Possible Causes: Open feed circuit, open EPR solenoid, an open or shorted EPR signal circuit.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
                <emph type="BOLD">343</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 0</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">EPR: EXCESSIVE EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 343 indicates that the ECM has detected exhaust back pressure greater than 77 (in. Hg.) which is
                greater than the maximum allowable working range.
            </para>
            <para>Possible Causes: Incorrect EBP signal due to faulty circuits or sensor, grounded EPR signal circuit, a
                collapsed exhaust pipe or stuck exhaust pressure regulator valve.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
                <emph type="BOLD">352</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 10</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">EPR: EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE ABOVE OR BELOW DESIRED LEVEL</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 352 may be set during normal engine operation through the continuous monitor function or during
                the engine running standard test. It indicates the measured pressure does not meet the expected value.
            </para>
            <para>Possible Causes: Incorrect EBP signal due to circuit or sensor malfunctions. EBP signal circuit may be
                shorted, grounded, or contain excessive resistance. The EPR valve may be sticking or blocked.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
                <emph type="BOLD">351</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 34 FMI 7</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="BOLD">EPR: EXHAUST BACK PRESSURE BELOW EXPECTED LEVEL AT HIGH ENGINE SPEEDS.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 351 may be set during normal engine operation through the continuous monitor function by the ECM.
                This code indicates the ECM did not see a minimum of of 20 (KPA) pressure data from low idle operation
                to 2300 RPM engine operation.
            </para>
            <para>Possible Causes: Incorrect EBP signal due to faulty circuit or sensor, plugged exhaust back pressure
                tube, or exhaust pressure valve stuck.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_252.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_HL1901718.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
