<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - REMOTE ACCELERATOR PEDAL SENSOR - FAULT DETECTION
        MANAGEMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
        <para>The ECM monitors the voltage at the RPS terminal for voltage to determine if the signal is in range. A
            minimum voltage level is established to verify that the circuit is not open and a maximum voltage level is
            established to verify that the signal is not shorted to a voltage source. When the ECM sees the voltage out
            of range the pedal will be disabled and a flash code 213 for out of rang low or 214 for out of range high.
            If the ignition is shut off the flash code will be recorded as an inactive code.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">213</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 29 FMI 4</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">REMOTE THROTTLE SIGNAL</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">OUT OF RANGE LOW</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Flash code 213 indicates that ECM pin 30 voltage was less than .25 volts. This indicates an open circuit
            for the VREF supply from ECM pin 5 or in the RPS signal circuit to pin 30 from the RPS. It may also result
            from a defective (open) remote pedal sensor.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">214</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE SID 29 FMI 3</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">REMOTE THROTTLE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Flash code 214 indicates the ECM pin 30 voltage was greater than 4.5 volts. This indicates a possible open
            circuit in RPS return to pin 6 or a short to another voltage supply on the RPS signal circuit. It may also
            result from a defective (shorted) remote pedal sensor.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_323.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_325.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
