<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.6: SENSOR OPERATION - TYPES OF SENSORS - HALL
        EFFECT SENSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="f1900607" svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>HALL EFFECT SENSOR</title>
        <para>The Hall Effect sensor is an electronic device which generates a voltage. The shape and frequency of this
            signal depends on how the magnetic field of this sensor is disturbed.
        </para>
        <para>The Camshaft Position sensor is an example of a Hall Effect sensor. It contains a permanent magnet,
            transducer, signal conditioner and a switching transistor as shown in
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1900608">1.26</hotlnk>.
            </emph>
            The sensor's permanent magnet generates a magnetic field around the transducer and the timing sensor disk
            mounted, to the camshaft gear. As the magnetic field is disturbed by the rotation of the timing disk (vanes
            and windows) the transducer generates a signal which is filtered and conditioned by the internal CMP sensor
            signal conditioner.
        </para>
        <para>Once the signal has been conditioned, it is applied to the switching transistor's base which causes the
            transistor to switch on and ground the 5 volt line from the ECM. At this time, the ECM no longer senses the
            5 volt reference signal.
        </para>
        <para>Each time a vane passes no signal is generated by the transducer. This action causes the transistor to
            shut off and allows the ECM to see it's 5 volt reference signal.
        </para>
        <para>This switching action allows the ECM to determine crankshaft position and engine speed which is required
            by the ECM to control engine operating parameters such as injector timing, duration (injection pulse width)
            and Injection Control Pressure.
        </para>
        <para>This sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires: a 5 volt signal supply, a 5 volt power feed for the
            signal conditioner VDREF and signal ground.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1900608" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg7368" filename="../figeg7/EG7368.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.26 Hall Effect Sensor (Camshaft Position Sensor)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900605.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900609.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
