<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - VEHICLE RETARDER (VRE) - VEHICLE RETARDER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VEHICLE RETARDER</title>
        <para>This group of parameters customizes the retarder feature. The purpose for the Vehicle Retarder is to
            provide the proper logic to enable or disable a mechanical engine/transmission brake. Several types of
            engine brakes exist.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Engine Exhaust Brakes</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Transmission Retarders</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Anti - Lock braking devices</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The purpose of these devices is to aid in a vehicle's deceleration by providing additional vehicle or
            engine load. This will reduce brake wear for vehicles in situations that require frequent braking. Also
            provided is over-speed protection which will decrease the odds of engine damage due to excessive engine
            speed.
        </para>
        <para>The on-board electronics provides the proper control logic necessary to determine when the vehicle
            retarder should be enabled. Currently, there are five states of electronic operation. OFF, LATCHED, COAST,
            TRANSMISSION LATCHED and OVER SPEED
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="underscr">Vehicle Retarder</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics the desired mode of operation for the vehicle
            retarder feature.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>OFF: Feature is disabled at all times.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>LATCHED: The vehicle retarder will be enabled when the proper engine/vehicle conditions are
                    satisfied. When either cruise control of PTO speed control is on, the brake pedal must be applied
                    before vehicle retarder will be enabled. It will remain enabled until such time that the accelerator
                    pedal is depressed or the low idle speed has been reached.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>COAST: The vehicle retarder will be enabled when the proper engine/vehicle conditions are
                    satisfied. When either the cruise control or PTO speed control is on, the brake pedal must be
                    applied before vehicle retarder will be enabled. It will remain enabled only if the brake pedal is
                    continually depressed.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>TRANSMISSION LATCHED: The vehicle retarder will be operated similarly to the LATCHED state.
                    However, the engine is allowed to operate at a higher RPM range in this state because the
                    transmission is the retarding device.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>OVER SPEED: This protection is provided in all active vehicle retarder states. This is included so
                    that the vehicle retarder will become enabled when RPM is too high.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">265</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 62 FMI 11</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">VEHICLE RETARDER RELAY OCC FAULT</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The Output Circuit Test, performed during an "ON Demand" Engine Standard Test, will test the coil side of
            the vehicle retarder relay and circuit for an open or short condition. If an out of range condition exists,
            flash code 265 will be set.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_407.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_409.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
