<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ENGINE COOLANT LEVEL SYSTEM - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The Engine Coolant Level sensor is used with the optional engine warning and protection feature. The
            purpose of the Coolant Level system is to monitor the level of the coolant in the surge tank to protect the
            engine from damage due to operating the engine when the coolant level is low. Since this is an optional
            feature, the system functions by programming three way warning or three way engine shutdown in the control
            module.
        </para>
        <para>In either mode when the feature has been enabled and the engine is running, the ECM will cause the red
            Oil/Water warning light to illuminate and the warning buzzer to sound if the coolant level is depleted below
            the level of the sender in the surge tank. If the system is programmed for engine shut down, the ECM will
            cause the engine to stop running after the coolant level has been depleted below the coolant level sensor
            and the preprogrammed warning time has expired. If the engine stops running in this condition, it can be
            restarted and run again for the warning time period, provided it is capable of restarting.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_192.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_194.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
