<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE (ECM) POWER SUPPLY - EXTENDED
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>Refer to the Electronic Control Module power supply circuit diagram (
            <emph type="BOLD">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e190_211.xml" xrefid="f1901748">3.47</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            )
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>for the following discussion.
        </para>
        <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) receives its power directly from the vehicle batteries when the ECM
            power relay is energized. This allows maximum power transfer from the batteries to the ECM with a minimum
            amount of power loss. The wire harness which supplies ECM power is fused at the battery to protect it from
            short circuits.
        </para>
        <para>When the key switch is turned ON, ignition power from fuse F5 (5 A) is supplied to cavity V of the ECM
            through the 22 pin cab cowl connecter. This indicates to the ECM that the ignition switch is ON and it is
            time to enable the ECM power relay.
        </para>
        <para>Power to the ECM Power Relay control coil (terminal 85) is provided by circuit 97CT from the battery feed
            stud through the 22 pin cab cowl connector. The ECM will enable the ECM power relay by completing the ground
            circuit (internally) to the relay at ECM pin 25.
        </para>
        <para>When the ECM Power Relay is enabled power at terminal 30 from the vehicle batteries is switched directly
            to the ECM from terminal 87 of the relay to pins 21, 22 and 41 of the ECM. The vehicle battery power for
            this relay to switch is supplied directly from the battery through connector 426 and to terminal 30 of the
            relay.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_206.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_208.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
