<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - REMOTE PTO SPEED CONTROL (RPTO) - SYSTEM FUNCTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SYSTEM FUNCTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The purpose of the Remote Power Takeoff feature is to allow the control of engine speed via remote
                switches for the use of ancillary engine devices such as hydraulic pumps, lift gates etc.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mode Selection</title>
            <para>Variable speed or preset PTO control (up to two speeds selected) can be selected and programmed into
                the module via the EST (Electronic Service Tool). The mode, variable and/or preset PTO must be selected
                and "turned on" by the EST tool for this feature to function. On/Off switches must also be installed to
                provide a 12v signal to the appropriate pin in the ECM. The Remote PTO feature will be disabled when
                vehicle speed is detected, the clutch pedal is depressed or if the engine is put into gear (automatic
                transmission only).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speed Selection</title>
            <para>Variable PTO speed is either increased or decreased by depressing the momentary speed control switch
                to the Set or Resume position. The speed at which the engine accelerates is noted as the "Ramp Rate" or
                RPM per seconds of acceleration that the engine is allowed to accelerate 'Ramp Rate" and maximum PTO
                speed are programmable by using the EST tool.
            </para>
            <para>In the preset PTO mode, the momentary speed control switch allows for two preset speeds to be
                selected. By momentarily depressing the switch in the preset #1 mode the first speed is selected, by
                momentarily depressing the switch in the preset #2 position a second speed can be selected. These speeds
                are programmable in the ECM by using the EST service tool.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_HL1901729.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_330.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
