<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - INJECTION PRESSURE REGULATION SYSTEM (IPR_SYS) - FAULT
        DETECTION/MANAGEMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
        <para>The fault codes associated with this system may indicate an electrical or electronic control system
            failure, but
            <emph type="BOLD">most likely will indicate a mechanical or hydraulic problem with the injection control
                pressure system.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>The ECM constantly monitors the injection control pressure in the system to assure the control system is
            providing the proper control pressure at all times. If the oil pressure feedback provided by the ICP sensor
            does not meet the ECM's programmed desired values, the ECM will set a fault code, illuminate the WARN lamp
            and control the operation of the injection control system by calculating the correct oil pressure for all
            engine operating conditions until the system is diagnosed and repaired.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM also monitors the injection control pressure developed while cranking the engine. If pressure does
            not develop within the ECM's expected time limit, it will set an appropriate fault code which will aid the
            technician in diagnosing the no start or hard start condition.
        </para>
        <para>The Electronic Service Tool (EST) may be used by the technician to command the ECM to perform an engine
            running test on the Injection Control Pressure system. The ECM controls the pressure regulator in a
            programmed sequence to evaluate system performance. At the end of the test, the ECM will transmit any fault
            codes if system performance is unsatisfactory.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_290.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_292.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
