<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE - OPERATION AND
        FUNCTION - III. MICROPROCESSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>III. MICROPROCESSOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ECM contains an internal microprocessor. The processor stores operating instructions (control
                strategies) and tables of values (calibration parameters). It compares these stored instructions and
                values to conditioned input values to determine the correct operating strategy for any given engine
                operating condition. Calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds referred to as the
                foreground and the background calculations. These calculations are performed on a continuous loop basis.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic strategies (instructions) are also programmed into the ECM. Some instructions monitor
                inputs on a continuous basis and command the necessary outputs to achieve the correct performance of the
                engine.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM's microprocessor is equipped with two types of memory. They are Random Access Memory (RAM) and
                Read Only Memory (ROM)
                <emph type="bold"></emph>(
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1900506">1.17</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). They allow the processor to store the necessary instructions, calibration tables and input values to
                control the engine.
            </para>
            <para>These strategies will instruct the ECM to continuously perform certain diagnostic procedures and other
                diagnostic tests upon the technician's demand.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic codes can be generated by the microprocessor in the event of any inputs or conditions not
                complying with pre-programmed expected values. Calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or
                speeds referred to as the foreground and the background calculations. These calculations are performed
                on a continuous loop basis.
            </para>
            <para>Foreground calculations occur at a much faster rate than the background calculations and are normally
                the more critical functions to engine operation. Engine speed control is an example of foreground
                calculations.
            </para>
            <para>Background calculations are normally variables that change at a slower rate such as engine
                temperature.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM's microprocessor is equipped with two types of memory Random Access (RAM) and Read Only (ROM)
                memory. These memories allow the processor to store the necessary instructions, calibration tables and
                input values necessary to control the engine.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ROM</title>
            <para>Read Only Memory is the memory where calibration tables and operating strategies are stored.
                Information in the ROM is permanent. It can not be changed or lost by turning the engine off or
                disconnecting the batteries.
            </para>
            <para>All the information regarding the engine rating are stored in this memory. Vehicle and Engine
                personality information are also stored in this memory and can be modified with the EST in order to
                comply with each individual customer's needs. This includes truck configuration, available features,
                warning / protection modes and many other parameters which will be described in more detail further in
                this manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RAM</title>
            <para>Random Access Memory is a temporary storage memory for current events such as current engine
                temperature or current speed, pedal position etc. It is the memory to which information is temporarily
                stored so that it can be compared to the information in the ROM. Unlike the Rom memory, the RAM is lost
                every time the key is turned off or when power is interrupted to the ECM.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1900506" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1273" filename="../figeg1/EG1273.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.17 Electronic Control Module Microprocessor Memory</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900504.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900507.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
