<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - REMOTE ACCELERATOR PEDAL SENSOR - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The remote accelerator pedal sensor is used for engine speed control outside of the vehicle cab. As part
            of the PTO engine speed control, connections for the RPS are supplied through the body builder's
            connections.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to circuit diagram (
            <emph type="BOLD">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e190_327.xml" xrefid="f19017102">3.84</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            )
            <emph type="BOLD"></emph>for the following description.
        </para>
        <para>To operate the Remote Accelerator Pedal sensor a 5 volt reference voltage is supplied by the ECM from pin
            5 through the body builder's connections circuit 97DD. Signal return for the RPS is supplied by a dedicated
            terminal number 6 through the body builder's connections circuit 97HM. The remote pedal sensor is a
            potentiometer that uses the 5 volt reference voltage and signal return to supply an analog voltage to
            terminal 30 through the body builder's connections circuit 99F. In the idle position, the voltage signal
            from the RPS is low. As the pedal is depressed, the voltage increases, indicating an increase in demand for
            speed from the operator.
        </para>
        <para>Before the RPS is operational the ECM must first have a 12 volt signal at pin 36. This is supplied through
            the body builder's connections circuit 97CC to enable the operation of the RPS.
        </para>
        <para>To interrupt the operation of the PTO speed control, if the Remote Variable circuit is open the engine
            will return to idle. Or if the brake or clutch pedal is depressed or with an automatic transmission, the
            transmission is placed in gear, the engine will return to idle. If the option has been programmed in the ECM
            for PTO operation disable the brake, clutch or transmission will not interrupt the PTO speed control. Also
            if the ECM receives a signal from the vehicle Speed Sensor the engine will return to idle. Remote PTO speed
            control will not function if the Brake or VSS circuits are in fault. And the RPS will not operate if the RPS
            system has an active fault present.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_321.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_323.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
