<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 2.1 DIAGNOSTIC FORMS</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection division="ENGINE" id="E19009" svcsectype="PRODSPEC" date="01/21/1998">
        <title>SECTION 2.1 DIAGNOSTIC FORMS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
            <para>No doubt almost any mechanical problem can be accurately diagnosed under ideal conditions. But what
                really matters is whether accurate diagnosis can become the norm under everyday conditions. Much of the
                long term success and acceptance of an engine is actually determined by the efficiency of thousands of
                shop foremen and technicians.
            </para>
            <para>The purpose of engine diagnostic forms are to provide the customer with satisfaction as well as assist
                the technician in troubleshooting the T 444E Diesel Engine. Diagnostic forms provide a guide to finding
                problems quickly and easily and to avoid unnecessary repairs and expense. Engine diagnostic forms should
                not remain buried in a book in the shop foreman's service library. They should be taken right to the job
                and used to provide a systematic and time saving method of diagnosing engine problems.
            </para>
            <para>Engine diagnostic forms begin with the basics progressing to the tests that are more difficult. This
                leads the technician in a path of diagnosis to check the more common problems first and proceed to the
                less likely. The form should be followed in sequence, starting at test number one (1) and continuing
                through to the final test. The order of the tests should be followed because some components depend on
                the function of other components for proper operation. Performing the tests out of order could cause an
                incorrect conclusion.
            </para>
            <para>Two diagnostic forms are required to properly diagnose the T 444E engine. The first form,
                <emph type="bold">Hard Start/No Start and Performance Engine Diagnostics</emph>, guides the technician
                through Hard Start or No Start conditions in which the engine does not start or is difficult to start.
                The Performance Engine Diagnostics portion guides the technician through conditions in which the engine
                is running with some type of performance problem. An example would be a low power complaint.
                Illustrations when applicable, are located on the reverse side of the form. They show the location of
                test points and how to hook up test equipment at each point.
            </para>
            <para>The second form,
                <emph type="bold">Electronic Control System Diagnostics</emph>, lists all engine and vehicle related
                fault codes on the front side. A circuit index adjacent to each fault code is provided to assist the
                technician to quickly refer to the appropriate section of the manual for each fault code. Fault code
                descriptions, comments and probable causes are listed for each fault code listed. This information will
                allow the technician to understand what the fault code is and the problem associated with it.
            </para>
            <para>The reverse side of this form contains a schematic wiring diagram of the T 444E engine and truck
                mounted electronic controls. In addition, a chart is supplied which describes the Electronic Control
                Module's expected signal values under specified conditions. The chart will enable the experienced
                technician to quickly identify and repair the problem.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_61.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_63.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
