<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.2: INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE SYSTEM -
        INJECTION CONTROL SYSTEM OPERATION - IPR VALVE OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="f1900205" svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="2">
        <title>IPR VALVE OPERATION</title>
        <para>The Injection Control Pressure Regulator valve is a pulse width (Duty cycle %) modulated valve operating
            at 400 Hz. The pulse width is modulated between 8 to 60% to control ICP pressure in the range of 3.4 to 20
            KPa (500 to 3000 psi). The regulator is mounted in the high pressure pump and maintains desired injection
            control pressure by dumping excess oil through a (internal shuttle) spool valve into the front cover and
            back to the oil pan.
        </para>
        <para>As the demand for injection control pressure increases, the ECM increases the pulse width (duty cycle %)
            over the IPR solenoid. This action forces the poppet against the drain orifice increasing the pressure
            behind the spool valve.
        </para>
        <para>As oil pressure increases
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1900206">1.8</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            behind the spool valve, it moves forward and blocks the drain ports on the sides of the IPR valve. When the
            demand for injection control pressure decreases,
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1900207">1.9</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            the ECM decreases the (duty cycle %) over the solenoid allowing oil to drain out of the drain orifice. This
            action is accomplished by relieving the pressure behind the spool valve which allows it to partially open
            the relief port decreasing the injection control pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The described operation allows the IPR to continuously adjust injection control pressure commanded by the
            ECM.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1900206" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1266" filename="../figeg1/eg1266.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.8 IPR Higher Injection Pressure</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1900207" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1267" filename="../figeg1/eg1267.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.9 IPR Lower Injection Pressure</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900202.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_E19003.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
