<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.8: DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION -
        INJECTOR "CYLINDER CONTRIBUTION" TEST (ENGINE RUNNING)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INJECTOR "CYLINDER CONTRIBUTION" TEST (ENGINE RUNNING)</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The Injector Test is designed to detect problems with injection and combustion events. This test will
                not only detect injector problems, but it will detect any problem that could affect the overall
                performance of the power cylinder (ie.: valves, push rods, pistons, rings, etc.)
            </para>
            <para>During this test the ECM will control fuel delivery and determine each cylinder's power contribution.
                If a cylinder is not performing satisfactorily, a fault code will be set.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TEST PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Injector Test from the Engine Running Test menu and press ENTER to begin test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The ECM will increase the normal amount of fuel delivery (overfuel) to the injector which cylinder is
                being tested and monitor the reduction of fuel required to operate the remaining injectors to maintain a
                constant engine speed. If the reduction in fuel delivery to the other cylinders is not what the ECM
                expects, it will set a fault code identifying the non-contributing cylinder.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Engine Running Standard test must be performed first in order to gain access to the
                        Injector (Engine Running) test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When testing is completed, normal engine operation is restored and fault codes will be transmitted to
                the EST.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_59.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_61.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
