<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - CRUISE CONTROL, PTO, HAND THROTTLE SYSTEM - CRUISE
        CONTROL
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRUISE CONTROL</title>
        <para>Cruise control allows the ECM to control the engine's power delivery to maintain a constant speed. The
            speed set point is determined by the driver, however, high and low set points are programmed into the ECM.
            These are the cruise high set limit and cruise low set limit. Also the minimum engine speed at which the
            cruise control can be engaged at is programmed into the ECM.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to circuit diagram (
            <emph type="BOLD">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e190_368.xml" xrefid="f19017114">3.93</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ) for the following description.
        </para>
        <para>Placing the cruise control ON/OFF switch in the on position supplies 12 volts to the ECM pin 35 to enable
            the cruise control. When the ON/OFF switch is in the ON position it supplies the voltage for the Set/Resume
            switch. Depressing the Set switch will supply a 12 volt signal at ECM pin 32 to engage the cruise control.
            If cruise is active, it will cause the set speed to decrease (coast). If the cruise is not active,
            depressing the Resume switch will supply a 12 volt signal to ECM pin 31 to reactivate the cruise set speed
            to the last active set speed. Or if the cruise is active, depressing the resume (accel) switch will cause
            the set speed to increase.
        </para>
        <para>Depressing the OFF switch, brake, clutch or placing the automatic transmission in neutral will deactivate
            the cruise control. Cruise control will not be functional if the VSS signal is in fault.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_354.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_356.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
