<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE (ECM) POWER SUPPLY - ECM
        DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>If the ECM detects more than 18 volts at pins 21, 22 and 41 it will set flash code 112. A voltage of less
            than 6.5 volts detected by the ECM will set flash code 113. The ECM is capable of detecting an intermittent
            interruption of power or ground circuits. Flash code 626 will be set indicating an unexpected reset has
            occurred.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">112</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 168 FMI 35</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ECM:</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">INTERNAL VOLTAGE POWER OUT OF RANGE HIGH</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 112 can be caused by:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Defective alternator causing an alternator output voltage in excess of 18 volts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Additional voltage provided while attempting to jump start engine or improper external
                battery connections that could cause the additional voltage increase.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>If the condition causing code 112 is intermittent, the code will change from active to inactive status.
            Code 112 does not cause the Engine Warning light to turn ON.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">113</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 168 FMI 36</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ECM:</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">INTERNAL VOLTAGE POWER OUT OF RANGE LOW</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 113 can be caused by consistently less than 6.5 volts being applied to ECM pins 21, 22 and 41. This
            can be caused by a defective alternator or ECM power relay, discharged batteries, and/or increased
            resistance in the battery feed circuits. Code 113 does not turn the Engine Warning Light ON. If the
            condition causing Code 113 to set is an intermittent condition, when the condition is no longer present, the
            code status will change from active to inactive.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">Flash Code</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">626</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 254 FMI 56</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ECM:</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">UNEXPECTED RESET FAULT</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Any time power is interrupted to the ECM due to intermittent power feed circuits caused by loose or dirty
            connections at the batteries or at ground cables, the ECM may "power down". When the power or ground circuit
            becomes intact again the ECM will "reboot" itself. This may cause erratic engine operation. Flash code 626
            will be set anytime flow of power is interrupted to the ECM. Turning the ignition key "OFF" and then "ON"
            again causes the code to change from an active to an inactive code status. Code 626 will not cause the
            Engine Warning light to illuminate.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_207.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_209.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
