<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE (EOT) SENSOR - ECM DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>With the ignition key "ON", the ECM continuously monitors the EOT signal to determine if it is within
            expected values. If the signal voltage is above or below the expected levels, the ECM will set a fault code.
        </para>
        <para>If the ECM detects a fault, it will use the value of the Engine Coolant Temperature signal, in place of
            the EOT signal. If the ECT sensor is not sending a correct signal, the ECM will default to 29&#176;F (-1.7&#176;C)
            for starting or 212&#176;F (100&#176;C) for engine running operation.
        </para>
        <para>EOT sensor faults can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or by reading the flash codes from
            the warning light using the STI diagnostic switch located on the vehicle dash. If the ignition key is shut
            off, the code will become an Inactive code. EOT codes will cause the Engine Warning light to be illuminated.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">311</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 175 FMI 4</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE LOW</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 311 out of range low, will be set if the signal voltage was less than 0.2 volts for more than 0.1
            seconds. If this code is set, the ECM will default to ECT temperature or a default value of -4&#176;F (-20&#176;C)
            for starting or 212&#176;F (100&#176;C) for engine running operation. This code will cause the ECM to
            illuminate the Engine Warning light.
        </para>
        <para>Code 311 may be set due to a short to ground in the signal circuit or a defective sensor.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">FLASH CODE</emph>
            <emph type="BOLD">312</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ATA CODE PID 175 FMI 3</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="BOLD">ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE SIGNAL OUT OF RANGE HIGH</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Code 312 out of range high,will be set if the signal voltage is more than 4.8 volts for more than 0.1
            seconds. If this code is set, the ECM will default to ECT temperature or a default value of -4&#176;F (-20&#176;C)
            for starting or 212&#176;F (100&#176;C) for engine running operation. This code will cause the ECM to
            illuminate the Engine Warning light.
        </para>
        <para>Code 312 may be set due to an open signal circuit between the ECM and the sensor or a short to a voltage
            source. A defective sensor may also cause code 312 to be set.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_248.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_HL1901717.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
