<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - Injector Drive Circuits (INJ) - INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUITS
        (INJ)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INJECTOR DRIVE CIRCUITS (INJ)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1900372">Injector Drive Circuit Operation Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1900372" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg7/EG7361.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Injector Drive Circuit Operation Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>High Side Drive Outputs - the high side drive output control the injector "On Time" (fuel quantity),
                injection timing (in relation to TDC) and sequencing (firing order). the ECM controls each individual
                injector by supplying currents to each injector solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>Low Side Drive Returns - The injector solenoids are grounded through the low side return circuits. The
                ECM monitors the low side return signal for diagnostic purposes and utilizes the fly-back current from
                the injector solenoids to help charge the drive capacitors internal to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FAULT DETECTION/MANAGEMENT</title>
            <para>The ECM is capable of detecting, while the engine is running, individual injector open or short
                circuits either to ground or battery voltage. It is also capable of detecting right or left bank low
                side opens or shorts to ground. A fault code will be set and the WARN lamp will be illuminated when
                these conditions occur.
            </para>
            <para>A special On-Demand Buzz test is also available to the technician to enable/'BUZZ' the injectors while
                in the service bay to verify circuit operation.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If a short to ground condition is detected on a high or low side circuit, the ECM will
                        discontinue operation of the affected bank of injectors, turn on the WARN lamp and continue to
                        operate on four cylinder operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1900373">Injector Drive Circuit Diagram</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="te1900337">Injector Drive Circuits Connector Checks</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1900373" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg7/EG7362.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Injector Drive Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>After removing connectors always check for damaged pins, corrosion, loose terminals etc.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Test all injector harness and valve cover connectors at Test Points indicated.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te1900337" frame="all">
                <title>Table 76 Injector Drive Circuits Connector Checks</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.33in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.67in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>Engine Harness Connector Check to Chassis Ground</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>B</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - codes 451 - 458 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector low side - codes 515 or 521 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>D</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - codes 451 - 458 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>Valve Cover Gasket Connector to Chassis Ground</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>(Check with pigtail connector installed on gasket connector)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>B</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - codes 451 - 458 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector low side - codes 515 or 521 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>D</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - codes 451 - 458 may be set if shorted to grd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>Under Valve Cover Harness and Injector Solenoid Resistance Checks</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>(Check with pigtail connector installed on gasket connector)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>B to C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3.4 &#177; ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry morerows="1">
                                <para>Resistance thru injector solenoid and UVC harness - codes 421 - 428 may be present
                                    if open, codes 431- 438 may be present if injector or harness shorted together.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>C to D</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3.4 &#177; 2 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>Engine Harness to IDM connector checks (measure to appropriate pin)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>B to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;5 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - codes 421 - 428 present if open present.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>C to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;5 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector low side - code(s) 513 or 514 present if open, code 524 indicates sides
                                    shorted together.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>D to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;5 ohms</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector high side - code(s) 421 - 428 present if open present.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUNCTION SYSTEM DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The ECM uses the fuel quantity control strategy and input from the engine sensors to determine how
                long each fuel injector is actuated in order to provide the proper fuel quantity and timing at any given
                engine operating condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>INJECTOR DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the voltage on the driver circuits and is capable of detecting an open or shorted
                circuit. If the ECM detects a short to ground or a multiple fault in a driver, the ECM will discontinue
                operation of that driver which would cause the engine to operate on the remaining bank of 4 cylinders.
                The ECM will set a fault code, illuminate the Engine Warning Light and compensate for inoperative
                cylinders to keep the engine running if mechanically possible.
            </para>
            <para>Faults can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool or the STI Self Test Input diagnostic Switch
                located on the vehicle dash.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The last digit of the flash code indicates the affected cylinder number. For example, code 421
                        indicates cylinder no. 1 has an open circuit between the ECM high side driver and the low side
                        (signal return) to the ECM. the SID nos. 1-8, indicate cylinder nos. in a similar manner.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 421 THROUGH 428</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 8 FMI 5</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE TO LOW SIDE OPEN</para>
            <para>Flash Codes for High Side to Low Side Open indicate an open circuit between high side driver and the
                low side (Signal return) to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating. the ECM will not illuminate
                the Engine Warning light when this situation occurs.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Open wire in injector harness, open injector return circuit or injector solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 431 THROUGH 438</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 8 FMI 4</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE SHORTED TO LOW SIDE</para>
            <para>Flash codes for High Side Shorted to Low side indicate the return voltage is too high due to a short
                circuit between the high side driver and return circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating. The ECM will not illuminate
                the Engine Warning light when this situation occurs.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Shorted injector solenoid or wiring harness.</para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 451 THROUGH 458</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 1 THROUGH 8 FMI 6</para>
            <para>LOW SIDE SHORTED TO GROUND</para>
            <para>Flash codes for Low Side Shorted to Ground indicate the return circuit shorted to ground.</para>
            <para>If the ECM detects this fault, it will disable the entire bank of cylinders associated with the
                cylinder indicated and illuminates the Engine Warning Lamp.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: Shorted injector solenoid or wiring harness to ground.</para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 513</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 5</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE OPEN, RIGHT GROUP</para>
            <para>With High Side Open right Group (Bank 1), the IDM has detected an open circuit to the injectors on
                cylinders 1, 3, 5 or 7 are inoperative.
            </para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 514</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 5</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE OPEN LEFT GROUP</para>
            <para>With the High Side Open Left Group (Bank 2), the ECM has detected an open circuit to the injectors on
                cylinders 2, 4, 6 and 8.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 513 active, the drivers for cylinders 2, 4, 6 and 8 are inoperative. The ECM will
                compensate for misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 515</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 151 FMI 6</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE BANK 1 SHORT TO GROUND OR B+</para>
            <para>Flash code 515 indicates the ECM has detected the high side driver for cylinders 1, 3, 5 and 7 has
                excessive current draw.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 515 active, the driver for cylinders 1, 3, 5 and 7 will be disabled. the ECM will
                compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine running. This code will cause the Engine Warning light
                to be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>FLASH CODE: 521</para>
            <para>ATA CODE SID 152 FMI 6</para>
            <para>HIGH SIDE BANK 2 SHORT TO GROUND OR B+</para>
            <para>Flash code 521 indicates the ECM has detected excessive current draw on high side driver for cylinder
                2, 4, 6 and 8.
            </para>
            <para>With flash code 521 active, the driver for cylinders 2, 4, 6 and 8 will be disabled. The ECM will
                compensate for engine misfire to keep the engine operating and will illuminate the Engine Warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_280.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_HL1901723.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
