<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 3.5: ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS,
        ACCELERATOR PEDAL POSITION SENSOR/IVS SWITCH (APS/IVS) - ENGINE CRANK INHIBIT SYSTEM (ECI) - START RELAY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>START RELAY</title>
        <para>The start relay is used to switch battery power to the crank motor solenoid when the crank inhibit relay
            is energized. When the engine crank inhibit relay is closed, current is supplied to the start relay terminal
            to energize the relay. The start relay control is grounded through the starter thermal overcrank protection
            thermocouple if equipped. Or if not, the relay is grounded directly to the ground stud on the starter. With
            the start relay energized, battery voltage is supplied to the start relay and then switched to the crank
            motor solenoid to crank the engine.
        </para>
        <para>Before troubleshooting,
            <emph type="BOLD">make sure the batteries are fully charged.</emph>
            Check battery cables and grounds for clean and tight connections free of damage. Voltage readings will not
            be accurate if the batteries are not fully charged.
        </para>
        <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose or damaged (spread or bent)
            terminals, or wires with cut strands etc. Wires and connections must be free of damage or corrosion. When
            some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must be removed.
        </para>
        <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect the suspect circuit ground for clean, tight connections, free of an
            damage.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_187.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_189.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
