<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>T 444E Diesel Engine Diagnostics (NAVPAK) (1997) - SECTION 1.2: INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE SYSTEM -
        INJECTION CONTROL SYSTEM OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INJECTION CONTROL SYSTEM OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1900201">1.5</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                for the injector oil system flow.
            </para>
            <para>The T 444E system utilizes a hydraulically actuated injector to pressurize fuel inside the injector.
                The hydraulic fluid used to actuate the injector is engine oil.
            </para>
            <para>Oil is drawn from the oil pan thru the pickup tube by the engine oil pump. The engine oil pump is a
                gerotor type pump driven by the crankshaft. Oil is fed through passages in the front cover to an oil
                reservoir mounted on top of the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir makes available a constant supply of oil to a high pressure hydraulic pump mounted in
                the engine "V". The high pressure pump is a gear driven seven plunger swash plate pump. High pressure
                oil is delivered by the high pressure pump to oil galleries machined into the cylinder heads and then
                drilled intersecting passages that supply high pressure oil to the injectors.
            </para>
            <para>This high pressure oil is utilized by the HEUI injector when the solenoid is energized to pressurize
                and atomize the fuel into the combustion chamber. After injection is completed the solenoid is
                de-energized and the oil inside the injector is vented through the top portion of the injector, splashed
                on the valve train and allowed to drain back into the oil pan.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1900201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="eg1206" filename="../figeg1/eg1206.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.5 Injector Oil System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1 . Oil Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1>2 . Reservoir (Located On Top of Front Cover)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3 . High Pressure Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1>4 . High Pressure Hoses</callout1>
                    <callout1>5 . Injection Control Pressure Sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1>6 . Cylinder Head High Pressure Rail</callout1>
                    <callout1>7 . Injector (8)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8 . Gallery (Crankcase)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9 . Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1>10 . Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1>11 . Injection Control Pressure Regulator</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Injection control pressure is governed by the Electronic Control Module (ECM) depending upon operating
                conditions and the driver's demand for power. The Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) is utilized by the
                ECM for this purpose.
            </para>
            <para>The IPR is a pressure regulator valve which is electronically controlled by the ECM to control the
                pressure of the entire injection control pressure system. The IPR valve is mounted on the high pressure
                pump and achieves injection control pressure regulation by dumping excess oil into the front cover and
                back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>The injection control pressure sensor provides pressure information in the form of an analog voltage
                signal to the ECM at any time.
            </para>
            <para>The injection control pressure ranges from 3.4 to 20 kPa (500 to 3000 psi), depending on the engine
                family.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_E19002.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190_F1900202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e190.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
