<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND
        CRANKCASE - DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT AND MAIN BEARINGS (RECONDITIONING) - INSPECTION AND REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="8">
        <title>INSPECTION AND REPAIR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vibration Damper and Pulley Assembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect vibration damper alignment marks.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The damper has an inner member and an outer member separated by a rubber insert.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If marks (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150742">7.42</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ) are misaligned by more than the specified maximum,
                    <emph type="bold">REPLACE THE DAMPER. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150701.xml" xrefid="hl4150701">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Viscous Vibration Damper</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the viscous damper for dents and leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for housing distortion with a micrometer as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove paint off damper at the four points shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150743">7.43</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure depth of damper housing at each point.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If any of the points (A, B, C, D) vary more than 0.25 mm (0.010 in.) it is necessary
                        to replace the damper.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The viscous vibration damper cannot be repaired. Dents, leakage or housing distortion
                                can result in improper damper functioning leading to extensive engine damage.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Whenever the vibration damper or oil pump assembly is removed, replace the crankshaft
                    front oil seal wear sleeve as follows:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Applications with a viscous damper have the wear sleeve located on the pulley hub.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Split wear sleeve with a muffler chisel to remove. Be careful not to damage the
                        crankshaft flange (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150744">7.44</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ). Discard sleeve.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply Aviation Permatex&#8482; No. 3 to the O.D. of a new wear sleeve and press into
                        the vibration damper using wear sleeve installer
                        <emph type="bold">SE-3004-A</emph>. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150745">7.45</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Install so chamfer on wear sleeve O.D. is facing out when viewing front end of
                                damper.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4150742" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11359" filename="../figcg1/CG11359.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.42. Vibration Damper Alignment Marks.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4150743" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg7928" filename="../figcg7/CG7928.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.43. Damper Housing Measurement Locations.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4150744" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12596" filename="../figcg1/CG12596.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.44. Remove Wear Sleeve.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crankshaft And Main Bearings</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the crankshaft journals (main and rod) for scratches, grooves and
                    scoring. Use dye penetrant methods to check for cracks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect all bearing inserts. Replace bearings that are scored, chipped or
                    worn.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the diameter of each journal using a micrometer. (See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150701.xml" xrefid="hl4150701">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>). Measure each
                    journal at two points, at right angles to each other. Move the micrometer over the entire width of
                    the journal. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150746">7.46</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If journals exceed maximum out-of-round specification, crankshaft must be reground.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The crankshaft can be ground 0.254 mm (0.010 in.), 0.508 mm (0.020 in.) or 0.762 mm
                    (0.030 in.) undersize as follows:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>An induction hardened fillet and journal crankshaft can be reground similar to any
                            precision crankshaft. However, these shafts require special treatment when grinding. Before
                            grinding all crankshafts must be checked for hardness.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check crankshaft hardness before regrinding and on every journal which incurred a
                        bearing failure or shows evidence of overheating.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Bearing failures can cause overheating of crankshaft journals and reduction of
                                hardness. When this occurs, the crankshaft strength may be unacceptably reduced.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check crankshaft journal hardness using a Rockwell Hardness Tester as follows:
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4150745" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12597" filename="../figcg1/CG12597.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.45. Install a New Vibration Damper Wear Sleeve.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4150746" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12180" filename="../figcg1/CG12180.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.46. Measure Crankshaft Bearing Journals.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>THE HARDNESS TEST IS DESTRUCTIVE AND IS ONLY MADE PRIOR TO GRINDING THE CRANKSHAFT.
                                THE GRINDING PROCESS WILL CORRECT THE DAMAGE MADE BY THE ROCKWELL HARDNESS TESTER. DO
                                NOT TEST FOR HARDNESS UNLESS THE CRANKSHAFT IS TO BE REGROUND.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Check crankshaft rod and main journals at three locations: the top, bottom and one other
                        location.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The top and bottom is determined with the crankshaft journal at TDC.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Check as close to the fillet as possible.</para>
                    <para>If any reading is below 50 RC hardness,
                        <emph type="underscr">REPLACE</emph>
                        the crankshaft. If hardness is acceptable, grind the crankshaft.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>THE SUPERIOR STRENGTH OF THE FILLET-HARDENED SHAFT IS DUE TO THE SPECIAL PROCESS BY
                                WHICH THE BEARING SURFACES AND FILLETS ARE HARDENED. THIS LOCALIZED HARDENING GREATLY
                                INCREASES THE BENDING STRENGTH OF THE CRANKSHAFT; IN ORDER TO MAINTAIN THIS STRENGTH,
                                SPECIAL PRECAUTIONS MUST BE TAKEN WHEN REGRINDING THE SHAFT. IF SPECIAL PRECAUTIONS ARE
                                NOT TAKEN, THE CRANK. SHAFT CAN BE SEVERELY WEAKENED. THE METALLURGICAL CHARACTERISTICS
                                OF THE SHAFT DEMAND EXACTING STANDARDS AND CONTROL WHEN REGRINDING JOURNALS. HOWEVER, IT
                                CAN BE REGROUND LOCALLY WHERE EQUIPMENT AND EXPERIENCE CAN PRODUCE QUALITY STANDARDS
                                OUTLINED IN THE FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Grind the crankshaft as any other precision crankshaft using the following
                        guidelines:
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>The crankshafts are reground similar to any precision crankshaft with the following
                            precautions:
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>A mechanical or an automatic wheel dresser is mandatory to prevent chatter, burning and
                            poor surface finish. A hand stone should NEVER be used to rough or fine dress the face or
                            radii of the wheel. The radii should blend evenly into the journal.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>The selection of the grinding wheel is important because too hard a wheel will increase
                            the possibility of burning. An aluminum-oxide wheel with a grit size of approximately 50 and
                            a maximum hardness of M will produce satisfactory results, with other conditions being
                            suitable.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>The coolant must be such that it minimizes burning. This requires a fluid with high
                            lubricity properties. The straight-cutting oils appear to be the best for grinding
                            crankshafts and are strongly recommended.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>USE EVERY PRECAUTION TO AVOID BURNS ON THE SHAFT DURING THE GRINDING OPERATION.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>A grinding wheel speed of 6500 surface feet per minute with a work spindle speed of
                            approximately 40 to 45 revolutions per minute is usually satisfactory.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Grind all journals with crankshaft rotating in a counterclockwise direction (viewed from
                            front of crankshaft), lap all journals with crankshaft rotating in clockwise direction.
                            <emph type="bold">DO NOT REFINISH REAR SEAL FLANGE.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Feed rates should be slower than normal to prevent any burning.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Maintain the undersize grinding limits specified in
                            <emph type="bold">Figure
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150747">7.47</hotlnk>
                            </emph>
                            .
                        </para>
                        <figure id="ef4150747" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="cg12181" filename="../figcg1/CG12181.webp" type="webp"/>
                            <caption>Figure 7.47. Limits for Undersize Crankshaft Grinding.</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <table id="t4150705">
                            <tgroup cols="8">
                                <colspec colname="1" colwidth="50p"/>
                                <colspec colname="2" colwidth="68p"/>
                                <colspec colname="3" colwidth="71p"/>
                                <colspec colname="4" colwidth="58p"/>
                                <colspec colname="5" colwidth="56p"/>
                                <colspec colname="6" colwidth="58p"/>
                                <colspec colname="7" colwidth="55p"/>
                                <colspec colname="8" colwidth="58p"/>
                                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="4" spanname="s1t4"/>
                                <spanspec namest="5" nameend="6" spanname="s5t6"/>
                                <spanspec namest="7" nameend="8" spanname="s7t8"/>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="s1t4">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="s5t6">
                                            <para>Below S/N 439619</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="s7t8">
                                            <para>Above S/N 439618</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>.010 in. Undersize Crankshaft</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>A</para>
                                            <para>Main Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>B</para>
                                            <para>Rod Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>C</para>
                                            <para>Width</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>Rod Journal</para>
                                            <para>Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>Rod Journal Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>DT/DTA 466-C</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>3.3642-3.3655 (85.451-84.484)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>2.9877-2.9890 (75.855-75.921)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>1.783-1.786 (45.29-45.36)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (5.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (95.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>0.192-0.208 (4.88-5.028)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>0.192-0.208 (4.88-5.28)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>.020 in. Undersize Crankshaft</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>A</para>
                                            <para>Main Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>B</para>
                                            <para>Rod Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>C</para>
                                            <para>Width</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>Rod Journal Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>Rod Journal Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>DT/DTA 466-C</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>3.3542-3.3555 (85.197-85.230)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>2.9777-2.9790 (75.634-75-867)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>1.783-1.786 (45.29-45.36)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (5.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (5.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>0.192-0.208 (4.88-5.28)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>0.192-0.208 (4.88-5.28)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>.030 in. Undersize Crankshaft</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>A</para>
                                            <para>Main Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>B</para>
                                            <para>Rod Journal</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>C</para>
                                            <para>Width</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>Rod Journal Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>Rod Journal Radii D</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>Main Journal Radii E</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>DT/DTA 466-C</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>3.3442-3.3455 (84.943-84.978)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="3">
                                            <para>2.9877-2.9690 (75.380-75.413)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="4">
                                            <para>1.795-1.798 (45.59-45.87)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (5.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="6">
                                            <para>0.220-0.235 (5.59-5.97)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="7">
                                            <para>0.190-0.208 (4.88-5.28)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="8">
                                            <para>0.192-0.208 (4.88-5.28)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Maximum allowable taper on crankpins (rod journals) and main journals 0.0038 mm (.00015)
                            per inch of length of length. Crankpins and journals must be polished to 20 Micro-inch
                            maximum to 5 Micro-inch minimum, and must not be over 0.0005 inch (0.003 mm) out of round.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>Do not grind the crankshaft flange.</para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                        <specpara>
                            <caution>
                                <para>AS A NORMAL PRECAUTION, IT IS RECOMMENDED THAT A CO2 FIRE EXTINGUISHER BE NEAR THE
                                    GRINDING MACHINE, JUST IN CASE ANY EXCESSIVE HEAT SHOULD IGNITE THE OIL. IF A FIRE
                                    SHOULD START, IT CAN BE RAPIDLY EXTINGUISHED WITHOUT CAUSING ANY DAMAGE TO THE
                                    MACHINE OR SURROUNDING AREA BY FOLLOWING THE NORMAL FIRE-EXTINGUISHING PROCEDURE.
                                </para>
                            </caution>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Inspection of the crankshaft for dimensional tolerances is the same as for conventionally
                            hardened crankshafts, except that extra care must be taken to be sure the shaft is cool
                            before inspecting. Scrap only those crankshafts which do not meet the specified tolerances.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>In addition to inspecting the dimensional tolerances, the crankshaft must also be
                            carefully checked for surface defects, particularly for grinding cracks and burns. It is
                            advisable to spray check the crankshaft (using dye penetrant methods) after grinding and
                            lapping to insure that there is no surface cracking.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">TARASOV ETCH: In order to establish the acceptability of a regrind procedure,
                        crankshaft should be etched before lapping to determine whether the crankshaft was burned during
                        the regrinding procedure. The best etch to use is the Tarasov etch, which will show both the
                        rehardened and the overtempered areas. The etching procedure is as follows:
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>DUE TO THE SHARP ODOR AND FLAMMABILITY OF THE TARASOV ETCH, THE ETCHING SHOULD BE DONE
                                IN A WELL-VENTILATED AREA, AWAY FROM ANY OPEN FLAME.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Clean surface with a scouring powder and water or a good solvent.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Wash thoroughly and rinse with alcohol.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Apply etchant No. 1 (4 parts nitric acid in 96 parts water) for approximately 16 seconds
                            with a cotton swab.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Rinse with water and dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Apply etchant No. 2 (2 parts hydrochloric acid in 98 parts acetone) for approximately 15
                            seconds with a cotton swab.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <caution>
                                <para>ACETONE IS HIGHLY FLAMMABLE.</para>
                            </caution>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Rinse with alcohol and dry thoroughly with compressed air.</para>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>IF THE CRANKSHAFT HAS BEEN BURNED, IT WILL SHOW UP AS A CHANGE OF COLOR AFTER THE
                                    ETCH. AREAS REHARDENED BY EXCESSIVE HEAT APPEAR NEARLY WHITE, WHILE SOFTENED AREAS
                                    TURN DARK GRAY OR BLACK. AREAS UNAFFECTED BY THE HEAT OF GRINDING ETCH A LIGHT GRAY.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>IF ANY BURNS SHOW UP AFTER THE ETCH IS USED, THE PHYSICAL PROPERTIES OF THE
                                    CRANKSHAFT WILL HAVE BEEN SERIOUSLY REDUCED, AND THE CRANKSHAFT SHOULD NOT BE USED.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>If burning becomes a serious problem, it can usually be eliminated by reducing the
                                    infeed rate, using a softer grade of wheel, or increasing the work spindle speed.
                                    Sometimes, a combination of these factors, along with the recommendations mentioned
                                    above, will be necessary to overcome the problem.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">After the crankshaft passes the Tarasov etch test, it may be lapped.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>THOROUGHLY CLEAN THE CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES WITH A NYLON BRISTLE BRUSH, SOAP AND
                                WATER TO REMOVE ALL DEBRIS WHICH MAY HAVE ACCUMULATED DURING THE REGRINDING PROCEDURE.
                                ANY DEBRIS LEFT IN THE CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES CANNOT BE REMOVED BY THE OIL FILTERS AND
                                WILL DAMAGE BEARINGS IMMEDIATELY UPON ENGINE START-UP. ONCE CLEANED, WRAP THE
                                CRANKSHAFT, TO PROTECT IT FROM CONTAMINATION, UNTIL IT IS INSTALLED.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the crankshaft gears for chipping or wear. If replacement is required,
                    the gears can be replaced as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place a chisel between the gear teeth and strike the chisel with a hammer to split
                        gear.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove oil pump drive spline first to access the crankshaft gear. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150748">7.48</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Be careful not to damage the crankshaft during gear removal.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With gears removed, heat crankshaft gear and oil pump drive spline to 188-202 &#176;
                        C (370-395&#176; F).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the crankshaft gear first. Be sure the locating pin on the crankshaft gear
                        aligns with the crankshaft properly. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150749">7.49</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . Press the gear into place.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the hot oil pump drive spline onto the crankshaft until flush with the
                        crankshaft gear
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4150748" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11292" filename="../figcg1/CG11292.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.48. Remove Gears, if Required.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4150749" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12182" filename="../figcg1/CG12182.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.49. Crankshaft Gear Installation.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_152.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_154.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
