<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - NOZZLES - PRE-RECONDITIONING INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="5">
        <title>PRE-RECONDITIONING INSPECTION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The prime requirements for a satisfactory nozzle assembly are: pressure tight seats; no
                excessive valve stem leakage; satisfactory spray and atomization characteristics.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">After removal from engine, test nozzles for spray condition, opening pressure and
                    leakage on a hand test pump
                    <emph type="bold">SE-2002</emph>.
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151206">12.6</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    shows an injection nozzle mounted for testing on the hand test pump.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>IT IS ADVISABLE TO TEST NOZZLES BEFORE CLEANING THEM. AFTER TESTING, PLACE NOZZLES IN A
                            COLD DECARBONIZING SOLUTION FOR AT LEAST ONE HOUR. AFTER REMOVING NOZZLES FROM SOLUTION,
                            WASH OFF THE OUTSIDE SURFACES.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4151204" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg13154" filename="../figcg1/CG13154.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12.4. Nozzle Injector Puller.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151205" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11696" filename="../figcg1/CG11696.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12.5. Remove Copper Sealing Gasket from Bore.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Prepare pump for making tests. Fill pump reservoir with Viscor 1487C calibration fluid.
                    Open pump valve slightly and operate pump handle to expel air from pump and outlet pipe. Operate
                    pump until solid fluid (without air bubbles) flows from the end of the outlet pipe. Close the pump
                    valve.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect injection nozzle to test pump. Avoid "cross-threading". Tighten connector nut
                    securely with open end wrench.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The gauge valve should be closed. Failure to close the gauge valve will lead to a damaged
                            gauge. The gauge valve should only be opened to check opening pressure and tip leakage. A
                            residual pressure should always be left in the pressure gauge.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Bleed air from the nozzle. Open the pump valve and operate the pump for several quick
                    strokes to expel (bleed) air from the injection nozzle. Fluid should discharge from the holes in the
                    nozzle tip.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>KEEP HANDS AWAY FROM NOZZLE DISCHARGE. FLUID DISCHARGING FROM THE NOZZLE UNDER HIGH
                            PRESSURE CAN PENETRATE SKIN AND CAUSE INFECTION. MEDICAL ATTENTION SHOULD BE PROVIDED
                            IMMEDIATELY IF SKIN PENETRATION OCCURS.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">OBSERVE THE DISCHARGE PATTERN. Operate the test pump in smooth, even strokes and observe
                    the pattern of fluid discharging from the four (4) nozzle tip discharge holes. The discharge should
                    be well atomized in an even pattern, free from solid streams and dribbling (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151207">Acceptable Nozzle Discharge</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">CHECK NOZZLE OPENING PRESSURE. Open the gauge valve, operate the test pump in slow,
                    smooth, even strokes and observe gauge pressure to determine pressure at which nozzle opens
                    (discharges fluid). The nozzle should operate within the specified opening pressure range. See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4151201.xml" xrefid="hl4151201">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>".
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4151206" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg7629" filename="../figcg7/CG7629.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12.6. Mount Nozzle Assembly to the Hand Test Pump.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151207" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg10855" filename="../figcg1/CG10855.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12.7. Acceptable Nozzle Discharge.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">CHECK FOR TIP LEAKAGE. Blow nozzle tip dry using filtered compressed air. Operate test
                    pump to maintain pressure at about 3447 kPa (500 psi) below opening pressure. Nozzle tip should
                    remain dry without an accumulation of fluid drops at spray holes. A slight wetting after about 5
                    seconds is permissible if no droplets are formed. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151208">12.8</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>DO NOT WIPE TIP WITH FINGERS AS THIS WILL TEND TO DRAW THE FLUID PRESENT IN THE SAC HOLE
                            THROUGH THE ORIFICES AND FALSELY INDICATE A LEAK AND REJECTION OF A GOOD VALVE.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">CHECK FUEL LEAK-OFF. Operate test pump in quick strokes and observe for flow of fluid
                    from leak-off part of nozzle. A very slight leak-off is normal. If more than 1.0 cc/minute of fluid
                    is expelled or if fluid surges from leak-off port when nozzle pressure is held @ 3447 kPa (500 psi)
                    below V.O.P., the nozzle is faulty.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the nozzle passes the above tests, it is suitable for further service in the engine
                following cleaning and removal of accumulated carbon. Nozzles showing irregular spray pattern, leakage
                at nozzle tip spray holes, excessive fluid leak-off or opening pressure below minimum permissible limit
                should be replaced or reconditioned (disassembled, cleaned and rebuilt).
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4151208" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg10857" filename="../figcg1/CG10857.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12.8. Unacceptable Tip Leakage.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_262.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_HL4151202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
