<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - TURBOCHARGERS - TURBOCHARGER A/R - GENERAL OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL OPERATION</title>
        <para>The turbocharger is an exhaust-driven centrifugal air compressor. Its purpose is to increase power output
            by supplying compressed air to the engine. The center housing is oil and air cooled. Engine oil is
            circulated through the center housing which acts as a heat barrier between the "hot" turbine and the "cold"
            compressor. Bearings are sleeve-type and are lubricated by engine oil. Oil is pumped directly from the
            clean-oil side of the engine oil filters, circulated in the center housing of the turbocharger and returned
            to the engine through an oil drain tube. Piston ring seals are used at each end of the shaft.
        </para>
        <para>High velocity engine exhaust gases drive the turbine shaft assembly to speeds up to 130,000 revolutions
            per minute. Filtered air entering the compressor side of the turbocharger is compressed and delivered to the
            engine intake manifold at a pressure higher than atmospheric pressure. Because more air is delivered to the
            intake manifold, the result is more power, fuel efficiency and the ability to maintain power at altitude.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
