<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - TURBOCHARGERS - RECONDITIONING - REPLACEMENT CORE ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="5">
        <title>REPLACEMENT CORE ASSEMBLY</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When it is not cost-effective to completely disassemble and recondition the turbocharger, a
                    replacement core assembly is available for service. When using this unit, it is only necessary to
                    remove the compressor and turbine housings from the old unit and install them on the new core
                    assembly. BE SURE CORRECT ALIGNMENT IS ACHIEVED SINCE THE CENTER HOUSING ON THE NEW CORE ASSEMBLY
                    WILL NOT HAVE ALIGNMENT MARKS.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>DO NOT REST CENTER HOUSING ON EITHER COMPRESSOR IMPELLER OR TURBINE WHEEL OR DAMAGE TO WHEEL
                    ASSEMBLY MAY RESULT.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the lock nut from the turbine shaft (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150228">2.28</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Construct shaft holding fixture using bar stock and a socket.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Support the center housing and shaft assembly vertically in the holding fixture and
                    vice.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach a socket and tee-handle wrench to the lock nut. Turn the tee-handle wrench to
                    remove the lock nut. Keep wrench straight.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Slide compressor wheel from turbine shaft.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If carbon buildup prevents easy removal, press the shaft from the compressor impeller as
                            explained in Step 2.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>DO NOT APPLY SIDE THRUST WHEN LOOSENING THE LOCK NUT AS IT IS POSSIBLE TO BEND THE
                            SHAFT.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support center housing assembly on an arbor press as shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150229">2.29</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                . Grind a radius on the end of a 1/4 inch bolt to fit the end of the shaft. Press the shaft from
                compressor wheel.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>HOLD TURBINE WHEEL AND SHAFT ASSEMBLY TO PREVENT DAMAGE DUE TO DROPPING.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4150228" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12144" filename="../figcg1/cg12144.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.28 Shaft Lock Nut Removal.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4150229" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11416" filename="../figcg1/cg11416.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.29 Separating Compressor Impeller from Turbine Shaft.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the center housing and back plate on a bench and remove the capscrews and washers
                which secure the center housing to the back plate. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150230">2.30</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                . Carefully lift the center housing from the back plate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the back plate removed, the following are easily removed:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the seal ring, thrust collar and thrust washer from the center housing (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150231">2.31</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). The thrust spring located in the back plate is replaceable, but should not be removed unless
                    replacement is necessary.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Using snap ring tool, remove the outboard bearing retainers and bearings from each side
                    of the center housing. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150232">2.32</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4150230" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11417" filename="../figcg1/cg11417.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.30 Center Housing and Back Plate Disassembly.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4150231" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11418" filename="../figcg1/cg11418.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.31 Center Housing and Back Plate Components.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4150232" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11419" filename="../figcg1/cg11419.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.32 Bearing Removal.</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The inboard retainers are subject to distortion during removal. Replace the inboard
                            retainers
                            <emph type="underscr">ONLY</emph>
                            if they appear to be damaged or worn.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the piston ring from the thrust collar using a small screwdriver to carefully pry
                    it free. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e415_16.xml" xrefid="ef4150233">2.33</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the piston ring from the turbine wheel and shaft assembly near the shroud, by
                    carefully prying it free with a small screwdriver.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150202.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
