<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - INSTALLATION OF NEW
        SOLENOID WIRING HARNESS ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INSTALLATION OF NEW SOLENOID WIRING HARNESS ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the metri-pack connector between the engine and the solenoid wiring harness.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Route conduit-covered wire with engine harness to starting motor magnetic switch mounted on
                cowl.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect eyelet terminal to same stud on starting motor magnetic switch that circuit 17 (
                <emph type="bold">HOT DURING START CYCLE ONLY</emph>) is connected. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151144">11.44</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                tighten nut at this time as adjustment will require removal.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4151144" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg13138" filename="../figcg1/CG13138.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.44. Cranking System Wiring Diagram.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shorten the green and yellow wires that were connected to the old fuel shut-off solenoid so
                that the ends are near the ends of the green and yellow wires in the adapter harness assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use butt splices to connect the green wires (Hold-in circuit) together and the yellow wires
                (Ground circuit) together.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>IF VEHICLE HAS A KYSOR SHUTDOWN SYSTEM, THEN SPLICE CIRCUIT 19E TO GREEN WIRE (HOLD-IN
                        CIRCUIT) AND CIRCUIT 19-GB TO YELLOW WIRE (PULL-IN CIRCUIT). REFER TO FIGURE
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151145">11.45</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4151145" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg13139" filename="../figcg1/CG13139.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.45. KYSOR Engine Shutdown System Wiring Diagram.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To test wiring and solenoid, turn key switch to
                <emph type="bold">"ON"</emph>
                position (energize circuit) and then disconnect eyelet terminal (installed in Step 3). Momentarily touch
                the eyelet terminal to the terminal opposite Circuit 17. This will cause the solenoid to energize and
                depress plunger to the bottom. When eyelet is removed, solenoid plunger will return.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reconnect eyelet terminal to Circuit 17 and tighten nut.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_248.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_250.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
