<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - TURBOCHARGERS - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Reference numbers refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150237">2.37</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the inboard bearing retaining rings (16) were removed, use a snap ring tool to
                    install new retaining rings into their grooves in the bore of the center housing. Insure the
                    retaining rings are properly seated in the grooves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the bearings (17) with clean engine oil and push them into the bores until
                    they seat against the inboard retaining rings (16). Install new outer retaining rings (16) after
                    installing bearings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully install the piston ring (20) into the groove on the turbine wheel assembly
                    (22).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Install piston ring by hand only. Use of tools will cause distortion of the piston ring.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4150237" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg10915" filename="../figcg1/CG10915.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.37 Turbocharger Components (T04E).</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">1. Housing, Turbine</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">2. Clamp, Housing</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">3. Screw, Hex Hd Cap</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">4. Core Assembly</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">5. Screw, Hex Hd Cap</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">6. Clamp, Housing</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">7. Housing, Compressor</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">8. Nut, Impeller Lock</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">9. Impeller, Compressor</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">10. Plate, Back</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">11. Ring, Plate Seal</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">12. Ring, Piston</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">13. Spring, Plate</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">14. Collar, Thrust</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">15. Washer, Thrust</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">16. Ring, Retaining</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">17. Bearing, Journal</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">18. Housing, Center</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">19. Screw, Hex Hd Cap</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">20. Ring, Seal</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">21. Shroud, Turbine</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">22. Turbine Wheel Assembly</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the shroud (21) over the turbine end of the center housing. Carefully insert the
                    turbine wheel assembly (22) through the shroud and center housing. The piston ring must be
                    positioned with the shroud to align with the center housing bore to prevent piston ring damage.
                    Apply a gentle downward pressure to the turbine wheel while rotating the wheel shroud. This will
                    help the piston ring seat in its bore.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new piston ring onto the thrust collar (14). Install the thrust washer onto
                    the collar with the flat surface of the washer next to the large diameter of the collar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the thrust collar and washer over the turbine wheel assembly shaft (22); thrust
                    washer first and engage the holes in the washer with the anti-rotating pins (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e415_15.xml" xrefid="ef4150231">2.31</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ) in the center housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new seal ring (11) into the groove in the compressor side of the center
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insure the thrust spring is correctly seated in the back plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the marks, made prior to disassembly, on the back plate (10) with those on the
                    center housing (18) and carefully install the back plate over the shaft and thrust collar.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Be careful not to damage the seal ring when engaging the thrust collar into the bore in
                            the back plate. The back plate is easily installed if the open side of the seal ring is
                            engaged into the back plate bore first.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the center housing to back plate capscrews (19) and tighten to specified torque.
                    See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150201.xml" xrefid="hl4150201">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip the compressor impeller (9) onto the shaft. Apply a small amount of clean engine
                    oil on the threads and washer face of the lock nut (8). Install the lock nut finger-tight.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully place the assembled center housing in a holding fixture (made locally). See
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e415_15.xml" xrefid="ef4150228">2.28</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . Support the assembly vertically in a vice with the compressor impeller nut in the holding fixture
                    socket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the shaft threads with clean engine oil. Install the lock nut (8)
                    finger-tight. Using a tee-handle wrench, with a double universal joint to avoid side (bending) load
                    on the shaft, turn an additional 90&#176;. This will achieve the specified torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the assembly from the vise and spin the wheel by hand. The wheels must rotate
                    freely; insure the turbine wheel does not rub the shroud (21).
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Hold at center housing in a vertical position (turbine end up) when performing this
                            check.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the marks made during disassembly on the center housing with those on the turbine
                    housing. Carefully install the turbine end of the center housing into the turbine housing. Be
                    careful during assembly so blades are not bent.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat the threads of the capscrews (3) with "NEVER SEEZ" compound. Install the clamps
                    (2), and capscrews (3). Tighten the capscrews to specified torque. See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150201.xml" xrefid="hl4150201">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the marks on the compressor housing with those on the center housing and back
                    plate. Carefully install the compressor housing and secure with capscrews (5) and clamps (6). Be
                    careful during assembly so blades are not bent. Tighten the capscrews to specified torque to secure
                    the housing (see
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150201.xml" xrefid="hl4150201">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the shaft as far as possible from the turbine end and check for binding during
                    rotation. Repeat check, pushing from compressor end. The shaft must rotate freely with no
                    interference at either end of the turbocharger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the turbocharger is not to be installed immediately, lubricate internally and install
                    protective covers on all openings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150203.xml" xrefid="hl4150203">"INSTALLATION"</hotlnk>
                    in this section for instructions on installing turbocharger to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
