<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - NOZZLES - RETESTING AND ADJUSTING CLEAN NOZZLE ASSEMBLIES</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>RETESTING AND ADJUSTING CLEAN NOZZLE ASSEMBLIES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>KEEP HANDS AWAY FROM NOZZLE DISCHARGE. FLUID DISCHARGING FROM THE NOZZLE UNDER HIGH PRESSURE
                        CAN PENETRATE SKIN AND CAUSE INFECTION. MEDICAL ATTENTION SHOULD BE PROVIDED IMMEDIATELY IF SKIN
                        PENETRATION OCCURS.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using VISCOR 1487C (SAE J967 Standard) calibration fluid and a standard hand test pump
                    <emph type="bold">SE-2002</emph>, equipped with a pressure gauge having a capacity of at least
                    27,579 kPa (4000 psi), proceed as follows: (Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151212">12.12</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach the nozzle tube assembly (
                        <emph type="bold">SE-2004-13</emph>) to the nozzle hand test pump.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach the 90&#176; adapter (
                        <emph type="bold">SE-2757</emph>) to the nozzle tube.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach nozzle and holder assembly loosely to the test pump. Pump the handle several
                        times to flush out the fittings; then tighten.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test each nozzle for opening pressure as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">OPENING PRESSURE TEST: Pump the test pump handle a few strokes to clear the air from
                        the nozzle and then raise the pressure steadily. Observe the gauge pressure at which the valve
                        opens. Refer to the Nozzle Test Chart in this section for the specified opening pressure. If the
                        pressure is incorrect, adjust by selecting a different size spacer.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>A 0.279 mm (0.001 in.) change in the spacer will result in an 55 psi (379 kPa) change
                                in pressure.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4151212" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11632" filename="../figcg1/CG11632.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 12.12. Nozzle Test Equipment.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test each nozzle for seat leakage as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">SEAT LEAKAGE TEST: Wipe the nozzle tip dry. Bring the pressure up slowly to 3447 kPa
                        (500 psi) below the nozzle opening pressure and maintain this pressure for 5 seconds. If fluid
                        leaks or drips from the nozzle or a visible drop forms, the nozzle is leaking (slight moistening
                        of the nozzle tip is permissible). Recondition or replace a leaking nozzle.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not wipe the tip with the fingers as this will tend to draw the fuel present in the
                                sac hole through the orifices and falsely indicate a leak resulting in the rejection of
                                a good valve.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Leakage at the seat may be caused by dirt or foreign material, carbon or gum
                        deposits at the seat area or excessive wear of the seat. If the seat is worn, replace the nozzle
                        body and nozzle valve.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Never lap the valve-to-body seat. This will only widen the seat area and prevent
                                sealing.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test each nozzle for spray pattern as follows:</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SPRAY PATTERN TEST: Close pressure gauge valve. Operate test pump at a moderate rate and
                    observe the spray pattern.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All of the fluid should be atomized and each hole should spray approximately the
                        same amount of fuel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The spray patterns for all holes should be uniform.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Upon operating the test pump you will note a distinct and relatively regular nozzle
                                chatter. A sharp pitched sound is not mandatory and an occasional skip or variation in
                                sound may occur. In addition, chatter may vary from nozzle to nozzle. Lack of chatter is
                                not a cause for rejection of a nozzle.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">STEM LEAKAGE: Bring the pressure on the nozzle to 10342 mm (1500 psi). If there is any
                    leakage from the return, collect it. To conserve time, nozzle may be in inverted position. The
                    maximum allowable leakage is 1.0 cc in one minute at this pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Excessive leakage at this point can be caused by scratches or poor sealing at the flat
                    lapped surfaces of the nozzle body, intermediate plate or valve body. If this possibility has been
                    already eliminated, there is excessive clearance between the valve stem and body. This condition
                    necessitates replacement of the nozzle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After nozzles meet testing standards and adjustments are made, you may install nozzle
                    assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_267.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_269.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
