<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - REASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="8">
        <title>REASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the injection pump and adapter housing assembly to the engine front cover plate
                using a new adapter housing gasket (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151135">11.35</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Adapter housing dowel pins will align the gasket and the adapter housing to the engine front
                        plate.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the adapter housing bolts, nuts and washers to the specified special torque (see
                <hotlnk document="e415_HL4151102.xml" xrefid="hl4151102">"SPECIAL TORQUE"</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the injection pump gear as follows:</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>VERIFY THAT THE ENGINE #1 CYLINDER IS ON THE COMPRESSION STROKE (TDC). ALSO VERIFY STATIC
                        TIMING BY CHECKING THE TIMING POINTER AND DEGREE MARKS ON THE DAMPER PULLEY. REFER TO "SET
                        INJECTION PUMP TO ENGINE TIMING PRIOR TO PUMP REMOVAL" IN THIS SECTION FOR A DETAILED PROCEDURE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosely install the injection pump drive gear to the injection pump drive hub.
                    <emph type="underscr">DO NOT TIGHTEN BOLTS.</emph>
                    Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151136">11.36</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Position bolts in the center of the kidney slotted holes.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Verify the alignment of the injection pump timing pointer to the drive hub scribe line
                    through the adapter housing sight plug. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151137">11.37</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . Rotate the pump gear and hub as required for proper alignment.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tighten three pump drive gear mounting bolts to specified
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4151102.xml" xrefid="hl4151102">"SPECIAL TORQUE"</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>BE SURE THE TIMING POINTER AND SCRIBE LINE ARE STILL ALIGNED AFTER THE BOLTS ARE
                            TIGHTENED.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Reinstall timing plug using a new copper gasket.</para>
                <figure id="ef4151135" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11845" filename="../figcg1/cg11845.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.35. Install Injection Pump and Housing Assembly to the Front Plate.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151136" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11843" filename="../figcg1/cg11843.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.36. Install Injection Pump Drive Gear.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151137" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg9934" filename="../figcg9/cg9934.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.37. MW Injection Pump Timing Pointer and Timing Mark.</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">1. Timing Pointer</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">2. Timing Mark</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the injection pump drive gear access cover using a new gasket as follows:</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prior to access cover installation, be sure to tighten the two engine front cover mounting
                        bolts which will be covered by the access cover (Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151138">11.38</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For engines equipped with a mechanical tachometer, install the drive adapter with new seal
                        ring on the access cover. Be sure that the tang of the drive adapter engages the slot in the end
                        of injection pump camshaft when access cover is installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Secure the three bolts and washers which fasten into the front cover casting. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151139">11.39</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Secure the bolts, washers and nuts which mount through the access cover, front cover and
                    adapter housing.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tighten the fasteners to the standard torque. See
                    <emph type="bold">Appendix</emph>.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lube oil supply line as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151140">11.40</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Current service MW and all PES6A lube oil supply lines are hose/tube assemblies for ease of
                        installation and removal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the protective cap at the crankcase oil outlet elbow and the pump oil inlet.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install a new rubber sealing sleeve at the compression nut end of the tube.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fasten the tube to the crankcase oil outlet tube and tighten the nut.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Using new copper gaskets, fasten the banjo fitting to the pump oil inlet with the hollow
                    screw.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4151138" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11629" filename="../figcg1/cg11629.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.38. Tighten Front Cover Bolts - Prior to Installing the Access Cover.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151139" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11913" filename="../figcg1/cg11913.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.39. Install Injection Pump Drive Gear Access Cover.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151140" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg14645" filename="../figcg1/cg14645.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.40. PES6A Injection Pump Lube Oil Supply Line.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, install the electric shut-off solenoid as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151141">11.41</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>THE FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS ARE TO BE USED IF THE ELECTRIC "INTERNAL SWITCH" SOLENOID IS
                        REINSTALLED ON AN MW PUMP. THE CURRENT SERVICE SOLENOID IS DESIGNATED AS "SWITCHLESS" AND
                        REQUIRES DIFFERENT INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS WHICH BEGIN ON THE FOLLOWING PAGE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Follow these procedures step by step to prevent solenoid burn out or internal damage to
                        injection pump.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove solenoid plunger from solenoid and cap opening.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Assemble solenoid to bracket and tighten bolts.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Assemble bracket to engine at front cover and crankcase mounting locations.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Assemble rod end to shutoff lever and tighten bolt.
                    <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                    connect rod end to adjusting rod at this time.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Thread adjusting rod to solenoid plunger until bottomed, then tighten locknut.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Reinstall plunger into solenoid, depress plunger to bottom, energize solenoid using a 12
                    volt D.C. power source with 8 ampere "slow blow" fuse protection (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151142">11.42</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). Be sure that positive lead is connected to positive terminal, negative to negative. When solenoid
                    is mounted to engine, the positive terminal will be closest to engine water pump. The solenoid is to
                    be energized through step g.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Lift shutoff lever and screw adjusting rod thread into rod end until shutoff lever just
                    stops its downward movement.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn adjusting rod upper end
                    <emph type="bold">Two Full Turns</emph>
                    in opposite direction (raising shutoff lever) and tighten locknut against upper rod end.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">De-energize solenoid.</para>
                <figure id="ef4151141" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11641" filename="../figcg1/cg11641.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.41. "Internal Switch" Solenoid (Model MW Injection Pump Only).</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151142" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg9683" filename="../figcg9/cg9683.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.42. Energize Solenoid.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assembly and adjusting steps
                <emph type="bold">a</emph>
                through
                <emph type="bold">h</emph>
                will ensure that solenoid plunger will be fully seated at bottom of stroke and internal injection pump
                shutoff lever will not contact internal housing stop tab nor interfere with injection pump fuel rack
                during "excess fuel" starting conditions. Shutoff stop screw has been factory preset limiting solenoid
                plunger total travel to approximately 25.4 mm (1.0 in.) from bottom of stroke (run position) to end of
                stroke (shutoff position).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not adjust shutoff lever stop screw. If stop screw position is changed, injection pump
                must be removed and stop screw position set on the test bench. When stop screw is improperly adjusted,
                control rack may not move sufficiently to stop fuel delivery or may damage internal injection pump rack
                stop.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cycle solenoid 3-4 times to assure proper operation. After cycling solenoid, make sure
                    solenoid rubber boot is properly seated. With solenoid energized, there should be no chatter.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>DO NOT CYCLE MORE THAN 6 TIMES WITHIN ONE MINUTE. ADDITIONAL CYCLING MAY CAUSE PULL-IN
                            COIL OVER-HEATING RESULTING IN BURNOUT.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS FOR "SWITCHLESS" TYPE SOLENOID ASSEMBLIES ON ENGINES WITH AN MW
                            INJECTION PUMP AND PREVIOUSLY EQUIPPED WITH AN "INTERNAL SWITCH" SOLENOID.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>FOR INSTALLATION AND ADJUSTMENT INSTRUCTIONS OF "SWITCHLESS" TYPE SOLENOID ASSEMBLIES ON
                            ENGINES EQUIPPED WITH AN "MW' INJECTION PUMP FOLLOW "INSTALLATION OF NEW "SWITCHLESS"
                            ELECTRIC SHUT-OFF AND "ADJUSTMENT OF NEW ELECTRIC "SWITCHLESS" SHUT-OFF SOLENOID".
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_245.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_247.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
