<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - ADJUSTMENT OF NEW
        ELECTRIC "SWITCHLESS" SHUT-OFF SOLENOID FOR MW INJECTION PUMP
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ADJUSTMENT OF NEW ELECTRIC "SWITCHLESS" SHUT-OFF SOLENOID FOR MW INJECTION PUMP</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk document="e415_248.xml" xrefid="ef4151143">11.43</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The adjustment procedure must be completed as specified to prevent solenoid burn-out or internal
                    damage to the injection pump.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Energize the solenoid by turning the ignition key to the
                <emph type="bold">"ON"</emph>
                or
                <emph type="bold">"RUN"</emph>
                position. (
                <emph type="bold">RUN</emph>
                position for those vehicles equipped with push-button start).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The solenoid plunger will not depress when energized.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Manually depress the plunger to the bottom of its travel.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While holding the plunger in, move the shut-off lever toward the
                <emph type="bold">RUN</emph>
                position and screw the solenoid swivel (with stud) into the rod end until the shut-off lever stops its
                downward movement.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn swivel
                <emph type="bold">TWO FULL TURNS</emph>
                in opposite direction (raising shut-off lever) and tighten locknut against rod end.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">De-energize Solenoid</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Following the installation and adjustment instructions will ensure that the solenoid plunger
                will be fully seated at bottom of stroke and internal injection pump shut-off lever will not contact
                interval housing stop tab nor interfere with injection pump fuel rack during "excess fuel" starting
                conditions. Shut-off stop screw has been factory preset limiting solenoid plunger total travel to
                approximately 25.4 mm (1.0 in.) from bottom of stroke (run position) to end of stroke (shut-off
                position).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not adjust shut-off lever stop screw. If stop screw position is changed, injection pump
                must be removed and stop screw position set on a test bench. When stop screw is improperly adjusted,
                control rack may not move sufficiently to stop fuel delivery or may damage internal injection pump rack
                stop.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cycle the solenoid 2-3 times making sure the shut-off lever travel is adequate to achieve
                the "fuel" and "no fuel" positions. This can be done by cranking the engine to activate the "Pull" coil
                causing the plunger to depress and turn the ignition off allowing the plunger to return under spring
                load.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT CYCLE MORE THAN 3 TIMES WITHIN ONE MINUTE. ADDITIONAL CYCLING MAY CAUSE PULL-IN COIL
                        OVER-HEATING RESULTING IN BURNOUT.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure wire and harnesses with strap locks to make sure that they will not interfere with
                solenoid operation or rub injection piping.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_249.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_251.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
