<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS, RINGS AND SLEEVES - RECONDITIONING -
        CONNECTING RODS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="7">
        <title>CONNECTING RODS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title></title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If required, install a new connecting rod piston pin bushing using a press and a
                    driver.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>LUBRICATE THE BUSHING BORE AND NEW BUSHING WITH CLEAN ENGINE OIL PRIOR TO PRESSING IN. BE
                            SURE THE OIL HOLE IN THE BUSHING IS ALIGNED WITH THE CORRESPONDING ORIFICE IN THE CONNECTING
                            ROD. REFER TO FIGURE
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150636">6.36</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After bushing installation, it must be honed to the proper I.D. (See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150601.xml" xrefid="hl4150601">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>). Use appropriate
                    honing equipment.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4150634" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11864" filename="../figcg1/cg11864.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.34. Check Ring End Gap at Top of Ring Travel.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4150635" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg12114" filename="../figcg1/cg12114.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.35. Check Ring End Gap Below Ring Travel Area.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4150636" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11568" filename="../figcg1/cg11568.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.36. Check Bushing and Rod Oil Hole Alignment.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl4150605">
            <title>Bearing Fitting Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If bearing-to-crankshaft running clearances exceed specifications because of wear on the
                    crankshaft, replace or regrind crankshaft and install undersize precision type bearing shells.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>DO NOT ATTEMPT TO REDUCE JOURNAL- TO-BEARING RUNNING CLEARANCES BY REWORKING BEARING CAP,
                            BEARINGS OR BOTH. REGRIND OR REPLACE THE CRANKSHAFT ONLY. REFER TO
                            <hotlnk document="e415_E41507.xml" xrefid="e41507">VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN
                                BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE.
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>REWORKING THE BEARING CAP WILL DESTROY THE ENGINEERED FIT OF THE BEARING SHELLS IN THEIR
                            BORES.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the connecting rod bolts alternately and evenly to the specified torque, using
                    an accurate torque wrench. (See
                    <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150602.xml" xrefid="hl4150602">"TORQUE SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>ABOUT BEARING CRUSH AND SPREAD! Bearing shells must fit tightly in the bore. When bearing
                            shells are inserted into the connecting rod and cap, they protrude above the parting line.
                            This protrusion is required to achieve "BEARING CRUSH". Bearing shells are designed with
                            "SPREAD". That is, the width across the open ends are slightly larger than the diameter of
                            the connecting rod bore into which they are assembled, as shown in Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150637">6.37</hotlnk>. This condition is designed into the bearing shell
                            causing it to spread outward at the parting line when "CRUSH" load is applied by tightening
                            the bolts. Some may be lost in normal use, but bearing replacement is not required because
                            of a nominal loss of
                            <emph type="bold">snap.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4150637" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg5756" filename="../figcg5/cg5756.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.37. Bearing Spread.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>When assembly is drawn up tight, bearing is compressed, assuring a positive contact between the
                    bearing back and the bore as shown in
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150638">6.38</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit connecting rod bearings and measure bearing running clearance as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With bearing cap removed, wipe oil from the face of the bearing insert and exposed
                        portion of the crankshaft journal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place a piece of "Plastigage(r)" across the full width of the bearing about 1/4 in.
                        off center.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the cap and tighten bolts evenly and alternately to specified torque.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not turn the crankshaft during running clearance check.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4150638" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11569" filename="../figcg1/cg11569.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.38. Bearing Crush.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove bearing cap. The "Plastigage(r)" material will be found adhering to either
                        the bearing shell or the crankshaft.
                        <emph type="bold">DO NOT REMOVE "PLASTIGAGE</emph>(r)
                        <emph type="bold">".</emph>
                        Use "Plastigage(r)" scale to measure widest point of flattened plastic material,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150639">6.39</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . The number within the graduated marks on the scale indicates the clearance in thousandths of
                        an inch or millimeters (See
                        <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150601.xml" xrefid="hl4150601">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the test material and the repeat test for each connecting rod bearing.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>With the precision bearings used, no problem should be encountered. However, if proper
                                clearance is NOT achieved, a problem with the crankshaft may exist which requires
                                regrinding and the use of undersize bearings. (Refer to
                                <hotlnk document="e415_E41507.xml" xrefid="e41507">VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN
                                    BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE.
                                </hotlnk>
                                for Crankshaft Rework Information.) Bearing cap torque is very important. Use a torque
                                wrench which is known to be accurate. Repeat running clearance check procedure before
                                condemning the crankshaft.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">4.Check connecting rod side clearance using a dial indicator as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the tip of the dial indicator on the connecting rod cap as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150640">6.40</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pry the connecting rod towards the rear of the engine and "zero" the dial
                        indicator.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pry the connecting rod toward the front of the engine and read the indicator. Refer
                        to
                        <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150601.xml" xrefid="hl4150601">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>
                        and repeat for all connecting rods.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The connecting rod side clearance must be checked to be certain that the specified
                                clearance exists.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lack of clearance could indicate a damaged rod or a rod bearing out of position.
                        Correct as required.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Excessive clearance may require replacement of the rods or crankshaft. Correct as
                        required.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4150639" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11570" filename="../figcg1/cg11570.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.39. Check Connecting Rod Bearing Clearance.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4150640" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11571" filename="../figcg1/cg11571.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.40. Check Connecting Rod Side Clearance.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_114.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_HL4150604.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
