<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - LUBRICATING OIL PUMP, OIL FILTERS AND COOLER - OIL COOLER AND
        COOLANT FILTER HEADER ASSEMBLY - COOLANT FILTER HEADER RECONDITIONING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>COOLANT FILTER HEADER RECONDITIONING</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150935">9.35</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Current style coolant filter header disassembly is only required when external valve leakage is
                    present (which indicates the need for O-Ring replacement) or when leakage is found during coolant
                    filter replacement. When the shut-off valve is in the "OFF" position and coolant leaks past the
                    valve, this indicates the need for coolant shut-off valve sleeve replacement.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the slotted spring pin (shut-off valve handle) from the valve.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount header in a soft jawed vise and drive shut-off valve out of the casting, from pin
                end.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The cup plug will pop out when the shut-off valve is driven out of the header. Discard the cup
                        plug.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the O-Ring from the shut-off valve and discard.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a pick to remove the two rubber sealing sleeves which are located in the filter header
                casting above the shut-off valve. Discard the sleeves.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the shut-off valve for wear, replace as required.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the O-Ring, shut-off valve and sleeves prior to assembly into the header using N
                LGI #2 multi-purpose lithium grease.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4150934" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12290" filename="../figcg1/cg12290.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.34. Current Coolant Filter Header Removal.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4150935" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12291" filename="../figcg1/cg12291.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.35. Coolant Filter Header Assembly.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install new sleeves in the header and a new O-Ring on the shut-off valve.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the valve into the header until the holes in the valve are aligned with the holes in
                the header (as viewed from the bottom of the header).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the spring pin into the shut-off valve shaft until the pin bottoms.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new cup plug flush with the header casting surface.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_200.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
