<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL INJECTION PUMP - FUEL FILTER HEADER AND
        THROTTLE LINKAGE ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="13">
        <title>FUEL FILTER HEADER AND THROTTLE LINKAGE ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using an appropriate filter wrench, remove the fuel filters from the header and discard.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove the three mounting bolts which secure the fuel filter header to the
                crankcase, then remove the header with throttle cable bracket attached. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151124">11.24</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>On those units equipped with a bellcrank bracket and control rod throttle linkage, remove ball
                        joint from engine control lever for filter header removal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4151122" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11653" filename="../figcg1/cg11653.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.22. Remove Upper and Lower Throttle Return Springs.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4151123" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11898" filename="../figcg1/cg11898.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.23. Fuel Return Tube Removal (Early Production w/MW Pump Shown).</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4151124" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11648" filename="../figcg1/cg11648.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.24. Remove Filter Header and Bracket.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the
                <emph type="bold">MW</emph>
                fuel injection pump is equipped with an electric shut-off solenoid, remove as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151125">11.25</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the harness at the solenoid connector.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the bolt and nut at rod end at stop lever control.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove solenoid mounting bracket bolts and remove solenoid and bracket as a unit.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the
                <emph type="bold">PES6A</emph>
                fuel injection pump is equipped with an electric shut-off solenoid, remove as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151126">11.26</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Solenoid is a "Switchless" design and is located on in-board side of Injection Pump.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen the jam nut at the female rod end.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Unscrew the swivel from the female rod end.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the metri-pack connector from the harness.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Access the injection pump to adapter housing mounting nuts and remove the solenoid and
                    bracket assembly.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4151125" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11652" filename="../figcg1/cg11652.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.25. Solenoid Removal "Internal Switch" (Model MW Injection Pump Shown).</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151126" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg14479" filename="../figcg1/cg14479.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.26. Solenoid Assembly (Installed View) (Model PES6A Injection Pump).</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the lube oil supply line as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151127">11.27</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the compression nut at the crankcase elbow.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the hex head hollow screw and copper gaskets from the banjo fitting at the fuel
                    injection pump oil inlet.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the tube assembly and discard the sealing sleeve at the compression nut end of
                    the tube.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cap the pump oil inlet and the elbow at the crankcase.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the injection pump drive gear access cover as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the six fasteners which secure the access cover. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151128">11.28</hotlnk>
                        or
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151129">11.29</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Three bolts and nuts secure the access cover to the injection pump adapter housing and
                            three bolts with washers secure the access cover to the housing casting.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4151127" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11655" filename="../figcg1/cg11655.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.27. Remove Lube Oil Supply Line (Model MW Injection Pump Shown).</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151128" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11918" filename="../figcg1/cg11918.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.28. Removal of Current Injection Pump Drive Gear Access Cover Bolts.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4151129" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11682" filename="../figcg1/cg11682.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.29. Removal of Early Injection Pump Drive Gear Access Cover Bolts.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the access cover and gasket from the front cover to expose the injection pump
                    drive gear. Discard the gasket. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151130">11.30</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If equipped, the mechanical tachometer drive adapter may be removed with the access
                            cover.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the injection pump drive gear bolts and hardened washers. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151131">11.31</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The injection pump and adapter assembly can be removed without removing the injection pump
                        drive gear. Drive gear removal is shown at this time for procedural purposes only.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the injection pump drive gear from the pump hub. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151132">11.32</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The polished side of the drive gear faces the hub.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4151130" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11915" filename="../figcg1/cg11915.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.30. Remove Access Cover.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4151131" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg9873" filename="../figcg9/cg9873.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.31. Remove Injection Pump Drive Gear Bolts.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4151132" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11685" filename="../figcg1/cg11685.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.32. Remove the Injection Pump Drive Gear.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the injection pump and mounting adapter as an assembly. Discard the gasket. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151133">11.33</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Dowels on the adapter housing hold the pump assembly to the front plate.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>IF THE FUEL INJECTION PUMP MOUNTING ADAPTER IS REMOVED FROM THE PUMP TO PERFORM REPAIRS,
                        REINSTALL THE ADAPTER WITH THE FACTORY SET SCRIBE MARKS ALIGNED ONLY AFTER THE PUMP IS FLOW
                        TIMED. IF THE FUEL INJECTION PUMP MOUNTING ADAPTER IS REMOVED FROM THE PUMP AND A NEW ADAPTER IS
                        INSTALLED, THE PUMP MUST BE FLOW TIMED. AFTER FLOW TIMING, STRIKE A NEW MARK ON THE REPLACEMENT
                        MOUNTING ADAPTER TO ALIGN WITH THE SCRIBE MARK LOCATED ON THE INBOARD SIDE OF THE PUMP MOUNTING
                        FLANGE (FIGURE
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4151134">11.34</hotlnk>). REFER TO ROBERT BOSCH FUEL INJECTION PUMP SERVICE
                        MANUAL FORM CGES-375 FOR FLOW TIMING PROCEDURE FOR THE MW INJECTION PUMP OR CGES-480 FOR THE
                        PES6A INJECTION PUMP.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4151133" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11681" filename="../figcg1/cg11681.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.33. Remove Injection Pump.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4151134" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14175" filename="../figcg1/cg14175.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.34. Mounting Adapter Installation (Model MW Injection Pump Shown).</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_244.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_246.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
