<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - TURBOCHARGERS - RECONDITIONING - CLEANING AND INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CLEANING AND INSPECTION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prior to cleaning, visually inspect ALL the components for signs of rubbing or wear which
                may not be evident after cleaning.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Soak all parts in Bendix Metal Cleaner or Gunk Hydroseal to clean.
                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                use a caustic solution.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean deposits using a soft brush or a plastic scraper.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dry parts using filtered compressed air.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>1. DO NOT USE A STEEL BRUSH OR STEEL BLADE SCRAPER TO CLEAN TURBOCHARGER PARTS.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>2. BE SURE ALL BLADES ARE THOROUGHLY CLEANED, AS ANY DEPOSITS LEFT ON THE BLADES WILL AFFECT
                        BALANCE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dry all internal cavities of the center housing using filtered compressed air.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect both wheels of the rotor assembly for damaged or distorted blades and for
                possible contact with their respective housings. Check for cracked, bent or broken blades. Replace
                components if necessary.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT ATTEMPT TO STRAIGHTEN BLADES.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4150233" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12021" filename="../figcg1/cg12021.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.33 Piston Ring Removal.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the turbine and compressor housings for cracks and/or scoring.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the thrust washer and collar for wear or damage and replace as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the thrust spring in the back plate for wear or damage.
                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                remove the thrust spring to inspect it. If damaged, remove and install a new thrust spring.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the bearing surfaces for scratches and wear. Replace bearings as
                necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the turbine wheel shaft for scratches, scoring or pitting. Replace as required.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>NEVER GRIND OR POLISH THE SHAFT; IT WILL ADVERSELY AFFECT BALANCE.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the piston ring groove walls on the shaft for scoring. Replace as required.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect for worn or scored surfaces in the center housing bearing bores.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the following mating surfaces for nicks or gouges:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turbine housing to center housing.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Center housing to back plate.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Back plate to compressor housing.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The mating surfaces must be smooth to seal and provide proper clearances for the compressor
                impeller and turbine wheel. Replace any part which does not meet the inspection criteria.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
