<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND
        CRANKCASE - COMPONENT CHANGES - LUBE OIL FLOW
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>LUBE OIL FLOW</title>
        <para>Effective with S/N 525618 the lube oil passage from the main oil gallery to the rocker arm shaft has been
            changed.
        </para>
        <para>Lube oil to the rocker arm shaft was previously routed through vertical and horizontal drilled passage
            holes in the crankcase, then around the rear cylinder head bolt to the rocker arm shaft. The vertical oil
            passage from the rear camshaft bushing was sealed at the crankcase top deck with a steel ball on early
            production engines. These engines utilized a horizontal drilling in the crankcase to conduct oil from the
            vertical passage to the rear cylinder head bolt and onto the rocker arm shaft.
        </para>
        <para>The horizontal passageway and the hex-socket plug in the rear of the crankcase are eliminated (
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150705">7.5</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ). Vertical passageway is open to the crankcase top deck (the steel ball is eliminated) and oil is conducted
            to the rear cylinder head bolt and rocker arm shaft by means of a new oil slot in the head gasket (
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150706">7.6</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            ).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>USE ONLY A CYLINDER HEAD GASKET WITH THE REAR OIL SLOT ON ENGINES WITH S/N AFTER 525617 OR WITH A
                    SERVICE CRANKCASE THAT DOES NOT HAVE THE REAR HEX-SOCKET PLUG.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="ef4150705" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg13059" filename="../figcg1/CG13059.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 7.5. Horizontal Drilling/Hex-Socket Plug Location.</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="ef4150706" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg11890" filename="../figcg1/CG11890.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 7.6. Cylinder Head Gasket Identification.</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The slotted gasket has been updated to eliminate three holes "A" at the front left corner of the
                    gasket. Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150707">7.7</hotlnk>. While the three holes are no longer utilized, the
                    surrounding "PRINTOSEAL" remains to enhance gasket sealing. This current gasket will work for
                    service on all DT/DTA-466 engines.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="ef4150707" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg14029" filename="../figcg1/CG14029.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 7.7. Location of Three Holes in Cylinder Head Gasket.</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_129.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_131.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
