<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service (1990) - VIBRATION DAMPER, CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND
        CRANKCASE - CRANKCASE (RECONDITIONING)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CRANKCASE (RECONDITIONING)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CLEANING</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The best way to clean the crankcase during engine overhaul is in a chemical bath or "HOT
                        TANK". This removes all carbonous material and mineral deposits which collect in the cooling
                        passages. If the "HOT TANK" is not available, use the following cleaning procedure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all old gasket material from the machined surfaces of the crankcase using a
                    scraper and a sanding block.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the cylinder sleeve bores using soap, water and a nylon brush.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the main oil gallery cup plugs, at the front and rear of the crankcase, as
                    follows:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Oil gallery cup plugs are 13/16" in diameter. Occasionally, engines are built with
                            oversized galleries requiring 7/8" cup plugs. These plugs can be identified by a diamond
                            with an MP stamped on it. When replacing these cup plugs, be sure to determine if the plug
                            is a standard 13/16" or an oversize 7/8". Refer to the Parts Catalog for the correct service
                            number.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Drill a small hole into the cup plug and insert a self tapping sheet metal screw
                        into plug.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using a small pry bar, pry the plug out. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150750">7.50</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        for plug locations.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a 13/16" nylon brush, with soap and water to clean the oil galleries.</para>
                    <figure id="ef4150750" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12183" filename="../figcg1/cg12183.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.50. Main Oil Gallery Plug Locations.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the three hex-socket plugs located on the right side of the crankcase (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150751">7.51</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the plugs removed from the crankcase, clean the crankcase as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a 21 mm (13/16 in.) nylon brush with soap and water to clean the oil
                        galleries.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean the cross drillings using a nylon brush with soap and water.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Blow out all oil galleries and cross drillings using filtered compressed air.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean all threaded holes using a tap of appropriate size.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the four hex-socket plugs on the right side of the crankcase. Use
                        Loctite(r) to seal the threads.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new main oil gallery cup plugs as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean mating surfaces on plug and crankcase.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply Loctite(r) to the outside edge of the cup plug.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Drive the cup plug in using an arbor approximately 6.4 mm (1/4 in.) smaller in
                        diameter than the plug being installed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Recess the plug 3.1 mm (1/8 in.)</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Effective with S/N 532981 two nylon patch bolts are used to attach the breather
                                opening cover. Installation of non-patch type bolts could result in oil leaks at the
                                cover opening. Refer to Figure
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4150751">7.51</hotlnk>
                                for cover location.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4150751" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11914" filename="../figcg1/cg11914.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7.51. Cross Drilling Plug and Breather Opening Cover Locations.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_153.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415_155.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e415.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
