<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        FUEL INJECTION NOZZLES - CARE OF LAPPING BLOCKS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CARE OF LAPPING BLOCKS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>It will be necessary to perform a certain amount of maintenance on the lapping blocks to keep them in
                top condition. The wear will be gradual but, by continued use, worn or low spots in the block must be
                removed.
            </para>
            <para>A short time spent each day in hand-lapping the blocks will be an effective way of maintaining the
                finish necessary for quality lapping.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reconditioning the Lapping Blocks</title>
            <para>The lapping blocks must be thoroughly cleaned before any reconditioning is started. Use a stiff
                bristle brush (not a wire brush) and scrub the blocks in a good solvent and blow dry with filtered
                compressed air.
            </para>
            <para>All lapping blocks in a set are involved in the reconditioning procedure outlined below:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spread a small amount of 1000 grit lapping compound (prepared in a paste) on block
                    number 1, assuming the blocks to be numbered 1, 2 and 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lap number 1 and 2 (face to face) together, using the figure eight pattern (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e435_202.xml" xrefid="ef4350953">9.53</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). Then take 1 and 3; and finally 2 and 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>After working 1 and 3 together, wipe off number 2 on a clean sheet of paper placed on a flat surface.
                Low spots, if any, will appear as dark spots and high spots as bright spots. Continue the lapping
                procedure until the overall appearance is a uniform grey surface.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the blocks have been refinished, clean them thoroughly in a good solvent using a
                    bristle brush, then blow dry with filtered compressed air.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_202.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_204.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
