<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        FUEL INJECTION NOZZLES - DISASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DISASSEMBLY</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Disassemble only those nozzle holder assemblies that fail to meet specifications.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>WHEN MORE THAN ONE FUEL INJECTION NOZZLE HOLDER IS DISASSEMBLED, KEEP PARTS OF EACH SEPARATE, THE
                    NOZZLE VALVE AND NOZZLE VALVE BODY ARE MATED PARTS AND MUST BE KEPT TOGETHER; IF REPLACEMENT OF
                    EITHER PART IS NECESSARY, A NOZZLE TIP ASSEMBLY MUST BE ORDERED. NEVER INTERCHANGE THE NOZZLE VALVES
                    AND NOZZLE VALVE BODIES.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Disassemble the nozzle holder assembly for cleaning, inspection and service as follows:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wash all external dirt, grease and carbon deposits from holder assembly with suitable
                cleaning agent.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove copper seal washer from nozzle, if not removed earlier. (Discard old copper seal
                washer.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A brass wire hand brush should be used to remove hardened deposits of dirt or carbon.</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>SOAK NOZZLE HOLDER ASSEMBLY IN A CARBON REMOVING CLEANING AGENT ("GUNK", "BENDIX CLEANER" OR
                        EQUIVALENT) FOR AT LEAST 4 HOURS BEFORE REMOVING NOZZLE CAP NUT; OTHERWISE, THE NOZZLE LOCATING
                        PINS MAY BE DAMAGED.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Injection nozzle and holder assembly should be clamped down and attached to a workbench to
                prevent it from moving during disassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a 19/32 in.12 point box wrench, loosen nozzle cap nut. Loosen until cap nut can be
                turned by hand.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A sharp blow to end of wrench may be required to break carbon bond between nozzle and cap
                        nut.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unclamp nozzle holder assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cap nut, nozzle spacer (with dowels) (+) and nozzle tip from holder body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove spring seat, spring and shims from holder body. (See
                <emph type="bold">Figure 9.47</emph>) Take care not to lose spacers (+).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_199.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_201.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
