<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS AND RINGS - CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS AND
        RINGS (Reconditioning) - Inspection
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="15">
        <title>Inspection</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PISTONS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the pistons for scuffed or scored skirts, cracked or worn ring lands
                    and cracked or scuffed pin bores, discarding any showing such condition.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4350517" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11723" filename="../figcg1/cg11723.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.17 Removing Piston Pin Retainers</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4350518" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11090" filename="../figcg1/cg11090.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.18 Removing Piston Pin Retainers</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Piston pins should be inspected and measured for wear. If piston pins show signs of
                    corrosion or etching or are not within specifications, they should be replaced with new pins. See
                    <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>. Piston
                    assemblies furnished for service replacement are complete with piston pins accurately fitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PISTON SELECTION GUIDELINES</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If pistons require replacement, a standard or oversize piston must be chosen as
                    follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure cylinder bore diameters using a telescoping gauge with outside micrometer or
                        dial bore gauge to determine cylinder out-of-round and taper,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350519">5.19</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure the diameter of each cylinder bore at the top of the piston ring travel at a
                        right angle to the crankshaft (
                        <emph type="bold">"A", Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350520">5.20</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        )
                        <emph type="bold"></emph>and to the centerline of the crankshaft (
                        <emph type="bold">"B", Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350520">5.20</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ). Record the readings and calculate the difference.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat measurements at the "Top" and at the "Bottom" of ring travel. Record the
                        readings and calculate the difference.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The out-of-round condition at the top and bottom of ring travel is the difference
                        between the "Top" reading and "Bottom" reading for each set of measurements.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Cylinder bore taper is the difference between the cylinder bore diameters measured
                        at the "Top" of ring travel (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350521">5.21</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ) and the "Bottom" of ring travel (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350521">5.21</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        )
                        <emph type="bold">(AT RIGHT ANGLES TO THE CENTERLINE OF THE CRANKSHAFT).</emph>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Refer to
                                <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>
                                for maximum out-of-round and cylinder bore taper.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4350519" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11133" filename="../figcg1/cg11133.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.19 Checking Cylinder Bore Using Dial Bore Gauge (At Top of Ring Travel)
                        </caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350520" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11091" filename="../figcg1/cg11091.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.20 Checking Cylinder for Out-of-Round and Taper (Dial Indicator Shown At
                            Bottom of Ring Travel)
                        </caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350521" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11092" filename="../figcg1/cg11092.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.21 Checking Cylinder Bore Taper</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If taper and out-of-round for cylinder walls are within specifications use new
                        standard size service pistons.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If cylinder bores exceed out-of-round and/or taper specifications reboring may be
                        required as described in Section 6. Such cylinder bore reconditioning will require the use of
                        oversize service pistons. In addition to the standard size service piston 0.010 in., 0.020 in.
                        and 0.030 in. oversize pistons are available. Verify piston size by measuring skirt diameter (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350522">5.22</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ).
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>THE SIZE PISTON SELECTED SHOULD BE LARGE ENOUGH TO PERMIT CLEANING UP THE CYLINDER
                                BORE AND PROVIDE THE PROPER RUNNING CLEARANCE IN THE CYLINDER BORE. REFER TO
                                <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For detailed procedures on reboring the cylinder bore refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="E43506">"CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE".</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PISTON RINGS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Faulty rings cannot always be detected by visual inspection. Therefore, whenever a piston is
                        removed from a cylinder, it is recommended that the piston rings be replaced.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect
                    <emph type="bold">NEW</emph>
                    rings for cleanliness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to installing the rings on the piston, check each ring for proper gap as
                    follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Push the ring down into the cylinder bore making sure the ring is square with the
                        cylinder wall.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure the gap between the ends of each ring with a feeler gauge as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350523">5.23</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                        <emph type="bold"></emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the gap does not meet the
                        <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>, select
                        another ring.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Piston rings are available for service in standard sizes as well as 0.010 in., 0.020
                                in. and 0.030 in. oversize piston rings. Each ring should be fitted and checked in the
                                cylinder in which it is to be used. Mark accordingly so they are installed in their
                                respective bores.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4350522" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11093" filename="../figcg1/cg11093.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.22 Piston Skirt Dia. Measurement (90&#176; to pin bore)</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350523" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11137" filename="../figcg1/cg11137.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.23 Checking Ring Gap</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check side clearance of piston rings in the groove of the piston on which they are to be
                    installed, as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the outer edge of the ring in the piston groove
                        <emph type="bold"></emph>(
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350524">5.24</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Roll the ring, in its respective groove, entirely around the piston. Make sure the
                        ring is "free" in the groove.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With a feeler gauge (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350524">5.24</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ) check the side clearance of each ring in its respective groove.
                        <emph type="bold">(See
                            <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>.)
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CONNECTING RODS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure inside diameter of piston pin bushing in connecting rod using a telescoping
                    gauge and a micrometer,
                    <emph type="bold">Figure 5.24.</emph>
                    (See
                    <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>. If bushings are
                    worn, new bushing must be installed after connecting rod passes inspection.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any worn bushing using Connecting Rod Bushing Remover and Installer Tool
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE4154</emph>. Place connecting rod under a hydraulic press in line with the
                    properly sized hole on the support block and use
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE4154</emph>
                    to press out the bushing,
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350525">5.26</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4350524" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg12355" filename="../figcg1/cg12355.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.24 Checking Ring-to-Groove Side Clearance with Feeler Gauge</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4350526" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11162" filename="../figcg1/cg11162.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.25 Checking Connecting Rod Piston Pin Bushing I.D.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4350525" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11094" filename="../figcg1/cg11094.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.26 Using ZTSE-4154 Tool to Remove Worn Connecting Rod Bushing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the connecting rod thoroughly and visually inspect for defects. Using telescoping
                    gauge and a micrometer, check connecting rod piston pin bushing bore diameter,
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350527">5.27</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . (See
                    <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>.) Replace as
                    required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue connecting rod inspection (crankshaft end) as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure connecting rod bearing bore diameter (with bearing inserts removed),
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350528">5.28</hotlnk>. (See
                            <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>)
                        </emph>
                        for bearing bore I.D.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Measure bore diameter with connecting rod nut tightened to specified special torque.
                                Replace as required.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With connecting rod assembled and rod bolts and nuts tightened to specified special
                        torque use a dial bore gauge indicator to measure out-of-round,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350529">5.29</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        (see
                        <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>). Replace rod
                        if maximum out-of-round specification is exceeded.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4350527" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11197" filename="../figcg1/cg11197.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.27 Checking Connecting Rod Piston Pin Bushing Bore Diameter</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350528" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11200" filename="../figcg1/cg11200.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.28 Measuring Connecting Rod Bearing Bore Diameter</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350529" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11095" filename="../figcg1/cg11095.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.29 Measuring Connecting Rod Bearing Bore Roundness</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure connecting rod bore taper (
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350530">5.30</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        ), by measuring the bore I. D. near the large chamfer, record reading and measure the bore I.D.
                        near the small chamfer, record reading. The difference between the two readings is the bore
                        taper. (See
                        <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350501.xml" xrefid="hl4350501">"SPECIFICATIONS"</hotlnk>). Replace rod
                        if maximum bore taper is exceeded.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With connecting rod cap removed, visually inspect the surface finish of the
                        connecting rod bearing bore. The bore must be smooth and free of scoring or nicks,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350531">5.31</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . Replace as required.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Connecting rod inspection (4a-d) can be made using accurate bore gauging instruments.
                                Refer to instructions included with the gauges.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>CONNECTING ROD BEND AND TWIST</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">An engine component wear pattern can be identified and used to diagnose a problem.
                    Common examples of connecting rod wear pattern diagnostic clues are presented as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A shiny surface on edge of piston pin bushing usually indicates that a connecting
                        rod is bent or piston pin hole is not in proper relation to piston skirt and ring grooves.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Abnormal connecting rod bearing wear can be caused by either a bent connecting rod,
                        an improperly machined journal, or a tapered connecting rod bore.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Twisted connecting rods will not create an easily identifiable wear pattern, but
                        badly twisted rods will disturb action of entire piston, rings, and connecting rod assembly and
                        may be the cause of excessive oil consumption.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>IF THE CONNECTING RODS DO NOT MEET THE REQUIREMENTS SET FORTH IN PARAGRAPHS 1-6
                                "CONNECTING ROD INSPECTION", REPLACE THE ENTIRE CONNECTING ROD ASSEMBLY.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4350530" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg10564" filename="../figcg1/cg10564.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.30 Measuring Bearing Bore Taper</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350531" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg5383" filename="../figcg5/cg5383.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.31 Inspection of Connecting Rod Bearing Bore Surface Finish</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_95.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_97.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
