<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        FUEL FILTER/WATER SEPARATOR ASSEMBLY REMOVAL AND REASSEMBLY (U-Haul Application Only) - MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <para>Water should be drained from the engine mounted fuel filter/water separator whenever the warning lamp
            comes on or every 5000 miles (8046 km).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>More frequent drain intervals may be required depending on fuel quality and vehicle usage.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The instrument panel warning lamp (water in fuel) will glow when approximately 0.1 quarts (0.1 liters) of
            water has accumulated in the drain bowl. When the warning lamp glows, shut off the engine as soon as safely
            possible and follow the drain procedure.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stop the vehicle and shut off the engine. (Wait 2-5 minutes for the water to settle).</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Failure to shut off the engine prior to draining the water separator will cause fuel
                        leakage.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a container under the water drain tube (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e435_178.xml" xrefid="ef4350913">9.13</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open the drain valve by turning counterclockwise (as viewed from the bottom) (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350924">9.24</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ). Drain for about 10 seconds or until clear diesel fuel flows from the drain bowl.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4350923" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12437" filename="../figcg1/cg12437.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.23</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350924" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11987" filename="../figcg1/cg11987.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.24</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the water is completely drained, close the valve by turning clockwise (CW) until the
                valve is fully seated. Verify draining has stopped. Properly dispose of the drained fluid.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Restart the engine and check the water in fuel lamp. The lamp should not glow.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_179.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_181.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
