<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - LUBRICATING OIL PUMP, OIL FILTER AND COOLER - GENERAL OPERATION -
        LUBRICATING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>LUBRICATING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350803">8.3</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <para>Lube oil is drawn out of the sump through the pick-up screen and oil pick-up to the oil pump. From the
                oil pump, oil is passed via drilled passageways in the crankcase to the oil cooler. Oil flows around the
                outside of the heat exchanger, tubes. (Coolant flows through the tubes.) The oil passes around the tubes
                rearward to the oil filter header. At the oil filter header the oil meets the pressure regulating valve,
                which regulates the oil flow and pressure to the oil filter and the engine oil galleries. Five cross
                passages distribute oil to vertical passages which feed the crankshaft main bearings, camshaft bearings
                and two valve lifter galleries. The piston cooling jets are fed from the same passage as the valve
                lifters. The connecting rod bearings are fed from the main bearings via drilled passages in the
                crankshaft. The timing gears are lubricated by oil exiting from the front camshaft bearing. Oil passes
                through the hydraulic valve lifter galleries and up the hollow push rods to lubricate the rocker arm
                assemblies and valve stems.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4350803" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12312" filename="../figcg1/CG12312.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8.3</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>By-Pass Valve</title>
            <para>The by-pass valve (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350804">8.4</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) is located in the oil filter- cooler header. The by-pass valve controls oil flow through the filter.
                Depending upon immediate conditions, the oil can travel in one of two directions or, in some cases,
                divide and travel in both directions.
            </para>
            <para>During normal operation, the flow of oil continues on through the filter element on its way to the
                crankcase main oil gallery. However, if the filter is not changed every 6000 miles (9656 km), 200 hours
                or 2 months, whichever occurs first, excessive filter contamination and pressure drop will result. When
                such contamination occurs, the pressure differential type of by-pass valve will open allowing the oil to
                by-pass the filters and flow directly into the crankcase main oil gallery where it is distributed to all
                parts of the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Pressure Regulator Valve</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350805">8.5</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <para>The unique design of the oil pressure regulator valve extends the life of the oil filter in that it
                controls the volume and pressure of the filtered oil supplied to the engine. The volume of oil supplied
                by the pump is in excess of what is needed to lubricate the engine. This valve divides that flow. The
                volume needed to lubricate the engine is directed to the filters and excess is dumped to return. When
                all points of lubrication within the engine are satisfied, restriction to flow causes pressure to build
                in the filtered oil gallery and on the face of the valve. As this force moves the valve toward the
                regulator spring the port in the unfiltered oil gallery is uncovered and excess oil is dumped to return.
                Due to volume changes caused by changes in engine RPM the valve will dump more or less oil to the return
                keeping filtered oil pressure and volume within the specified range. Thus, the only oil filtered is that
                which is needed to lubricate the engine.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The oil pressure regulator and by-pass valves are not serviced separately. If valves are
                        suspected of being faulty, the oil filter-cooler header must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350804" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg10540a" filename="../figcg1/CG10540A.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8.4</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Pump</title>
            <para>The oil pump is a positive displacement gear driven unit located in the front of the front bearing cap
                and driven by the crankshaft gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Cooler</title>
            <para>The oil cooler is mounted on the left side of the engine. All of the engine oil is circulated from the
                oil pump through the cooler and into the oil filter. Coolant flows from the radiator through the
                numerous tubes in the cooler. Headers are die cast aluminum. The oil filter-cooler header houses the
                filter by-pass pressure regulator valves.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4350805" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg10541" filename="../figcg1/CG10541.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8.5</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_150.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_152.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
