<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INTRODUCTION - FUEL SYSTEM - ALL APPLICATIONS EXCEPT U-HAUL
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ALL APPLICATIONS EXCEPT U-HAUL</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef435IN18">i.18</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <para>Fuel from the tank is routed to the fuel supply pump through a primary filter/water separator.</para>
        <para>Fuel then passes through the final fuel filter, which contains an orifice bleed off system which aids dry
            starting by eliminating the need to manually prime the fuel filter.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Properly filtered diesel fuel cannot be overemphasized. It is essential for long component life
                    and reliability.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Fuel enters the inlet of the injection pump and is delivered under high pressure through injection nozzles
            into the engine cylinders for combustion. On each nozzle is a fuel return fitting that returns excess fuel
            to the fuel tank. Excess fuel from the injection pump and each injection nozzle are collected in bleed off
            lines and returned to the fuel tank.
        </para>
        <para>Injection nozzles are located on the inboard side of the cylinder head. This configuration has the
            following advantages:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Injection nozzles operate in a cooler environment far removed from the exhaust manifold and
                exhaust ports.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Injection lines do NOT interfere with engine accessories and provide better access to the
                engine for servicing.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef435IN18" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12386" filename="../figcg1/cg12386.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure i.18 Fuel Flow Schematic, All Except U-Haul Application.</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
