<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        Removing Injection Pump (all applications) - INJECTION PUMP INSTALLATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INJECTION PUMP INSTALLATION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prepare injection pump for mounting to engine by rotating injection pump drive shaft so slot
                in drive shaft is approximately at 4 o'clock (viewed from front of engine).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the injection pump assembly on the adapter housing over the three mounting studs and
                align the dowel on the injection pump drive gear with the slot in the drive shaft.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not slide the injection pump all the way forward on the studs. Slide about halfway to allow
                        clearance for nut installation on studs at the injection pump mounting flange.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the scribed line on the pump with the scribed line on the adapter housing (at the
                10:00 position) after the mounting nuts are started on the adapter housing studs. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350942">9.42</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>NEW ENGINE AND INJECTION PUMP TIMING IS SET IN TWO STEPS DURING THE PRODUCTION PROCESS.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>step one: initial or static timing is marked at the 12:00 position on the pump flange and
                        adapter housing. these marks are only used as an approximate timing setting prior to step two,
                        dynamically timing the engine.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>STEP TWO: FINAL TIMING IS DONE DYNAMICLY. IF TIMING ADJUSTMENT IS REQUIRED, A ROBOTIC DEVISE
                        AUTOMATICALLY ADJUSTS THE INJECTION PUMP POSITION BY ROTATING IT SLIGHTLY (ADVANCE OR RETARD),
                        AND STRIKING NEW MARKS AT THE 10:00 POSITION. THE 12:00 MARKS MAY BE OUT OF ALIGNMENT DUE TO THE
                        PUMP DURING THE DYNAMIC TIMING ADJUSTMENT. ONLY THE 10:00 MARKS MUST BE IN ALIGNMENT.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If service requires injection pump replacement, use the 12:00 scribe marks as a reference,
                        then dynamically time the pump using the Tach-N'-Timet Instrument (ZTSE4142) and scribe new
                        alignment at the 10:00 position. Refer to CGES-460 "7.3 L Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual".
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350942" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14304" filename="../figcg1/cg14304.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.42</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the three injection pump gear mounting bolts and tighten to specified torque (see
                <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350901.xml" xrefid="hl4350901">Specifications</hotlnk>). Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350943">9.43</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten injection pump mounting nuts using injection pump wrench
                <emph type="bold">ZTSE4132</emph>. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e435_190.xml" xrefid="ef4350935">9.35</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the oil fill tube and apply R.T.V. at the mounting surface prior to installation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all protective caps and install the fuel return hose, filter to pump supply tube and
                fuel injection line to nozzles. Tighten to
                <hotlnk document="e435_HL4350901.xml" xrefid="hl4350901">SPECIFIED TORQUES</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>USE NEW RUBBER SEALING SLEEVES ON ALL FUEL LINE CONNECTORS, EXCEPT HIGH PRESSURE NOZZLE LINES
                        WHICH HAVE SWEDGED FITTINGS.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>FOR DETAILED INSTRUCTIONS ON CLEANING, INSPECTING AND SERVICING THE FUEL INJECTION PUMP, REFER
                        TO CGES-475 "THE STANADYNE DB-2 FUEL INJECTION PUMP SERVICE MANUAL.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350943" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12402" filename="../figcg1/cg12402.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.43</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_193.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_195.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
