<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - CRANKSHAFT
        (Reconditioning) - INSTALLATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="6">
        <title>INSTALLATION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a lint-free cloth, wipe the bearing supports of the crankcase free of oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the bearing inserts and caps thoroughly in solvent and dry with compressed air.
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT SCRAPE GUM OR VARNISH DEPOSITS FROM BEARING SHELLS.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect each bearing. Replace bearings that are scored, chipped or worn.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check bearing clearance as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the bearing halves into the crankcase. Be sure locking tangs on the bearings are
                    snapped into the crankcase saddle and the oil holes in the bearing shells line up with the oil holes
                    in the crankcase.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Carefully install the crankshaft into the crankshaft bearing saddle.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install bearing halves with cap and tighten the inner and outer bolts to the specified
                    torque.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4350631" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11222" filename="../figcg1/cg11222.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.31</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4350632" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg10656" filename="../figcg1/cg10656.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.32</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove one bearing cap and insert one at a time. Remaining caps are left tight while
                    checking the fit of the bearing with the cap removed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wipe the oil from all contact surfaces of the exposed journal, bearing insert and cap.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place a piece of Plastigage(r) across the full width of the bearing surface on the
                    crankshaft journal (or bearing cap insert) approximately 1/4 in. off center. Install bearing cap and
                    tighten cap bolt to "specified" torque.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not turn crankshaft while making check with Plastigage(r).</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>IN CHASSIS SERVICE ONLY - When bearing clearance is checked, the crankshaft will have to
                            be supported and held against the upper main bearing halves to get a correct Plastigage(r)
                            reading. Use a jack at the counterweight next to each main bearing being checked to support
                            the crankshaft. Failure to support the crankshaft will result in inaccurate readings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove bearing cap and insert.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Do not disturb Plastigage(r). Using the Plastigage(r) envelope, measure the widest point
                    of the Plastigage(r),
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350633">6.33</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . This reading indicates the bearing clearance in thousandths of an inch or millimeters.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the bearing clearance is not within specifications, the crankshaft must be reground
                    and undersize bearings installed (as described earlier in this section).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When acceptable bearing clearance is achieved with either old or new parts, proceed as
                follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean Plastigage(r) from the bearing or crankshaft journal surface.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Coat all bearing surface journals and bolts with clean engine oil.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place the bearing caps and bearing lower halves over the crankshaft. Be sure the bearing
                    caps are properly installed. Number 1 is in the front position.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The bearing caps can be only put on one way. Finger-tighten the bearing caps. Using a
                    soft hammer, tap the number 1, 2 and 4 bearing caps until the rear machined faces of the caps are
                    flush with the machined faces of the crankcase.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4350633" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11219" filename="../figcg1/cg11219.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.33</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Repeat the same operation for bearing cap number 5 only aligning the front face of the
                    cap with the crankcase. The number 3 bearing rear thrust flanges must be flush with each other.
                    Aligning caps in this manner will assure proper cap location. Check this alignment at both sides
                    (left and right) of the bearing caps. Tighten the main bearing cap bolts to specified torque.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install crankshaft gear
                    <emph type="bold">(IF REMOVED)</emph>, using
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE1900-69</emph>
                    damper, crankshaft and camshaft gear installer,
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350634">6.34</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    .
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>Assemble the spacer tube, disc, thrust washer and nut onto the end of the
                    crankshaft. Turn the nut on the installer
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE1900-69</emph>
                    to install the crankshaft gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align the timing marks of both the camshaft and crankshaft gears as shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350635">6.35</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The thrust bearing (No. 3 Main Bearing) provides the initial location of the crankshaft in
                relation to the crankcase. Check crankshaft end play using a dial indicator as follows: (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350636">6.36</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Mount the dial indicator on the crankcase with the indicator tip on the crankcase flange
                    face.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With all bearing caps (except No. 3 thrust bearing) tightened to specified torque and
                    No. 3 thrust bearing finger-tight, adjust end play be prying the crankshaft forward and backward.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tighten the thrust bearing to the specified torque and "zero" the dial indicator.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the end play be moving the crankshaft back and forth using a pry bar while reading
                    the dial indicator.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If end play exceeds specification, replace the thrust bearing. If the end play is less than
                the minimum limit, the thrust bearing faces are damaged or dirty. If not damaged or dirty they were
                probably misaligned. After inspection either clean, replace or install the thrust bearing and align the
                faces following the bearing installation procedure in this section. Recheck crankshaft end play.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4350634" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11221" filename="../figcg1/cg11221.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.34</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350635" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11105" filename="../figcg1/cg11105.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.35</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350636" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11218" filename="../figcg1/cg11218.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.36</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the crankshaft and camshaft to verify that the gears do not bind or interfere. With
                the use of a dial indicator,
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e435_118.xml" xrefid="ef4350637">6.37</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                , check the gear backlash (see
                <hotlnk document="e435_99.xml" xrefid="hl4350601">"SPECIFICATIONS".</hotlnk>). If backlash limits are
                exceeded, timing gears should be replaced.
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_114.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_116.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
