<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        FUEL INJECTION NOZZLES - FLAT LAPPING PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FLAT LAPPING PROCEDURES</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use lapping block set SE2250. Obtain directly from: Bacharach, Inc., 625 Alpha Drive, Pittsburgh,
                    PA 15238.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prepare the lapping blocks for use by washing them in fuel oil and using a bristle brush.
                Dry off with filtered compressed air.
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT USE WIPING RAGS.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mix a small amount of lapping compound (1000 grit) into a thin paste using calibrating
                fluid.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In some areas, prepared lapping compound can be obtained in small tubes.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a very small amount of lapping compound (well spread out) to the lapped side of the
                block. Keep this amount at a minimum to obtain the best results.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Blocks that are grooved on both sides are generally marked to indicate which side is the
                        lapped surface.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The part to be lapped should be placed upon the lapping block and moved about in a figure
                eight pattern.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>To equalize the wear in the lapping block, the series of figure eight strokes should start at one side and
            progress across the block as shown in
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350953">9.53</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <figure id="ef4350953" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg6453" filename="../figcg6/cg6453.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 9.53</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply only enough pressure to keep the part flat on the block. After four or five "passes",
                lift the part off the block and clean the compound off by rubbing the part across a clean sheet of paper
                placed on a flat surface. (Avoid excessive lapping.) If the surface of the lapped part does not appear
                uniform in reflected light or if there are any depressions around the sealing surfaces, repeat the
                lapping procedure above (see
                <emph type="bold">Note</emph>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the lapping process does not remove depressions or provide good sealing surfaces, the
                        component must be replaced with a new one.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform the last step,
                <emph type="bold">DRY LAPPING</emph>, which produces a mirror-like finish and provides an excellent
                sealing surface. Proceed as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the block in the same manner as described earlier and dry with filtered compressed
                    air. The block used
                    <emph type="bold">MUST BE FREE OF ANY LAPPING COMPOUND.</emph>
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place the part to be lapped on the block surface and move it about in a figure eight
                    pattern across the whole area of the block (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e435_204.xml" xrefid="ef4350954">9.54</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ). Make four or five passes, then inspect the finish before repeating (if necessary).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply only enough pressure to keep the part flat on the block.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not handle parts on the lapped surfaces as corrosion will appear in the are as
                            touched.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>KEEP THE LAPPING BLOCKS COVERED WHEN NOT BEING USED, TO KEEP DUST OR OTHER FOREIGN MATTER
                            FROM THE SURFACE.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_201.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_203.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
