<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INJECTION PUMP, NOZZLES, FUEL FILTER, SUPPLY PUMP AND GLOW PLUGS -
        FUEL INJECTION NOZZLES - REASSEMBLY (NOZZLE COMPONENTS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REASSEMBLY (NOZZLE COMPONENTS)</title>
        <para>After cleaning, inspecting, reconditioning and/or replacing the disassembled nozzle components, reassemble
            as follows: (Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350954">9.54</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .)
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place nozzle holder in a vise standing in a vertical position.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not touch lapped surfaces. To avoid interchanging nozzle parts, reassemble one nozzle at a
                        time.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dip all parts in clean calibrating fluid. Do not touch mating surfaces of components with
                fingers after dipping.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install pressure adjusting shims, pressure adjusting spring and spring seat into nozzle
                holder body.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The thickest shim of the pack should contact the pressure adjusting spring.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install nozzle spacer on holder body assuring that locating dowels are positioned
                correctly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With nozzle valve dipped in clean calibrating fluid, assemble valve into nozzle body and
                move valve up and down several times to assure the valve
                <emph type="bold">DOES NOT STICK.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a thin, even coat of "Lubriplate - 630 AAA", or equivalent, to the nozzle body seating
                shoulder, align nozzle body locating pin holes with spacer pins and assemble nozzle to spacer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Hold nozzle tightly against nozzle spacer while tightening.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure assembly with nozzle cap nut turned hand-tight. Be sure nozzle tip is concentric with
                holder.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With nozzle clamped securely in a soft jawed vise, tighten nozzle cap nut using a 19/32 in.
                12 pt. box wrench. Tighten to the specified torque using a torque wrench.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4350954" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14521" filename="../figcg1/cg14521.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.54</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_203.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_205.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
