<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - LUBRICATING OIL PUMP, OIL FILTER AND COOLER - OIL COOLER - LUBE OIL
        RECOMMENDATIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>LUBE OIL RECOMMENDATIONS</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350815">8.15</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the crankcase with 16 qts. (15.1 L) w/filter change (or 15 qts. [14.2 L] without filter
                change) of oil meeting the API (American Petroleum Institute) categories of both SG and CF-4 or CE
                (SG/CF-4 or SG/CE) and having Military Specification MIL-L-46152E and MIL-L-2104E approval. Do NOT use
                oils labeled as SG or CF-4 or CE only, as they could cause piston ring sticking or excessive valve train
                wear. Fleetrite Heavy Duty 30 Engine Oil is the preferred viscosity grade for 7.3 L diesel engines
                operating where the temperature will not be colder than +3O&#176; F (-1&#176; C). When temperatures are
                expected to consistently remain below +30&#176; F (-1&#176; C) and above 0&#176; F (-18&#176; C) before
                the next oil change interval, SAE 15W-40 should be used for improved oil flow and cold starting. Refer
                to Chart 1. Shaded areas in Chart 1 indicate the preferred oil for the expected temperature range. CD
                engine oils should only be used when CF-4 or CE oils are NOT available in viscosity grades such as ,
                5W-30 and 10W-30, which are required for low temperature engine operation.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>ADD ONE (1) EXTRA QUART OF OIL IF OIL COOLER WAS REMOVED OR DRAINED OF OIL.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>CHANGE THE ENGINE OIL AND FILTER EVERY 6000 MILES (9656 KM), 200 HOURS OR 2 MONTHS, WHICHEVER
                        OCCURS FIRST.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350815" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg9893" filename="../figcg9/cg9893.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8.15</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <seqlist style="arabic">
                        <item>
                            <para>SAE 30 is the preferred viscosity grade for 7.3 liter diesel engines for all operating
                                conditions where the temperature will not be colder than +30&#176; F (-1&#176; C). Use
                                SAE 15W-40 when temperatures consistently remain below +3O&#176; F (-1&#176; C).
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Some increase in oil consumption may be expected when SAE OW-30, 5W-20, 5W-30, 10W,
                                and 10W-30 oils are used. Check oil level more frequently.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>SAE 5W-20 oils are NOT recommended for continuous, high speed operation.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not use the low viscosity oils (SAE 10W, 5W-20, 5W-30 and OW-30) when the
                                temperature is consistently above +50&#176; F (+10&#176; C), as higher engine wear and
                                engine damage may occur.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Start the engine and check for leaks, correct as necessary. Shut engine down and
                                recheck oil level. Add oil (if needed) or drain oil (if needed to bring oil level to
                                "FULL" mark on oil level gauge.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not "overfill" past the full mark.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_159.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_161.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
