<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - CRANKCASE
        (Reconditioning) - INSPECTION AND REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="9">
        <title>INSPECTION AND REPAIR</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect crankcase, after cleaning, for scoring, roughness or wear at the cylinder
                bores. Also check for cracks or water leaks.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check for cracks using a spray dye penetrant method of crack detection. (A 3 step method:
                cleaner, dye and developer).
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Replace the crankcase if cracked; do not attempt to weld.</para>
                <figure id="ef4350640" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11220" filename="../figcg1/CG11220.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.40</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the top surface of the crankcase for flatness. Using a straightedge, check by
                attempting to insert a.003 in. feeler gauge ribbon between the straightedge and crankcase head surface.
                <emph type="bold">IF THIS IS POSSIBLE, REPLACE THE CRANKCASE.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check cylinder bore out-of-round and taper using an accurate dial bore gauge as shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350641">6.41</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the diameter of the cylinder bore at the top of the piston ring travel at a right
                angle "
                <emph type="bold">A", Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350642">6.42</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                to the centerline of the crankshaft. Record the readings. Next, measure each bore so the gauge reading
                coincides with the centerline
                <emph type="bold">"B", Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350642">6.42</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                of the crankshaft. Record that reading. The difference between
                <emph type="bold">"A"</emph>
                and
                <emph type="bold">"B"</emph>
                is the out-of-round condition at the top of the cylinder bore. Repeat the same procedure at the bottom
                of the ring travel to check for out-of-round condition. (See
                <hotlnk document="e435_99.xml" xrefid="hl4350601">"SPECIFICATIONS".</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the reading recorded in step 5, determine the taper of the bore by determining the
                difference between the diameters measured at the "top" and "bottom" of the bore as shown in the
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350643">6.43</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                . (See
                <hotlnk document="e435_99.xml" xrefid="hl4350601">"SPECIFICATIONS".</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To determine taper, use measurements made at right angles to the centerline of the
                        crankshaft.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the cylinder bore is within the specifications, use new standard size pistons and rings.
                Refer to Section 5.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refinish cylinders that are deeply scored and/or when out-of-round and/or taper exceeds
                        specifications.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If cylinder walls have minor surface damage, but out-of-round and taper are within limits, it may be
                possible to remove such damage by honing cylinder walls and installing new service pistons, providing
                piston clearance is within specified limits. Refer to Section 5.
            </para>
            <para>If cylinder bore is suitable for use without reconditioning, deglaze the bore using glaze breaker
                brush then reassemble.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>IF THE CYLINDER BORES ARE TO BE DEGLAZED, THE PISTON COOLING JET TUBES MUST BE REMOVED.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350641" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11133" filename="../figcg1/CG11133.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.41</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350642" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11091" filename="../figcg1/CG11091.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.42</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350643" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11092" filename="../figcg1/CG11092.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.43</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <title>Deglazing</title>
            </para>
            <para>Cylinder bore can be deglazed using a 120 grit (no color code) glaze breaker brush such as the BRM
                Flex Honer (see Note) GBD4-1/8. (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350644">6.44</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Order the BRM Flex Honer GBD4-1/8 directly from:</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Brush Research Manufacturing Co., Inc.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">4642 East Floral Drive</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Los Angeles, CA 90022</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">(213)261-2193</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This Silicone carbide-tipped nylon flexible brush quickly deglazes cylinder walls and produces a
                crosshatch pattern on the cylinder wall surface in a single operation. The brush contours itself to the
                cylinder wall and conditions the wall surface without altering the cylinder bore.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is
                <emph type="underscr"></emph>
                <emph type="underscr">NOT</emph>
                necessary to remove the crankshaft prior to deglazing the cylinder walls; however, it is good practice
                to insert a hose of suitable length and diameter over the BRM Flex Honer shaft to protect the crankshaft
                (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350644">6.44</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is good practice to rotate the crankshaft, prior to deglazing, so the journal is at its
                        lowest point in the bore.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Obtain a 12 oz. can of PE-12 "Solvent and Penetrating Fluid" manufactured by AGS, available
                at any well-stocked auto supply house. This spray contains colloidal graphite and has a black
                appearance. Spray both the cylinder to be deglazed and the flex hone.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deglaze the cylinder as follows: (Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350645">6.45</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                )
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach the flex hone to an electric or air powered drill
                    <emph type="bold">WITH ADJUSTABLE SPEED.</emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>A SPEED OF APPROXIMATELY 100-200 RPM IS REQUIRED. SPEED ADJUSTMENT IS REQUIRED FOR THE
                            PROCEDURE TO BE SUCCESSFUL.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Hone the cylinder wall for about 3 seconds while stroking up and down at a rate of one
                    up and down stroke per second.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4350644" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg12427" filename="../figcg1/CG12427.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.44</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4350645" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg8821" filename="../figcg8/CG8821.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.45</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Withdraw the flex hone from the cylinder bore while the hone is rotating. Wipe a portion
                    of the cylinder wall and visually inspect the crosshatch pattern comparing it to an untouched
                    cylinder bore (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350646">6.46</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The crosshatch pattern should be approximately 45&#176;. Visual comparison with a "virgin"
                            bore is best, provided the engine has not been previously repaired.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the pattern is "flatter" than required, increase the up and down stroke speed or slow
                    down the drill rotation.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Continue deglazing the cylinder bore (after adjusting your technique) for an additional
                    10-15 seconds (approximately 20-25 strokes).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>DURING THE DEGLAZING, AN ASSISTANT MUST CONTINUALLY SPRAY THE PE-12 "SOLVENT AND
                            PENETRATING FLUID" BY AGS, ONTO THE CYLINDER WALL.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wipe the cylinder bore clean and once again visually inspect the bore for the proper 45&#176;
                    crosshatch pattern (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350646">6.46</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After deglazing, thoroughly clean the cylinder bores using soap and water, dry with filtered
                compressed air and re-oil using clean engine oil.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <title>Reboring Cylinder Bore</title>
            </para>
            <para>However, if the wear exceeds the taper and out-of-round limits, it is recommended to rebore the
                cylinder or cylinders to within 0.003 in. of the required oversize diameter,
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350647">6.47</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                . This will allow enough stock for the final step of honing the bores,
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350648">6.48</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                , so that the exact clearance may be obtained for the selected oversize piston. When performing the
                honing operation, the hone should be stroked up and down to produce a crosshatch pattern on the cylinder
                wall as shown in
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350646">6.46</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                . The faster the hone rotates, the faster it must be stroked up and down to produce the desired
                crosshatch pattern.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>PISTON COOLING JET TUBES MUST BE REMOVED FOR REBORING AND HONING OPERATIONS.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4350646" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg5370" filename="../figcg5/CG5370.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.46</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350647" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg8820" filename="../figcg8/CG8820.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.47</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef4350648" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg8822" filename="../figcg8/CG8822.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.48</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After the honing operation is completed, the sharp burred edge that develops at the top and
                        bottom of a newly honed cylinder should be removed manually with emery cloth. Then thoroughly
                        clean the block and cylinder bores.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the honing operation is completed, thoroughly clean the cylinder bores using soap and
                water. Dry with filtered compressed air and re-oil using clean engine oil.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Failure to properly clean the cylinder bores can result in rapid engine wear and piston ring
                        failure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <title>Expansion Plugs</title>
            </para>
            <para>It it becomes necessary to remove an expansion plug due to water leaks, drill a 1/2 in. hole in the
                center of the plug and remove by prying with a small pry bar.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the new expansion plugs with the concave side toward the engine. Coat the edges of
                the plug with Aviation Permatext No. 3. Use expansion plug replacer
                <emph type="bold">ZTSE4155A</emph>
                which consists of a driver and driver sleeve which accurately indents the expansion plugs upon striking
                with a hammer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>With crankcase disassembled, inspect the camshaft bushings and service as described in Section
                        4.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_122.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_124.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
