<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INTRODUCTION - SOLID STATE GLOW PLUG SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SOLID STATE GLOW PLUG SYSTEM</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef435IN20">i.20</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            .
        </para>
        <para>The 7.3 Liter Diesel Engine is equipped with a "solid state" glow plug system. The "solid state" system
            consists of a glow plug controller assembly, glow plug harness assembly and positive temperature coefficient
            (PTC) glow plugs.
        </para>
        <para>The "solid state" system determines the glow plug temperature by electronically measuring the resistance
            of the glow plugs and maintains the temperature regardless of ambient conditions. The system is actuated
            when the ignition switch is turned on. A "wait to start" light indicates when the glow plugs have reached
            proper temperature by going out. An after glow operation of the glow plugs continues after the "wait to
            start" light has been turned off. This cyclic operation of the glow plugs provides for reduced white start
            up smoke. The after glow can be determined by listening to the relay operation.
        </para>
        <para>A special feature of the "solid state" glow plug system is its instant recycling ability. If the switch is
            turned off, the operator can immediately recycle the system by turning the ignition switch on which will
            start the reheat cycle of the glow plugs and the "wait to start" light will come on. Engine cranking can
            begin as soon as the "wait to start" light goes out.
        </para>
        <para>The power relay is mounted above the controller which contains the circuit board and the entire unit is
            covered by a plastic protective cover. The cover prevents accidental contact of the large resistor or relay
            parts during the operation of the system. If batteries are low, jump starting must be accomplished by
            connecting to the normal battery terminals, not the power relay.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>DO NOT JUMP START BY CONNECTING POWER LEADS TO THE CONTROLLER MOUNTED RELAY. DOING SO WILL RESULT
                    IN GLOW PLUG FAILURE.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="ef435IN20" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg15010" filename="../figcg1/cg15010.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure i.20 Solid State Glow Plug Wiring Diagram.</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
