<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - CRANKCASE
        (Reconditioning)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CRANKCASE (Reconditioning)</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>THROUGHLY CLEAN AND INSPECT THE CRANKCASE BEFORE AND AFTER RECONDITIONING.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CLEANING</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all old gasket material from the machined surfaces of the crankcase, using a
                    scraper. Clean the cylinder bore using soap, water and a nylon brush.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the pipe plugs (located in the rear of the crankcase) which seal the oil passages
                    and thoroughly clean all passages and bolt holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the main oil gallery plug and use a nylon brush (3/8 in. dia.) to clean the main
                    oil gallery,
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk document="e435_123.xml" xrefid="ef4350640">6.40</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . Replace oil plug after coating with Aviation Permatext No. 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the valve lifter oil gallery plugs (located in the front of the crankcase) by
                    drilling a small hole in the plug and prying with a screwdriver. Clean the valve lifter oil
                    galleries with a nylon brush (5/16 in. dia.). Replace the valve lifter gallery plugs flush to 9.060
                    in. (1.52 mm) below the crankcase surface, then stake.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use Aviation Permatext No. 3 prior. to installing the main and valve lifter oil gallery
                            plugs.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>THREADS IN CRANKCASE BOLT HOLES MUST BE CLEAN AND BLOWN DRY WITH FILTERED COMPRESSED AIR.
                            DIRT OR OIL IN HOLES MAY CAUSE BINDING AND/OR FALSE TORQUE READING DURING REASSEMBLY.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_121.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_123.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
