<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - CRANKSHAFT
        (Reconditioning) - CRANKSHAFT UNDERSIZE GRINDING LIMITS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRANKSHAFT UNDERSIZE GRINDING LIMITS</title>
        <para>Grinding Limits:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Maximum allowable taper on crankpins (rod journals) and main journals 0.00015 per inch of
                length (.013 mm per 25.4 mm) of length. Crankpins and journals must be polished to 20 Micro-inch maximum
                - to 5 Micro-inch minimum, and must not be over 0.0003 inch (0.003 mm) out of round.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The main journal fillet radii should be 0.121- 0.127 in. (3.07 - 3.226 mm) with the
                crankpins (rod journals) fillet radii held at 0.120 in. (3.05 mm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The third main journal controls crankshaft end thrust and provides initial location of
                crankshaft in relation to crankcase. For this reason the width of the third journal must be 1.1325 -
                1.1355 in. (28.765 - 28.842 mm).
            </para>
            <table id="et4350605">
                <title>GRINDING LIMITS CHART</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="119p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="213p"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>PRODUCTION SIZE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Main Journal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>3.1228-3.1236 in. (79.319-79.340 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Crankpin (rod journal)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>2.498-2.499 in. (63.45-63.47 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>0.10 INCH UNDERSIZE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Main Journal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>3.1128-3.1136 in. (79.065-79.085 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Crankpin (rod journal)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>2.488-2.489 in. (63.20-63.22 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>0.20 INCH UNDERSIZE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Main Journal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>3.1028-3.1036 in. (78.811-78.831 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Crankpin (rod journal)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>2.476-2.478 in. (62.94-62.87 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>0.30 INCH UNDERSIZE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Main Journal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>3.0928-3.0936 in. (78.557-78.577 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Crankpin (rod journal)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>2.468-2.469 in. (62.69-62.71 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TARASOV ETCH:</emph>
                In order to establish the acceptability of a regrind procedure, equipment and operator, the first
                reground crankshafts should be etched before lapping to determine whether the crankshaft was burned
                during the regrinding cycle. The best etch to use is the Tarasov etch, which will show both the
                rehardened and the over-tempered areas. The etching procedure is as follows:
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>due to the sharp odor and flammability of the tarasov etch, the etching should be done in a
                        well ventilated area, away from any open flame.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean surface with a scouring powder and water or a good solvent.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Wash thoroughly and rinse with alcohol.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply etchant No. 1 (4 parts nitric acid in 96 parts water) for approximately 16 seconds
                    with a cotton swab.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Rinse with water and dry.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply etchant No. 2 (2 parts hydrochloric acid in 98 parts acetone) for approximately 15
                    seconds with a cotton swab.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>ACETONE IS HIGHLY FLAMMABLE.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Rinse with alcohol and dry thoroughly with compressed air.</para>
                <para>If the crankshaft has been burned, it will show up as a change of color after the etch. Areas
                    rehardened by excessive heat appear nearly white, while softened areas turn dark gray or black.
                    Areas unaffected by the heat of grinding etch a light gray.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>IF ANY BURNS SHOW UP AFTER THE ETCH IS USED, THE PHYSICAL PROPERTIES OF THE CRANKSHAFT
                            WILL HAVE BEEN SERIOUSLY REDUCED, AND THE CRANKSHAFT
                            <emph type="underscr">SHOULD NOT BE USED</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If burning becomes a serious problem, it can usually be eliminated by reducing the infeed
                            rate, using a softer grade of wheel, or increasing the work spindle speed. Sometimes, a
                            combination of these factors, along with the recommendations mentioned above, will be
                            necessary to overcome the problem.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">After the crankshaft passes the Tarasov etch test, it may be lapped.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>THROUGHLY CLEAN THE CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES WITH A NYLON BRISTLE BRUSH, SOAP AND WATER TO
                            REMOVE ALL DEBRIS WHICH MAY HAVE ACCUMULATED DURING THE REGRINDING PROCEDURE. ANY DEBRIS
                            LEFT IN THE CRANKSHAFT OIL PASSAGES CANNOT BE REMOVED BY THE OIL FILTERS AND WILL DAMAGE
                            BEARINGS IMMEDIATELY UPON ENGINE START-UP. ONCE CLEANED, WRAP THE CRANKSHAFT, TO PROTECT IT
                            FROM CONTAMINATION, UNTIL IT IS INSTALLED.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>VISUALLY INSPECT THE SEAL SURFACE ON THE CRANKSHAFT FLANGE FOR NICKS, ETC. THE SEAL
                            WITNESS MARK (FIGURE
                            <hotlnk document="e435_115.xml" xrefid="ef4350631">6.31</hotlnk>) ON THE CRANKSHAFT FLANGE
                            SHOULD BE CONTINUOUS AND UNBROKEN. IF THE CONDITION OF THE FLANGE SURFACE IS QUESTIONABLE,
                            INSTALL THE OPTIONAL CRANKSHAFT WEAR SLEEVE AND REAR OIL SEAL PACKAGE (P/N 1 807 788 C92).
                            FOLLOW THE INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS INCLUDED WITH THE PACKAGE.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_112.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_114.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
