<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - MANUAL AND
        AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MANUAL AND AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="8">
            <title>INSTALLATION (REAR COVER ASSEMBLY AND FLYWHEEL)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If new ring gear is required, heat the new ring gear evenly until the gear expands
                    enough to slip onto the flywheel. Make sure the gear is sealed properly against the shoulder. Do not
                    heat any portion of the gear to a temperature higher than 500&#176; F (278&#176; C). If this limit
                    is exceeded, the hardness will be removed from the ring gear teeth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the rear cover with rear oil seal installed (as described earlier in this
                    section) as follows:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>SEAL PROTECTOR SHOWN IN FIGURE IS FOR STANDARD SIZE REAR OIL SEAL INSTALLATION. WHEN
                            INSTALLING OPTIONAL OVERSIZED REAR OIL SEAL, USE PROTECTOR INCLUDED IN WEAR SLEEVE PACKAGE
                            (P/N 1 807 788 C92). REFER TO INSTRUCTIONS INCLUDED WITH WEAR SLEEVE PACKAGE.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply a thin coat of Aviation Permatext #3 to crankcase cover gasket surface as
                        shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350650">6.50</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                        <emph type="bold"></emph>
                        Install rear cover gasket. Repeat above application of sealant on gasket.
                        <emph type="bold">DO NOT ALLOW PERMATEX TO GET ON CRANKSHAFT OIL SEAL FLANGE.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>DO NOT GET ANY AVIATION PERMATEX&#8482; #3 SEALANT ON THE SEAL LIP.</para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With appropriate seal protector installed over crankshaft flange to protect the seal
                        lip, coat the seal lip with a thin film of clean engine oil.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install rear cover and seal assembly over seal protector as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350651">6.51</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . Remove seal protector after rear cover and seal assembly installation. Tighten all bolts to
                        standard torque.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Apply an additional 1/4 in. bead of R.T.V. sealant in 2 places as shown in Figure
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350650">6.50</hotlnk>, prior to rear cover and seal installation.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4350650" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11108" filename="../figcg1/CG11108.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.50</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350651" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg9998" filename="../figcg9/CG9998.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.51</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Apply R.T.V. sealant (Dow 732 or GE Silmate 1473) to oil pan surface as follows:
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>If Oil Pan is Removed:</para>
                    <para>1/8 in. dia. bead for side rails as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk document="e435_130.xml" xrefid="ef4350663">6.63</hotlnk>.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>1/4 in. dia. bead for corners, front and rear ends as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk document="e435_130.xml" xrefid="ef4350663">6.63</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . Corners have double bead.
                    </para>
                    <para>If Oil Pan is Not Removed:</para>
                    <para>1/4 in. dia. bead for front corners as shown in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350650">6.50</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>ASSEMBLE PARTS WITHIN 10 MINUTES OF APPLICATION OF RTV COMPONENTS.</para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the rear cover and seal assembly in place check seal run-out as follows (
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350652">6.52</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    ):
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Position a magnetic base dial indicator on the end of the crankshaft flange.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the indicator against the rear surface of the seal body at the 12 o'clock
                        position. Remove crankshaft end play by pushing (or pulling) against the crankshaft and "zero"
                        the dial indicator.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Bar the engine over and take a reading at four (4) points, approximately 90&#176;
                        apart.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Crankshaft seal run-out should not exceed specified run-out.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>NEVER TAKE AN INDICATOR READING WITH THE INDICATOR PROBE RESTING ON LETTERS OR NUMBERS
                                WHICH APPEAR ON THE REAR SURFACE OF THE SEAL.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If rear crankshaft oil seal run-out exceeds specifications, adjust the seal as follows:
                    (Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure 6.56</emph>.) (Note location of seal which protrudes out the farthest.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">It is recommended that a pressing plate be fabricated as specified in
                        <emph type="bold">Figure 6.52</emph>
                        and used in conjunction with an SAE No. 16 woodruff key, 3/8 in. cap screw and washer as
                        follows:
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4350652" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg11224" filename="../figcg1/CG11224.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.52</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Install fabricated tool
                            <emph type="bold"></emph>(
                            <emph type="bold">Figure
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350653">6.53</hotlnk>
                            </emph>
                            ) using the 3/8 in. bolt and washer onto the crankshaft flange bolt hole nearest the seal
                            area which protrudes. Insert SAE No.16 woodruff key under the fabricated tool as shown in
                            <emph type="bold">Figure
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350654">6.54</hotlnk>
                            </emph>
                            .
                            <emph type="bold"></emph>
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Gently tighten the bolt against the seal to depress the area of the seal which exceeds the
                            run-out specification.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>After adjustment, measure rear crankshaft seal run-out to assure specified run-out.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Repeat if necessary.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the flywheel housing (if removed), using the six mounting bolts and hardened
                    washers. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350655">6.55</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    . Tighten to standard torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install flywheel as follows:</para>
                <para>
                    <title>Manual Transmissions:</title>Apply Lock N' Sealant (P/N 577 588 C1) to all nine mounting
                    bolts and tighten to specified torque.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <title>Automatic Transmissions:</title>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Engine Ser. No.s' 848 166 and Below:</emph>
                        If reinstalling original mounting bolts apply Lock N' Sealant (P/N 577 588 C1) to all nine
                        mounting bolts and tighten to specified torque.
                    </para>
                    <para>If new mounting bolts are being installed refer to Step b below.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">All Engines w/Automatic Transmissions:</emph>When installing new flywheel
                        mounting bolts for the first time, check mounting bolt thread color. Six to eight threads should
                        be silver color.
                    </para>
                    <para>This silver color is a pre-applied sealant and DOES NOT require the application of additional
                        sealant to the threads.
                    </para>
                    <para>However, each time mounting bolt is removed to service flywheel apply Lock N' Sealant (P/N 577
                        588 C1) to the clean bolt threads before reinstalling bolt and tighten to specified torque.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4350653" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg10519" filename="../figcg1/CG10519.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.53</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350654" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg9999" filename="../figcg9/CG9999.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.54</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350655" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12366" filename="../figcg1/CG12366.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.55</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the flywheel installed on the crankshaft, check flywheel face and ring gear run-out
                    as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">flywheel face run-out, install a dial indicator so the indicator point bears against
                        the flywheel face, one inch in from the edge of the flywheel,
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350656">6.56</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        . For checking ring gear run-out, install the dial indicator point on the face of the ring gear
                        adjacent to the gear teeth. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4350657">6.57</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Push flywheel forward prior to turning the flywheel, so crankshaft "end play" will
                        not be indicated as flywheel run-out.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Set the dial indicator to zero. Turn the flywheel one complete revolution while
                        observing the total indicator run-out (T.I.R.).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If flywheel face T.I.R. exceeds specifications, remove flywheel and check for burrs
                        between the flywheel and face of the crankshaft mounting flange. Remove burrs as required.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If no burrs exist, recheck the crankshaft flange run-out, using a dial indicator.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If run-out is excessive, replace the crankshaft.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the crankshaft flange run-out is within specifications, resurface (manual
                        transmission only) or replace the flywheel as required.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ring gear T.I.R. exceeds specifications, check ring gear installation. Reheat the
                        gear evenly until it expands enough to be properly seated on the flywheel shoulder.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Recheck run-out; if not within specifications, replace the flywheel and ring gear
                        assembly.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Flywheel housing pilot bore concentricity and flywheel housing face run-out should be
                                checked to ensure proper engine to transmission alignment.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="ef4350656" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12369" filename="../figcg1/CG12369.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.56</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4350657" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12370" filename="../figcg1/CG12370.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.57</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check flywheel housing bore concentricity as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach a magnetic base dial indicator to the flywheel and place the indicator tip
                        against the flywheel housing pilot bore. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk document="e435_128.xml" xrefid="ef4350658">6.58</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">"Zero" the dial indicator.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the crankshaft slowly and record the total indicator variation. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="e435_99.xml" xrefid="hl4350601">"SPECIFICATIONS".</hotlnk>
                        for housing bore concentricity tolerance.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check flywheel housing face run-out as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach a dial indicator to the flywheel and place the indicator tip against the
                        flywheel housing face. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk document="e435_128.xml" xrefid="ef4350659">6.59</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure at four points, 90&#176; apart, for total face variation.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>"ZERO" THE CRANKSHAFT END PLAY BY PUSHING THE CRANKSHAFT IN THE SAME DIRECTION FOR ALL
                                MEASUREMENTS.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engines with automatic transmissions must have the reinforcement ring and flex plate
                    installed after the flywheel passes inspection.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_126.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_128.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
