<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - VALVE TRAIN: CAMSHAFT, HYDRAULIC VALVE LIFTERS AND PUSH RODS -
        HYDRAULIC VALVE LIFTER ROLLER TYPE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>HYDRAULIC VALVE LIFTER ROLLER TYPE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>Oil from oil gallery, is supplied to the lifter through a hole in the side of the lifter body which
                indexes with a groove and hole in the lifter plunger. Oil is then metered past the oil metering valve in
                the lifter, through the push-rods to the rocker arms.
            </para>
            <para>When the lifter begins to roll up the cam lobe, the check valve is held against its seat in the
                plunger by the check valve spring which traps the oil in the base of the lifter body below the plunger.
                The plunger and lifter body then raise as a unit, pushing up the push-rod to open the valve. The force
                of the valve spring which is exerted on the plunger through the rocker arm and push-rod causes a slight
                amount of leakage between the plunger and lifter body. This "leak-down" allows a slow escape of trapped
                oil in the base of the lifter body. As the lifter rides down the other side of the cam lobe and reaches
                the base circle or "valve closed" position, the plunger spring quickly moves the plunger back (up) to
                its original position. This movement causes the check valve to open against the check valve spring and
                oil from which the plunger is drawn into the base of the lifter. This restores the lifter to zero lash (
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e435_65.xml" xrefid="ef4350402">4.2</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Valve lifters and push rods should be kept in order so they can be re-installed in their
                        original position. Good oil quality and following the recommended oil drain intervals are the
                        key to long valve train life.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_63.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_65.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
