<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - INTRODUCTION - FUEL SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>FUEL SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
            <title>U-HAUL Applications Only</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef435IN17">i.17</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
            <para>Fuel from the tank is routed to the fuel supply pump which pumps fuel through a combination fuel
                filter, heater and water separator. The filter header contains a continuous vent (orifice bleed off
                system) which aids starting by eliminating the need to manually prime the fuel filter. A vacuum switch
                is incorporated into the fuel filter header indicating the need for filter replacement. The water
                separator portion of the filter assembly has a probe which will activate a instrument panel light when
                the filter requires draining at the water and sediment drain located on the bottom of the assembly.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Properly filtered diesel fuel cannot be over emphasized. It is essential for long component
                        life and reliability.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>DO NOT USE SUBSTITUTE FUEL FILTER ELEMENTS. USE ONLY AN APPROVED INTERNATIONAL&#174; FILTER.
                        REFER TO THE PARTS CATALOG WHEN ORDERING.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Fuel enters the inlet of the injection pump and is delivered under high pressure through injection
                nozzles into the engine cylinders for combustion.
            </para>
            <para>On each nozzle is a fuel return fitting that returns excess fuel to the fuel tank. Excess fuel from
                the injection pump and each injection nozzle is collected in bleed off lines and returned to the fuel
                tank.
            </para>
            <para>Injection nozzles are located on the inboard side of the cylinder head. This configuration has the
                following advantages:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Injection nozzles operate in a cooler environment far removed from the exhaust manifold
                    and exhaust ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Injection lines do
                    <emph type="bold">NOT</emph>
                    interfere with engine accessories and provide better access to the engine for servicing.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef435IN17" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11974" filename="../figcg1/CG11974.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure i.17 Fuel Flow Schematic U-Haul Application Only.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
