<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Service (1991) - CRANKSHAFT, MAIN BEARINGS, FLYWHEEL AND CRANKCASE - FRONT COVER,
        DAMPER AND OIL PAN Installation - PRIME LUBRICATING SYSTEM:
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PRIME LUBRICATING SYSTEM:</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When assembling the engine during over-haul, it is important to prelubricate the running
                parts with clean engine oil to assure initial lubrication when the engine is started.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To further assure complete initial lubrication, the engine lubricating system should be
                pressure primed or charged with oil. Priming the lubricating system will minimize the possibility of
                scuffing or heat build-up during initial engine operation which could lead to immediate or low mileage
                failure. After priming, check engine oil level and adjust (fill or drain) as needed before starting
                engine,
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>New or overhauled engines which have been in storage should be primed at installation.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Refer to Section 8, "LUBRICATING OIL PUMP, OIL COOLER AND FILTER" for oil quality and viscosity
                    recommendations, as well as oil fill capacity.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate the engine and check for leaks, correct as necessary. Shut engine down and recheck
                oil level. Add oil (if needed) or drain oil (if needed) to bring oil level to "full" mark on oil level
                gauge.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not "overfill" past the full mark.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_130.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435_132.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e435.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
