<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS -
        CREATIVE TOOL MODEL CT-4000 DIESEL TIMING AND TACHOMETER INSTRUMENT [SE-2783] OR [3005A] CURRENT MODEL -
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The diesel timing and tachometer instrument
                <emph type="bold">(Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500407">4.6</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                is a solid state electronic instrument used to dynamically measure fuel injection pump timing and
                automatic advance in degrees. This instrument also reads engine RPM from cranking to high idle speeds.
                The 14 mm Split-Nut Transducer No. CT-4000-13 is used for DT/DTI-466 A and B Series Diesel Engines with
                UTDS Model 100 Pumps. The 14 mm In-Line Transducer No. CT-4000-5 is used for the DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel
                Engines with Robert Bosch MW Pumps.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4500407" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg7359" filename="../figcg7/cg7359.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.6 Diesel Timing and Tachometer Instrument (SE-2783 or 3005A)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>KEYBOARD DESCRIPTION</title>
            <figure id="ef4500408" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg7358" filename="../figcg7/cg7358.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.7 Control Keyboard (SE-2783)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The following is a description of SE-2783's or 3005A's Control Keyboard.
                <emph type="bold">(Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500408">4.7</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                From this keyboard, each function of SE-2783 or 3005A can be selected. ONCE A KEY HAS BEEN DEPRESSED, IT
                MAY BE RELEASED. With the possible exception of the "&#8595;" and "&#8593;" keys, it is not necessary to
                hold the key depressed. SE-2783 or 3005A reacts as soon as the key is depressed, and remains in that
                mode until another key has been depressed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"RST"</title>
            <para>The Reset Key will place the SE-2783 or 3005A in the "power-up" mode. Often times when an engine is
                cranked, the battery voltage will drop below the 9 volt minimum required to operate the SE-2783 or
                3005A. To place the instrument into proper operation after this has happened, release and depress the
                <emph type="bold">"RST"</emph>
                Key.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The "RST" key is a latching key and will remain down until depressed again -- to release it.
                        The key must be depressed when the instrument is in operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"2 CYC"</title>
            <para>This key is a latching key used on 2 cycle engines. It should be depressed for 2 cycle engines and
                released for 4 cycle engines.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"TST"</title>
            <para>This test key has two functions. Each time the SE-2783 or 3005A is connected to a power source, this
                key MUST be depressed before any other function can be selected. This places the SE-2783 or 3005A in an
                operational mode.
            </para>
            <para>Additionally, each time
                <emph type="bold">"TST"</emph>
                is depressed, the SE-2783 or 3005A checks to see if a signal is being received from the transducer. If a
                signal is being received"8888" appears in the lighted display. If the display shows " -----" a problem
                exists.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"RPM"</title>
            <para>This key, when depressed, places the SE-2783 or 3005A in the "RPM" mode. Engine speed will be
                displayed on the digital readout.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"ADV"</title>
            <para>This key, when depressed, places the SE-2783 or 3005A in the "ADVANCE" mode so injection timing can be
                easily measured as described in the OPERATING PROCEDURES section. Robert Bosh MW and A-Model pumps have
                no advance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"STB ON"</title>
            <para>This key operates the remote strobe light unit. To turn on the strobe light, depress "STB ON" key. To
                turn the light off, depress and release the key. The timing light can be turned on whether in "RPM" or
                "ADV" mode of operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"&#8593;"</title>
            <para>This key "&#8593;" functions during the "ADV" mode. In the "ADVANCE" mode, it will increase or
                increment the advance angle by one if it is depressed and released quickly. If it is depressed and held
                for greater than one-half second, the advance angle will be incremented by one; then at the end of
                one-half second, it will begin to slew or increase at a rate of four degrees per second for as long as
                the key is depressed. When the key is released, the display shows the accumulated advance angle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"&#8595;"</title>
            <para>This key "&#8595;" is identical to the "&#8593;" key in operation, but when depressed, it decreases or
                decrements the display in the same manner as the "&#8593;" increased it.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It will not go below 0 in the "ADV" mode.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
