<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST
        PROCEDURES - DT/DTI/DTA - 466 C SERIES DIESEL ENGINES - TEST INJECTION NOZZLES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TEST INJECTION NOZZLES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
            <title>DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Engines (With Robert Bosch "MW" or "A" Fuel Injection Pump)</title>
            <table id="t4500614">
                <title>FROM FORM NO. CGED-365-*</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="36p"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="115p"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="101p"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="130p"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="58p"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="72p"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="2" nameend="6" spanname="S2T6"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>TEST INJECTION NOZZLES</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>13</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="S2T6">
                                <para>A. SPRAY CONDITION.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="S2T6">
                                <para>B. VALVE OPENING PRESSURE</para>
                                <para>C. LEAKAGE.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>INSTRUMENT GUIDELINE DATA 1 st Check 2 nd Check</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>HAND TEST PUMP</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>(NOZZLE TESTER)</para>
                                <para>(ZTSE-4045)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Refer to "Performance Data Guidelines" in this section.</para>
            <para>This is a functional test of injection nozzle performance. Nozzles must be removed from the engine and
                tested for SPRAY CONDITION, VALVE OPENING PRESSURE and LEAKAGE.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If proper tools and facilities are not available to test or repair nozzles, and nozzles are
                        the suspected problem; replace all nozzles with new or ReNEWed nozzles.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>IN OUTLINING THE PROCEDURE FOR INSPECTION OF INJECTION NOZZLES, THE NECESSITY OF CLEANLINESS
                        CANNOT BE OVER-EMPHASIZED. A CLEAN WORKBENCH, CLEAN WASHING FLUID AND CLEAN TOOLS ARE ALL
                        ESSENTIAL TO PRODUCE SATISFACTORY RESULTS. THE USE OF SUITABLE TOOLS FOR THIS TYPE OF WORK IS
                        EQUALLY IMPORTANT.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Injection Nozzle Removal:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean the top of the engine to prevent dirt from entering any openings.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Detach high-pressure tubing and leak-off lines, covering their opening ends with
                        plastic caps to protect against the entrance of dirt.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove mounting (crab) bolt and clamp. Pull nozzle assembly from the cylinder head,
                        being careful not to strike the end of the nozzle against any hard surface. If the assembly
                        seems to be stuck, break it loose from carbon deposits to facilitate removal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Cover nozzle openings with protector caps to prevent the entrance of dirt. Also
                        protect nozzle tip with protective caps.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove injection nozzle gasket from nozzle bore with a suitable tool and discard.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Injection Nozzle Testing:</para>
                <para>The prime requirements for a satisfactory nozzle assembly are: pressure tight seats; no excessive
                    valve stem leakage; satisfactory spray and atomization characteristics.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">After removal from engine, test nozzles for spray condition, opening pressure and
                        leakage on a hand test pump ZTSE-4045.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500648">6.48</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        shows an injection nozzle mounted for testing on the hand test pump.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>IT IS ADVISABLE TO TEST NOZZLES BEFORE CLEANING THEM. AFTER TESTING, PLACE NOZZLES IN
                                A COLD DECARBONIZING SOLUTION FOR AT LEAST ONE HOUR. AFTER REMOVING NOZZLES FROM
                                SOLUTION, WASH OFF THE OUTSIDE SURFACES.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">* - Form specified with latest revision.</emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Prepare pump for making tests. Fill pump reservoir with Viscor 1487AW (SAE J967D)
                        calibration fluid. Open pump valve slightly and operate pump handle to expel air from pump and
                        outlet pipe. Operate pump until solid fluid (without air bubbles) flows from end of outlet pipe.
                        Close pump valve.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect injection nozzle to test pump. Avoid "cross-threading." Tighten connector
                        nut securely with open end wrench.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The gauge valve should be closed. Failure to close the gauge valve will lead to a
                                damaged gauge. The gauge valve should only be opened to check opening pressure and tip
                                leakage. A residual pressure should always be left in the pressure gauge.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Bleed air from the nozzle. Open the pump valve and operate the pump for several
                        quick strokes to expel (bleed) air from the injection nozzle. Fluid should discharge from the
                        holes in the nozzle tip.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4500648" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg7829" filename="../figcg7/cg7829.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.48 Typical Nozzle Assembly Mounted in the Hand Test Pump</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>KEEP HANDS AWAY FROM NOZZLE SPRAY. FLUID SPRAYING FROM THE NOZZLE UNDER HIGH PRESSURE
                                CAN PENETRATE THE SKIN AND CAUSE INFECTION. MEDICAL ATTENTION SHOULD BE PROVIDED
                                IMMEDIATELY IN THE EVENT OF SKIN PENETRATION.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">OBSERVE THE DISCHARGE PATTERN. Operate the test pump in smooth, even strokes and
                        observe the pattern of fluid discharging from the four (4) nozzle tip discharge holes. The
                        discharge should be well atomized in an even pattern, free from solid streams and dribbling.
                        <emph type="bold">Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500649">6.49</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CHECK NOZZLE OPENING PRESSURE. Open the gauge valve, operate the test pump in slow,
                        smooth, even strokes and observe gauge pressure to determine pressure at which nozzle opens
                        (discharges fluid). The nozzle should operate within the specified opening pressure range.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4500649" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg10855" filename="../figcg1/cg10855.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.49 Acceptable Nozzle Discharge</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>SPECIFIED VALVE OPENING</para>
                    <para>PRESSURE CHART</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">400 Series On-Highway and OEM Robert Bosch MW and A Pumps</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>New or Rebuilt.....................3675 psi &#177; 75 psi</para>
                    <para>...............................(25,337 kPa &#177; 517 kPa)</para>
                    <para>Minimum Permissible.........................2900 psi</para>
                    <para>(Used)....................................(20,000 kPa)</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CHECK FOR TIP LEAKAGE. Blow nozzle tip dry using filtered compressed air.Operate
                        test pump to maintain pressure at about 500 psi (3447 kPa) below opening pressure. Nozzle tip
                        should remain dry without an accumulation of fluid drops at spray holes. A slight wetting after
                        about 5 seconds is permissible if no droplets are formed.
                        <emph type="bold">Refer to Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500650">6.50</hotlnk>.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>DO NOT WIPE TIP WITH FINGERS AS THIS WILL TEND TO DRAW THE FLUID PRESENT IN THE SAC
                                HOLE THROUGH THE ORIFICES AND FALSELY INDICATE A LEAK AND REJECTION OF A GOOD VALVE.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CHECK FUEL LEAK-OFF. Operate test pump in quick strokes and observe for flow of
                        fluid from leak-off part of nozzle. A very slight leak-off is normal. If an excessive amount of
                        fluid is expelled or if fluid surges from leak-off port when test pump is operated, nozzle is
                        faulty.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4500650" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg10857" filename="../figcg1/cg10857.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.50 Unacceptable Nozzle Tip Leakage</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>If nozzle passes above tests, it is suitable for further service in the engine following
                        cleaning and removal of accumulated carbon. Nozzles showing irregular spray pattern, leakage at
                        nozzle tip spray holes, excessive fluid leak-off or opening pressure below minimum permissible
                        limit should be replaced or serviced (disassembled, cleaned and rebuilt).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Injection Nozzle Installation:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Thoroughly clean nozzle bore in cylinder head before reinserting nozzle holder
                        assembly. Pay particular attention to seating surfaces, in order that no small particles or
                        carbon will cause assembly to be cocked or permit blow-by of combustion gases. Don't use hard or
                        sharp tools for cleaning. A round piece of brass properly shaped or a round steel bristle brush
                        is permitted if used with care.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install nozzle assemblies with copper gasket, carefully held in place with a dab of
                        grease, into its bore.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Make sure old nozzle gasket is not left in bore.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the nozzle crab bolts to 20 lbf-ft. (27N.m).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect the fuel supply and return lines to the nozzles. Tighten the fuel supply
                        line fittings to 30 lbf-ft. (41 N.m).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Operate engine and check for fuel or combustion gas leakage.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_137.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_139.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
