<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST
        PROCEDURES - DT/DTI/DTA - 466 C SERIES DIESEL ENGINES - SHUTOFF CABLE/ELECTRIC SHUTOFF DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Engines
        (With Robert Bosch "MW" or "A" Fuel Injection Pump) - II. INTERNALLY SWITCHED ELECTRIC SHUTOFF (AUTOMATIC
        SHUTOFF) - PRIOR TO 1989 M0DEL YEAR
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>II. INTERNALLY SWITCHED ELECTRIC SHUTOFF (AUTOMATIC SHUTOFF) -
            <emph type="bold">PRIOR TO 1989 M0DEL YEAR</emph>
        </title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">PROBLEM: ENGINE WILL CRANK, BUT WILL NOT START.</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>PLACE THE TRANSMISSION IN NEUTRAL WITH THE PARKING BRAKE ENGAGED.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>VERIFY THE ELECTRIC SHUTOFF IS INOPERABLE AS FOLLOWS: VISUALLY OBSERVE SHUTOFF LEVER (1, F1GURE
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500621">6.21</hotlnk>) AND TURN THE IGNITION SWITCH TO THE "IGNITION" POSITION.
                    THE SHUTOFF LEVER SHOULD ROTATE COUNTERCLOCKWISE (CCW) AS THE SOLENOID PLUNGER "PULLS IN". IF THIS
                    DOES NOT OCCUR, TURN THE IGNITION SWITCH TO THE "START" POSITION. IF THE PLUNGER STILL HAS NOT
                    "PULLED IN", DETERMINE THE CAUSE AND CORRECT AS FOLLOWS:
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fuse - Inspect the electric shutoff fuse. If burned out, replace.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">12 Volt Supply - Check for 12 volts between the positive and negative terminals of the
                solenoid mating connector with the fuse in place.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Turn the key switch to the "ignition" position. The minimum voltage required for the solenoid topull in is
            9 volts.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>DO NOT "JUMP" OR BYPASS THE FUSE. DO NOT ALLOW VOLTMETER NEGATIVE TEST LEAD TO SHORT BETWEEN THE
                    (-) NEGATIVE AND SMALLER "AUX" TERMINAL ON THE SOLENOID. IF THIS OCCURS, FUSE OR SOLENOID FAILURE
                    MAY RESULT. (SEE FIGURE
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500621">6.21</hotlnk>
                    FOR TERMINAL LOCATION).
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>"AUX" terminal is present only on early model solenoids used on "MW" pumps.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>IF VOLTAGE AVAILABLE TO SOLENOID IS UNDER 12 V DC, CHECK BATTERY CONDITION, WIRING AND
                    CONNECTIONS, IGNITION SWITCH AND ELECTRIC SHUTOFF RELAY (IF APPLICABLE). REPLACE ANY STAR TYPE
                    LOCKWASHERS FOUND ON SOLENOID TERMINALS WITH SPLIT TYPE LOCKWASHERS.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rubber Boot - The rubber boot seals the core from dirt and moisture.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>Verify that the boot is firmly attached to the sole noid body.</para>
        <para>Replace any solenoid which has a torn boot.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The boot should be free of paint. Paint will cause the boot to become soft and catch between the
                    spring and plunger. This will prevent the plunger from seating properly. The boot should also have a
                    small breather hole in the second pleat from the base of the solenoid.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Solenoid Worn - Inspect as follows:</para>
        </step1>
        <para>Inspect for evidence of dust, dirt, brass powder, or blackened deposits on the plunger or in the solenoid
            core.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If evidence of a worn solenoid is found, as described above, solenoid condition is marginal and
                    may not "pull in" quickly or consistently.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure resistance (ohms) across the positive and negative terminals of the solenoid as
                follows: (Refer to the Internal Switch Description and
                <emph type="bold">Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500622">6.23</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Be sure the ignition switch is off. Disconnect the power supply to the solenoid. Remove the plunger and
            connect an ohm meter to the (+) positive and (-) negative terminals
            <emph type="bold">(Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500623">6.22</hotlnk>).
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>With the plunger removed, .16 to .23 ohms resistance should be observed.</para>
        <para>Using a wooden dowel rod, depress the switch button in the bottom of the solenoid core. (This simulates
            the plunger in position). 11.6 to 16.5 ohms resistance should be observed.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef4500621" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg9840" filename="../figcg9/CG9840.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 6.21 Internally Switched Electric Shutoff Solenoid (Installed View on Robert Bosch "MW"
                Pump)
            </caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. ShutOff Lever</callout1>
                <callout1>2. Ball Joint</callout1>
                <callout1>3. Locknut</callout1>
                <callout1>4. Adjusting Rod</callout1>
                <callout1>5. Solenoid Plunger</callout1>
                <callout1>6. Rubber Boot (Surrounds Return Spring and Plunger)</callout1>
                <callout1>7. Solenoid Core With Housing</callout1>
                <callout1>8. Negative Terminal</callout1>
                <callout1>9. Auxiliary Connection* (Not Used)</callout1>
                <callout1>10. Positive Terminal</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">*-"AUX" terminal is present only on early model solenoids.</emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="ef4500623" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg9838" filename="../figcg9/CG9838.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 6.22 Solenoid Resistance Check</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>INTERNAL SWITCH DESCRIPTION
            <emph type="bold">(Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500622">6.23</hotlnk>.)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>The solenoid contains a built-in switch that is activated when the plunger nears the bottom of its stroke.
            The switch button extends from the bottom of the solenoid end cap into the core.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If Solenoid replacement is required, refer to the DT/DTA-466 Diesel Engine Service Manual
                    [CGES-415-*] for removal, installation and adjustment procedures.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">* - Manual specified with latest revision.</emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="ef4500622" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg9839" filename="../figcg9/CG9839.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 6.23 Internal Switch Button [Located in the Bottom of the Solenoid Core]</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_123.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_125.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
