<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS -
        CREATIVE TOOL MODEL CT-400 DIESEL TIMING AND TACHOMETER INSTRUMENT [SE-2783] OR [3005] EARLIER MODEL - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"CALIBRATE TO________________"</title>
            <para>The numbers shown are the numbers at which this specific instrument is calibrated for accuracy.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"RPM x 10 ADVANCE"</title>
            <para>This three digit lighted display shows both engine RPM and degrees of advance. When the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH.- ADVANCE"</emph>
                switch is in the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH."</emph>
                position, engine RPM is shown in hundreds. Multiply by 10 to determine RPM. When the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH.-ADVANCE"</emph>
                switch is in the
                <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                position, the degrees of advance are shown to the nearest tenth of a degree. The lights to the left of
                the display indicate which mode the instrument is in.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"CAL. ADJ."</title>
            <para>This screw is used to set the instrument to the correct calibration. When the
                <emph type="bold">"CAL. SWITCH"</emph>
                is moved to the on position and the lighted display does not indicate the correct
                <emph type="bold">"CALIBRATE TO_____________ "</emph>
                setting, loosen the locknut and while holding the
                <emph type="bold">"CAL. SWITCH"</emph>
                in the on position, rotate the screw with a small screwdriver until the proper
                <emph type="bold">"CALIBRATE TO"</emph>
                number appears on the lighted display. Tighten the locknut.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"CAL. SWITCH"</title>
            <para>This switch is used to check the accuracy of the instrument at any time during a test. Move the switch
                and hold. Observe the lighted display. The
                <emph type="bold">"CALIBRATE TO__________"</emph>
                number should appear on the lighted display. If the number shown is not correct, adjust as described
                under
                <emph type="bold">"CAL. ADJ."</emph>
                above.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Red Light</title>
            <para>This light indicates whether the instrument is on or off.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"ADVANCE"</title>
            <para>This knob is used in conjunction with the timing light to determine degrees of advance. The
                <emph type="bold">"TACH.- OFF-T. LIGHT"</emph>
                switch must be in the
                <emph type="bold">"T. LIGHT"</emph>
                position and the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH.-ADVANCE"</emph>switch must be in the
                <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                position. With the engine at the desired RPM, rotate the knob counterclockwise to obtain 00.0 on the
                lighted display. Aiming the timing light at the damper and timing pointer, slowly rotate the knob
                clockwise until the
                <emph type="bold">"TDC"</emph>
                timing mark on the damper and the timing pointer are in alignment. When the marks are in alignment,
                release the knob. The actual timing will be shown on the lighted display.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Whenever changing engine speeds, the knob must be rotated back to 00.0 on the display before
                        proceeding.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"TACH.-ADVANCE"</title>
            <para>This switch with the red plastic handle has two positions. When it is in the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH."</emph>
                position, the lighted display will show engine RPM. When it is in the
                <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                position, the lighted display will show the degrees of advance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"TACH.-OFF-T. LIGHT"</title>
            <para>This switch has three positions. The center,
                <emph type="bold">"OFF,"</emph>
                position cuts off the power to the instrument and the red light is out. When the switch is moved to the
                <emph type="bold">"TACH."</emph>
                position, engine RPM is shown on the lighted display. When the switch is moved to the
                <emph type="bold">"T. LIGHT"</emph>
                position, the timing light is activated and degrees of advance are shown on the lighted display.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Both the "TACH.-ADVANCE" and the "TACH..OFF-T. LIGHT" switches must be in the same modes for
                        the instrument to function properly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
