<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS -
        DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS PROCEDURES FOR.. - ...COOLANT IN LUBRICATING OIL OR LUBRICATING OIL IN COOLANT.
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>...COOLANT IN LUBRICATING OIL OR
            <emph type="bold">LUBRICATING OIL IN COOLANT.</emph>
        </title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Run engine coolant pressure (leakage) test.</para>
            <para>POSSIBLE LOCATIONS OF LEAKAGE</para>
            <seqlist style="alphalc">
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or porous cylinder head - top deck, core plug area or blown head gasket.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection nozzle sleeve area - top deck area.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Porous crankcase - in area of main bearing crankcase webbing.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Lower cylinder sleeve "O" ring area. [Damaged or eroded.]</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cracked or porous power cylinder sleeve.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Lube oil cooler. [Cracked or loose tubes.]</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blown air compressor head gasket.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intercooler [DTI-466B/C only (cracked or loose tubes).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>PRESSURE (Leakage) TEST PROCEDURE</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Drain all lube oil and coolant from engine and radiator.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the radiator from the engine and cap off all the engine connections (with
                    hose clamps and plugs).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the unit's cab heater connections at the engine and cap engine openings.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air compressor coolant supply and discharge line then cap lines at engine.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect and remove air discharge pipe from turbocharger to the engine mounted
                    intercooler [if equipped].
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect intercooler coolant supply and discharge lines at the engine [if equipped].
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect and leave open oil supply return line to crankcase from air compressor (if
                    equipped).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the valve cover, lube oil pan and oil drain plug from the lube oil cooler.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>DO NOT LOOSEN OR REMOVE ANY INJECTION NOZZLES FROM THE CYLINDER HEAD WHILE THE COOLING
                            SYSTEM IS UNDER PRESSURE.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fill the engine with water and attach an air line connection coupled with a regulator
                    assembly to the water drain in cylinder block.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Pressurize the crankcase cooling system to 30 psi. Pressure must be maintained until
                    leakage location is evident. It may be necessary for the engine to remain pressurized over night to
                    locate porous castings or tiny cracks.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">It is essential that all points of leakage identified prior to teardown and repair. NO
                    EXTERNAL OR INTERNAL LEAKAGE IS ALLOWABLE.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>On water cooled engines, pressure test the intercooler separately after complete engine
                            pressure test. Cracked or loose tubes in the intercooler may cause coolant to leak into the
                            intake manifold and eventually into the cylinders.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the location of the leak is found and repaired, clean the contaminated engine using
                Butyl Cellosolve or Butyl jaysolve as directed.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
