<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS -
        CREATIVE TOOL MODEL CT-4000 DIESEL TIMING AND TACHOMETER INSTRUMENT [SE-2783] OR [3005A] CURRENT MODEL -
        OPERATING PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATING PROCEDURES</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>It is important that the following sequence of events be strictly adhered to.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the area of the injection pump where the transducer is to be installed (at #1 or #6
                fuel outlet). Do
                <emph type="bold">NOT</emph>
                install at the nozzle end of the line.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the Split-Nut Transducer No. CT-4000-13 as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the fuel line connector nut
                    <emph type="bold">(1,Figure 4.4)</emph>
                    and slide it up the pipe. Secure the displaced nut with tape to prevent bouncing of the nut and
                    possible erratic readings.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the Split-Nut Transducer
                    <emph type="bold">(2, Figure 4.4)</emph>
                    over the fuel line by slipping the slotted portion of the transducer on the line and tighten the
                    Split-Nut Transducer to allow slight fuel leakage at the split-nut when the engine is started.
                    Tighten the split-nut only until leakage stops. Use of this method will allow you to achieve the
                    required torque of 15-20 lbf-ft.(20-27 N.m).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Loosen the fuel injection line nut at the pump while holding the delivery valve holder
                            with a modified 7/8 in. 12 pt. box wrench to prevent delivery valve movement (which could
                            affect rack travel) The 7/8 in. wrench used to hold the delivery valve mist be modified by
                            cutting a slot which allows it to pass over the fuel line. Refer to (CGES-415-*)
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">* - Manual specified with latest revision.</emph>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>2: When applying or removing the Split-Nut Transducer, always make sure the short coaxial
                            (white) cable (3, Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500406">4.8</hotlnk>) is not caught up in the lines. Pulling apart of the
                            short white cable from the transducer damages the ground, causing erratic readings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4500406" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg7361" filename="../figcg7/cg7361.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.8 14 mm Split-Nut Transducer Installed (UTDS Model 100 Pump Shown)</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. Displaced Fuel Line Connector Nut (Taped on Fuel Line)</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. 14 mm Split-Nut Transducer</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. Short Coaxial (White) Cable</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. Lead to Coaxial Cable from SE-2783 or 3005A Unit. Attach Using BNC (Bayonet)
                            Connector.
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>5. #6 Fuel Injection Line (#1 May be Used)</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Static timing must be checked before any timing checks are made with the timing light.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check static timing (engine stopped)</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>ONLY THE TACHOMETER FUNCTION OF THE TOOL (SE-2783) IS USED TO DIAGNOSE DT/DTI/DTA-466 C DIESEL
                        ENGINES. DYNAMIC TIMING IS NOT MEASURED.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mark the "TDC" dot on the crankshaft pulley and the front cover pointer with white paint or
                similar product so a clear reading can be obtained when the strobe light is used.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect power leads to any 12 or 24 volt negative ground electrical system. The power leads
                are not color coded. Connect either lead to the positive (+) side of the battery and the other to a good
                ground.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the lead
                <emph type="bold">(4, Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500406">4.8</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                provided to couple the tachometer and timing light unit (SE-2783) or (3005A) to the white coaxial cable
                at the Split-Nut Transducer
                <emph type="bold">(2, Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500406">4.8</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine. Check for fuel leaks.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform the speed and timing checks as follows: (See KEYBOARD DESCRIPTION, this section).
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Depress the
                    <emph type="bold">"RST"</emph>
                    ( Reset) key.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If it is already depressed, release and depress. SE-2783 or 3005A should be "powered up"
                            at this point, as indicated by the "----- " appearing in the digital display.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Depress and release the
                    <emph type="bold">"TST"</emph>
                    (Test) key on the keyboard to place the SE-2783 or 3005A in the operational mode. "8888"appearing in
                    the digital display indicates the unit is operational and a signal is being received from the
                    transducer. "-----" on the digital display indicates:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">The transducer is disconnected.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">The unit is NOT functioning properly.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">The appearance of any other character or number at this time means the
                                unit is not functioning properly.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Once the SE-2783 or 3005A has been placed in the operational mode, any of the functions
                            can be selected.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Depress and release the
                    <emph type="bold">"RPM"</emph>
                    key. The instrument is now in the "RPM" mode. Engine speed will be displayed on the digital readout.
                    Adjust engine speed to the specification listed in the PERFORMANCE DATA GUIDELINES, Sections 5 and
                    6.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Depress and release the
                    <emph type="bold">"ADV"</emph>
                    key. The instrument is now in the
                    <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                    mode. Set
                    <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                    mode to double zero (00). Depress
                    <emph type="bold">"STB ON"</emph>
                    key to activate the strobe light. Aim the strobe light and increase
                    <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                    mode (by one increment at a time) using the "&#8593;" key until
                    <emph type="bold">"TDC"</emph>
                    mark and front cover pointer align. When the marks are in alignment, release the "&#8595;" key. The
                    actual timing will be shown on the display.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>WHENEVER CHANGING ENGINE SPEEDS, DEPRESS THE "&#8595;" BUTTON TO REACH DOUBLE ZERO (00) ON
                            THE DISPLAY BEFORE PROCEEDING.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Depress the
                    <emph type="bold">"RPM"</emph>
                    key and increase engine RPM to total pump timing speed, as specified in PERFORMANCE DATA GUIDELINES,
                    Section 5.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With the
                    <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE"</emph>
                    mode reset to double zero (00), increase the
                    <emph type="bold">"ADVANCE'</emph>
                    mode (by one increment at a time) using the "&#8593;" key until the
                    <emph type="bold">"TDC"</emph>mark and front cover pointer align. When marks are in alignment,
                    release the "&#8593;"
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>key. The injection pump timing (Degrees of Advance) will appear on the
                    digital display. Compare readings with specifications.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not exceed specified maximum total pump timing speed (RPM).</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>IF THERE IS A QUESTION OF TIMING LIGHT ACCURACY, FLOW TIME THE PUMP AS DESCRIBED IN
                            SECTION 5. FLOW TIMING IS ACCOMPLISHED WITHOUT REMOVING THE PUMP DELIVERY VALVE.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
