<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT/DTI-466 A and B Series DT/DTI/DTA-466 C Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1993) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST
        PROCEDURES - DT/DTI - 466 A AND B SERIES DIESEL ENGINES - AIR CLEANER MAXIMUM RESTRICTION DT/DTI-466 A and B
        Series (With UTDS Model 100 Fuel Injection Pump) - DUAL ELEMENT CLEANER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>DUAL ELEMENT CLEANER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The dual element air cleaner provides a large primary (outer) filter element and an optional small
                secondary (inner) filter element. The secondary element should be used in dusty environments, such as
                dump and mixer applications.
            </para>
            <para>The current dual element air cleaner assembly air cleaner restriction connection
                <emph type="bold">(Figures
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500516">5.16</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500517">5.17</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
                is located between the primary and the secondary elements in the bottom of the air cleaner housing. This
                arrangement allows only the primary (outer) element to be sensed by the restriction indicator or dash
                mounted vacuum gauge.
                <emph type="bold">THE INNER ELEMENT IS NOT RECORDED ON THE RESTRICTION INDICATOR OR DASH MOUNTED VACUUM
                    GAUGE.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>To determine inner element restriction use the:</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Visual Check Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the restriction indicator built into the inner element or inner element
                    retaining nut.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Two different indicators are the result of two different suppliers. Replace the element
                            when the green dot disappears from the element or from the window in the retaining nut.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>EACH SUPPLIER'S RETAINING NUT REQUIRES A DIFFERENT TORQUE. REFER TO FIGURES
                            <emph type="bold">
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500516">5.16</hotlnk>
                                and
                                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500517">5.17</hotlnk>
                            </emph>
                            .
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4500516" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg10992" filename="../figcg1/cg10992.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.16 Dual Element Air Cleaner (w/Indicator in Cartridge)</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="ef4500517" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg10993" filename="../figcg1/cg10993.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.17 Dual Element Air Cleaner (w/Indicator in Retaining Nut)</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A low air cleaner restriction reading or a lack of movement by the air cleaner restriction
                            indicator could be caused by a plugged sintered fitting. There are two different types of
                            this fitting (Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4500518">5.18</hotlnk>). The first fitting has a filter screen in the
                            fitting. This screen can become plugged and not allow a correct air cleaner restriction
                            reading to be taken. If this type of fitting is found, drill center of screen with a 1/32"
                            size drill. This fitting is welded in place and is not a serviceable part. The other type of
                            fitting has a 0.020 in. (0.51mm) orifice fitting. This type of fitting can be easily cleaned
                            with a fine piece of wire. Reworking the first type fitting and cleaning the second type
                            fitting before running diagnostic tests will eliminate false air cleaner restriction
                            readings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4500518" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg12462" filename="../figcg1/cg12462.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.18 Restriction Indicator Filter Screening</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_73.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450_75.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e450.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
