<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST PROCEDURES FOR 7.3 LITER DIESEL ENGINES
        - TEST INJECTION NOZZLES - Removal
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Removal</title>
        <para>Before removing nozzle assemblies, clean exterior of each nozzle assembly and the surrounding area with
            clean fuel oil or solvent to prevent entry of dirt into engine when nozzle assemblies are removed. Also,
            clean fuel inlet and fuel leak-off piping connections. Blow dry with filtered compressed air.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Remove and cap the line pressure sensor on the #4 cylinder nozzle to allow fuel return tee
                    removal.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the high pressure fuel injection line connector nuts at each nozzle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the fuel return (leak-off) lines as an assembly, as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the pump to fuel return tube hose at the fuel return elbow at pump. Cap elbow at
                    pump. Disconnect hose from leak-off tee to fuel filter at the leak-off tee.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen the two fuel return tubes and retaining clamps (one at the intake manifold and
                    one at the engine lifting eye).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With clamps removed, remove the return lines and tees as an assembly by lifting tees off
                    the nozzles.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install protective caps from ZTSE-4135 onto the high pressure lines which were disconnected.
                Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600534">5.34</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4600534" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg9808" filename="../figcg9/cg9808.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.34 Protective Cap from ZTSE-4135 on High Pressure Fuel Lines</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install protective cap onto nozzles using ZTSE-4135 protective cap set. Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600535">5.35</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4600535" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11192" filename="../figcg1/cg11192.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.35 Installing Protective Caps on Nozzles</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the nozzle from the cylinder head bore using a box wrench. Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600536">5.36</hotlnk>. TURN COUNTERCLOCKWISE TO REMOVE NOZZLES.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4600536" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11193" filename="../figcg1/cg11193.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.36 Nozzle Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">As nozzles are removed, place a protective cap on the nozzle tip. Place nozzle assemblies in
                a holding rack (ZTSE-4141). Identify each nozzle as to the cylinder from which it was removed. This
                permits replacing the nozzles in their respective ports during installation. Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600537">5.37</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4600537" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12403" filename="../figcg1/cg12403.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.37 Nozzle Holder Rack</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>BE EXTREMELY CAREFUL NOT TO DAMAGE NOZZLE TIPS DURING REMOVAL.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the nozzle code is marked one of the following: "BB" code [CAV Nozzles] or "C" or "D"
                code [STANADYNE Nozzles] Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600538">5.38</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Effective with engine S/N 622179 and above, Stanadyne nozzle and holder assemblies are
                        available as an alternate source to CAV nozzle and holder assemblies, for production. The
                        Stanadyne "C" and "D" code nozzles have no notches on the nozzle holder body flats. The CAV
                        nozzles have two notches at each flat. This provides quick vendor identification.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4600538" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14520" filename="../figcg1/cg14520.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.38 Nozzle Code Location Injection Nozzle Testing</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_52.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_54.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
