<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS GUIDES - INSTRUCTIONS FOR
        PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS GUIDES - ENGINE TEST NOMENCLATURE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ENGINE TEST NOMENCLATURE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>INJECTION PUMP TIMING</title>
            <para>Factory Dynamic Timing Procedure [Production Procedure Only]</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>NEW ENGINE AND INJECTION PUMP TIMING IS SET IN STEPS DURING THE PRODUCTION PROCESS.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">STEP ONE:</emph>INITIAL OR STATIC TIMING IS MARKED AT THE 12:00 POSITION
                        ON THE PUMP FLANGE AND ADAPTER HOUSING. THESE MARKS ARE ONLY USED AS AN APPROXIMATE TIMING
                        SETTING PRIOR TO STEP TWO, DYNAMICALLY TIMING THE ENGINE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">STEP TWO:</emph>
                        <emph type="bold"></emph>
                        FINAL TIMING IS DONE DYNAMICALLY. IF TIMING ADJUSTMENT IS REQUIRED, A ROBOTIC DEVICE
                        AUTOMATICALLY ADJUSTS THE INJECTION PUMP POSITION BY ROTATING IT SLIGHTLY (ADVANCE OR RETARD),
                        AND STRIKING NEW MARKS AT THE 10:00 POSITION. THE 12:00 MARKS MAY BE OUT OF ALIGNMENT DUE TO THE
                        AUTOMATIC ROTATION OF THE PUMP DURING THE DYNAMIC TIMING ADJUSTMENT. ONLY THE 10:00 MARKS
                        <emph type="bold">MUST</emph>
                        BE IN ALIGNMENT.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Later production engines have the 12:00 o'clock mark on the pump flange removed. Service pumps
                        will continue to have a 12:00 o'clock mark as a reference/starting point.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">* - Manual specified with latest revision</emph>
            </para>
            <para>FIELD DYNAMIC TIMING ADJUSTMENT</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>IF SERVICE REQUIRES INJECTION PUMP TIMING ADJUSTMENT, THE TIMING MARKS AT THE 10:00 POSITION
                        WHICH WERE SET AT THE FACTORY MAY BE MISALIGNED WITHIN 0.030 INCH. MISALIGNMENT BY MORE THAN
                        0.030 INCH IS NOT PERMISSIBLE. IF INJECTION PUMP REPAIR OR REPLACEMENT IS REQUIRED, THE SERVICE
                        PUMP MUST BE RETIMED DYNAMICALLY. REFER TO SPECIFICATION IN PERFORMANCE GUIDELINE DATA.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4600301" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg14305" filename="../figcg1/CG14305.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.1 Injection Pump Timing Marks</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ENGINE SPEED (RPM)</title>
            <para>High idle is the highest engine speed at full throttle position and no load condition. High idle is
                normally 10 to 12% over engine rated speed.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>HIGH IDLE ADJUSTMENT IS NOT MADE EXTERNALLY ON THE DB-2 FUEL INJECTION PUMP. HIGH IDLE CAN
                        ONLY BE ADJUSTED INTERNALLY BY A CERTIFIED DEALER.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Low idle is the lowest recommended speed that engine should run at no load, thus providing adequate
                output for mounted accessories. Below this speed, throttle control will normally start to activate
                engine shutoff.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL PRESSURE</title>
            <para>The fuel pressure test reflects the availability of sufficient quantity and resistance to flow of
                fuel.
            </para>
            <para>The pressure is developed by the injection pump supply pump and is required to charge the injection
                pump's high pressure system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AIR CLEANER RESTRICTION</title>
            <para>The air cleaner restriction check measures the resistance to flow of air thru the complete air intake
                system "air filter, piping, hosing, etc." of the engine. Excessively high resistance will result in
                improper air fuel ratio, high smoke level, over heating and low power. The tools needed to perform this
                check are included in the Model 200 Engine Field Test Kit (ZTSE-2239) or a water manometer. Readings
                beyond the guidelines indicate dirty filters or obstructions in the air intake opening.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CRANKCASE PRESSURE</title>
            <para>This test measures the restricted combustion "blow-by" gas flow as designed by the crankcase breather
                system. It is measured in inches of water. Constant monitoring of this pressure will allow one to follow
                internal engine power cylinder wear.
            </para>
            <para>Positive crankcase pressure is normal and is intentionally designed into the engines. Readings
                recorded beyond guideline tolerances signal a need to completely review engine condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
