<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - MODEL 200 PRESSURE TEST KIT
        (ZTSE-2239)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>MODEL 200 PRESSURE TEST KIT (ZTSE-2239)</title>
        <para>DESCRIPTION</para>
        <para>The pressure test kit (Figure
            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600407">4.7</hotlnk>) can be used to measure fuel pressures, air cleaner restriction and
            crankcase pressure. It may also be used to test the accuracy of the gauges within the kit.
        </para>
        <figure id="ef4600407" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg12449" filename="../figcg1/CG12449.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 4.7 Pressure Test Kit</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The Model 100 Engine Field Test Kit (ZTSE-4327) may also be used in place of the Model 200
                    (ZTSE-2239) for most tests. The differences are as follows: The Model 100 has a 0-15 psi gauge and
                    the Model-200 has a 0-30 in. Hg. gauge, needed valves and adapters for pressure dampening.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The 0-30 psi gauge may be used to check mechanical lift pump (fuel supply) and fuel return pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The 0-30 in Hg. gauge is used to check fuel system restriction at the supply pump inlet. This test will
            require the use of the Model 200 test kit.
        </para>
        <para>The 0-60 inches of water (magnehelic) gauge may be used to measure air cleaner restriction and crankcase
            pressure. The water manometer may also be used for measuring crankcase pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The 0-160 psi gauge is used to check transfer pump pressure.</para>
        <para>The 0-300 psi gauge is not normally used for any engine diagnostic check on the 7.3 Liter.</para>
        <para>MAINTENANCE AND GAUGE ACCURACY TEST</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cover of pressure test kit and inspect for damage to gauges such as broken cover
                glass, bent gauge needles, and for missing pressure connectors and nylon tubing. Replace damaged or
                missing parts so that the kit will operate when needed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the screws holding gauge panel to carrying case and lift panel from carrying case. If
                any liquids are found in the tubing behind the panel, loosen the connections and blow out the liquids.
                Tighten all connectors as required and reassemble gauge panel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The hand operated pump is directly connected to 0-30 psi gauge with the kit is received.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>OPERATING INSTRUCTIONS</para>
        <para>Connect tubes between the test ports on the panel and the test points shown in Section 5.</para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>THE QUICK DISCONNECTS HAVE SHUT-OFF VALVES IN THE PANEL CONNECTORS NOT IN THE PLUG. DO NOT CONNECT
                    OR DISCONNECT LINES WHILE UNDER PRESSURE.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When using the inches of water, magnahelic gauge, be sure to use the proper panel connector,
                    either "pressure" or "vacuum". Whichever is used, the opposite connector MUST be vented to the
                    atmosphere by installing a quick connective plug in the port.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
