<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - "SOLID STATE" GLOW PLUG ANALYSIS GUIDE</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection division="ENGINE" id="E46006" svcsectype="prodspec" date="04/10/1996">
        <title>"SOLID STATE" GLOW PLUG ANALYSIS GUIDE</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>"SOLID STATE" GLOW PLUG SYSTEM</title>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Description and Operation</title>
                    <para>The glow plug controller assembly incorporates all control functions and the power relay in
                        one "solid state" electronic module which is engine mounted on the rear of the intake manifold,
                        Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600601">6.1</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <para>The "Solid State" Glow Plug System uses positive temperature coefficient (PTC) glow plugs with
                        push-on "bullet" terminals. The glow plugs change resistance with temperature and the controller
                        senses the change in resistance to control the glow plug cycle time. Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600602">6.2</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <para>The wiring harness used on the "solid state" system must be routed as shown in Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600601">6.1</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4600601" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12485" filename="../figcg1/CG12485.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.1 Top View of 7.3 Liter Engine [1988 Model Year and before shown]</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="ef4600602" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12484" filename="../figcg1/CG12484.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6.2 Glow Plug Identification</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The "Solid State" system determines the glow plug temperature and maintains the temperature
                        regardless of ambient conditions by electronically measuring the resistance of the glow plugs.
                        The power to the system is actuated when the ignition switch is turned on. A wait light
                        indicates when the glow plugs have reached proper temperature by going out. An after glow
                        operation of the glow plugs continues after the wait light has been turned off. This cyclic
                        operation of the glow plugs reduces white "start-up" smoke. The after glow can be determined by
                        listening to the relay cycle on and off. (A rapid "clicking" sound will be heard [with hood
                        open] during after glow cycling).
                    </para>
                    <para>A special feature of the "Solid State" Glow Plug System is its instant recycle ability. If the
                        switch is turned off, the operator can immediately recycle by turning the ignition on, which
                        will start the reheat cycle of the glow plugs and the wait light will come on. Engine cranking
                        can begin as soon as the wait light goes out.
                    </para>
                    <para>The power relay is located above the controller and the entire unit is covered by a plastic
                        protective cover. The cover prevents accidental contact of the large resistor or relay parts
                        during the operation of the system. If batteries are low, jump starting should be accomplished
                        by connecting to the normal battery terminals,
                        <emph type="bold">not the power relay.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>DO NOT JUMP START BY CONNECTING POWER LEADS TO THE CONTROLLER MOUNTED RELAY. DOING SO
                                WILL RESULT IN GLOW PLUG FAILURE. THE CONTROLLER IS SERVICED ONLY AS AN ASSEMBLY.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_61.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_63.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
