<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST PROCEDURES FOR 7.3 LITER DIESEL ENGINES
        - TEST INJECTION NOZZLES - TEST 2
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>TEST 2</title>
        <para>CHECK FOR TIP LEAKAGE. Blow nozzle tip dry using filtered compressed air. Operate test pump to maintain
            pressure at about 200 psi (1378 kPa) below the opening pressure obtained in Test 1. Wetting of the nozzle
            tip is acceptable as long as a drop does not fall within 5 seconds. (Refer to Figure
            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600540">5.40</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Make sure that any fluid accumulation at the nozzle tip is not due to fuel leaking down the
                    outside of the nozzle body from the return openings. If questionable, wrap a shop cloth around the
                    nozzle body to prevent fluid leaking down the outside of the nozzle body from reaching the tip.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>DO NOT WIPE NOZZLE TIP WITH FINGERS AS INJURY COULD OCCUR AS A RESULT OF HIGH PRESSURE FUEL BEING
                    RELEASED IF THE PINTLE VALVE IS MOVED INWARD. FUEL COULD PENETRATE THE SKIN CAUSING INJURY.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>IF THE NOZZLE PASSES THE NOZZLE OPENING PRESSURE AND TIP LEAKAGE TESTS, IT IS SUITABLE FOR FURTHER
                    SERVICE IN THE ENGINE.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>NOZZLES SHOWING LEAKAGE AT THE NOZZLE TIP OR OPENING PRESSURE BELOW THE MINIMUM PERMISSIBLE LIMIT
                    ARE DEFECTIVE AND MUST BE REPLACED (IF WITHIN THE WARRANTY PERIOD) OR MAY BE SERVICED (DISASSEMBLED,
                    CLEANED, INSPECTED AND REBUILT), IF OUTSIDE THE WARRANTY PERIOD.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the fuel injection nozzles are to be reconditioned, refer to Section 9 in CGES-435-*, 7.3 Liter
                    Diesel Engine Service Manual for instructions. DO NOT INTERMIX INDIVIDUAL SERVICE REPAIR PARTS
                    BETWEEN CAV "BB" CODE AND STANADYNE "C" OR "D" CODE NOZZLES.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Warranty claims for replacement of the nozzle(s) will not be accepted unless the completed Engine
                    Performance Analysis Guide (CGED-440-*) is submitted with the returned part(s).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="ef4600540" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="cg10713" filename="../figcg1/CG10713.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 5.40 Acceptable vs. Unacceptable Nozzle Tip Leakage</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">* - Manual specified with latest revision</emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
