<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST PROCEDURES FOR 7.3 LITER DIESEL ENGINES
        - INJECTION PUMP DYNAMIC TIMING - DYNAMIC INJECTION TIMING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="4">
        <title>DYNAMIC INJECTION TIMING</title>
        <para>Dynamic timing is checked using the Tach-n-Time instrument (ZTSE-4142) with a clamp pick-up (ZTSE-4142-73)
            attached to an engine mounted line pressure sensor.
        </para>
        <para>The dynamic timing specification at 2000 RPM, no load, is 3.5&#176; &#177; 2&#176; BTDC as measured with
            ZTSE-4142.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>THE 7.3 LITER FUEL INJECTION PUMPS FOR INTERNATIONAL(r) 1000, 3000, 4000, S-SERIES AND METRO II
                    APPLICATIONS, AND FORD MOTOR COMPANY E &#38; F SERIES APPLICATIONS ARE TIMED IDENTICALLY AT THE
                    FACTORY. HOWEVER, DYNAMIC TIMING SPECIFICATIONS FOR SERVICE ARE DIFFERENT DUE TO DIFFERENT TIMING
                    METERS USED BY INTERNATIONAL AND FORD. EACH METER HAS DIFFERENT ELECTRONIC CIRCUITRY AND FILTERING
                    WHICH ACCOUNTS FOR THE DIFFERENT SERVICE DYNAMIC TIMING SPECIFICATIONS. THE DYNAMIC TIMING
                    SPECIFICATION LISTED ABOVE IS VALID ONLY WHEN USING THE TACH-N-TIME (ZTSE-4142). OTHER TIMING METERS
                    WILL NOT PROVIDE THE SAME RESULTS.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>Timing advance, measured at 2000 RPM, no load, with the HPCA Solenoid activated MUST be 2_ min.( above the
            first timing check.)
        </para>
        <para>PROCEDURE</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Slide the plastic protective cap off the line pressure sensor (Figure
                <hotlnk document="e460_HL4600506.xml" xrefid="ef4600524">5.24</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clamp the "alligator style" pick-up (ZTSE-4142-73) to the line pressure sensor on the #4
                cylinder injection nozzle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the ground clamp from the pick-up clamp harness to an appropriate ground as shown in
                Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600525">5.25</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>LINE PRESSURE SENSOR AND PICK-UP CLAMP MUST BE DRY. WET CONDITIONS CAN CAUSE ERRATIC READINGS.
                        IF ERRATIC READINGS ARE OBSERVED, REMOVE THE PICK-UP CLAMP AND DRY THE CLAMP AND LINE PRESSURE
                        SENSOR WITH A CLEAN, DRY CLOTH. SPRAY THE PICK-UP CLAMP AND LINE PRESSURE SENSOR ON ALL
                        SURFACES, WITH A WATER DISPLACING SUBSTANCE, SUCH AS WD-40(r) AND RECLAMP THE PICK-UP TO THE
                        LINE PRESSURE SENSOR.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4600525" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg11740" filename="../figcg1/cg11740.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.25 Dynamic Injection Pump Timing</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set "SENSOR SIGNAL" rocker switch to the "CLAMP ON" position. Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600526">5.26</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the magnetic probe into the magnetic pick-up access hole (top hole) located on the
                crankcase front cover. See Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600525">5.25</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Plug the magnetic probe terminal into the crankshaft sensor jack on the ZTSE-4142 body
                labeled "MAGNETIC PICK-UP". Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600526">5.26</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set rocker switch to "MAGNETIC PICK-UP" position. Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600526">5.26</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the ZTSE-4142 battery leads to the vehicle battery (red to "+", black to "-").
                Display should light up and read (Set...20.0).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>THE ZTSE-4142 MUST BE GROUNDED TO THE ENGINE BLOCK. REFER TO FIGURE
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600526">5.26</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ef4600526" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12452" filename="../figcg1/cg12452.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.26 ZTSE-4142 Control Panel</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The timing meter automatically reads a 20&#176; timing offset. No offset adjustment is
                required for the 7.3 Liter Diesel Engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure all cables and wires are clear of fan, belts or any other moving parts. Keep wires
                away from exhaust manifolds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start engine. The sensor light on the ZTSE-4142 should be blinking regularly, indicating
                proper function of the connectors. Allow the engine to reach normal operating temperature.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>HPCA SOLENOID MALFUNCTIONING AFFECTS TIMING. VERIFY PROPER HPCA OpERATION AS FOLLOWS:</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WITH ENGINE COLD (Coolant temperature below 85</emph>&#176;
                <emph type="bold">F).</emph>
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With timing meter properly installed, disconnect yellow wire (Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600527">5.27</hotlnk>) to DEACTIVATE the HPCA Solenoid.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4600527" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11753" filename="../figcg1/cg11753.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.27 Deactivate HPCA Solenoid</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If RPM on timing meter decreases or a timing change is observed, the HPCA Solenoid is
                    functioning.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If NO decrease in RPM or timing is observed, the HPCA or the temperature sensor in the
                    top/rear inboard side of the left cylinder head is faulty. Confirm temperature sensor function and
                    replace HPCA or sensor as required.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">WITH ENGINE WARM (Coolant temperature above 140</emph>&#176;
                <emph type="bold">F).</emph>
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With the timing meter properly installed and the HPCA Solenoid Connected, use a jumper
                    wire to activate the HPCA Solenoid. Refer to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600528">5.28</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If RPM on the meter increases or a timing change is observed, the HPCA Solenoid is
                    functioning.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If NO increase in RPM or timing is observed, the HPCA or the temperature sensor is not
                    functioning. Confirm temperature sensor operation and replace HPCA or sensor as required.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4600528" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg14582" filename="../figcg1/cg14582.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.28 Activate HPCA Solenoid</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
