<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - TACH-N-TIME DYNAMIC TIMING METER
        (ZTSE-4142)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TACH-N-TIME DYNAMIC TIMING METER (ZTSE-4142)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The ZTSE-4142 TACH-N-TIME uses the latest in microprocessor technology to quickly and accurately
                measure fuel injection pump timing.
            </para>
            <para>The pump pulse is picked up by a clamp on pick-up which fastens to the engine mounted line pressure
                sensor on the No. 4 injection nozzle.
            </para>
            <para>Crankshaft location is picked up with a magnetic probe. The probe offset is automatically computed by
                the ZTSE-4142 TACH-N-TIME at 20&#176; offset.
            </para>
            <para>Using the pump pulse signal and the crankshaft location signal, a microprocessor gives a digital
                display of exact engine RPM and injection pump timing in degrees.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef4600404" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12448" filename="../figcg1/CG12448.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.4 TACH-N-TIME INSTRUMENT (ZTSE-4142)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OPERATING PROCEDURES</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select the clamp on pick-up (ZTSE-4142-73) for the line pressure sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the "alligator style" pick-up (ZTSE-4142-73) to the line pressure sensor on the
                    No. 4 injection nozzle.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>SLIDE THE PROTECTIVE CAP OFF THE LINE PRESSURE SENSOR PRIOR TO INSTALLING THE PICK-UP.
                            REFER TO FIGURE
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600405">4.5</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect ground clamp from pick-up clamp harness to an appropriate ground as shown in
                    Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600405">4.5</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the remaining wire from the pick-up clamp harness to the plug in receptacle on
                    the ZTSE-4142 body labeled "SENSOR SIGNAL".
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>LINE PRESSURE SENSOR AND PICK-UP CLAMP MUST BE DRY. WET CONDITIONS CAN CAUSE ERRATIC
                            READINGS. IF ERRATIC READINGS ARE OBSERVED, REMOVE THE PICK-UP CLAMP AND DRY THE CLAMP AND
                            LINE PRESSURE SENSOR WITH A CLEAN, DRY CLOTH. SPRAY THE PICK-UP CLAMP AND LINE PRESSURE
                            SENSOR ON ALL SURFACES WITH A WATER DISPLACING SUBSTANCE SUCH AS WD-40 AND RECLAMP THE
                            PICK-UP TO THE LINE PRESSURE SENSOR.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set "SENSOR SIGNAL" toggle switch to the "CLAMP ON" position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">7.3 Liter Diesel uses magnetic probe method for determining crankshaft position.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MAGNETIC PROBE-METHOD CRANKSHAFT MONITORING</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the magnetic probe into the magnetic pick-up access hole located on engine. (See
                    Figure
                    <hotlnk document="e460_19.xml" xrefid="ef4600402">4.2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4600405" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg11740" filename="../figcg1/CG11740.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.5 Dynamic Injection Pump Timing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug probe terminal into the receptacle on the ZTSE-4142 body labeled "MAGNETIC
                    PICK-UP".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set toggle switch to "MAGNETIC PICK-UP" position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the ZTSE-4142 battery leads to the vehicle battery (red to "+", black to "-").
                    Display should light up and read Set...20.0).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>DO NOT CONNECT TO BATTERY SYSTEM WITH A "FLOATING GROUND". THE ZTSE-4142 SHOULD BE POWERED
                            FROM A SOURCE WITH A FIXED GROUND.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The meter automatically reads 20&#176; timing offset. No presetting or adjustment is
                    required for the 7.3 Liter Diesel Engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure all cables and wires are clear of fan, belts or any other moving parts. Keep
                    wires away from exhaust manifolds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine. Sensor light on ZTSE-4142 should be blinking regularly, indicating proper
                    function of connectors. Allow engine to reach operating temperature.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check initial dynamic timing with the Housing Pressure Cold Advance (HPCA) Solenoid
                    disconnected from the HPCA terminal. Run the engine at 2000 RPM, no load, and record dynamic timing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the HPCA Solenoid terminal and apply battery voltage using a jumper wire to
                    activate the HPCA Solenoid. Run the engine at 2000 RPM, no load, and record the timing. Refer to
                    Figure 4.3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Calculate the degrees of advance by subtracting the initial timing recorded in Step 8
                    from the advance timing recorded in Step 9. The difference equals the degrees of advance.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Timing Advance should be 2&#176; (minimum) above initial timing. Engine RPM and timing
                            angle can be read directly from the ZTSE-4142 display.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4600406" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg14582" filename="../figcg1/CG14582.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.6 Activating HPCA Using a Jumper Wire</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After timing operation is complete, reinstall the plastic line pressure sensor cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
