<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>7.3 Liter Diesel Engine Diagnostics (1991) - ENGINE DIAGNOSTIC TEST PROCEDURES FOR 7.3 LITER DIESEL ENGINES
        - EXTERNAL LEAKAGE - AIR INDUCTION TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="7">
        <title>AIR INDUCTION TEST</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>TOOLS REQUIRED: (Refer to Figure
                <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600503">5.3</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Air pressure regulator with 0-30 psi gauge.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clean plastic garbage bag.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Duct tape.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Spray bottle.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Soap (children's bubble blowing soap is best).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1.040 in. plug with air hose connector. (Make locally).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>2 hose clamps (1.5 in. and 4.5 in. dia.).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="ef4600503" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="cg12477" filename="../figcg1/cg12477.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.3 Required Tools for Air Induction Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TEST PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block off the air cleaner inlet snorkel, using the clean plastic trash bag, duct tape
                    and 4.5 in. hose clamp as shown in Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600504">5.4</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the CDR intake manifold hose from the CDR mounting spud. Install the 1.040 in.
                    plug with air hose connector. Attach an air hose with a pressure regulator and 0-30 psi gauge. Refer
                    to Figure
                    <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600504">5.4</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Regulate air pressure being introduced into the CDR hose to 6-9 psi. A constant supply
                    of air is required to compensate for internal leakage past the open intake valves and the air inlet
                    snorkel to filter housing mating surface.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Leakage from the air inlet snorkel can be reduced by applying a bead of silicone sealant
                            around the snorkel to housing mating surface. This is not mandatory, but will improve the
                            sensitivity of the test.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a spray bottle with "bubble blowing" soap, coat the following areas and check for
                    leaks. Leaks will cause air bubbles to form.
                </para>
                <figure id="ef4600504" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg12478" filename="../figcg1/cg12478.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.4 Air Induction Test Set-Up</caption>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Restriction indicator spud and air cleaner housing wing nut and sealing washer.
                        Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600505">5.5</hotlnk>. No leakage is permissible.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4600505" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12479" filename="../figcg1/cg12479.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.5 Leakage Check at Air Cleaner Housing</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air cleaner sealing gasket at the intake manifold inlet. Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600506">5.6</hotlnk>. No leakage is permissible.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4600506" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12480" filename="../figcg1/cg12480.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.6 Leakage Check at Intake Manifold Sealing Gasket</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All intake manifold and cylinder head mating surfaces. Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600507">5.7</hotlnk>. No leakage is permissible.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4600507" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12481" filename="../figcg1/cg12481.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.7 Leakage Check at Intake Manifold and Cylinder Head Mating Surfaces</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CDR hose inlet into the intake manifold. Refer to Figure
                        <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600508">5.8</hotlnk>. No leakage is permissible.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="ef4600508" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="cg12474" filename="../figcg1/cg12474.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5.8 Leakage Check at CDR Hose Inlet to Intake Manifold [ 1988 MODEL YEAR SHOWN
                            ]
                        </caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system holds pressure and NO leaks are detected, no further action is required
                    beyond inspecting the air cleaner element for holes, damaged seals and sooting. Replace as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If leakage is detected, remove the air cleaner housing and the intake manifold inlet
                    screen. Using your finger, sample the oil film in the inlet manifold for grit. If grit is felt, dirt
                    has entered the engine.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <seqlist style="arabic">
                            <item>
                                <para>Oil in the intake manifold is normal and expected, due to carry-over of oil vapors
                                    by the CDR valve.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Any leaks found in air induction system could have allowed dirt to enter engine.
                                    Dirt entering engine can cause high oil consumption because of badly worn or broken
                                    piston rings, excessive blue smoke. If any leaks are found in the air intake system,
                                    you can check the internal condition of the engine by running a crankcase pressure
                                    check.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Service the engine as required after determining the extent of the damage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Also correct any area which was identified as a point of leakage (i.e. sealing gaskets,
                    air cleaner housing distortion, etc.).
                </para>
                <para>Low Air Cleaner Restiction Reading:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A low air cleaner restiction reading or a lack of movement by the air cleaner restriction
                            indicator could be caused by a plugged/ restricted fitting. The air cleaner restriction
                            indicator spud is not a serviceable part, thus a restriction requires that it be reworked by
                            drilling a 1/32" size hole through the center. Reworking will eliminate false air cleaner
                            restiction readings. DO NOT ALLOW DRILLING DEBRIS TO ENTER THE INTAKE MANIFOLD. Refer to
                            Figure
                            <hotlnk xrefid="ef4600509">5.9</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="ef4600509" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="cg14578" filename="../figcg1/cg14578.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.9 Air Cleaner Restiction Indicator Spud</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="e460.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
