<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Front Cover, Cooling System, and
        Related Components - Clean, Inspect, and Measure
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Clean, Inspect, and Measure</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields. Limit compressed
                        air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean water supply housing, water pump, water inlet elbow, water outlet tube, oil pump
                    housing, front engine mount, and front cover with a suitable non-caustic solvent.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Blow parts dry using filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean coolant and oil seal mating surfaces on the cylinder head, water supply housing,
                    water pump, water inlet elbow, water outlet tube, oil pump housing, and front cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect alternator bracket, secondary Freon&#174; compressor support, water supply
                    housing, water inlet elbow, vibration damper assembly, oil pump and rotor housing, oil pump inner
                    and outer rotors, front cover, and idler gears for cracks, damage, or excessive wear. Replace parts
                    if required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect drive belt for excessive cracks and wear. Replace if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect automatic belt tensioner and pulley to make sure tensioner arm and pulley are
                    properly in line with the fan drive belt and not coming apart. Make sure tensioner arm is not
                    binding and pulley bearing is not loose. Replace belt tensioner if required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect thermostat and gasket. If thermostat is stuck open, damaged, cracked, or not
                    opening properly replace thermostat and gasket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect fan drive bearing by wiggling fan pulley. If bearing has excess play, replace
                    fan housing or mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect water pump. Wiggle water pump pulley. If water pump bearing has excess play,
                    replace water pump. Inspect water pump housing for coolant leaks. Replace water pump if leaking.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_277.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_279.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
