<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL&#174; VT 365 DIESEL ENGINE - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT and BEARINGS, CAMSHAFT and BUSHINGS -
        Cleaning, Inspection, and Reconditioning - Crankcase Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Crankcase Assembly</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cleaning the Crankcase</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Clean the crankcase in a chemical bath or hot tank. This removes all carbonized material and
                        mineral deposits in coolant passages.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Thoroughly clean and inspect crankcase before and after reconditioning.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use nonmetalic brushes and scrapers to clean gasket material from machined surfaces of
                    crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean cylinder bore with soap, water, and a nylon brush.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean lower crankcase in solvent. Dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove main oil gallery cup plug (in rear of crankcase), use a punch and hammer near
                    edge of plug and strike with a hammer. Remove plug from crankcase and discard. Clean main oil
                    galleries with a Oil Gallery Cleaning Brush .
                </para>
                <figure id="f2650820" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figd06/d0637.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Figure 305. Removal of oil gallery cup plugs</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Punch</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Hammer</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Oil gallery cup plug</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean main galleries with an Oil Gallery Cleaning Brush .</para>
                <figure id="f2650821" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figd06/d0638.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Figure 306. Oil Gallery Cleaning Brush</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use Liquid Gasket (RTV) before installing main oil gallery core plugs.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat edges of new cup plugs with sealant. Use a Oil Gallery Plug Driver to install new
                    cup plugs. The Oil Gallery Plug Driver installs cup plug to the proper depth. It should be flush
                    with the crankcase surface to approximately 1.50 mm (0.060 in) below surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, threads in the crankcase bolt holes must be clean and blown dry with
                        filtered compressed air.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f2650822" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/d0648.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 307. Head Bolt Bottoming Tap</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all cylinder head bolt holes with a Head Bolt Bottoming Tap . Blow out chips with
                    filtered compressed air.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspecting the Crankcase</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After cleaning, inspect crankcase for cracks, scoring, roughness or wear at cylinder
                    bores.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650823" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/d0614.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 308. Flatness check for top surface of cylinder block</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Straightedge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Feeler gauge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder block top surface</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a Straightedge to check top surface of crankcase (top deck) for flatness. Insert a
                    feeler gauge between Straightedge and crankcase head surface. If gap exceeds specifications ,
                    crankcase must be replaced.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not resurface the crankcase. Surface defects beyond those listed above are not
                            correctable.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cylinder walls have minor surface damage, but are otherwise within out-of-round
                    specifications, it may be possible to remove such damage by honing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a Cylinder Bore Gauge to check cylinder bore out-of-round conditions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure diameter of cylinder bore at top of piston ring travel. Be sure to measure at a
                    right angle to the center line of crankshaft (dimension A). Record reading. Next, measure each bore
                    so gauge reading coincides with center line of crankshaft (dimension B). Record reading.
                </para>
                <para>The difference between readings from dimension A and dimension B is the out-of-round condition at
                    the top of the cylinder bore. Repeat the same procedure at the bottom of ring travel to check for
                    out-of-round condition.
                </para>
                <figure id="f2650824" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figd06/d0615.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Figure 309. Out-of-round cylinder bore check</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, if cylinder bores are deeply scored, out-of-round, or exceed
                        specifications, all cylinders must be bored out to an oversize.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cylinder bore is within specifications , standard size pistons and rings may be used.
                    If cylinder bore is suitable for use without reconditioning, deglaze the cylinder bore before
                    assembling. See Cylinder Deglazing in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cylinder Deglazing</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If cylinder bores are to be deglazed, all piston cooling tubes must be removed.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a 4 inch Deglazing Hone to deglaze the cylinder bore. This silicone carbide-tipped
                    nylon flexible brush quickly deglazes cylinder walls and produces a crosshatch pattern on the
                    cylinder wall surface in a single operation. The brush contours itself to the cylinder wall and
                    conditions wall surface without altering cylinder bore.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray both the cylinder to be deglazed and the Deglazing Hone brush with penetrating
                    fluid or equivalent. This spray contains colloidal graphite and works well for this application.
                </para>
                <figure id="f2650825" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figd06/d0618.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Figure 310. Deglazing Hone</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Deglaze cylinder as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach Deglazing Hone to a variable speed electric or air powered drill.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>100-120 rpm and speed adjustment is required.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Deglaze cylinder wall for about 15 seconds. Stroke bore up and down at a rate of one
                        complete up and down stroke per second.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Withdraw Deglazing Hone from cylinder bore while brush is rotating. Wipe portion of
                        cylinder wall and inspect cross-hatch pattern.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The crosshatch pattern left by the abrasive tool should be approximately 45&#176;.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If pattern is "flatter" than required, increase up and down stroke speed or slow
                        down drill rotation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Continue deglazing cylinder bore for 10-15 seconds or 20-25 strokes.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Wipe cylinder bore clean and inspect bore for proper 45&#176; cross-hatch pattern.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After deglazing, thoroughly clean cylinder bores with soft bristle brush, soap and
                    water. Dry with filtered compressed air . Lubricate bore with clean engine oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_130.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_132.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
