<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - INTRODUCTION - Engine Description
        - Injection Control Pressure System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Injection Control Pressure System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f120in20" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Injector Oil System Diagram (Left Side)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lubricating Oil Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Reservoir (Located On Top of Front Cover)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High Pressure Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High Pressure Lines</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder Head High Pressure Oil Rail</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel Injectors (4)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main Oil Gallery (Crankcase)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Control Pressure Regulator</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f120in21" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1091.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>ECM, IDM and IPR Configuration</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>The T 444E system utilizes a hydraulically actuated injector to pressurize fuel inside the injector.
                The hydraulic fluid used to actuate the injector is engine oil.
            </para>
            <para>Oil is drawn from the oil pan through the pick up tube by the engine oil pump. The engine oil pump is
                a gerotor type pump driven by the crankshaft. Oil is fed through passages in the front cover to an oil
                reservoir mounted on top of the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir makes available a constant supply of oil to a high pressure hydraulic pump mounted in
                the engine "V." The high pressure pump is a gear driven seven plunger swash plate pump. High pressure
                oil is delivered by the high pressure pump, through high pressure oil lines, to oil galleries machined
                into the cylinder heads. Drilled intersecting passages supply high pressure oil to the fuel injectors.
            </para>
            <para>This high pressure oil is utilized by the Hydraulically actuated Electronically controlled Unit
                Injectors (HEUI) when the solenoid is energized to pressurize and atomize the fuel into the combustion
                chamber. After injection is complete, the solenoid is de-energized and the oil inside the injector is
                vented through the top portion of the injector, splashed on the valve train and allowed to drain back
                into the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>The injection control pressure system is a closed loop operating system. The system consists of the
                Electronic Control Module (ECM), Injector Driver Module (IDM), Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor,
                Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM is programmed with an injection pressure control strategy which determines the correct
                injection control pressure at each engine operating condition. The ECM receives a 0 - 5 volt (DC) analog
                feedback signal from the ICP sensor located in the high pressure oil supply gallery on the left cylinder
                head that indicates Injection Control Pressure information. The ECM processes this signal and controls
                Injection Control Pressure by controlling the ground to the IPR valve.
            </para>
            <para>The IDM is a device that performs four major functions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Electronic distributor for the injectors.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The IDM receives a signal from the ECM to control injector timing and the quantity of fuel
                        that is delivered by each injector.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Power source for the injectors.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The IDM supplies a constant 115 + volt (DC) supply to all injectors.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Output driver for the injectors.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The IDM controls when, and how long the injector is turned on by closing the circuit to ground
                        by the use of output driver transistors.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Performs diagnostics for itself and the injectors.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The IDM identifies if and injector is drawing too much or too little current and sends a fault
                        code to the ECM. It also sends a fault code if the self test indicates IDM failure.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Injection Pressure Control</title>
            <figure id="f120in22" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1265.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Closed Loop Operation Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECM controls the injection control pressure by operating the IPR valve. The result of this control
                is continuously monitored by the ECM using the ICP sensor. The pressure signal obtained from the ICP
                allows the ECM to know the actual injection control pressure at all times of engine operation, even
                during cranking mode. This operation is known as "Closed Loop."
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic codes can be set by the ECM if the ICP electrical signal is out of range or if the ICP
                signal received corresponds to an out of range value for the injection control pressure at a given
                operating condition.
            </para>
            <para>Should any of these occur, the ECM will ignore the ICP signal and control the IPR valve operation from
                previously programmed default values. This condition is known as an "Open Loop."
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IPR Valve Operation</title>
            <para>The IPR valve is a pulse width (duty cycle %) modulated valve operating at 400 Hz. The pulse width is
                modulated between 8 and 60% to control ICP pressure. The regulator is mounted in the high pressure pump.
                The regulator maintains the desired injection control pressure by dumping excess oil through an internal
                shuttle spool valve into the front cover and back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>As the demand for injection control pressure increases, the ECM increases the pulse width (duty cycle
                %) over the IPR solenoid. This action forces the poppet against the drain hole, thereby increasing the
                pressure behind the spool valve.
            </para>
            <para>As oil pressure increases behind the spool valve, it moves forward and blocks the drain ports on the
                sides of the IPR valve .
            </para>
            <para>When the demand for injection control pressure decreases, the ECM decreases the pulse width (duty
                cycle %) over the solenoid allowing oil to drain out of the drain hole. This is accomplished by
                relieving the pressure behind the spool valve. This reduction in pressure allows the spool valve to
                partially open the relief port, decreasing the injection control pressure .
            </para>
            <para>The described operation allows the IPR to continuously adjust the injection control pressure commanded
                by the ECM.
            </para>
            <figure id="f120in23" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1266.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>IPR Higher Injection Pressure Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f120in24" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1267.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>IPR Lower Injection Pressure Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
