<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Engine
        Lubrication System - Oil Flow
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="1">
        <title>Oil Flow</title>
        <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Lubrication system</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Sump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase breather assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil filter</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure regulator valve</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil reservoir for high-pressure pump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">To high-pressure oil system</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Cam bearing</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Main bearings</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Piston cooling tube (6)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Connecting rods</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Rocker arm shaft</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Unfiltered oil is drawn from the oil pan through the pickup tube and front cover passage by the crankshaft
            driven oil pump. Pressurized oil is forced through a front cover passage, into the crankcase gallery, and to
            the oil system module assembly. Oil flow at the oil system module assembly is controlled by the oil thermal
            valve assembly.
        </para>
        <para>The thermal valve assembly allows unfiltered oil to bypass the oil cooler when the oil temperature is
            cold, and flow directly to the oil filter. As the oil temperature begins to warm, the thermal valve assembly
            begins to open. This allows unfiltered oil to flow into the oil cooler and oil filter.
        </para>
        <para>When the oil temperature is hot, the thermal valve assembly allows unfiltered oil to flow through the oil
            cooler before entering the oil filter.
        </para>
        <para>Unfiltered oil moves through plates in the oil cooler heat exchanger. Engine coolant flows around the
            plates to cool the surrounding oil.
        </para>
        <para>Oil that exits or bypasses the oil cooler mixes and enters the spin-on oil filter. Oil flows from outside
            the filter element towards the inside to remove debris. When the filter is restricted, the oil filter bypass
            (located in the oil system module assembly) opens and allows oil to bypass the filter to maintain engine
            lubrication. The filter bypass valve opens when pressure reaches 345 kPa (50 psi).
        </para>
        <para>After passing through the filter, the oil travels past the oil pressure regulator. The regulator directs
            excess oil back to the oil pan to maintain oil pressure at a maximum of 379 kPa (55 psi).
        </para>
        <para>Clean regulated oil enters the main oil gallery of the engine to lubricate the crankshaft, camshaft, and
            tappets. The crankshaft has cross-drillings that direct oil to the connecting rods.
        </para>
        <para>Oil is also provided to the high-pressure reservoir through a passage in the front cover.</para>
        <para>Piston cooling jets continuously direct cooled oil to the bottom of the piston crowns.</para>
        <para>Oil from the main oil gallery exits upwards through a passage at the rear of the crankcase. Oil flows
            through a passage in the cylinder head and enters the hollow rocker shaft which lubricates the rocker arms.
        </para>
        <para>The crankcase breather assembly is driven by unfiltered oil pressure taken from the right side of the
            crankcase. Oil flows from the crankcase into the breather assembly. Passages direct the oil through a
            pressed brass nozzle that controls oil flow into a drive wheel. Oil drains into the base and mixes with
            waste oil from the breather system. The collected oil drains into the crankcase and then into the oil pan.
        </para>
        <para>The turbocharger is lubricated with filtered oil from a supply tube assembly that connects the oil system
            module assembly to the center housing of the turbocharger. Oil drains back to the oil pan through a drain
            tube connected to the crankcase.
        </para>
        <para>The optional air compressor is lubricated with filtered engine oil through a flexible hose. The hose is
            connected to a tee on the left side of the crankcase near the Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) sensor. Oil drains
            into the front cover and to the oil pan. Oil can also drain from the bottom of the air compressor through a
            tube into the crankcase.
        </para>
        <para>The front gear train is splash lubricated with oil that drains from the high-pressure reservoir and the
            optional air compressor.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
