<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - INTRODUCTION - Engine Description
        - Fuel Injector
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Fuel Injector</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The fuel injector is a unitized fuel injector that is hydraulically actuated and electronically
                controlled.
            </para>
            <para>Hydraulic actuation is accomplished when the injector solenoid is energized, opening a poppet valve
                and allowing ICP pressure to flow on top of the intensifier piston.
            </para>
            <para>Fuel is supplied to the injector by passages drilled through the cylinder head that intersect fill
                ports in the injector.
            </para>
            <para>The area under the intensifier piston plunger is filled with fuel from pressure supplied by the
                transfer pump. As the plunger moves down, the increase in pressure closes the fuel inlet check ball.
                Pressure continues to rise until the nozzle valve pressure setting is overcome. Fuel is pressurized
                through the nozzle orifices and atomized into the combustion chamber. Injection is terminated when the
                solenoid is de-energized and ICP pressure is released.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Solenoid</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The solenoid is a very fast acting electromagnet that, when energized, pulls the poppet valve off its
                seat.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Poppet Valve</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The poppet valve is held on its seat by a spring. In this closed position, high pressure inlet oil is
                blocked and the intensifier cavity is opened to drain.
            </para>
            <para>When the solenoid is energized, the poppet is quickly lifted off its seat. The passage to the drain is
                closed and the inlet for high pressure oil is opened.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Intensifier Piston and Plunger</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the poppet valve opens the inlet port, high pressure oil enters the injector and acts on the top
                of the intensifier piston. Pressure builds on the intensifier, pushing it and the plunger down. The
                intensifier is seven times larger in surface area than the plunger. This difference allows for an equal
                multiplication of force. The downward movement of the plunger pressurizes the fuel in the plunger
                cavity, causing the nozzle to open.
            </para>
            <figure id="f120in26" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Injector Component Location</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Solenoid</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Poppet Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intensifier Piston</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Check Ball</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Nozzle Assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Nozzle Valve</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>On engines with Serial Number 460194 and lower, the injection operation is divided into three stages
                or cycles:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Fill stage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection stage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>End of injection</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f120in27" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1268A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Stages of Injector Operation, Engines With Serial Number 460194 and Lower</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>During the fill stage, the solenoid is de-energized and the poppet valve is in the closed position.
                This position prevents the flow of high pressure oil to the intensifier piston. At this point the
                intensifier piston is in the upper position allowing fuel supply to enter and fill the nozzle of the
                injector.
            </para>
            <para>Once the ECM commands injection, the solenoid is energized and the injection stage is initiated. Such
                action rapidly lifts the poppet valve from its seat, allowing high pressure oil to enter the injector.
                At the intensifier piston, the pressure is transmitted from the high pressure oil to the fuel, and
                multiplied seven times.
            </para>
            <para>As the fuel pressure increases, check valves prevent the fuel from flowing back to the supply
                manifold. Once the pressure is high enough to lift the nozzle valve, high pressure fuel is atomized and
                forced into the combustion chamber.
            </para>
            <para>Once the injection stage is completed, the ECM de-energizes the solenoid, the poppet valve,
                intensifier piston and nozzle valve return to their closed position and the injector returns to the fill
                stage.
            </para>
            <para>Engines with Serial Numbers 460195 and up are equipped with split shot injectors. The injection
                operation is divided into two stages or cycles.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Pre-injection</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Primary injection</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f120in28" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1269.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Stages of Injector Operation, Engines With Serial Number 460195 and Up</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>On these injectors the injection cycle is executed in two stages. Some fuel is pre-injected into the
                combustion chamber to initiate the combustion. Following combustion initiation, the primary injection
                takes place. This feature reduces emission levels during light load operations. It also reduces light
                load engine noise.
            </para>
            <para>Both the electrical and the hydraulic portions of the Split-Shot Injector operate identically to the
                regular HEUI injector except for the fuel distribution.
            </para>
            <para>The barrel and plunger were redesigned and a spill port was incorporated. When injection is initiated,
                the first shot of fuel is pre-injected into the combustion chamber. Pre-injection is complete when the
                spill port of the plunger coincides with the slot on the barrel.
            </para>
            <para>At this time, some fuel is allowed to return to the fuel supply port until the spill port slot is once
                again blocked by the plunger and the primary injection stroke takes place.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
