<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Systems - Inlet Air Heater Control System</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.6" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Inlet Air Heater Control System</title>
        <figure id="f3050155" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/J31146.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
            <caption>Inlet air heater control system</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The inlet air heater control system warms the incoming air to aid cold engine starting and reduce exhaust
            emissions during warm-up.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM energizes the inlet air heater, by energizing inlet air heater relay while monitoring programmed
            conditions for engine operating temperature, inlet air temperature, and atmospheric pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM controls the WAIT TO START lamp and inlet air heater relay separately.</para>
        <para>The engine is ready to start when the WAIT TO START lamp is turned off by the ECM. The ECM will turn the
            inlet air heater on for a predetermined amount of time, based on EOT, IAT, and BAP. The inlet air heater can
            remain on while the engine is running to reduce exhaust emissions and white smoke during engine warm-up.
        </para>
        <para>If the EOT is above 70 &#176;C (158 &#176;F) the inlet air heater will not reactivate when restarting the
            engine unless the IAT is 15 &#176;C (59 &#176;F) or colder.
        </para>
        <para>Once the engine starts to crank, the IAH is turned off. Depending on factory calibration once the engine
            starts the IAH can be reactivated for a calibrated amount of time.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050102.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
