<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - POWER CYLINDERS - Cleaning and Inspection - Connecting Rod Bore
        Out-of-round and Taper Check
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s26507.2.5" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Connecting Rod Bore Out-of-round and Taper Check</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, check connecting rod bolts for binding. Bolts should thread into
                    connecting rod freely, when lubricated with clean engine oil. If not, discard the connecting rod.
                    Connecting rod threads cannot be retapped, if binding. Check thread condition carefully during
                    inspection.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate connecting rod bolts with clean engine oil. Assemble cap to rod without bearing
                insert. Tighten bolts to special torque .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f2650716" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd04/D0421.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Measurement for out-of-round of bore of connecting rod bearing</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a telescoping gauge , measure connecting rod at two locations, 90&#176; apart.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the difference between dimension A and B exceeds out-of-round specifications , replace
                connecting rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f2650717" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd04/D0406.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Measurement for bore taper of connecting rod</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure connecting rod taper as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Insert a telescoping gauge near chamfer on either side.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Measure inner diameter of connecting rod bearing bore near chamfer on other side.</para>
                <para>The difference between the two readings is the connecting rod bore taper. If connecting rod bore
                    taper exceeds specification , replace connecting rod.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With connecting rod cap removed, inspect surface finish of connecting rod bearing bore. Bore
                must be smooth and free of scoring, nicks or burrs. Replace as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_141.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_143.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
