<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Fuel System - Installation - Priming
        Fuel System After Out of Fuel
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="prime" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Priming Fuel System After Out of Fuel</title>
        <figure id="h11033.webp" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh11/h11033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Fuel filter components and schrader valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Water drain valve</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter cover</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter header</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Drain valve (fuel)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel primer pump assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel valve assembly (air bleed and pressure test port)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, make sure the
                    transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set and wheels are blocked before doing diagnostic or
                    service procedures on engine or vehicle.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not add fuel to the fuel filter header, this can add contaminates to the fuel.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>If the engine runs out of fuel, do the following:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set parking brake and place transmission control lever to NEUTRAL or PARK.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unlock the fuel primer pump assembly by turning the knob counter-clockwise.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the fuel filter header with fuel by pumping the fuel primer pump.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To aid in filling the fuel filter header and bleed the fuel rail, do the following:</para>
        </step1>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Bleed the fuel rail by pressing down on the stem of the schrader valve and pumping the fuel primer
                    pump until fuel starts coming out of the schrader valve.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Once the air has bled out of the fuel rail, release the stem of the schrader valve and push the
                    fuel primer pump a couple of more times.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Push the fuel primer pump in one more time and turn the knob clockwise to lock in place.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refer to specific starting procedures in the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_245.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_247.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
