<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT and BEARINGS, CAMSHAFT and BUSHINGS -
        Cleaning, Inspection, and Testing - Crankcase Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s26508.2.1" svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Crankcase Assembly</title>
        <svcsubproc id="s26508.2.1.1">
            <title>Cleaning the Crankcase</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Clean the crankcase in a chemical bath or hot tank. This removes all carbonized material and
                        mineral deposits in coolant passages.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>If a hot tank is not available, do the following steps:</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Thoroughly clean and inspect crankcase before and after reconditioning.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use nonmetallic stiff bristle brushes and scrapers to clean gasket material from
                    machined surfaces of crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean cylinder bore with soap, water, and a nylon stiff bristle brush.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean lower crankcase in solvent.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes.
                        Limit compressed air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650820" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0637.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Removal of oil gallery cup plugs</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Punch</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Hammer</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil gallery cup plug</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove main oil gallery cup plug (in rear of crankcase), use a punch and hammer near
                    edge of plug and strike with a hammer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove plug from crankcase and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650821" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0638.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Main oil gallery</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean main galleries with an Oil Gallery Cleaning Brush .</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use Liquid Gasket (RTV) before installing main oil gallery core plugs.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat edges of new oil gallery cup plugs with liquid gasket. Use an Oil Gallery Plug
                    Driver and install new oil gallery cup plugs. The oil gallery plug driver installs the oil gallery
                    cup plug to the correct depth. It should be flush with the crankcase surface to approximately 1.50
                    mm (0.060 in) below surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, threads in the crankcase bolt holes must be clean and blown dry with
                        filtered compressed air. Dirt or oil left in holes may cause binding and a false torque reading
                        during assembly.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f2650822" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0648.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Cylinder head bolt holes</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean cylinder head bolt holes with a head bolt bottoming tap .</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes.
                        Limit compressed air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Blow out chips with filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s26508.2.1.2">
            <title>Inspecting the Crankcase</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After cleaning, inspect crankcase for cracks, scoring, roughness or wear at cylinder
                    bores.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650823" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0614.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Flatness check for top surface of cylinder block</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Straightedge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Feeler gauge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder block top surface</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a straightedge to check the cylinder block top surface of crankcase (firing deck)
                    for flatness. Insert a feeler gauge between straightedge and crankcase head surface.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure the whole deck surface. If the gap exceeds the specifications , the
                        crankcase must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Divide the deck surface into 150 mm x 150 mm areas and measure each square area. If
                        the gap exceeds the specifications , the crankcase must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Divide the deck surface into 25 mm x 25 mm areas and measure each square area. If
                        the gap exceeds the specifications , the crankcase must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not resurface the crankcase. Surface defects beyond those listed above are not
                        correctable.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cylinder walls have minor surface damage, but are otherwise within out-of-round
                    specifications, it may be possible to remove damage by honing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650824" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0615.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Out-of-round cylinder bore check</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a cylinder bore gauge to check cylinder bore out-of-round conditions.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure diameter of cylinder bore at top of piston ring travel. Be sure to measure
                        at a right angle to the center line of crankshaft (dimension A). Record reading.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure each bore so gauge reading coincides with center line of crankshaft
                        (dimension B). Record reading.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The difference between dimension A and dimension B is the out-of-round condition at
                        the top of the cylinder bore.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the same procedure at the bottom of ring travel to check for out-of-round
                    condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, if cylinder bores are deeply scored, out-of-round or exceeds
                        specifications, all cylinders must be bored out to an oversize dimension.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cylinder bore is within specifications , standard size pistons and rings may be
                    used.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If cylinder bore is suitable for use without reconditioning, deglaze the cylinder bore
                            before assembling. See Cylinder deglazing in this section for further details.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s26508.2.1.3">
            <title>Cylinder Deglazing</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Piston cooling tubes must be removed before deglazing cylinder bores.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a Deglazing Hone (four-inch) to deglaze the cylinder bore. This silicone
                    carbide-tipped nylon flexible brush quickly deglazes cylinder walls and produces a crosshatch
                    pattern on the cylinder wall surface in a single operation. The brush contours itself to the
                    cylinder wall and conditions wall surface without altering cylinder bore.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650825" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd06/D0618.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Deglazing Hone</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray cylinder and Deglazing Hone with penetrating fluid or equivalent. This spray
                    contains colloidal graphite and works well.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach Deglazing Hone to a variable speed electric or air powered drill.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For a successful procedure 100 to 120 rpm is required.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Deglaze cylinder wall for about 15 seconds. Stroke bore up and down at a rate of one
                    complete up and down stroke per second.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Withdraw deglazing hone from cylinder bore while rotating. Wipe portion of cylinder wall
                    and inspect cross hatch pattern.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The cross hatch pattern left by the abrasive tool should be approximately 45&#176;.</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>If pattern is "flatter" than required, increase up and down stroke speed or slow down
                                drill rotation as required.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue deglazing cylinder bore for 10 to 15 seconds or 20 to 25 strokes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe cylinder bore clean and inspect bore for correct 45&#176; cross hatch pattern.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After deglazing, thoroughly clean cylinder bores with soft bristle brush, soap and
                    water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes.
                        Limit compressed air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate bores with clean engine oil</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_158.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_160.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
