<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System -
        Sensors and Switches
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.4" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Sensors and Switches</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermistor Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3050146" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Thermistor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Thermistor sensors:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Temperature (EGT)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Thermistor sensors change electrical resistance with changes in temperature. Resistance in the
                thermistor decreases as temperature increases, and increases as temperature decreases. Thermistors work
                with a resistor that limits current in the ECM to form a voltage signal matched with a temperature
                value.
            </para>
            <para>The top half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor inside the ECM. Thermistor
                sensors have two electrical connectors, signal return and ground. The output of a thermistor sensor is a
                nonlinear analog signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) Sensor</title>The ECM monitors the EOT signal to control fuel
                quantity and inlet air heater operation. The EOT signal allows the ECM to compensate for differences in
                oil viscosity as oil temperature changes. The EOT sensor is installed in the oil filter base.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) Sensor</title>The ECM monitors the ECT signal and uses this
                information for the instrument panel temperature gauge, coolant compensation, Engine Warning Protection
                System (EWPS), and glow plug operation. The ECM will use ECT sensor input as a backup, if EOT sensor
                values are out of range. The ECT sensor is installed in the left side of the front cover assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT) Sensor</title>The ECM monitors the MAT signal for EGR operation.
                The MAT sensor is installed in the left side of the intake manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Intake Air Temperature (IAT) Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the IAT signal to control fuel timing and rate during cold starts. The IAT sensor is
                mounted in the turbocharger air intake, between the inlet of the turbocharger and the air filter.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Exhaust Gas Temperature (EGT) Sensors</title>
            </para>
            <para>Three EGT sensors are used in the aftertreatment system.</para>
            <para>The EGT1 sensor provides a signal to the ECM indicating Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC) inlet
                temperature. The EGT1 sensor is the first temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and just
                before the DOC.
            </para>
            <para>The EGT2 sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) inlet
                temperature. The EGT2 sensor is the second temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and just
                after the DOC.
            </para>
            <para>The EGT3 sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating DPF outlet temperature. The EGT3
                sensor is the third temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and just after the DPF.
            </para>
            <para>During catalyst regeneration, the ECM monitors all three EGT sensors and adjusts the Intake Throttle
                Valve (ITV) and Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve as needed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Variable Capacitance Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35157.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Variable capacitance sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Variable capacitance sensors:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Differential Pressure (EGDP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors measure pressure. When pressure is applied to the sensor a ceramic
                material is forced closer to a thin metal disk which changes the capacitance of the sensor.
            </para>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors are connected to the ECM by three wires:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>VREF</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal ground</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The sensor receives the VREF and returns an analog signal voltage to the ECM. The ECM compares the
                voltage with pre-programmed values to determine pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The operational range of a variable capacitance sensor is linked to the thickness of the ceramic disk.
                The thicker the ceramic disk the more pressure the sensor can measure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Exhaust Gas Differential Pressure (EGDP) Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EGDP sensor provides a signal to the ECM indicating the pressure difference between the inlet and
                outlet of the Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF). During catalyst regeneration, the ECM monitors this
                sensor, three Exhaust Gas Temperature (EGT) sensors, the EGR System, and the Intake Throttle Valve
                (ITV).
            </para>
            <para>The EGDP sensor is a differential pressure sensor with two tap-offs installed past the turbocharger. A
                tap-off is located before and after the DPF.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors exhaust back pressure to control turbocharger, EGR, and intake throttle systems. The
                EBP sensor is installed in a tube connected to the left exhaust manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the MAP signal to determine intake manifold pressure (boost). This information is
                used to control the turbocharger boost. The MAP sensor is installed in the intake manifold, left of the
                MAT sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050150" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31034.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>MSG sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Micro strain gauge sensor:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) sensor measures pressure. Pressure exerts force on a pressure vessel that
                stretches and compresses to change resistance of strain gauges bonded to the surface of the pressure
                vessel. Internal sensor electronics convert the changes in resistance to a ratiometric voltage output.
            </para>
            <para>The Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>VREF</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal ground</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The sensor is powered by VREF received from the ECM and is grounded through the ECM to a common sensor
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Sensor</title>The ICP sensor measures injection control
                pressure. The ECM monitors the ICP signal for closed loop control of the Injection Pressure Regulator
                (IPR) valve. The ICP sensor is installed through the right side valve cover in the oil high-pressure oil
                rail.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Potentiometer</title>
            <figure id="f3050152" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31036.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Potentiometer</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Potentiometer:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>APS</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A potentiometer is a variable voltage divider that senses the position of a mechanical component. A
                reference voltage is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical rotary or linear motion moves
                the wiper along the resistance material, changing voltage at each point along the resistive material.
                Voltage is proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</title>The APS provides the ECM with a feedback signal (linear
                analog voltage) that indicates the operator's demand for power. The APS is mounted in the accelerator
                pedal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Magnetic Pickup Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3050151" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figN35/N35106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Magnetic pickup</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Magnetic pickup sensors:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Crankshaft Position (CKP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position (CMP)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Magnetic pickup sensors generate an alternating frequency that indicates speed. Magnetic pickups have
                a two wire connection for signal and ground. This sensor has a permanent magnetic core surrounded by a
                wire coil. The signal frequency is generated by the rotation of gear teeth that disturb the magnetic
                field.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Crankshaft Position (CKP) Sensor</title>The CKP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that
                indicates crankshaft speed and position. As the crankshaft turns the CKP sensor detects a 60 tooth
                timing disk on the crankshaft. Teeth 59 and 60 are missing. By comparing the CKP signal with the CMP
                signal, the ECM calculates engine rpm and timing requirements. The CKP is installed in the front right
                side of the lower crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Camshaft Position (CMP) Sensor</title>The CMP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that
                indicates camshaft position. As the cam rotates, the sensor identifies the position of the cam by
                locating a peg on the cam. The CMP is installed in the front left side of the lower crankcase.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Switches</title>
            <figure id="f3050153" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31037.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Switch</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Switches:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS) (transmission select)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Water In Fuel (WIF)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) switch</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Switches indicate position or condition. They operate OPEN or closed, allowing or preventing the flow
                of current. A switch can be a voltage input switch or a grounding switch. A voltage input switch
                supplies the ECM with a voltage when it is closed. A grounding switch grounds the circuit when closed,
                causing a zero voltage signal. Grounding switches are usually installed in series with a current
                limiting resistor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</title>The Transmission Control Module (TCM) monitors the
                transmission shifter position. A signal from the TCM functions as the DDS signal to the ECM. A manual
                transmission application will have a clutch switch for the DDS signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>The IVS is a redundant switch that provides the ECM with a
                signal that verifies when the APS is in the idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Water In Fuel (WIF) Switch</title>
                A WIF switch detects water in the fuel filter of the HFCM. When enough water accumulates in the filter
                housing, the WIF switch sends a signal to the ECM. The ECM sets a Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC) and
                illuminates the amber water in fuel lamp (fuel pump next to a fuel tank) on the right side of the
                instrument panel. The WIF switch is installed in the HFCM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Switch</title>The ECM monitors the EOP signal for reference only. The
                ECM uses the EOP signal to control EWPS warning and lights the red Stop Engine Lamp for low oil
                pressure. The EOP switch closes a circuit to ground when the engine oil pressure reaches 34 to 48 kPa (5
                to 7 psi). The EOP switch is installed in the oil filter base assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Coolant Level (ECL) Switch</title>The ECL is part of the Engine Warning Protection System
                (EWPS). The ECL switch is used in plastic deaeration tanks. When a magnetic switch is OPEN, the tank is
                full.
            </para>
            <para>If engine coolant is low, the red Stop Engine Lamp on the instrument panel is illuminated.</para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) switch</title>The ECM monitors the EFP to detect low fuel supply
                pressure. If fuel supply pressure drops below 30 psi, due to a fuel filter restriction or other problem,
                the ECM reduces ICP pressure to 14 MPa. The EFP is installed in the secondary fuel filter housing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_39.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
