<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS AND ACCESSORIES - Using Master Diagnostics (MD
        32) - Text Window and Adding Parameter Identifiers (PID)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="11">
        <title>Text Window and Adding Parameter Identifiers (PID)</title>
        <para>To monitor engine parameter data in text format, first create a text window.</para>
        <figure id="f17505053" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8661.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select File and then New on the menu bar to open the Select a File Type dialog box.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505054" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8662.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select International Text View (.ntv) and click on OK.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505055" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8663.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <para>An empty Text View display window will appear. Text view windows have three columns: PID, Value, and
            Units. The PID column shows the PID description or acronym. The Value column shows the current data value.
            The Units column shows the display value units (English or metric).
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505056" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8665.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To add parameters to this window, right click in the window, then select Add/Delete
                Parameters on the pop-up menu.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505060" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8668.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <step1 id="p17505076.1">
            <para count="1">To add parameters to the Selected Parameter list box, double click on a parameter or click
                on all of the desired parameters in the Available Parameter list box. Then click the >>ADD>>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>The order in which PIDs are displayed in the Text View window is dependent on when a parameter is added to
            the Selected Parameter list. For example, a double click on the Fuel Rate first and then Fueling Pulse
            Width, then Fuel Rate will be displayed on top of Fueling Pulse Width in the Text View window. Use the
            vertical scroll bar to view additional parameters in the Available Parameters list box.
        </para>
        <para>Double clicking a parameter in the Selected Parameter list will remove it from the Text View window.
        </para>
        <para>To recall the original settings, click on the Defaults button to restore the attributes to the factory
            defaults.
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505062" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8670.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When done adding or deleting parameters and modifying the attributes, click the OK button in
                the ADD/DELETE PARAMETERS dialog box. The text window will display the selected parameters.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505068" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8676.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <para>This Text View window is configured and ready to be used. Opening the COM port at this time will allow the
            data to be displayed. The resulting window illustrates some parameter values (static data w/engine off).
        </para>
        <para>By clicking on Units, the units of all the displayed parameters can be toggled between metric or
            English.
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505071" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8679.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To print the information in these Text View windows, select File and then Print on the menu
                bar.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505072" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8680.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <para>The printout can be sent to the printer or to a file.</para>
        <figure id="f17505073" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8681.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The configuration of these Text Views may be saved for later retrieval; the list of
                displayed parameters, font size, and type information is saved. The actual parameter data is not part of
                the configuration. Click File on the menu bar and then click Save As.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f17505074" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8682.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
        </figure>
        <para>The Save As file dialog box will appear. Type a file name inside the File name edit box and click Save
            button.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_205.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_207.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
