<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS -
        DIAGNOSING SCUFFED INJECTORS - Key-On Engine-Running Injector Test
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="P17504001" svcproctype="svcproc" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Key-On Engine-Running Injector Test</title>
        <para>The injector test is designed to detect problems with injection and combustion events. Performing a
            cylinder contribution test will analyze the individual contribution of each of the power cylinders. Its
            primary function is to detect a bad injector. The test will also detect problems that could affect the
            overall performance of the power cylinders (i.e.: valves, pushrods, pistons, rings, etc.).
        </para>
        <para>During this test the ECM will control fuel delivery and determine each cylinder's power contribution. If a
            cylinder is not performing satisfactorily, a Diagnostic Trouble Code will be set.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1750402" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg9/Eg9017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Good Cylinder Contribution Test Recording</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Some of the key areas to examine on the graphical display of the cylinder contribution test are:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the test begins, the engine speed increases in increments up to 850 rpm.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The ECM increases fuel delivery to cylinder #1 (over-fuels) which causes engine speed to
                increase.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fuel is reduced to remaining cylinders to maintain 850 rpm</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The ECM decreases fuel delivery to cylinder #1 (under-fuels) which causes engine speed to
                decrease.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fuel is increased to the remaining cylinders to maintain 850 rpm</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">At this point 2 key observations are noted:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM compares fuel delivery of the remaining 5 cylinders during over-fuel condition</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM compares fuel delivery of remaining 5 cylinders during under-fuel condition</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the difference is not what the ECM expects, a DTC is set for non-contributing cylinder. The
                procedure will repeat for the remaining cylinders until the test is complete.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The engine speed returns to low idle. The test is complete</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>During the cylinder contribution test, the fuel rate graph represents fuel delivery to the
                    remaining 5 cylinders.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The cylinder contribution test begins with cylinder #1 (front cylinder) and is performed sequentially. The
            rpm fluctuation on engines with more than one severely scuffed injector can be enough to stop the cylinder
            contribution test.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_120.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_122.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
