<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Symptoms Diagnostics - Test Procedures - Coolant
        Over-Temperature
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010402.6" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Coolant Over-Temperature</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010402.6.1">
            <table id="t305010404" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>Causes</title>
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low engine coolant level</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>External coolant leaks</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Internal or external radiator blockage</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Broken/worn drive belt</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Belt tensioner failure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Coolant thermostat missing or stuck (closed)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Slipping cooling fan drive clutch</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Water pump failure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cooling fan blade assembly wrong or damaged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor biased</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Incorrect radiator</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Internal coolant leak</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Chassis effects, transmission, or after-market equipment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010402.6.2">
            <title>Inspection for Coolant Over-Temperature Conditions</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check coolant deaeration tank for correct fill level.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant level is low, look for external leaks at radiator, engine, and all coolant
                            related hoses.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the condition of the following items: cooling fan blade, shroud, accessory drive
                    belt, accessory drive belt tensioner, cooling fan drive clutch, and radiator.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If vehicle is new or recently repaired, verify the correct part number for any component
                            related to the cooling system.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify that the cooling fan blade, cooling fan drive clutch, and radiator are clean of
                            debris and dirt build-up. Clean areas as required.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid radiator damage, when using high pressure washer, be careful not to get wand to
                            close to radiator fins.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install Electronic Service Tool (EST) and check for active and inactive Diagnostic
                    Trouble Codes (DTC) related to engine coolant over-temp conditions.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Using the EST, compare Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT), Engine Oil Temperature (EOT),
                            Manifold Air Temperature (MAT), and Intake Air Temperature (IAT) with Key On Engine Off. All
                            of the sensors should read within 2 &#176;C (5 &#176;F) of each other.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This is only accurate if done after a cold soak of at least eight hours on the engine.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run engine up to an operating temperature of at least 70 &#176;C (158 &#176;F). Monitor
                    ECT using the EST.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attempt to duplicate the operator's concern of coolant over-temperature.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid radiator damage, when using high pressure washer, be careful not to get wand too
                            close to radiator fins.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If concern cannot be duplicated, clean radiator fins (if not done previously). Flush the
                            radiator fins with water on the cooling fan side of the radiator. Do not continue further
                            with diagnostics.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant over-temperature is duplicated, continue with step 6.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death from hot coolant or steam scalding, use the following
                        procedure to remove the pressure cap from the cooling system. Allow the engine to cool. Wrap a
                        thick cloth around the cap. Unscrew cap slowly, then pause to allow pressure to release.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow procedure in the above warning to remove cooling system pressure cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the radiator Vacuum Pump and Gauge (ZTSE7559) on the deaeration tank and run
                    engine at elevated idle. Monitor the pressure in the system using the tester gauge to see if
                    pressure rises above normal value of deaeration tank cap.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If pressure is higher than the pressure rating of the cooling system cap, continue with "
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_65.xml" xrefid="s305010402.2.1">Combustion Leak to Coolant
                            </hotlnk>
                            " in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If pressure gauge reading is below pressure rating of system, continue with step 8.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and inspect thermostat following the procedure in the Engine Service Manual.
                    Check for opening temperature.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace as needed. Retest for condition after repair.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If thermostat passes test, continue with step 9.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use vehicle diagnostics manual to review automatic transmission diagnostics.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If over-temperature condition remains, remove radiator and have flow checked at radiator
                    shop.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Retest engine for over-temperature condition with repaired or replaced radiator.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_68.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_70.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
