<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT, CONNECTING
        RODS AND PISTONS - Connecting Rods, Pistons and Piston Rings - Check Connecting Rod Bearing Bore for
        Out-of-Round and Taper
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Check Connecting Rod Bearing Bore for Out-of-Round and Taper</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When lubricated with clean engine oil, the rod nuts must thread onto the connecting rod studs by
                    hand. If excessive resistance is felt, clean the connecting rod threads and try a new nut. If the
                    new nut does not thread on freely, the connecting rod bolt must be replaced. Failure to do so may
                    result in engine damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the connecting rod nuts with clean engine oil. Assemble the cap to the rod with
                the bearing insert removed. Tighten the nuts to the special torque value.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1200732" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8034.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="392px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Measuring the Connecting Rod Bearing Bore for Out-of-Round</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Inside Micrometer</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Bearing Insert Removed</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Torque Nuts To Special Torque</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use an inside micrometer (telescoping gauge) to measure the connecting rod at three
                locations approximately 120&#176; apart. Label them A, B and C.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the difference between micrometer reading "B" and the average of reading "A" and reading
                "C" exceeds the out-of-round specification, the connecting rod must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">[(A+C)&#247;2] - B = actual reading</emph>
                (If the result is negative, disregard the negative sign.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the connecting rod bearing bore taper by measuring the bore inner diameter near the
                large chamfer. Record the reading. Then measure the bore inner diameter near the small chamfer. Record
                the reading.
            </para>
            <para>The difference between the two readings is the bore taper. If the connecting rod exceeds the
                specification, replace the connecting rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the connecting rod cap removed, inspect the surface finish of the connecting rod
                bearing bore. The bore must be smooth and free of scoring, nicks and burrs. Replace as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_178.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_180.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
