<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Symptoms Diagnostics - Test Procedures - Rough Idle</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010402.14" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Rough Idle</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010402.14.1">
            <table id="t305010411" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>Causes</title>
                <tgroup cols="1" align="left">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine oil (aerated, incorrect grade, low oil level, extended drain interval)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Poor fuel quality</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low fuel pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Aerated fuel</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Electronic control system faults (ECM and IDM)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system problems</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel injectors not working properly</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve stuck open</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power cylinder problems</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Valve train problems</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine or flywheel balance problems</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Exhaust system to cab or chassis ground out</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Loose or worn engine mounts</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Mismatched balance shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010402.14.2">
            <title>Diagnostics for Verifying Rough Idle</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify complaint. Confirm conditions when complaint is present.</para>
                <para>When does engine rough idle occur?</para>
                <table id="t305010412" frame="topbot">
                    <tgroup cols="1" align="left">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Hot - operating temperature</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Cold</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>After high speed operation</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Over entire engine speed range</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Combination of the above conditions</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Is there chassis vibration or any other conditions or observations present
                                        when engine idles rough.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect exhaust system for contact with frame or body of vehicle.</para>
                <para>Engine exhaust pipe contact with cab may transmit engine vibrations to cab, especially on
                    acceleration or engine shifts. This condition may be incorrectly diagnosed as a rough idle
                    complaint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Complete the following tests on the Performance Diagnostic Form. See the "
                <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                " section in this manual for specific details on each test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_98.xml" xrefid="tp305010601">Test 1. Diagnostic Trouble Codes</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. Intermittent sensor, injector, or
                    wiring harness faults can affect engine idle conditions. The ECM may have detected and recorded
                    these conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_99.xml" xrefid="tp305010602">Test 2. KOEO Standard Test</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. The KOEO Standard test will verify
                    electrical operation of actuators.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_100.xml" xrefid="tp305010603">Test 3. KOEO Injector Test</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. This test will verify that the
                    injectors are working properly electronically.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_101.xml" xrefid="tp305010604">Test 4. Engine Oil</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. Check engine oil level. Verify
                    correct oil grade for ambient temperature. See Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Engine
                    Lubrication Requirements section. Confirm oil meets correct API specification for model and year of
                    engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_102.xml" xrefid="tp305010605.1">Test 5. Fuel Supply System</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. Verify quality and quantity of
                    diesel fuel, fuel aeration, and fuel pressure. Poor quality fuel or low cetane rating can cause
                    white smoke, engine misfire, and low power. See Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Fuel
                    Requirements section for model and year of engine to determine minimum necessary fuel grade and
                    cetane rating.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_104.xml" xrefid="tp305010607">Test 7. KOER Standard Test</hotlnk>
                    in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_105.xml" xrefid="tp305010608">Test 8. Injection Control Pressure</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. This test will verify the
                    functionality of the ICP system. The engine must be at operating temperature 70 &#176;C (158 &#176;F)to
                    do this test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_106.xml" xrefid="tp305010609">Test 9. Injector Disable</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. This test will confirm if the ICP
                    system is functioning properly and verify ICP stability.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Test 9 is used in conjunction with Test 10 to distinguish between an injector and a
                            mechanical problem.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_107.xml" xrefid="tp305010610">Test 10. Relative Compression</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. The primary function of this test
                    is to show the contributions of the individual power cylinders. The test will detect a weak cylinder
                    which could be the result of an injector or base engine problem.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Test 10 is used in conjunction with Test 9 to distinguish between an injector and a
                            mechanical problem.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_108.xml" xrefid="tp305010611">Test 11. Air Management</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics Form. The test will verify EGR valve
                    movement and MAF.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_111.xml" xrefid="tp305010614">Test 14. Crankcase Pressure</hotlnk>
                    " in the "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050106.xml" xrefid="e3050106">Performance Diagnostics</hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual or on the Performance Diagnostics form.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, support the
                        vibration damper during mounting bolt removal. The damper can slide off the nose of the
                        crankshaft very easily.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, replace all vibration mounting bolts when installing the vibration
                        damper. Do not use anti-seize compounds, grease, or any lubricants. Lubricants have a adverse
                        effect on torque results.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to the engine, do not run engine for an extended period with the accessory
                        drive belt removed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for engine and flexplate balance. Engine roughness at idle that gets worse with
                    a no load acceleration may be caused by an out of balance condition. Remove the accessory drive belt
                    to isolate the accessories during balance testing.
                </para>
                <table id="t305010413" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="table" frame="topbot">
                    <title>Engine and Flexplate Balance Inspection</title>
                    <tgroup cols="1">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Isolate the engine from transmission by removing the transmission and torque
                                        converter. Start the engine and evaluate for roughness. If the engine runs
                                        smooth, diagnose the torque convert and transmission, see applicable truck
                                        Service Manual.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the vibration
                                        damper and inspect the elastomer layer for cracks and misalignment. If no
                                        problem is found, reinstall the vibration damper following the exact assembly
                                        procedure in the Engine Service Manual. Verify that locating dowel at the end of
                                        the crankshaft is aligned with the locating hole in the balancer for proper
                                        installation.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the flexplate
                                        and verify proper orientation. If orientation is correct, replace or rebalance
                                        flexplate. When removing or installing the flexplate, ensure that the locating
                                        dowel is in the right place and that the flexplate is located properly on the
                                        dowel.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the front cover,
                                        inspect the primary balancer shaft to ensure it is properly installed.
                                    </para>
                                    <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the rear cover,
                                        to see if the balance shaft is linked correctly.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the lower and
                                        upper oil pan and inspect the crankshaft counterweights to ensure balance holes
                                        exist.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_75.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_77.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
