<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Crankcase, Crankshaft, Connecting
        Rods, And Pistons - Crankshaft and Main Bearings - Main Bearing Fitting Procedure
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Main Bearing Fitting Procedure</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install all of the main bearing caps. Tighten the mounting bolts to the special torque
                value.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove one bearing cap and insert. Leave the remaining caps tight while checking the fit of
                the bearing with the cap removed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the bearing surface and the exposed half of the crankshaft journal. Make sure these
                surfaces are free of oil.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a piece of Plastigage&#174; across the full width of the bearing surface on the
                crankshaft journal or bearing cap insert approximately 6 mm (.250 in) off center. Install the main
                bearing cap and tighten mounting bolts to the special torque value.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not turn the crankshaft while the Plastigage&#174; is on the journal.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>In chassis service only, before checking for bearing oil clearance, the crankshaft must be
                    supported and held up against the upper main insert bearing halves. Failure to do so may result in
                    incorrect oil clearance values and may cause personal injury or engine damage.
                </para>
                <para>Use a jack and a piece of wood around the center of the crankshaft to provide adequate support.
                    The oil clearance checking procedure is performed exactly the same as an engine that is mounted on
                    an engine stand.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the main bearing cap and insert. Do not disturb the Plastigage&#174;.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1200757" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1858.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Checking the Bearing Clearance of the Crankshaft Journal</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Clearance Scale</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Main Bearing Journal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Flattened Plastigage&#174;</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the Plastigage&#174; scale located on the envelope/wrapper, measure the widest point of
                the flattened Plastigage&#174;. This reading indicates the bearing running oil clearance in thousandths
                of an inch or millimeter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the bearing running oil clearance is not within specifications, the crankshaft must be
                replaced or machined and undersized bearings installed. Refer to Crankshaft in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform this procedure for each main bearing. Then continue on to
                <emph type="bold">Installation of Main Bearing Cap</emph>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_191.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_193.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
