<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL&#174; VT 365 DIESEL ENGINE - ELECTRONICALLY CONTROLLED VARIABLE GEOMETRY TURBOCHARGER (VGT) -
        Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Operation</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The key feature of the VGT is actuated vanes in the turbine housing. The vanes modify flow
                characteristics of exhaust gases through the turbine housing. The benefit is the ability to control
                boost pressure needed for various engine speeds and load conditions. An additional benefit is lower
                exhaust emissions.
            </para>
            <para>The VGT is a closed loop system that uses the Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor to provide feedback
                to the Electronic Control Module (ECM). The ECM uses the EBP sensor to continuously monitor EBP and
                adjust the duty cycle to the VGT to match engine requirements.
            </para>
            <para>The solenoid receives a pulse width modulated signal from the ECM that indicates the on / off time
                that the control valve is energized. The control valve directs lube oil flow to both sides of the piston
                in the actuator housing. Directing oil to different sides of the piston increases or decreases exhaust
                back pressure.
            </para>
            <para>Actuated vanes are mounted around the inside circumference of the turbine housing. A unison ring links
                all the vanes. When the unison ring moves, all vanes move to the same position. Unison ring movement
                occurs when either side of the actuator piston is pressurized by engine oil.
            </para>
            <para>Exhaust gas flow can be regulated depending on required exhaust back pressure for engine speed and
                load.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>The VGT is an exhaust driven centrifugal air compressor that uses signals from the ECM to control
                intake manifold pressure. The VGT uses a set of moveable vanes in the turbine housing to change the flow
                of exhaust gases through the VGT. These vanes can be positioned to change the angle or direction of flow
                to the turbine wheel depending on engine operating conditions. As power demands increase, exhaust gas
                velocity increases in direct relation, as does intake manifold boost pressure. Conversely, as the flow
                of exhaust gas diminishes, intake manifold boost pressure is also reduced at the same rate.
            </para>
            <para>Vanes mounted around the internal circumference of the turbine housing are connected to a unison ring.
                When the unison ring moves, all vanes move to the same position. The unison ring moves, when either side
                of the actuator piston receives pressurized engine oil, regulated by the control valve, part of a Pulse
                Width Modulated (PWM) circuit regulated by the ECM. An increase in duty cycle of the PWM circuit routes
                oil through the control valve in a way that will cause piston movement that increases manifold pressure.
                Decreasing the pulse width will direct oil such that the manifold pressure will be decreased. The VGT
                control is a closed loop system using the EBP sensor to provide feedback to the ECM. The ECM provides a
                duty cycle in response to engine speed, engine load, manifold pressure, and barometric pressure in order
                to adjust the duty cycle to match the requirements of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>The VGT increases power output by supplying compressed air to the engine. The internal components are
                oil and air cooled. Engine oil is circulated through the housing, which acts as a heat barrier between
                the "hot" turbine and the "cold" compressor. Sleeve Bearings are lubricated by engine oil. Oil is pumped
                directly from the oil filter base, circulates to the VGT housing, and returns to the sump through an oil
                drain in the VGT center housing.
            </para>
            <para>Expanding exhaust gases drive the turbine shaft assembly to speeds over 100,000 rpm. Filtered air
                entering the compressor side of the VGT is compressed and delivered through a charge air cooler. Hot
                compressed air is cooled, filling the intake manifold at a pressure higher than atmospheric pressure.
                Because considerably more air is forced into the intake manifold, the results are increased power, fuel
                efficiency and the ability to maintain power at higher altitudes.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_E2350203.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
