<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEMS DIAGNOSTICS - Circuit Diagnostics -
        Glow Plug Control (GPC) Circuit
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Glow Plug Control (GPC) Circuit</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3358" filename="../figd33/d3358.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for the Glow Plug Control (GPC) Function</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Function Diagram for the Glow Plug Control system includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Glow plugs</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Glow plug relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Temperature sensor (ECT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Barometric Absolute Pressure sensor (BAP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Battery</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The glow plug control system warms the engine cylinders to aid cold engine starting and reduce exhaust
                emissions during warm-up.
            </para>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) is programmed to energize the glow plugs (through the glow plug
                relay) while monitoring certain programmed conditions for engine coolant temperature and atmospheric
                pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors battery voltage and uses information from the Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)
                sensor and Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor to determine the amount of time that the WAIT TO
                START lamp is ON and the activation time of the glow plugs. The ECM controls the WAIT TO START lamp and
                the activation of the glow plugs separately. The glow plug WAIT TO START lamp indicates when the glow
                plugs have been on long enough to start the engine. The on time normally varies between 2 to 10 seconds.
                The glow plugs are self limiting and do not require cycling on and off. The glow plug relay will only
                cycle on and off repeatedly if system voltage is greater than 14.0 volts.
            </para>
            <para>Glow plugs are activated for a longer time, if the engine is cold or the barometric pressure is low
                (high altitude).
            </para>
            <para>The engine is ready to start when the WAIT TO START lamp is turned off by the ECM. The glow plugs can
                remain on up to 120 seconds while the engine is running to reduce exhaust emissions during engine
                warm-up.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The WAIT TO START lamp on time is independent from the glow plug relay on time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>GPC Circuit Operation</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3359" filename="../figd33/d3359.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"/>
                <caption>Glow Plug Control (GPC) Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The glow plug control system operation on time is dependent upon the ECT, BAP, and battery voltage.
                The glow plug relay is activated by power supplied by the ECM through terminal X1-17 to circuit 97CH.
                The coil of the glow plug relay is grounded through circuit 97IG8, the 12 pin connector and to the
                battery negative terminal. Power is supplied to the switch side of the glow plug relay from the starter
                motor. When the relay coil is energized, power is supplied to the glow plugs which are grounded through
                the cylinder head.
            </para>
            <para>The Wait to Start lamp time is transmitted over the CAN 1 datalink. See truck Chassis Electrical
                Circuit Diagram manual.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            </para>
            <para>An open or short to ground in the glow plug relay circuit can be detected by an on demand Output
                Circuit Check (OCC) performed during the Key ON Engine OFF (KOEO) Standard tests. Glow plug and glow
                plug harness problems can not be detected by the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Glow Plug Control Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTCs are read using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by counting the flashes from the amber and
                red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc251">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 251</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">GPC Output Circuit Check self-test failed.</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 251 is set by the ECM when the OCC test has failed after the KOEO Standard test has been
                        run.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 251 can be set for an open or shorted GPC signal circuit, an open feed circuit, or an open
                        glow plug relay coil.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Tools</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout box</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12 pin breakout harness</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The GPC circuit requires the use of vehicle circuit diagrams. See truck Chassis Electrical
                        Circuit Diagram manual for circuit numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>GPC Pin Point Diagnostics</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3359" filename="../figd33/d3359.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"/>
                <caption>Glow Plug Control (GPC) Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te24007049" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="topbot">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Glow Plug Relay Voltage Checks</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Relay feed to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>B+</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Relay switch power, B+ should be present at all times (terminal with single 6
                                    gauge wire). Check connection at starter or fusible links if no voltage is present.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Glow Plug feed to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>B+</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Glow plug feed voltage should be present 0 to 120 seconds after key is cycled on
                                    (temperature dependent). (large terminal with 3 wires)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97CH to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>B+ or 0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Glow Plug Control ECM commands relay ON = B+, OFF=0V</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97IG8 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>GPC relay grounded from batteries. If voltage is present, check for open
                                    circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Checks</emph>
                                    (Check with specific connections disconnected and Key OFF.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97IG8 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check for open circuit between relay and gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97IG8 to PIN 1 on 12 pin breakout harness</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If>5&#x2126;, check for open from relay to 12 pin connector.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97CH to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If &#60;1k&#x2126;, check for short to ground from relay to X1-17</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>97CH at relay to X1-17</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check for open circuit between relay and ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>For glow plug and harness diagnostics, see Section 5 in the manual.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Circuit 97FU1 is for future diagnostics and is not used at this time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_149.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_151.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
