<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        ENGINE AND VEHICLE SENSORS - Hall Effect Sensor
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Hall Effect Sensor</title>
        <para>The Hall Effect sensor generates voltage signals.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP)</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>A CMP sensor contains a permanent magnet, transducer, signal conditioner, and a switching transistor. The
            shape and frequency of voltage signals result from disturbances in the magnetic field of the sensor. The
            permanent magnet generates a magnetic field around the transducer. As the timing disk (vanes and windows)
            rotates, the magnetic field is disturbed and the transducer generates a signal that is filtered and
            conditioned within the CMP.
        </para>
        <para>Once conditioned, the signal is sent to the base of the switching transistor, causing the transistor to
            ground the 5 volt line from the ECM. At this time, the ECM will receive a 0 volt signal.
        </para>
        <para>Each time a vane passes the sensor the signal is grounded by the transducer. Without a signal the
            transistor shuts off and the ECM receives a 5 volt signal. This allows the ECM to determine engine speed and
            position. The shorter duration of the narrow vane on the trigger wheel allows the ECM to determine the
            position of the crankshaft.
        </para>
        <para>The CMP sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires: a 5 volt signal, a 5 volt V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>, and a signal ground.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1750122" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1276.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Camshaft Position Sensor</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
