<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Fuel System - Periodic Service</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Periodic Service</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information"
                        section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not turn ignition "KEY ON" during any phase of fuel
                        system disassembly. Turning on the ignition key could pump fuel to disconnected tubing,
                        resulting in fire.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, disconnect the main battery negative terminal before
                        disconnecting or connecting electrical components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields. Limit compressed
                        air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not let engine fluids stay on your skin. Clean skin
                        and nails using hand cleaner, and wash with soap and water. Wash or discard clothing and rags
                        contaminated with engine fluids.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not smoke and keep fuel away from flames and sparks.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <regulation>
                    <para>Dispose of fuel according to applicable regulations in a correct container clearly marked
                        DIESEL FUEL.
                    </para>
                </regulation>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <regulation>
                    <para>Engine fluids (oil, fuel, and coolant) may be a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose
                        of engine fluids and filters according to applicable regulations. Never put engine fluids in the
                        trash, on the ground, in sewers or bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </regulation>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc graphiccount="1">
            <title>Primary Fuel Filter Element</title>
            <figure id="f3900007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figN11/N11006.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Primary fuel filter (chassis mounted)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Primary fuel filter element cap</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cap O-ring seal</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Primary fuel filter element</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Horizontal Fuel Conditioning Module (HFCM)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not smoke and keep fuel away from flames and sparks.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Collect fuel in a correct container clearly marked DIESEL FUEL. Loosen water drain plug
                    and drain HFCM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove primary fuel filter element cap from HFCM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard cap O-ring seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull fuel filter out of HFCM and dispose of filter element properly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean seal areas and install a new cap O-ring seal on fuel filter cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean out debris from inside the HFCM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new primary fuel filter element in the HFCM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate fuel filter cap threads and new O-ring with clean diesel fuel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten primary fuel filter cap to
                    <hotlnk document="eges390_208.xml" xrefid="t390000702">special torque</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t390000702"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring on the water drain plug. Install and tighten drain plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When all fuel system components are installed and tight, turn key on and check for fuel
                    leaks. If fuel is leaking turn off engine and repair leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_190.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_192.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
