<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Crankcase, Crankshaft, and
        Camshaft - Clean, Inspect, and Measure - Crankcase, Cup Plugs, and Piston Cooling Tubes
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Crankcase, Cup Plugs, and Piston Cooling Tubes</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The best way to clean the crankcase during an engine overhaul is in a chemical bath or "hot tank".
                    If hot tank cleaning is not available, use the following cleaning procedure.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove deposits and gasket material from gasket surfaces using a rotary wire brush or
                sanding block with mineral spirits.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f3350016514" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg5/EG5364.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Crankcase cup (freeze) plug removal</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the main oil gallery cup plug, located in the rear of the crankcase. Carefully knock
                out cup plugs with a hammer and chisel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean oil galleries in the crankcase using a
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_428.xml" xrefid="t335001603">Stiff Nylon Brush</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001603"/>
                with soap and water.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean cross drillings in the crankcase using a Nylon Brush with soap and water.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Blow out oil galleries and cross drillings with filtered compressed air.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all cylinder head bolt holes with
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_428.xml" xrefid="t335001603">Head Bolt Bottoming Tap</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001603"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all crankcase threaded holes using an appropriate sized tap from
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_428.xml" xrefid="t335001603">Tap Set</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001603"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean crankcase mating surfaces for cup plugs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_428.xml" xrefid="t335001603">Loctite&#174; 262</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001603"/>
                to the outside edge of cup plugs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drive cup plug into the crankcase using a punch approximately 6 mm (0.25 in) smaller in
                diameter than the plug being installed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recess cup plugs 2.3 mm (0.09 in) below machined surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect both ends of each piston cooling tube. Verify the flanged end is intact and the
                orifice end protruding from the crankcase is not broken. Replace any cooling tubes that are damaged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold each piston cooling tube under running water. Water should stream out of tube end.
                Clear blocked piston cooling tubes using filtered compressed air. Replace piston cooling tube if
                blockage can not be cleared.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean engine block heater port in the intake side of the crankcase.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect each crankcase counterbore for cracks.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_408.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_410.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
