<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT, CONNECTING
        RODS AND PISTONS - Connecting Rods, Pistons and Piston Rings - Check Connecting Rod for Bend or Twist
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Check Connecting Rod for Bend or Twist</title>
        <para>Often, engine component wear patterns can be identified and used to diagnose a problem. Some common
            examples of connecting rod wear patterns include the following:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>A shiny surface on the edge of the piston pin bushing usually indicates that a connecting rod is
                    bent or a piston pin hole is not in proper position to the piston shirt and ring grooves.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Abnormal connecting rod bearing wear can be caused by a bent connecting rod, an improperly
                    machined journal or a tapered connecting rod bore.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Twisted connecting rods will not create an easily identifiable wear pattern, but severely twisted
                    connecting rods will disturb the action of an entire piston, ring and connecting rod assembly. It
                    may also be the cause of excessive oil consumption.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If any of these conditions exist, use a suitable alignment fixture to check the connecting rods for bends
            or twists. Follow the instructions of the fixture manufacturer. If bend or twist exceeds specifications,
            replace the connecting rod.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, if the connecting rod does not meet the requirements set forth in other
                    connecting rod inspections, replace the entire connecting rod assembly.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_179.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_181.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
