<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - POWER CYLINDERS - Cleaning and Inspection - Connecting Rod Bearing
        Fit Check
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s26507.2.6" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Connecting Rod Bearing Fit Check</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Bearing shells must fit tightly in the bore. When bearing shells are inserted into the connecting
                    rod and cap, they protrude above the parting line. This protrusion is required to achieve "bearing
                    crush."
                </para>
                <para>Bearing shells across the open ends are slightly larger than the diameter of the connecting rod
                    bore into which they are assembled. This condition is designed into the bearing shell, causing it to
                    spread outward at the parting line when "bearing crush" load is applied by tightening the bolts.
                    Some snap may be lost in normal use, but bearing replacement is not required because of a nominal
                    loss of snap.
                </para>
                <para>When the assembly is drawn up tight, the bearing is compressed, ensuring positive contact between
                    the backside of the bearing and the bore.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate connecting rod bolts with clean engine oil. Assemble cap to rod with new bearing
                shells installed. Tighten bolts alternately and evenly to special torque value .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a telescoping gauge , measure inside diameter of connecting rod bearing at two locations
                90&#176; apart. Average the two inside diameters.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a micrometer to measure each crankshaft rod journal diameter.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Subtract the crankshaft rod journal diameter from the respective connecting rod bearing
                inside diameter to obtain bearing-to-crankshaft running clearance. Repeat for each crankshaft rod
                journal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If bearing-to-crankshaft running clearances exceed specifications because of wear on
                crankshaft, replace or grind crankshaft and install under-size precision type bearing shells.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, grind or replace the crankshaft only. Do not rework bearing cap or
                    bearings; this will reduce running clearance of journal-to-bearing.
                </para>
            </caution>
            <note>
                <para>Plastigage&#174; may be used as an alternate method, to determine running clearance.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_142.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_144.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
