<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Air Management System - Exhaust Gas Recirculation
        (EGR) System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System</title>
        <para>
            <title>The EGR system includes the following:</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>EGR control valve</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EGR cooler</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Air intake manifold</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Exhaust tube assembly, right</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) system reduces Nitrogen Oxide (NOx) emissions.</para>
        <para>NO
            <subscript>X</subscript>
            forms during a reaction between nitrogen and oxygen at high temperature during combustion. Combustion starts
            when fuel is injected into the cylinder before or slightly after the piston reaches top-dead-center.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EGR flow</title>
        </para>
        <para>Some exhaust from the right exhaust tube assembly flows into the EGR cooler. Exhaust from the EGR cooler
            flows into a passage in the air intake manifold that intersects with the EGR valve.
        </para>
        <para>When EGR is commanded, the EGR control valve opens allowing cooled exhaust gases to enter the intake
            manifold to be mixed with filtered intake air then recycled through the combustion process. Cooling the
            exhaust gases increases the engine's tolerance for EGR.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EGR control valve</title>
        </para>
        <figure id="f2400117" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D31171.png" type="png" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>EGR control valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Actuator coil</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Valve heads (2)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Common shaft</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The EGR valve uses a linear actuator to control the position of the flow-metering valve. The actuator
            pushes directly on the valve assembly. The valve assembly has two valve heads on a common shaft.
        </para>
        <figure id="f2400118" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D31181.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>EGR closed loop operation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The actuator generates a magnetic force that acts directly on the valve. By changing the voltage input to
            the actuator coil, the available magnetic force is varied to change the valve position.
        </para>
        <para>The actuator includes a built-in valve position sensor to provide the ECM with a feedback signal. The
            signal, based on a 5 volts (V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>), is directly proportional to the valve opening. This output signal provides the
            information on the valve position relative to its seat.
        </para>
        <para>The EGR is a closed loop system that uses the Exhaust Gas Recirculation Position sensor (EGRP) to provide
            feedback to the ECM. The ECM uses the EGRP sensor to continuously monitor EBP and adjust the duty cycle to
            the EGR control valve to match engine requirements.
        </para>
        <figure id="f2400119" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D31184.png" type="png" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>EGR control</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The actuator coil receives a pulse width modulated signal from the ECM that indicates the on/off time that
            the control valve is energized
        </para>
        <para>When actuated the valve shaft moves away from the actuator, unseating both valve heads at the same time.
            Exhaust enters the EGR valve between the two valve heads and exits through each valve head and seat
            interface.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
