<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTICS - Vehicle Information</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Vehicle Information</title>
        <figure id="f2400602" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D3176.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before starting diagnostic tests, fill out the heading for vehicle information on the front side
                    of Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Technician and Unit numbers are for reference only</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Date, Miles, and Hours are for warranty claims</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Serial Number (ESN) and Vehicle Identification Number (VIN) are for ordering parts and
                    referencing service information. The engine serial number is on a machined pad behind the left rear
                    of block below the left cylinder head. The Vehicle Identification Number is on the door jamb on the
                    driver's side.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Horsepower / Emissions Information and Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC) helps determine if
                    the engine is the correct horsepower for the application and if the ECM is calibrated to the correct
                    horsepower and emissions level. Information for engine horsepower and emissions is on the emission
                    label on the right side valve cover.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Family Rating Codes and calibrations for the Electronic Control Module (ECM) and the
                    Injector Drive Module (IDM) are found with the Electronic Service Tool (EST).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fill in the Turbocharger No. and Injector No. only if there is a suspected mismatch of
                    components.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 is available in 50 sheet pads from:</para>
        <verbatim>
            <line>
                <emph type="bold">International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation</emph>
            </line>
            <line>Printing, Procurement and Distribution</line>
            <line>4956 Wayne Road</line>
            <line>Battle Creek, Michigan 49015</line>
        </verbatim>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_93.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_95.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
