<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Engine Cooling
        System - Cooling System Flow
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cooling System Flow</title>
        <para>Coolant is drawn from the radiator through an inlet elbow and front cover by the water pump. The water
            pump pushes coolant into two passages in the front cover.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows to the crankcase and through the water jackets from front to rear. This coolant flows around
            the cylinder liners to absorb heat from combustion. The coolant may also pass by the optional engine coolant
            heater.
        </para>
        <para>Swirling coolant flow in the cylinder liner jackets directs coolant through passages in the head gasket
            and upwards into the cylinder head.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows through the cylinder head water jackets towards the thermostat cavity at the front of the
            cylinder head. Depending on coolant temperature, the thermostat can direct in two directions to exit the
            cylinder head.
        </para>
        <para>When the thermostat is closed, coolant is directed through the bypass port, crankcase, front cover, and
            into the water pump.
        </para>
        <para>When the thermostat is open, the bypass port is blocked, and coolant is directed from the engine into the
            radiator.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant passes through the radiator and is cooled by moving air from the coolant fan. The coolant will
            return to the engine through the inlet elbow.
        </para>
        <para>The air compressor is cooled with engine coolant supplied by a hose from the left side of the crankcase.
            Coolant passes through the air compressor cylinder head and returns through a hose back into the crankcase.
        </para>
        <para>The oil system module assembly receives coolant from a passage in the crankcase. Coolant passes between
            the oil cooler plates and returns through a tube leading back to the water pump suction passage located in
            the front cover.
        </para>
        <para>The exhaust side EGR cooler receives coolant from the water pump through a supply tube. Coolant passes
            between the EGR cooler plates, travels parallel to the exhaust flow, and exits into another coolant tube.
            Coolant is supplied to the intake side EGR cooler from this tube. Coolant passes between the EGR cooler
            plates, parallel to the exhaust flow, and exits into the coolant return tube which connects to the cylinder
            head water jacket. The deaeration port on the top of the intake side EGR cooler directs coolant and trapped
            air through the EGR valve and towards the coolant surge tank.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
