<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Hard Start and No Start Diagnostics - Test Procedures - 10. Fuel Supply
        System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010503.10" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="12">
        <title>10. Fuel Supply System</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010503.10.1">
            <figure id="f305010527" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
            <para id="tp305010510">
                <title>Purpose</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>To check the fuel supply system for efficient engine operation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To check for fuel aeration</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To check for fuel system contamination</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Breaking any fuel system joints will induce air in the fuel system.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>0-160 psi gauge (on Gauge Bar Tool)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP System Test Adapter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>In-line shut off valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3/8 inch clear sample line</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clear container with a wide opening (approximately 1 liter or 1 quart US)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, read all safety
                        instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, comply with the following:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not mix gasoline, gasohol or alcohol with diesel fuel. This practice creates a fire
                                hazard and is potentially explosive.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not allow engine fluids to stay on your skin. Clean skin and nails with soap and
                                water, or a good hand cleaner. Wash or properly dispose of clothing or rags containing
                                engine fluids. Engine fluids contain elements that may be unhealthy for skin and could
                                cause cancer.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>Engine fluids, oil, fuel, and coolant, are a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose of
                        engine fluids according to local regulations. Never put engine fluids in the trash, on the
                        ground, in sewers, or other bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010503.10.2">
            <title>10.1. Pressure, Quality, and Aerated Fuel</title>
            <para id="tp305010510.1"></para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">See "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050111.xml" xrefid="e3050111">Appendix A: VT 275 Performance
                        Specifications
                    </hotlnk>
                    " for fuel pump pressure specification and record on Diagnostic Form.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify there is fuel in the fuel tank(s). Check fuel in fuel tank(s) for odors other
                    than diesel fuel, for example: kerosene, alcohol, or gasoline.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Low Biodiesel blends (up to 5%) should not cause engine or fuel system problems. If low
                            biodiesel blends are used the odor in the fuel tank(s) may not match diesel fuel.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to ON, listen for a hum coming from the fuel pump. The ECM turns
                    fuel pump on, it should run for 60 seconds. After 60 seconds the ECM turns the fuel pump off unless
                    the engine is running.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Engine may run without the fuel pump, but damage to the injectors could occur.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the fuel pump can be heard running, continue with step 4.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <seqlist style="alphalc">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the fuel pump cannot be heard running, turn ignition switch to OFF.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Disconnect the fuel pump harness connector and measure voltage between the power and
                            ground circuits.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn ignition switch to ON, battery voltage should be present for 60 seconds.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If battery voltage is not present, see "
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_148.xml" xrefid="s305010706.20.3.1">Fuel Pump Pin-Point
                                Diagnostics
                            </hotlnk>
                            " in the "
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050107.xml" xrefid="e3050107">Electronic Control Systems
                                Diagnostics</hotlnk>" section of this manual, and see the applicable truck Circuit
                            Diagram Manualfor relay and fuse locations.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, use care to prevent contact with the door edge when the cab is up
                        and the door is open.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air inlet duct on the engine to aid in plug removal and system testing.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to the engine, take precautions to prevent foreign materials from entering the
                        air intake system when the air inlet duct is removed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing the test plug, there is a possibility of a small amount of fuel leaking out. Put
                        in a drain pan or rag to collect this leakage. Collect and dispose of this fuel according to
                        local regulations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010616" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj11/j11004.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Secondary fuel filter</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel return to fuel pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel supply from fuel pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel pressure test port plug</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Conditioned fuel to left cylinder head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Conditioned fuel to right cylinder head</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove plug from the fuel pressure test port plug at the bottom of the secondary fuel
                    filter housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010617" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Pressure Gauge</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Test fitting connection (remove to adapt to the ICP System Test Adapter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure test line</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure gauge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">In-line shut off valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">3/8 inch clear sample line</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010618" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D3191.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>ICP System Test Adapter</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010619" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31293.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Fuel pressure setup</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Gauge Bar Tool (0-160 psi gauge)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">In-line shut off valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure test line</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ICP System Test Adapter (attached to test fitting connection)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">3/8 inch clear sample line</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010632" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31296.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>ICP System Test Adapter installed with Fuel Pressure Gauge</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Test line</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ICP System Test Adapter</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the ICP System Test Adapter and assemble and attach Fuel Pressure Gauge.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The Fuel Pressure Gauge is available through the tool supplier. It is recommend this tool
                            be used for pressure and sampling.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the Fuel Pressure Gauge can not be obtained. Test setup can be made using tools from
                            the dealer supplied Essential Tool Kits .
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the clear test line to clear container</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to ON (do not crank the engine).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Dispose of fuel according to local regulations in the correct container clearly marked
                                DIESEL FUEL.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>DO NOT smoke.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Keep away from open flames and sparks.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the in-line shut off valve, drain sample in the clear container. As filling,
                    observe the clear test line for indication of air bubbles.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Breaking any fuel system joints will induce air in the fuel system, it should clear shortly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close in-line shut off valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for contamination and record results on Diagnostics Form.</para>
                <table id="t305010608" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                    <title>Sample should be clear, free of debris, water and other contaminates. Sample should not be
                        cloudy or dyed (blue or red).
                    </title>
                    <tgroup cols="1">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If air bubbles stop with sample flowing, the fuel is not aerated and if there
                                        is no contamination, continue with step 15.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If the air bubbles do not clear before the sample container is almost full, a
                                        second sample needs to be taken to determine if air bubbles have cleared,
                                        continue with step 13.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If fuel is contaminated with water, debris or other contaminates, take a
                                        second sample. Some sediment and water may be present in the fuel sample if the
                                        fuel filter has not been replaced for a prolonged period of time or if the
                                        sediment and water have not been drained recently, continue with step 13.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If the fuel sample is cloudy in colder temperatures, this indicates waxing or
                                        gelling. Summer fuels are not suitable in colder temperatures. Change to the
                                        recommended fuel grade. See "Fuel Requirements" in the Engine Operation and
                                        Maintenance Manual(for engine's model number and model year).
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If the fuel sample is dyed, either blue or red, this indicates off-road use
                                        fuel and could cause a performance problem. Change to a recommended fuel grade.
                                        See "Fuel Requirements" in the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual (for
                                        engine's model number and model year).
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a second sample is needed, cycle the ignition switch to restart the fuel pump, drain
                    sample and check for air bubbles and contamination in the fuel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the results on the Diagnostic Form.</para>
                <table id="t305010609" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                    <tgroup cols="1">
                        <colspec colname="col1"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If air bubbles did not clear, check the fuel supply system from the fuel
                                        tank(s) to the HFCM inlet for leaks. Correct the condition and retest. The check
                                        should include wiggling all fuel line connections, checking the primary fuel
                                        filter cover and the HFCM drain plug for leaks with the fuel pump turned off.
                                        With the fuel pump off, the primary fuel filter cover and the drain plug may
                                        show a slow drip of fuel indicating cover or plug is loose or seals are worn,
                                        cracked, or broken.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Excessive water or contaminants may indicate that the tank and fuel system may
                                        need to be flushed and cleaned. Take a sample from the HFCM drain plug for
                                        verification. See "
                                        <hotlnk document="eges3052_74.xml" xrefid="s305010402.11.2.1">Drain Water from
                                            HFCM
                                        </hotlnk>
                                        " in the "
                                        <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050104.xml" xrefid="e3050104">Engine Symptoms
                                            Diagnostics
                                        </hotlnk>
                                        " section of this manual.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row rowsep="0">
                                <entry>
                                    <para>If fuel doesn't clear up, the system may have to be flushed to correct the
                                        condition. Replace the primary and secondary fuel filters and verify fuel is the
                                        recommended grade and clean.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <para></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Any residue or microbial growth in the tank(s) will compound with the use of biodiesel.
                            This can cause serious plugging of filters and deposits in the fuel system. Fuel tanks
                            should be thoroughly cleaned and dried before operating with any biodiesel blends. Adding
                            biocides will help minimize growth.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cycle ignition switch to OFF and back to ON.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check fuel pressure on the fuel pressure gauge when the pump starts. Pressure should
                    increase to specification quickly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the results on the Diagnostic Form.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If fuel pressure is within specification, do "
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_90.xml" xrefid="tp305010511">Test 11. Main Power Relay Voltage to
                                ECM
                            </hotlnk>
                            " in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If fuel pressure is below specification, replace both the primary and secondary fuel
                            filters and retest.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If fuel pressure is still below specification, after replacing both primary and secondary
                            fuel filters, measure fuel pump discharge pressure. Do "
                            <hotlnk xrefid="tp305010510.2">Test 10.2. Fuel Pump Discharge Pressure</hotlnk>
                            " in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <table id="t305010515" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>Possible Causes</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="5">
                                <para>Contaminated Fuel</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Water or contaminants in fuel tank</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ice in fuel lines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Debris in fuel tank(s)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel colored, cloudy, or colored</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel is waxy or gelled</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off road fuel red colored or blue colored</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="4">
                                <para>Aeration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low or no fuel level in fuel tank(s).</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed seals for fuel lines between fuel tank(s) and the HFCM, fuel supply line
                                    broken or crimped.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A cracked or restricted pickup tube screen or pickup tube.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>HFCM fuel filter cap seal damaged, HFCM drain plug loose, or HFCM drain plug
                                    O-ring broken or missing
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A loose fuel line or fuel line connector on the suction side of the fuel pump
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="3">
                                <para>No Fuel</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low or no fuel level in fuel tank(s).</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed fuel tank transfer pump</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A restricted, kinked, bent, loose, cracked, or broken fuel pickup tube or
                                    screen.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed seals for fuel lines between fuel tanks, ice in fuel lines, fuel supply
                                    line broken or crimped, or restriction in the fuel line from the fuel tank to the
                                    HFCM.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="7">
                                <para>Low fuel pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Debris in tank</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Restriction from the fuel tank to the HFCM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A kinked or bent fuel supply line or a blocked pickup tube screen</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A loose fuel line or fuel line connector on the suction side of the fuel system
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Dirty or plugged fuel filters</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed fuel pump</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Debris in the fuel regulator valve</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed or stuck fuel pressure regulator valve.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="4">
                                <para>Fuel Restriction</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Debris in fuel</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A kinked or bent fuel supply line or a blocked pickup tube strainer</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Dirty or plugged filter element</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Waxed or gelled fuel in the fuel filter</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ice in fuel lines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="3">
                                <para>High fuel pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Debris in the fuel regulator valve</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed fuel pressure regulator valve.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Restriction in the fuel return to the HFCM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Combustion gases leaking into fuel system</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010503.10.3">
            <title>10.2. Fuel Pump Discharge Pressure</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure should only be performed when directed by "
                        <hotlnk xrefid="tp305010510.1">Test 10.1. Pressure, Quality, and Aerated Fuel</hotlnk>
                        " when fuel pressure is still below specification or slow to build, after replacing both primary
                        and secondary fuel filters.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para id="tp305010510.2">
                <title>Purpose</title>
            </para>
            <para>To measure fuel pump discharge pressure</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Breaking any fuel system joints will induce air in the fuel system.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>0-160 psi gauge (on Gauge Bar Tool)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel Pressure Test Adapter</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing the banjo bolt, fuel will leak out. Put in a suitable container to collect this
                        leakage. Collect and dispose of this fuel according to local regulations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010621" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj11/j11004.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Secondary fuel filter</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel return to fuel pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel supply from fuel pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel pressure test port plug</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Conditioned fuel to left cylinder head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Conditioned fuel to right cylinder head</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the banjo bolt from fuel supply from fuel pump (item 2) at the bottom of the
                    secondary fuel filter housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use existing copper gaskets for testing. Replace the copper gaskets on the banjo bolt when
                        testing is over and repairs have been made.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010622" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31237.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Pressure Test Adapter</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010623" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31297.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Pressure Test Adapter installed in fuel supply from fuel pump</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel Pressure Test Adapter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Test line</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Banjo bolt</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Copper gaskets</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the Fuel Pressure Test Adapter to the fuel supply, using the banjo bolt and
                    copper gaskets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the Fuel Pressure Gauge to the Fuel Pressure Test Adapter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to ON (do not crank the engine).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check fuel pressure on the test gauge immediately when the pump starts. The fuel
                    pressure should increase to specification quickly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010624" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj11/j11006.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Replace two copper gaskets</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent possible fire and damage to the engine from leaking fuel, replace the two copper
                        gaskets when reattaching fuel supply from the HFCM to the secondary fuel filter housing.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the results on the Diagnostic Form.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the discharge pressure is within specification, turn ignition switch to OFF, continue
                            with step 7.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the discharge pressure is not within specifications, turn ignition switch to OFF.
                            Reconnect the fuel line and banjo bolt to the secondary fuel filter housing, do "
                            <hotlnk xrefid="tp305010510.3">Test 10.3. Fuel Inlet Restriction</hotlnk>
                            " in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the Fuel Pressure Test Adapter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove, clean, and inspect the fuel pressure regulator, see the Engine Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After reinstallation of the secondary fuel filter housing and all fuel line. Attach the
                    filter pressure gauge to the secondary fuel filter test port, and retest fuel pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010503.10.4">
            <title>10.3. Fuel Inlet Restriction</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure should only be performed when directed by "
                        <hotlnk xrefid="tp305010510.2">Test 10.2. Fuel Pump Discharge Pressure</hotlnk>
                        " when discharge pressure is within specification or slow to build.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para id="tp305010510.3">
                <title>Purpose</title>
            </para>
            <para>To measure fuel pump inlet restriction</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Breaking any fuel system joints will induce air in the fuel system.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>0-30 in Hg gauge (on gauge bar tool)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel Inlet Restriction Adapter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>In-line shut off valve</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a clean flat drain pan under the HFCM drain plug</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe down the frame around and under the drain plug. Wipe down the HFCM area around the
                    drain plug also.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the drain plug and drain the HFCM to flat drain pan.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing the drain plug fuel will leak out. Collect and dispose of this fuel according to
                        local regulations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010625" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31349.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Inlet Restriction Adapter</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010626" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31298.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Fuel inlet restriction test setup (typical)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Gauge Bar Tool</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel Inlet Restriction Adapter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Catch pan</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the HFCM drain plug, install the fuel inlet restriction adapter, hand tighten
                    only.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Inspect the drain plug O-ring for damage from removal. Care must be taken when installing
                        drain plug to prevent damaging the O-ring.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect to 0-30 in Hg gauge on the gauge bar tool through an in-line shut off valve.
                    Make sure the shut off valve is in the closed position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The fuel pump runs for 60 seconds when ignition switch is turned on. The in-line shut off
                        valve must be closed before the fuel pump shuts off. This will prevent the gauge from filling
                        with fuel.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to ON. Open the in-line shut off valve and check for restriction
                    indication on the test gauge. Close the in-line shut off valve. Turn ignition switch to OFF.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record results on Diagnostic Form.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If vacuum indication is above the specification, check for restrictions in the fuel supply
                            lines from the fuel pickup tube in the fuel tank to the HFCM. Visually inspect for bent,
                            crimped, or damaged fuel supply lines and connections from the fuel tank(s) to the HFCM.
                            Correct any restrictions and retest fuel pressure at the secondary fuel filter housing test
                            port.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If vacuum indication is below the specification and fuel pump discharge pressure is low,
                            replace the fuel pump and retest fuel pressure at the secondary fuel filter housing test
                            port.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_88.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_90.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
