<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Glow Plug Control System</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Glow Plug Control System</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <figure id="f2400141" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD33/D3388.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Glow plug control system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The glow plug control system warms the engine cylinders to aid cold engine starting and reduce exhaust
                emissions during warm-up.
            </para>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) is programmed to energize the glow plugs (through the glow plug
                relay), while monitoring programmed conditions for engine coolant temperature and atmospheric pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors battery voltage and uses information from the Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)
                sensor and Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor to determine the amount of time that the WAIT TO
                START lamp is ON and the activation time of the glow plugs. The ECM controls the WAIT TO START lamp and
                the activation of the glow plugs separately. The glow plugs are self limiting and do not require cycling
                on and off. The glow plug relay will only cycle on and off repeatedly if system voltage is greater than
                14.0 volts.
            </para>
            <para>Glow plugs are activated for a longer time, if the engine is cold or the barometric pressure is low
                (high altitude).
            </para>
            <para>The engine is ready to start when the WAIT TO START lamp is turned off by the ECM. The glow plugs can
                remain on up to 120 seconds, while the engine is running, to reduce exhaust emissions during engine
                warm-up.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_E2950002.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
