<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Symptoms
        Diagnostics - Problems and Conditions - Rough Idle
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Rough Idle</title>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Cause</title>
            <item>
                <para>Engine oil (aerated, incorrect grade, low oil level, extended drain interval)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Poor fuel quality</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Low fuel pressure</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Aerated fuel</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Electronic control system faults (ECM and IDM)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Injection control pressure system problems</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fuel injectors not working properly</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EGR valve stuck open</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Power cylinder problems</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Valve train problems</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine or flywheel balance problems</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Exhaust system to cab/chassis contact</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Loose/worn engine mounts</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify complaint. Confirm conditions when complaint is present.</para>
            <para>When does engine rough idle occur?</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Hot - operating temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cold</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After high speed operation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Over entire engine speed range</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Combination of the above conditions</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Is there chassis vibration or any other conditions/observations present when engine idles
                        rough.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect exhaust system for contact with cab, frame or body of vehicle.</para>
            <para>Engine exhaust pipe contact with cab may transmit engine vibrations to cab, especially on acceleration
                or engine shifts. This condition may be incorrectly diagnosed as a rough idle complaint.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Complete the following tests on the Performance Diagnostic form. See
                <hotlnk document="eges270_E2700106.xml" xrefid="s27005021">"Performance Diagnostics"</hotlnk>
                - Section 6 in this manual for specific details on each test.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 1 (Diagnostic Trouble Codes) on Performance Diagnostics form. Intermittent sensor,
                injector or wiring harness faults can affect engine idle conditions. The ECM may have detected and
                recorded these conditions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 2 (KOEO Standard Test) on Performance Diagnostics form. This test will verify
                electrical operation of actuators.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 3 (KOEO Injector Test) on Performance Diagnostics form. This test will verify that
                the injectors are working electronically.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 4 (Engine Oil) on Performance Diagnostics form. Check engine oil level. Verify
                correct oil grade for ambient temperature. See Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Engine
                Lubrication Requirements section. Confirm oil meets correct API specification for your model and year of
                engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 5 (Fuel) on Performance Diagnostics form. Verify quality and quantity of diesel
                fuel. Poor quality fuel or low cetane rating can cause white smoking, engine misfire, and low power. See
                Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Fuel Requirements section for your model and year of engine to
                determine minimum necessary fuel grade and cetane rating.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 6 (Fuel Pressure and Aerated Fuel) on Performance Diagnostics form. Measure fuel
                pressure at fuel rail (intake manifold). Low fuel pressure, aerated fuel, and fuel inlet restriction
                will cause the engine to misfire and a loss of power.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 9 (KOER Standard Test) on Performance Diagnostics form. This test will verify the
                functionality of the injection control pressure system. The engine must be at operating temperature 70
                &#176;C (158 &#176;F) to do this test.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 10 (Injection Control Pressure) on Performance Diagnostics form. This test will
                confirm if the injection control pressure system is functioning properly and verify injection control
                pressure stability.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 11 (Injector Disable) on Performance Diagnostics form. The primary function of this
                test is to show the contributions of the individual power cylinders. The test will detect a weak
                cylinder which could be the result of an injector or base engine problem.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Test 11 is used in conjunction with Test 12 (Relative Compression) to distinguish between an
                        injector or mechanical problem.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 12 (Relative Compression) on Performance Diagnostics form. This will verify base
                engine compression.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Test 12 is used in conjunction with Test 11 (Injector Disable) to distinguish between an
                        injector or mechanical problem.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do Test 16 (Crankcase Pressure) on Performance Diagnostics form. This test will determine
                the condition of the power cylinders and base engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect for engine and flywheel balance. Engine roughness at idle that gets worse with a no
                load acceleration may be caused by an out of balance condition.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, support
                        the vibration damper during mounting bolt removal. The damper can slide off the nose of the
                        crankshaft very easily.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Following the procedure in the Engine Service Manual remove the vibration damper and inspect
                        the elastomer layer for cracks and misalignment. If no problem is found, install vibration
                        damper following the assembly procedure found in the Engine Service Manual. Verify that locating
                        dowel on the end of the crankshaft pulley is aligned with locating hole in the balancer for
                        proper installation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Isolate the engine from transmission by removing the transmission, clutch and pressure plate
                        or torque converter. Start the engine and evaluate for roughness. If the engine runs smooth,
                        replace the torque converter or replace clutch and pressure plate.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Following the procedure in the Engine Service Manual, remove the flywheel and verify proper
                        orientation. If orientation is correct, replace or rebalance flywheel. When removing/installing
                        the flywheel, ensure that the locating dowel is in the right place and that the flywheel is
                        located properly on the dowel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>For new engines only remove the oil pan following the procedure in the Engine Service Manual.
                        Inspect the crankshaft counterweights to ensure balance holes exist.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_74.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_76.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
