<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE - Microprocessor Input and Output
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="OVERVIEW" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Microprocessor Input and Output</title>
        <para>The ECM internal microprocessor stores operating instructions (control strategies) and value tables
            (calibration parameters). The ECM compares stored instructions with input values to determine the correct
            operating strategy for all engine conditions.
        </para>
        <para>Diagnostic codes are generated by the microprocessor if inputs or conditions do not comply with expected
            values. Continuous calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds: Foreground and
            Background.
        </para>
        <para>Foreground calculations are much faster than background calculations and are normally more critical for
            engine operation. Engine speed control is an example.
        </para>
        <para>Background calculations are normally variables that change at a slower rates. Engine temperature is an
            example.
        </para>
        <para>Diagnostic strategies are also programmed into the ECM. Some strategies monitor inputs continuously and
            command the necessary outputs to achieve the correct performance of the engine. These strategies instruct
            the ECM to continuously perform other diagnostic tests.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Microprocessor Memory</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The ECM microprocessor includes Random Access Memory (RAM) and Read Only Memory (ROM). Refer to Electronic
            Control Module Microprocessor Memory .
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ROM</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Read Only Memory stores permanent information for calibration tables and operating strategies. Permanently
            stored Information cannot be changed or lost by turning the engine OFF or when ECM power is interrupted. ROM
            information includes the following:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle configuration, modes of operation, and options</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Family Ratings Code (EFRC)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine warning and protection modes</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">RAM</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Random Access Memory stores temporary information for current conditions. Temporary information in RAM is
            lost when the key is turned OFF or when ECM power is interrupted. RAM information includes the following:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Engine temperature</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine rpm</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Accelerator pedal position</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f1750113" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="eg1273" filename="../figeg1/eg1273.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Electronic Control Module Microprocessor Memory</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
