<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYMPTOMS DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - Coolant in Lube
        Oil
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Coolant in Lube Oil</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Glow plug sleeve failure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cylinder head cup plug failure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil cooler bundle or O-ring failure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Front cover gasket damage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Front cover, cylinder head or crankcase porosity</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cylinder head gasket leak</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injector sleeve leak</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accessory leak (water cooled air compressor)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection Procedure for Lube Oil Contamination</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check coolant level and oil level gauge to verify oil contamination complaint.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The presence of coolant in the oil will generally give the oil a white milky appearance.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant in the oil is not verified, an oil sample can be taken for analysis.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When oil contamination is verified, plug in cylinder block heater to warm coolant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400408" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D31219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Air compressor isolated from engine for coolant leak test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine is equipped with an air compressor, isolate compressor from the engine and
                    test for coolant leak.
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the coolant inlet and outlet hoses for the air compressor cylinder head and remove
                            the oil drain back line from the bottom of the air compressor mounting bracket.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fill air compressor coolant passage and hoses with coolant.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Adapt air pressure fitting and regulator to one of the coolant hoses and block opposite
                            hose.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Pressurize air compressor coolant hoses to 96 kPa (14 psi).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect for coolant leakage from oil drain back line and listen for escaping air.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If leak is found, repair or replace air compressor. If no leak is found, proceed to next
                            step.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove glow plug harnesses, glow plugs and valve covers. Drain engine oil and remove oil
                    filter.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Leave oil drain plug out of pan and oil filter cap off.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pressurize cooling system to 96 kPa (14 psi).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If coolant is leaking from oil pan, do the following.</para>
                <figure id="f2400409" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="f2400403.6" filename="../figd08/D0897.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Cylinder Head Cup Plug Locations</caption>
                </figure>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect entire cylinder head area for leaks at the cup plugs.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect oil filter housing for coolant leaks from oil cooler.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If no leaks are found in above areas do step 9 to inspect for upper crankcase leakage.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant system pressure is dropping and no coolant is leaking from oil pan, do step
                            7.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bar engine over by hand and check for coolant flooding the top of piston and flowing out
                    of the glow plug bore.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If leaks are found, do step 8.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If leaks are not found, do step 9.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cylinder head from engine following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual.
                    Perform all inspections and pressure test cylinder head to verify leak path. Inspect cylinder head
                    gasket for damage at sealing areas which may have caused leak. Verify crankcase and cylinder head
                    surface flatness using a straight edge and feeler gauge.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If glow plug or injector sleeve was replaced, retest cylinder head with pressure test
                            plate to verify repair.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper and lower oil pans following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for leakage in crankcase.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify 96 kPa (14 psi) pressure is maintained on radiator pressure tester.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If no leakage is found, do step 11.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil cooler and oil filter housing from the engine following the procedures in the
                    Engine Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400410" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400404" filename="../figd13/D1362.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         box="yes"/>
                <caption>Oil Cooler</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air pressure regulator</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air adapter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Test plate</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do oil cooler pressure test following procedures in the Engine Service Manual.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a leak is found, replace oil cooler assembly.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If no leak is found, do step 13.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400411" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400405.5" filename="../figd06/D0644A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Front Cover Coolant Sealing Surfaces</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cover and inspect gaskets and sealing surfaces following the procedures in
                    the Engine Service Manual. Check front cover and crankcase with straight edge and feeler gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Retest cooling system after any repair to confirm repair.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_59.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_61.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
