<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Engine
        Identification - Engine Description
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Engine Description</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <title>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9, and 10 Diesel Engines</title>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="bottom">
                                <para>Engine configuration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="bottom">
                                <para>4 stroke, inline six cylinder diesel</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT displacement</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7.6 L (466 in
                                    <supscript>3</supscript>)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9 and 10 displacement</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>9.3 L (570 in
                                    <supscript>3</supscript>)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Bore (sleeve diameter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>116.6 mm (4.59 in)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Stroke</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9 and 10</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>119 mm (4.68 in)</para>
                                <para>146 mm (5.75 in)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Compression ratio</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9 and 10</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>16.9 : 1</para>
                                <para>17.2 : 1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Aspiration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>VGT turbocharged and Charge Air Cooled (CAC)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Rated power @ rpm
                                    <ftnote id="BR">Example ratings shown. See Performance Specifications appendix in
                                        Diagnostic Manual for additional ratings.
                                    </ftnote>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 10</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>245 bhp @ 2600 rpm</para>
                                <para>310 bhp @ 2200 rpm</para>
                                <para>310 bhp @ 2200 rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Peak torque @ rpm
                                    <ftnref xrefid="BR"/>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 10</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>620 lbf&#183;ft @ 1400 rpm</para>
                                <para>950 lbf&#183;ft @ 1200 rpm</para>
                                <para>1050 lbf&#183;ft @ 1200 rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine rotation (facing flywheel)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Counterclockwise</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Combustion system</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Direct injection turbocharged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel system</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Electro-hydraulic injection</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Total engine weight (oil and accessories)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MaxxForce&#8482; 9 and 10</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>881 kg (1,943 lbs)</para>
                                <para>905 kg (1,995 lbs)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cooling system capacity (engine only)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12.8 L (13.5 qts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Lube system capacity (including filter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>28 L (30 qts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Lube system capacity (overhaul only, with filter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>33 L (35 qts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Firing order</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1-5-3-6-2-4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Features</title>
            <para>MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9, and 10 diesel engines are designed for increased durability, reliability, and
                ease of maintenance.
            </para>
            <para>The cylinder head has four valves per cylinder with centrally located fuel injectors directing fuel
                over the pistons. This configuration provides improved performance and reduces emissions.
            </para>
            <para>The camshaft is supported by four insert bushings pressed into the crankcase. The camshaft gear is
                driven from the front of the engine. A thrust flange is located between the camshaft and the drive gear.
                The overhead valve train includes mechanical roller lifters, push rods, rocker arms, and dual valves
                that open using a valve bridge.
            </para>
            <para>MaxxForce&#8482;DT engines use one piece aluminum alloy pistons. MaxxForce&#8482; 9 and 10 engines use
                one piece steel pistons. All pistons use an offset piston axis and centered combustion bowls. Crown
                markings show correct piston orientation in the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>The one piece crankcase uses replaceable wet cylinder sleeves that are sealed by a single crevice
                seal. Some applications include a crankcase ladder which is designed to support heavier loads and reduce
                engine noise.
            </para>
            <para>The crankshaft has seven main bearings with fore and aft thrust controlled at the rear bearing. One
                fractured cap connecting rod is attached at each crankshaft journal. A piston pin moves freely inside
                the connecting rod and piston. Piston pin retaining rings secure the piston pin in the piston. The rear
                oil seal carrier is part of the flywheel housing.
            </para>
            <para>A gerotor lube oil pump is mounted on the front cover and is driven by the crankshaft. Pressurized oil
                is supplied to engine components and the high-pressure injection system. All MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9, and
                10 engines use an engine oil cooler and spin-on engine oil filter.
            </para>
            <para>The water supply housing serves as the mounting bracket for the Freon&#174; compressor. Mounting
                capabilities for a dual Freon&#174; compressor are available as an option. The pad mounting design of
                the alternator and Freon&#174; compressor brackets provide easy removal and improved durability.
            </para>
            <para>The low-pressure fuel supply pump draws fuel from the fuel tank through the fuel filter housing. The
                housing includes a strainer, filter, primer pump, drain valve, Water in Fuel (WIF) sensor, and Engine
                Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor. If equipped, an optional fuel heater element is located in the fuel filter
                housing. Conditioned fuel is pumped through the intake manifold and cylinder head to the fuel injectors.
            </para>
            <para>The WIF sensor detects water in the fuel system. When a programmed value of water is collected in the
                fuel filter housing, the instrument panel's amber FUEL FILTER lamp will illuminate. The collected water
                must be removed immediately. The water is drained by using the drain valve located on the fuel filter
                housing.
            </para>
            <para>The fuel injection system is electro-hydraulic. The system includes an under-valve-cover high-pressure
                oil manifold, fuel injectors, and a high-pressure oil pump. The injectors are installed in the cylinder
                head, under the high-pressure oil manifold.
            </para>
            <para>The Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) has actuated vanes in the turbine housing. These vanes modify
                exhaust gas flow through the VGT. The ECM commands the VGT in response to boost and exhaust back
                pressure for various engine speeds and load conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The Inlet Air Heater (IAH) system warms the incoming air supply prior to cranking to aid cold engine
                starting and reduce white smoke during warm-up. The IAH system will initially illuminate the WAIT TO
                START lamp located on the instrument panel. When the lamp turns off, the engine can be started.
            </para>
            <para>The Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) system circulates cooled exhaust into the intake air stream in the
                intake manifold. This cools the combustion process and reduces the formation of NO
                <subscript>X</subscript>
                engine emissions.
            </para>
            <para>A closed crankcase breather system uses an engine mounted oil separator to return oil to the crankcase
                and vent crankcase pressure into the intake system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Optional Features</title>
            <para>Optional features available include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Air compressor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Power Takeoff (PTO)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine or exhaust brake</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>An air compressor is available for applications that require air brakes or air suspension. A hydraulic
                power steering pump can be used with or without the air compressor.
            </para>
            <para>The front cover has a mounting flange available for PTO accessories. The air compressor drive gear
                train is used with a spline adapter and provides power for front mounted PTO accessories.
            </para>
            <para>The Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake is available for all engine displacements. The engine brake is a
                compression release brake system that provides additional braking performance. The operator can control
                the engine brake for different operating conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The Diamond Logic&#174; exhaust brake system is also available for all engine displacements. The
                exhaust brake uses the turbocharger to restrict exhaust flow for additional braking. The operator can
                control the exhaust brake for different operating conditions.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Optional Cold Climate Features</title>
            </para>
            <para>Optional cold climate features available include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Oil pan heater</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant heater</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel heater</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>All three heaters use an electric element to warm engine fluids in cold weather conditions.</para>
            <para>The oil pan heater warms engine oil to ensure optimum oil flow.</para>
            <para>The coolant heater warms engine coolant surrounding the cylinders. Warmed engine coolant aids in
                performance and fuel economy during start-up.
            </para>
            <para>The fuel heater is installed in the fuel filter header assembly and warms the supply fuel. Warmed
                supply fuel prevents waxing, and improves performance and fuel economy during cold weather start-up.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Chassis Mounted Features</title>
            <para>A Charge Air Cooler (CAC) is an air-to-air heat exchanger which increases the density of the air
                charge.
            </para>
            <para>The Aftertreatment System, part of the larger Exhaust System, processes engine exhaust to meet
                tailpipe emission requirements.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC) burns oxygen and hydrocarbons in the exhaust stream.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) captures and burns particulates in the exhaust stream.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
