<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System -
        Actuators
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s01.6.2" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Actuators</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s01.6.2.1">
            <para>The ECM controls engine operation with the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>EGR valve and control</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VGT control</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake throttle control and throttle position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Glow plug relay</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>H-bridge Circuit</title>
            <para>The EGR valve and ITV actuator motors are operated by an H-bridge (by-polar) circuit in each valve
                assembly.
            </para>
            <para>An H-bridge circuit operates like putting a power source on one side of a motor and hooking the other
                side of the motor to a ground. This turns the motor. By shifting the leads on the motor it will turn in
                the opposite direction.
            </para>
            <para>To control the motor in both forward and reverse with a processor, you will need an H-Bridge. Relays
                configured in this fashion make an H-Bridge. The "high side drivers" are the relays that control the
                positive voltage to the motor. This is called sourcing current. The "low side drivers" are the relays
                that control the negative voltage to sink current to the motor. "Sinking current" is the term for
                connecting the circuit to the negative side of the power supply, which is usually ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.6.2.2">
            <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculating (EGR) Valve and Control</title>
            <para>The EGR valve controls the flow of exhaust gases to the intake manifold. The EGR valve is integrated
                with an EGRP sensor.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM controls the EGR valve with a Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) signal through H-bridge
                circuitry.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM controls motor speed using PWM. The EGR is closed by driving the Exhaust Gas Recirculating
                High (EGRH) circuit high. When driving the EGRH high, this causes Exhaust Gas Recirculating Low (EGRL)
                circuit to go low.
            </para>
            <para>Variable voltage is needed to move the valve and minimal voltage is needed to maintain its position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.6.2.3">
            <title>Intake Throttle Valve (ITV) Actuator and Position Sensor</title>
            <para>The ITV is used to control air/fuel mixture during a regeneration process of the aftertreatment
                system. The ITV is also used to insure a smooth engine shut down by restricting air flow to the engine
                at shut down.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM controls the ITV with a Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) signal through H-bridge circuitry.</para>
            <para>The ECM controls motor speed using PWM. The ITV is close by driving the Intake Throttle Valve High
                (ITVH) circuit high. When driving the ITVH high, this causes Intake Throttle Valve Low (ITVL) circuit to
                go low.
            </para>
            <para>Variable voltage is needed to move the valve and minimal voltage is needed to maintain its position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.6.2.4">
            <title>Glow Plug Relay</title>
            <para>The ECM activates the glow plug relay. The relay delivers VBAT to the glow plugs for up to 120
                seconds, depending on engine coolant temperature and altitude. The ground circuit is supplied directly
                from the battery ground at all times. Relay is controlled by switching on a voltage source from the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
