<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Terminology -
        Terminology
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Terminology</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <deflist>
                <term>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</term>
                <def>A potentiometer sensor that indicates the position of the accelerator pedal.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Accessory work</term>
                <def>The work per cycle required to drive engine accessories (normally, only those essential to engine
                    operation).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Actuator</term>
                <def>A device that performs work in response to an input signal.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Aeration</term>
                <def>The entrainment of gas (air or combustion gas) in the coolant, lubricant, or fuel.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>After cooler (Charge Air Cooler)</term>
                <def>A heat exchanger mounted in the charge air path between the turbocharger and engine intake
                    manifold. The after cooler reduces the charge air temperature by transferring heat from the charge
                    air to a cooling medium (usually air).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Air Management System (AMS)</term>
                <def>The AMS controls and directs air through the intake and exhaust which affects engine performance
                    and controls emissions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Alternating Current (AC)</term>
                <def>An electric current that reverses its direction at regularly recurring intervals.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Ambient temperature</term>
                <def>The environmental air temperature in which a unit is operating. In general, the temperature is
                    measured in the shade (no solar radiation) and represents the air temperature for other engine
                    cooling performance measurement purposes. Air entering the radiator may or may not be the same
                    ambient due to possible heating from other sources or recirculation. (SAE J1004 SEP81)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Ampere (amp)</term>
                <def>The standard unit for measuring the strength of an electrical current. The flow rate of a charge in
                    a conductor or conducting medium of one coulomb per second. (SAE J1213 NOV82)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Analog</term>
                <def>A continuously variable voltage.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Analog to digital converter (A/D)</term>
                <def>A circuit in the ECM processing section that converts an analog signal (DC or AC) to a usable
                    digital signal for the microprocessor.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>American Trucking Association (ATA) Data link</term>
                <def>A serial data link specified by the American Trucking Association and the SAE.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Acoustic Wave Attenuator</term>
                <def>A component of the high-pressure oil rail designed to reduce hydraulic fluctuations resulting in a
                    decrease of acoustic energy.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP) sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor which, when supplied with a 5 volt reference signal from the ECM,
                    produces a linear analog voltage signal indicating atmospheric pressure.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Boost pressure</term>
                <def>1. The pressure of the charge air leaving the turbocharger.</def>
            </deflist>
            <para>2. Inlet manifold pressure that is greater than atmospheric pressure. Obtained by turbocharging.
            </para>
            <deflist>
                <term>Bottom Dead Center (BDC)</term>
                <def>The lowest position of the piston during the stroke.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor</term>
                <def>The BCP sensor is a variable capacitance sensor that senses the oil pressure in the brake gallery
                    of the high-pressure oil rail.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>
                    <emph type="bold">Brake Horsepower (bhp)</emph>
                </term>
                <def>The power output from an engine, not the indicated horsepower. The power output of an engine,
                    sometimes called flywheel horsepower is less than the indicated horsepower by the amount of friction
                    horsepower consumed in the engine.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Brake Horsepower (bhp) net</term>
                <def>Net brake horsepower is measured with all engine components. The power of an engine when configured
                    as a fully equipped engine. (SAE J1349 JUN90)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Calibration</term>
                <def>The data values used by the strategy to solve equations and make decisions. Calibration values are
                    stored in ROM and put into the processor during programming to allow the engine to operate within
                    certain parameters.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor</term>
                <def>The CMP sensor is a magnetic pickup sensor which indicates engine position. Speed is indicated by
                    the number of vanes counted per revolution of the camshaft. Camshaft position is indicated by a
                    single position peg that indicates Cylinder Number 1.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Catalyst</term>
                <def>A substance that produces a chemical reaction without undergoing a chemical change itself.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Catalytic converter</term>
                <def>An antipollution device in the exhaust system that contains a catalyst for chemically converting
                    some pollutants in the exhaust gases (carbon monoxide, unburned hydrocarbons, and oxides of
                    nitrogen) into harmless compounds.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Cavitation</term>
                <def>A dynamic condition in a fluid system that forms gas-filled bubbles (cavities) in the fluid.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Cetane number</term>
                <def>1. The auto ignition quality of diesel fuel.</def>
            </deflist>
            <para>2. A rating applied to diesel fuel similar to octane rating for gasoline.</para>
            <para>3. A measure of how readily diesel fuel starts to burn (autoignites) at high compression
                temperature.
            </para>
            <para>Diesel fuel with a high cetane number autoignites shortly after injection into the combustion chamber.
                Therefore, it has a short ignition delay time. Diesel fuel with a low cetane number resists
                autoignition. Therefore, it has a longer ignition delay time.
            </para>
            <deflist>
                <term>Charge air</term>
                <def>Dense, pressurized, heated air discharged from the turbocharger.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Charge Air Cooler (CAC)</term>
                <def>See
                    <emph type="bold">After cooler</emph>.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Closed crankcase</term>
                <def>Crankcase ventilation system that recycles crankcase gases through a breather, then back to the
                    clean air intake.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Closed loop operation</term>
                <def>A system that uses a sensor to provide feedback to the ECM. The ECM uses the sensor to continuously
                    monitor variables and it make adjustments to match engine requirements.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Cloud point</term>
                <def>The point when wax crystals occur in fuel, making fuel cloudy or hazy. Usually below -12&#176;C (10&#176;F).</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Cold cranking ampere rating (battery rating)</term>
                <def>The sustained constant current (in amperes) needed to produce a minimum terminal voltage under a
                    load of 7.2 volts per battery after 30 seconds.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Continuous Monitor Test</term>
                <def>An ECM function that continuously monitors the inputs and outputs to ensure that readings are
                    within set limits.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Controller Area Network (CAN)</term>
                <def>This is a J1939 high speed communication link.
                    <emph type="bold">CAN 1</emph>
                    is a public drive train data link between the vehicle modules and ECM.
                    <emph type="bold">CAN 2</emph>
                    is a private link between the ECM and IDM.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Coolant</term>
                <def>A fluid used to transport heat from one point to another.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Coolant level switch</term>
                <def>A switch used to indicate coolant level.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Cooling system capacity (volume)</term>
                <def>The amount of coolant that completely fills a cooling system to its designated cold level mark.
                    (SAE J1004 SEP81)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Crankcase</term>
                <def>The housing that encloses the crankshaft, connecting rods, and allied parts.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Crankcase breather</term>
                <def>A vent for the crankcase to release excess interior air pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Crankcase pressure</term>
                <def>The force of air inside the crankcase against the crankcase housing.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Crankshaft (CKP) sensor</term>
                <def>The CKP sensor is a magnetic pickup sensor that indicates crankshaft speed and position.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Current</term>
                <def>The flow of electrons passing through a conductor. Measured in amperes.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Damper</term>
                <def>A device that reduces the amplitude of torsional vibration. (SAE J1479 JAN85)</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Deaeration</term>
                <def>The removal or purging of gases (air or combustion gas) entrapped in coolant or lubricating oil.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Deaeration tank</term>
                <def>A separate tank in the cooling system used for one or more of the following functions:</def>
            </deflist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Deaeration</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant reservoir (fluid expansion and after boil)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant retention</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Filling</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fluid level indication (visible)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC)</term>
                <def>Formerly called a Fault Code or Flash Code. A DTC is a three digit numeric code used for
                    troubleshooting.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Diamond Logic&#174; Engine Brake</term>
                <def>The Diamond Logic&#174; Engine Brake is a compression release braking system that uses a
                    high-pressure oil rail components together with the VGT for additional braking. The operator
                    controls the engine brake for different operating conditions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Diamond Logic&#174; Exhaust Brake</term>
                <def>The Diamond Logic&#174; Exhaust Brake is an exhaust brake system that uses only the VGT to restrict
                    exhaust flow for additional braking. The operator controls the exhaust brake for different operating
                    conditions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</term>
                <def>An electronic meter that uses a digital display to indicate a measured value. Preferred for use on
                    microprocessor systems because it has a very high internal impedance and will not load down the
                    circuit being measured.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Direct Current (DC)</term>
                <def>An electric current flowing in one direction only and substantially constant in value.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Disable</term>
                <def>A computer decision that deactivates a system and prevents operation of the system.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Displacement</term>
                <def>The stroke of the piston multiplied by the area of the cylinder bore multiplied by the number of
                    cylinders in the engine.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</term>
                <def>A switch that indicates when the driveline is disengaged from the engine.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Driver (high side)</term>
                <def>A transistor in an electronic module that controls the power to an actuator circuit.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Driver (low side)</term>
                <def>A transistor in an electronic module that controls the ground to an actuator circuit.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Drivetrain data link (CAN 1) J1939</term>
                <def>The primary communication link for the ECM, ESC, and instrument cluster.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Duty cycle</term>
                <def>A control signal that has a controlled on/off time measurement from 0 to 100%. Normally used to
                    control solenoids.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Elastomer</term>
                <def>An elastic, rubber like substance such as natural or synthetic rubber material. (SAE J111 MAR85)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</term>
                <def>The Electronic Control Module is an electronic microprocessor that monitors and controls engine
                    performance, exhaust emissions, and vehicle system performance (cruise control, transmission
                    control, starter engagement, etc.). The ECM provides diagnostic information for engine and vehicle
                    systems and can be programmed at different levels for engine protection, warning, and shutdown.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Electronic Service Tool (EST)</term>
                <def>A computer diagnostic and programming tool for the ECM and ESC. The hardware is typically a laptop
                    computer or notebook computer. The diagnostic and programming software includes International Master
                    Diagnostics, ISIS on-line documentation, and NETS for factory programming.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Electronic System Controller (ESC)</term>
                <def>An electronic module that provides multiple analog and switched input interfaces to monitor vehicle
                    functions through solid state switches, relay driver outputs, and serial data communication.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Control Module (ECM) power relay</term>
                <def>An ECM controlled relay that supplies power to the ECM.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor</term>
                <def>A thermistor sensor that senses engine coolant temperature.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor that senses fuel pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC)</term>
                <def>A readable code in the calibration list of the EST that identifies engine horsepower and emission
                    calibrations.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine lamp</term>
                <def>An instrument panel lamp that comes on when DTCs are set. DTCs can be read as flash codes (red and
                    amber instrument panel lamps).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine OFF tests</term>
                <def>Tests that are done with the ignition key ON and the engine OFF.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine RUNNING tests</term>
                <def>Tests done with the engine running.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor that senses engine oil pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) sensor</term>
                <def>A thermistor sensor that senses engine oil temperature.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust brake</term>
                <def>A brake device using engine exhaust back pressure as a retarding medium.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR)</term>
                <def>The Exhaust Gas Recirculation is a system that recycles a controlled portion of exhaust gas back
                    into the combustion chamber to reduce Nitrogen Oxide exhaust emissions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) drive module</term>
                <def>The EGR drive module controls the position of the EGR valve.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) cooler</term>
                <def>The exhaust gas is cooled in the EGR cooler and flows through the EGR control valve to the EGR
                    mixer duct.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve</term>
                <def>The EGR valve, when open, will mix exhaust gas with filtered intake air which flows into the intake
                    manifold. The EGR valve, when closed, only allows filtered air to flow into the intake manifold.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Exhaust manifold</term>
                <def>Exhaust gases flow through the exhaust manifold to the turbocharger exhaust inlet and are directed
                    to the EGR cooler or out the exhaust system.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EVRT&#174; electronic controlled turbocharger</term>
                <def>International's version of a Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT).</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EZ-Tech&#174; inerface cable</term>
                <def>The EZ-Tech&#174; inerface cable connects to the EST to communicate with the Electronic Controlled
                    Module (ECM).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fault detection and management</term>
                <def>An alternate control strategy that reduces adverse effects that can be caused by a system failure.
                    If a sensor fails, the ECM substitutes a good sensor signal or assumed sensor value in its place. A
                    lit amber or red instrument panel lamp signals that the vehicle needs service.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Filter restriction</term>
                <def>A blockage, usually from contaminants, that prevents the flow of fluid through a filter.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Flash code</term>
                <def>See
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC)</emph>.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fuel inlet restriction</term>
                <def>A blockage, usually from contaminants, that prevents the flow of fluid through the fuel inlet
                    line.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fuel pressure</term>
                <def>The force that the fuel exerts on the fuel system as it is pumped through the fuel system.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fuel strainer</term>
                <def>A pre filter in the fuel system that keeps larger contaminants from entering the fuel system.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fully equipped engine</term>
                <def>A fully equipped engine is an engine equipped with only those accessories necessary to perform its
                    intended service. A fully equipped engine does not include components that are used to power
                    auxiliary systems. If these components are integral with the engine or for any reason are included
                    on the test engine, the power absorbed may be determined and add to the net brake power. (SAE J1995
                    JUN90)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Fusible link (fuse link)</term>
                <def>A fusible link is a special section of low tension cable designed to open the circuit when
                    subjected to an extreme current overload. (SAE J1156 APR86)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Gradeability</term>
                <def>The maximum percent grade which the vehicle can transverse for a specified time at a specified
                    speed. The gradeability limit is the grade upon which the vehicle can just move forward. (SAE J227a)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Gross brake horsepower</term>
                <def>The power of a complete basic engine, with air cleaner, without fan, and alternator and air
                    compressor not charging.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Hall effect</term>
                <def>The development of a transverse electric potential gradient in a current-carrying conductor or
                    semiconductor when a magnetic field is applied.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Hall effect sensor</term>
                <def>Generates a digital on or off signal that indicates speed or position.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>High speed digital inputs</term>
                <def>Inputs to the ECM from a sensor that generates varying frequencies (engine speed and vehicle speed
                    sensors).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Horsepower (hp)</term>
                <def>Horsepower is the unit of work done in a given period of time, equal to 33,000 pounds multiplied by
                    one foot per minute.
                    <emph type="bold">1 hp = 33,000 lb x 1 ft /1 min</emph>.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Hydrocarbons</term>
                <def>Unburned or partially burned fuel molecules.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Idle speed</term>
                <def>Low idle is the minimum engine speed. High idle is the maximum governed engine speed with no
                    load.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</term>
                <def>An On/Off switch that senses when the accelerator pedal is in the idle position. There is also a
                    cold idle advance that increases low idle speed for a short period to aid in engine warm-up in cold
                    temperatures.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Injector Drive Module (IDM) power relay</term>
                <def>An IDM controlled relay that supplies power to the IDM.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Indicated horsepower</term>
                <def>The theoretical power transmitted to the pistons by gas in the cylinders.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</term>
                <def>High lube oil pressure generated by a high-pressure pump/pressure regulator used to hydraulically
                    actuate the fuel injectors and the optional Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</term>
                <def>A Pulse Width Modulated (PWM) regulator valve, controlled by the ECM, that regulates injection
                    control pressure.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor that senses injection control pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Intake Air Temperature (IAT) sensor</term>
                <def>A thermistor sensor that senses intake air temperature.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Intake manifold</term>
                <def>A plenum through which the air mixture flows from the charged air cooler piping to the intake
                    passages of the cylinder head.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>International NGV Tool Utilized for Next Generation Electronics (INTUNE)</term>
                <def>The diagnostics software for chassis related components and systems.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Low speed digital inputs</term>
                <def>Switched sensor inputs that generate an on/off (high/low) signal to the ECM. The input to the ECM
                    from the sensor could be from a high input source switch (usually 5 or 12 volts) or from a grounding
                    switch that grounds the signal from a current limiting resistor in the ECM that creates a low signal
                    (0 volts).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Lubricity</term>
                <def>Lubricity is the ability of a substance to reduce friction between solid surfaces in relative
                    motion under loaded conditions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Lug (engine)</term>
                <def>A condition when the engine is operating at or below maximum torque speed.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</term>
                <def>Intake manifold pressure (boost pressure).</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor that senses intake manifold pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Manometer</term>
                <def>A double-leg liquid-column gauge, or a single inclined gauge, used to measure the difference
                    between two fluid pressures. Typically, a manometer records in inches of water.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Master Diagnostics (MD)</term>
                <def>The diagnostics software for engine related components and systems to use on the electronic service
                    tool or personal computer.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</term>
                <def>Intake manifold air temperature</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT) sensor</term>
                <def>A thermistor style sensor housed in the intake manifold used to indicate air temperature after
                    passing through the charge air cooler.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Microprocessor</term>
                <def>An integrated circuit in a microcomputer that controls information flow.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Nitrogen Oxides (NO
                    <subscript>x</subscript>)
                </term>
                <def>Nitrogen oxides form by a reaction between nitrogen and oxygen at high temperatures and pressures
                    in the combustion chamber.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Normally closed</term>
                <def>Refers to a switch that remains closed when no control force is acting on it.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Normally open</term>
                <def>Refers to a switch that remains open when no control force is acting on it.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Ohm (&#x2126;)</term>
                <def>The unit of resistance. One ohm is the value of resistance through which a potential of one volt
                    will maintain a current of one ampere. (SAE J1213 NOV82)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>On demand test</term>
                <def>A self test that the technician initiates using the EST. It is run from a program in the
                    processor.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Output Circuit Check (OCC)</term>
                <def>An On demand test done during an Engine OFF self test to check the continuity of selected
                    actuators.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Output State Check (OSC)</term>
                <def>An On demand test that forces the processor to activate actuators (High or Low) for additional
                    diagnostics.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>pH</term>
                <def>A measure of the acidity or alkalinity of a solution.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Particulate matter</term>
                <def>Particulate matter includes mostly burned particles of fuel and engine oil.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Piezometer</term>
                <def>An instrument for measuring fluid pressure.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Positive On Shaft Excluder (POSE)</term>
                <def>It is a separate piece from the rest of the front or rear seal used to keep out dust / debris.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Potentiometer</term>
                <def>A potentiometer is a variable voltage divider that senses the position of a mechanical component. A
                    reference voltage is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical rotary or linear motion
                    moves the wiper along the resistance material, changing voltage at each point along the resistive
                    material. Voltage is proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Power</term>
                <def>Power is a measure of the rate at which work is done. Compare with
                    <emph type="bold">Torque</emph>.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Power Take Off (PTO)</term>
                <def>Accessory output, usually from the transmission, used to power a hydraulic pump for a special
                    auxiliary feature (garbage packing, lift equipment, etc.).
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Pulse Width Modulation (PWM)</term>
                <def>The time that an actuator, such as an injector, remains energized.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Random Access Memory (RAM)</term>
                <def>Computer memory that stores information. Information can be written to and read from RAM. Input
                    information (current engine speed or temperature) can be stored in RAM to be compared to values
                    stored in Read Only Memory (ROM). All memory in RAM is lost when the ignition switch is turned off.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Rated gross horsepower</term>
                <def>Engine gross horsepower at rated speed as declared by the manufacturer. (SAE J1995 JUN90)</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Rated horsepower</term>
                <def>Maximum brake horsepower output of an engine as certified by the engine manufacturer. The power of
                    an engine when configured as a basic engine. (SAE J1995 JUN90)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Rated net horsepower</term>
                <def>Engine net horsepower at rated speed as declared by the manufacturer. (SAE J1349 JUN90)</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Rated speed</term>
                <def>The speed, as determined by the manufacturer, at which the engine is rated. (SAE J1995 JUN90)</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Rated torque</term>
                <def>Maximum torque produced by an engine as certified by the manufacturer.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Read Only Memory (ROM)</term>
                <def>Computer memory that stores permanent information for calibration tables and operating strategies.
                    Permanently stored information in ROM cannot be changed or lost by turning the engine off or when
                    ECM power is interrupted.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Reference voltage (V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>)
                </term>
                <def>A 5 volt reference supplied by the ECM to operate the engine and chassis sensors.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Reserve capacity</term>
                <def>Time in minutes that a fully charged battery can be discharged to 10.5 volts at 25 amperes.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Signal ground</term>
                <def>The common ground wire from the ECM for the sensors.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Speed Control Command Switches (SCCS)</term>
                <def>A set of switches used for cruise control, Power Take Off (PTO), and remote hand throttle system.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Steady state condition</term>
                <def>An engine operating at a constant speed and load and at stabilized temperatures and pressures. (SAE
                    J215 JAN80)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Strategy</term>
                <def>A plan or set of operating instructions that the microprocessor follows for a desired goal.
                    Strategy is the computer program itself, including all equations and decision making logic. Strategy
                    is always stored in ROM and cannot be changed during calibration.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Stroke</term>
                <def>Stroke is the movement of the piston from Top Dead Center (TDC) to Bottom Dead Center (BDC).</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Substrate</term>
                <def>Material that supports the wash coating or catalytic materials.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Sulfur dioxide (SO
                    <subscript>2</subscript>)
                </term>
                <def>Sulfur dioxide is caused by oxidation of sulfur contained in fuel.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Switch sensors</term>
                <def>Switch sensors indicate position. They operate open or closed, allowing or preventing the flow of
                    current. A switch sensor can be a voltage input switch or a grounding switch. A voltage input switch
                    supplies the ECM with a voltage when it is closed. A grounding switch grounds the circuit closed,
                    causing a zero voltage signal. Grounding switches are usually installed in series with a current
                    limiting resistor.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>System restriction (air)</term>
                <def>The static pressure differential that occurs at a given air flow from air entrance through air exit
                    in a system. Usually measured in inches (millimeters) of water. (SAE J1004 SEP81)
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Tachometer output signal</term>
                <def>Engine speed signal for remote tachometers.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Thermistor</term>
                <def>A thermistor sensor changes its electrical resistance to temperature. Resistance in the thermistor
                    decreases as temperature increases, and increases as temperature decreases. Thermistors works with a
                    resistor that limits current in the ECM to form a voltage signal matched with a temperature value.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Thrust load</term>
                <def>A thrust load pushes or reacts through a bearing in a direction parallel to the shaft.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Top Dead Center (TDC)</term>
                <def>The highest position of the piston during the stroke.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Top Dead Center (compression)</term>
                <def>Top Dead Center (compression) is when the piston is at the highest position and both intake and
                    exhaust valves are closed.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Torque</term>
                <def>Torque is a measure of force producing torsion and rotation around an axis. Torque is the product
                    of the force, usually measured in pounds, and radius perpendicular to the axis of the force
                    extending to the point where the force is applied or where it originates, usually measured in feet.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Truck Computer Analysis of Performance and Economy (TCAPE)</term>
                <def>Truck Computer Analysis of Performance and Economy is a computer program that simulates the
                    performance and fuel economy of trucks.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Turbocharger</term>
                <def>A turbine driven compressor mounted to the exhaust manifold. The turbocharger increases the
                    pressure, temperature and density of intake air to charge air.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Valve cover gasket</term>
                <def>A valve cover gasket that contains the pass through electronic wiring harness connectors for the
                    ICP and BCP sensors, the brake shutoff valve, and six fuel injectors.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Variable capacitance sensor</term>
                <def>A variable capacitance sensor is a sensor that measures pressure. The pressure measured is applied
                    to a ceramic material. The pressure forces the ceramic material closer to a thin metal disk. This
                    action changes the capacitance of the sensor.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</term>
                <def>The VGT is a turbocharger with actuated vanes inside the turbine housing. The vanes modify flow
                    characteristics of exhaust gases through the turbine housing for boast pressure control at various
                    engine speeds and load conditions.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>(VGT) control module</term>
                <def>The VGT control module is an electronic microprocessor that converts a pulse width modulated signal
                    from the ECM to control a DC motor that controls the VGT vane position.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Vehicle Electronic System Programming System</term>
                <def>The computer system used to program electronically controlled vehicles.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Vehicle Retarder Enable/Engage</term>
                <def>Output from the ECM to a vehicle retarder.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</term>
                <def>A magnetic pickup sensor mounted in the tail shaft housing of the transmission, used to calculate
                    ground speed.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Viscosity</term>
                <def>The internal resistance to the flow of any fluid.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Viscous fan</term>
                <def>A fan drive that is activated when a thermostat, sensing high air temperature, forces fluid through
                    a special coupling. The fluid activates the fan.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Volt (v)</term>
                <def>A unit of electromotive force that will move a current of one ampere through a resistance of one
                    Ohm.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Voltage</term>
                <def>Electrical potential expressed in volts.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Voltage drop</term>
                <def>Reduction in applied voltage from the current flowing through a circuit or portion of the circuit
                    current multiplied by resistance.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Voltage ignition</term>
                <def>Voltage supplied by the ignition switch when the key is ON.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Water In Fuel (WIF) switch</term>
                <def>The WIF switch detects water in the fuel.</def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Water supply housing (Freon bracket)</term>
                <def>The water supply housing (Freon Bracket) is a coolant supply housing with a deaeration port and a
                    connection for cab heat.
                </def>
            </deflist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_E2700110.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_E2700111.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
