<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL&#174; VT 365 DIESEL ENGINE - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Engine Systems - Fuel Management</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Fuel Management</title>
        <svcsubproc id="s235in01">
            <title>Fuel Injection</title>
            <para>The engine uses an electrohydraulic injector as part of its fuel system. This ECM controlled injector
                uses high-pressure lube oil to provide the necessary force to inject fuel into the combustion chamber at
                pressures up to 144 MPa (21,000 psi) at rated horsepower.
            </para>
            <para>The injector fits into a sleeved bore machined into the cylinder head. The injector bore intersects
                with a machined fuel passage that runs the length of the head. Each injector has two O-rings around the
                outer body, one above the fuel passage, and one below. A fuel inlet port between the O-rings allows fuel
                under transfer pump pressure to enter the pressure amplification area of the injector. High-pressure
                engine oil enters the injector through the top. The high-pressure oil rail assembly is mounted on top of
                the injectors.
            </para>
            <para>The injector is composed of 3 sections with the following components:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Oil control</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Spool valve</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Opening coil</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Closing coil</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Control valve body</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pressure amplification</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Intensifier piston and plunger</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Piston return spring</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inlet check valve</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Outlet check valve</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fuel injection</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Nozzle tip</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Valve Opening Pressure (VOP) spring</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fuel strainers</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Casenut</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f235in19" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd11/D1117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="264px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Fuel Injector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Closing coil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Control valve body</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intensifier piston (7:1 ratio)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston return spring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Plunger</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve opening pressure spring, 260 bar (3,770 psi)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Needle</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Opening coil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Spool valve (control valve)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Casenut</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel strainer (3)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Nozzle assembly</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The injection operation is divided into three major stages or cycles:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Fill stage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection stage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>End of injection</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The oil control section uses a spool valve to direct high-pressure oil from the injection control
                pressure system into and out of the injector. The spool valve floats in a bore machined into the valve
                housing, and is positioned by the magnetic field created when voltage is applied to either the opening
                or closing coils.
            </para>
            <para>When voltage is applied to the opening coil, the spool valve opens, allowing high-pressure oil from
                the inlet port to enter the pressure amplification area of the injector. With the spool allowing oil to
                enter the injector, pressure begins to push on the intensifier piston. The large diameter intensifier
                piston and small diameter plunger are pushed downward together. The upper piston surface area is open to
                the high-pressure oil and the lower plunger surface area pushes against a column of fuel. The ratio of
                the surfaces areas are approximately 7 to 1. Therefore, if the ICP oil pressure is about 7 MPa (1,000
                psi), then the plunger movement creates a fuel pressure of approximately 48-49 MPa (7,000 psi). The
                increased fuel pressure causes the inlet check valve to close, trapping the fuel from moving back into
                the head.
            </para>
            <para>The high pressure fuel from the plunger travels down the injector to the nozzle area where it works
                against the bevel on the nozzle valve. When fuel pressure reaches 18 MPa (2,700 psi) the thrust of the
                pressurized fuel overcomes the nozzle valve spring and lifts the nozzle valve off its seat, allowing
                fuel under extremely high pressure to enter the combustion chamber through the nozzle tip holes. Fuel
                continues to flow until the proper amount of fuel enters the combustion chamber. At that point, the
                closing coil is energized, the spool valve moves, and the oil flow stops. When fuel pressure drops, the
                valve opening pressure spring forces the nozzle valve closed and fuel flow stops. Combustion gases will
                be restricted from entering the injector past the fuel outlet check valve. The injector is again in a
                static position to allow fuel to enter past the inlet check valve and refill the lower area of the
                plunger.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="S235in03">
            <title>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) System</title>
            <figure id="f2351101" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd31/d3109.png" type="png" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. High-pressure oil system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Hydraulic pump assembly (high-pressure), w/discharge tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">IPR valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ICP sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Hydraulic pump cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel injector assembly (8)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil rail assembly (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil rail fitting w/ check valve (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil hose (right side)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase to head tube assembly (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Branch tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil hose (left side)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">General System Flow</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure oil system is composed of two subsystems:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel injector assembly</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The hydraulic force necessary to inject fuel into the combustion chamber is provided by the ICP
                system. The fuel injectors on the engine are hydraulically actuated and electronically controlled .
            </para>
            <para>The ICP system is composed of the following components:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Oil reservoir</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hydraulic pump assembly, high-pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hydraulic pump cover</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High-pressure tubes and hoses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High-pressure rail assemblies</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check valves</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The high-pressure hydraulic pump receives engine lube oil from a reservoir cast into the vee of the
                crankcase. This reservoir makes available a constant supply of engine oil for the pump. Oil for this
                reservoir is constantly refilled by the low-pressure lube oil system with filtered oil from a passage in
                the oil cooler housing.
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure hydraulic pump is mounted at the rear of the crankcase and is driven by the camshaft
                gear. Oil for the pump is drawn from the oil reservoir through a 150 micron screen and into a passage to
                the pump inlet port. High-pressure oil from the pump is distributed to the injectors through a series of
                pipes and hoses.
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure discharge tube is mounted to the pump and serves to connect the oil flow from the
                high-pressure hydraulic pump to the rear engine tube assembly. This tube assembly divides oil flow into
                two pipes or branches, one for each side of the engine. Rigid pipes thread into each branch and direct
                oil up into the rocker carrier of each cylinder head. Flexible hoses with quick disconnect ends connect
                the rigid pipes to check valves, which are mounted on each of the oil rail assemblies. Oil from the
                rails enter the injectors through O-ring sealed ports at the top of each injector. When the injector
                opening coil is energized, high-pressure oil is used to push fuel into the combustion chamber. After
                injection is complete, the oil inside the injector is vented through the top portion of the injector and
                allowed to drain back to the oil sump.
            </para>
            <figure id="f235in16" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31013.png" type="png" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. ICP closed loop system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ICP System Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Electronic control of the high pressure oil system consists of the following components:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>ECM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IDM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP sensor, located on the hydraulic oil pump cover, at the rear of the engine.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IPR valve, located on the hydraulic oil pump cover, at the rear of the engine.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The ECM controls the injection control pressure by operating the IPR regulator. The results are
                continuously monitored by the ECM using the ICP sensor. The injection control pressure sensor provides
                pressure information in the form of an analog voltage signal to the ECM at any given time. The pressure
                signal obtained from the ICP allows the ECM to know the actual injection control pressure at all times
                of engine operation, or even during cranking mode. This operation is known as Closed Loop.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic codes can be set by the ECM if the ICP signal is out of range or if the ICP signal received
                corresponds to an out of range value for the injection control pressure at a given operating condition.
            </para>
            <para>Should any of these occur, the ECM will ignore the ICP signal and control the IPR valve operation from
                programmed default values. This condition is known as Open Loop.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IPR</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The IPR is an electrically controlled pilot operated (small flow that controls a large flow) pressure
                control valve. The IPR controls injection control pressure from approximately 3 - 20 MPa (500 - 3,000
                psi). An electrical signal from the ECM to the IPR solenoid creates a magnetic field, which applies a
                variable force on the poppet valve to control pressure. Injection control pressure is governed by the
                ECM, depending upon ICP sensor input and the driver's demand for power.
            </para>
            <para>The IPR valve is a pulse width (duty cycle %) modulated valve operating at 200 Hz. The pulse width is
                modulated between 6 to 65% to control ICP pressure in the range of 3 to 20 MPa (500 to 3,000 psi). The
                IPR valve is mounted in the hydraulic pump and maintains desired injection control pressure by dumping
                excess oil through a set of main dump ports into the crankcase and back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>As the demand for injection control pressure increases, the ECM increases the pulse width (duty cycle
                %) to the IPR valve. This action forces the poppet against the drain orifice, increasing the pressure
                behind the poppet valve. As oil pressure increases behind the poppet valve, it moves forward and blocks
                the drain ports on the sides of the IPR valve.
            </para>
            <para>When the demand for injection control pressure decreases, the ECM decreases the pulse width (duty
                cycle %) to the IPR valve coil windings, allowing oil to drain out of the main dump ports. This action
                is accomplished by relieving the pressure behind the poppet valve, which allows it to partially open the
                relief port, decreasing ICP pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The described operation allows the IPR to continuously adjust injection control pressure commanded by
                the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
