<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Air Management System -
        Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System</title>
        <para>The EGR system reduces Nitrogen Oxide (NO
            <subscript>X</subscript>) emissions. NO
            <subscript>X</subscript>
            gas forms when nitrogen and oxygen react during high combustion temperatures. Mixing exhaust with inlet air
            reduces combustion temperature and NO
            <subscript>X</subscript>
            gas formation.
        </para>
        <para>Some exhaust from the exhaust tube assembly flows through the EGR cooler, intake manifold EGR passage, and
            to the EGR valve. The Electronic Control Module (ECM) commands the EGR valve to open, when needed, allowing
            cooled exhaust gases to enter the intake manifold to mix with intake air.
        </para>
        <figure id="f3050116" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk35/K35120.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>EGR closed loop operation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The ECM commands EGR valve position based on engine speed, Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP), Manifold Air
            Temperature (MAP), and Manifold Air Pressure (MAT) sensor input. The EGR valve provides feedback to the ECM
            on current valve position.
        </para>
        <figure id="f3050115" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figN17/N17002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>EGR valve</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The EGR valve assembly consists of three major components; a dual poppet valve, a DC motor, and an
            Integrated Circuit (IC). The IC has three Hall effect position sensors to monitor valve movement. The EGR
            valve uses a DC motor to control the position of the valve assembly. The valve assembly has two valve heads
            on a common shaft.
        </para>
        <para>The EGR valve is installed in the front of the intake manifold.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
