<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Fuel Management
        System - ICP System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="5">
        <title>ICP System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f3350007172" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/k35174.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="no"/>
                <caption>ICP system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector oil inlet from high-pressure oil manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil outlet (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel inlet port (4)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil inlet from front cover reservoir</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil pump assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel injector assembly (6)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil hose</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>High-Pressure Oil Flow</title>
            <para>The lubrication system constantly refills the oil reservoir located in the front cover. The reservoir
                provides oil for the high-pressure oil pump. The pump is mounted on the backside of the front cover and
                gear driven from the front of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>High-pressure oil is directed to the high-pressure oil hose, cylinder head passage, and high-pressure
                oil manifold, which is located beneath the valve cover.
            </para>
            <para>High-pressure oil is used by the fuel injectors to inject, pressurize, and atomize fuel in the
                cylinders. This occurs when the OPEN coil for each fuel injector is energized.
            </para>
            <para>Excess high-pressure oil is directed to the crankcase sump by the Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)
                valve. The IPR valve is controlled by the Engine Control Module (ECM) to maintain a desired injection
                control pressure.
            </para>
            <para>If equipped with the optional engine brake, some high-pressure oil is directed internally to the
                engine brake pistons when the brake is activated.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ICP Closed Loop System</title>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/k35124.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>ICP closed loop system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ICP system is a closed loop system that uses the ICP sensor to continuously provide injection
                control pressure feedback to the ECM. The ECM commands the IPR duty cycle to adjust ICP pressure to
                match engine requirements.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ICP Control System</title>
            <figure id="f3700007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/k35050.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>ICP sensor control system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The IPR solenoid receives a pulse-width modulated signal from the ECM. This indicates the on and off
                time the IPR control valve is energized. The pulse is calibrated to control ICP pressure which ranges
                from 5 MPa (725 psi) up to 32 MPa (4,650 psi).
            </para>
            <para>The IPR valve is mounted in the body of the high-pressure pump. The IPR valve maintains desired
                injection control pressure by dumping excess oil back to the crankcase sump.
            </para>
            <para>As demand for injection control pressure increases, the ECM increases the pulse-width modulation to
                the IPR solenoid. When demand for injection control pressure decreases, the duty cycle to the IPR
                solenoid decreases and more oil is allowed to flow to the drain orifice.
            </para>
            <para>When the injection control pressure electrical signal is out-of-range, the ECM sets a Diagnostic
                Trouble Code (DTC). The ECM will not set DTCs if an injection control pressure signal corresponds to an
                in-range valve for injection control pressure for a given operating condition.
            </para>
            <para>When ICP signals that are out-of-range, the ECM ignores out-of-range signals and go into open loop
                operation. The IPR valve will operate from programmed default values.
            </para>
            <para>The ICP sensor is installed in the high-pressure oil manifold under the valve cover.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Injector</title>
            <figure id="f3350007xxx" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figK11/K11023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="592px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Fuel injector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Upper O-ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lower O-ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Nozzle gasket</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector nozzle</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel inlet port</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel Injector Features</title>
            </para>
            <para>Two 48 volt, 20 amp coils control a spool valve that directs oil flow in and out of the injector. The
                injector coils are turned on for approximately 800 &#181;s (microseconds). Each injector has a single
                four pin connector that couples to the valve cover gasket assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injector Coils and Spool Valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>An OPEN coil and a CLOSE coil on the injector move the spool valve from side to side using magnetic
                force. The spool has two positions:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When the spool valve is open, oil flows into the injector from the high-pressure oil
                        manifold.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the spool valve is closed, oil exits from the top of the fuel injector and drains back to
                        the crankcase.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Intensifier Piston and Plunger</title>
            </para>
            <para>When the spool valve is open, high-pressure oil enters the injector pushing down the intensifier
                piston and plunger. Since the intensifier piston is 7.1 times greater in surface area than the plunger,
                the injection pressure is also 7.1 times greater than injection control pressure on the plunger.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Plunger and Barrel</title>
            </para>
            <para>Fuel pressure builds at the base of the plunger in the barrel. When the intensifier piston pushes the
                plunger down, the plunger increases fuel pressure in the barrel 7.1 times greater than injection control
                pressure. The plunger has a hardened coating to resist scuffing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injector Needle</title>
            </para>
            <para>The injector needle opens inward when fuel pressure overcomes the Valve Opening Pressure (VOP) of 28
                MPa (4,075 psi). Fuel is atomized at high-pressure through the nozzle tip.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel Injector Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The injector operation has three stages:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Fill stage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>End of injection</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figK11/K11042a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="592px"
                         scalefitheight="432px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Fuel injector cross section</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Fill Stage</title>
            </para>
            <para>During the fill stage both coils are de-energized and the spool valve is closed. High-pressure oil
                from the high-pressure oil manifold is stopped at the spool valve.
            </para>
            <para>Low-pressure fuel fills the four ports and enters through the edge filter on its way to the chamber
                beneath the plunger. The needle control spring holds the needle onto its seat to prevent fuel from
                entering the combustion chamber.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injection</title>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>A pulse-width controlled current energizes the OPEN coil. Magnetic force moves the spool valve
                        open. High-pressure oil flows past the spool valve and onto the top of the intensifier piston.
                        Oil pressure overcomes the force of the intensifier piston spring and the intensifier starts to
                        move down. An increase in fuel pressure under the plunger seats the fuel inlet check ball, and
                        fuel pressure starts to build on the needle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The pulse-width controlled current to the OPEN coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains
                        open. High-pressure oil from high-pressure oil manifold continues to flow past the spool valve.
                        The intensifier piston and plunger continue to move and fuel pressure increases in the barrel.
                        When fuel pressure rises above the VOP, the needle lifts off its seat and injection begins.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>End of Injection</title>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>When the ECM determines that the correct injector on-time has been reached (the correct amount
                        of fuel has been delivered), the ECM sends a pulse-width controlled current to the CLOSE coil of
                        the injector. The current energizes the CLOSE coil and magnetic force closes the spool valve.
                        High-pressure oil is stopped against the spool valve.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The pulse-width controlled current to close the coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains
                        closed. Oil above the intensifier piston flows past the spool valve through the exhaust ports.
                        The intensifier piston and plunger return to their initial positions. Fuel pressure decreases
                        until the needle control spring forces the needle back onto its seat.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
