<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Fuel System - Fuel System
        Components
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s01.3.1" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Fuel System Components</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s01.3.1.1">
            <figure id="f3450001016" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figm11/m11001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="532px"/>
                <caption>Fuel system schematic</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f3450001017" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figm11/m11010.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>High-pressure fuel system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pump left tube assembly (pump-to-rail)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Left rail assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pump return tube connection (pump-to-cooler)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filter to pump tube connection (pump-to-secondary fuel filter)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure Fuel Pump (HPFP) assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pump right tube assembly (pump-to-rail)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Right rail assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel Rail Pressure (FRP) sensor port</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel rail to injector fuel tube ports (4 for each rail)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">HPFP gear</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f3450001018" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figm11/m11009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="502px"/>
                <caption>Low-pressure fuel system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filter to pump tube assembly (high-pressure pump-to-secondary fuel filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel pressure diagnostic port (dirty side)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel pressure diagnostic boss (clean side)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filter to pump tube assembly M12 banjo fitting</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure pump to cooler tube assembly M12 banjo fitting</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure pump to cooler tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel cooler to filter tube assembly (cooler-to-secondary fuel filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel cooler assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel return to tank tube assembly (secondary fuel filter-to-fuel tank)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel supply to filter tube (low-pressure fuel pump-to-secondary fuel
                        filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Left injector return tube assembly 1/4 inch banjo fitting</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Right injector return tube assembly 1/4 inch banjo fitting</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Fuel Temperature (EFT) sensor</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f3450001019" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figm11/m11002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Low-pressure fuel supply system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel primer pump assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel supply tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel return from primer tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel return tube assembly (secondary fuel filter-to-fuel tank)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel supply tube assembly (low-pressure fuel pump-to-secondary fuel
                        filter)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter primary header</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Primary filter element assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel drain valve (water and sediment drain for fuel filter)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Bowl assembly with fuel heater/probe (optional)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel from tank</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Primary filter to pump tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Prescreen bowl (Fuel pump strainer)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Gear driven fuel pump assembly (low-pressure fuel pump)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The fuel system includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Low-pressure fuel system</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Low-pressure fuel pump assembly</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Primary fuel filter assembly</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Secondary fuel filter assembly</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fuel cooler assembly</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fuel primer pump assembly</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High-pressure fuel system</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>High-pressure Fuel Pump (HPFP) assembly</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>High-pressure fuel rails assemblies (left and right)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fuel injector assemblies (8)</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.3.1.2">
            <title>Low-pressure Fuel System</title>
            <para>
                <title>Low-pressure fuel pump</title>The low-pressure fuel pump draws fuel from the fuel tank(s) through
                the primary fuel filter and supplies fuel to the secondary fuel filter. It is mounted on the right side
                of the flywheel housing and driven through idler gears by the crankshaft.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Primary fuel filter assembly</title>The primary filter removes water and filters fuel from the
                fuel tank(s). It is mounted in front of the low-pressure fuel pump.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel primer pump</title>The manual priming pump draws fuel from the fuel tank(s) through the
                primary filter after filter replacement or when the fuel system has run out of fuel. This primes the
                fuel system to minimize the amount of air injected into the system on initial startup.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Secondary fuel filter assembly</title>The secondary fuel filter assembly is a two stage filter
                with an internal pressure regulator mounted adjacent to the oil filter.
            </para>
            <para>An internal pressure relief valve maintains a constant pressure throughout the low-pressure system.
            </para>
            <para>A five micron first stage filter filters fuel from the low-pressure fuel pump. The first stage filter
                has an internal drilled air bleed orifice to automatically remove air from the fuel. The filtered fuel
                is mixed with the cooled fuel from the fuel cooler and is directed to a four micron secondary filter.
                Pressure is maintained by an internal pressure regulator.
            </para>
            <para>Fuel is additionally filtered in the second stage filter and is directed to the high-pressure fuel
                pump. This second stage filter also has an internal drilled air bleed orifice to automatically remove
                air from the fuel.
            </para>
            <para>Fuel from the pressure regulator and both air bleed orifices return to the fuel tank(s) through a
                check valve that maintains constant back pressure in the bleed header.
            </para>
            <para>The secondary fuel filter assembly has a temperature sensor mounted in the supply line to the HPFP.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel cooler</title>The fuel from the fuel injectors and the HPFP flows through the fuel cooler
                where it is cooled by the secondary radiator. Cooled fuel is then directed to the secondary fuel filter
                assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.3.1.3">
            <title>High-pressure Fuel System</title>
            <para>
                <revst/>
                <title>High-pressure Fuel Pump (HPFP) assembly</title>The HPFP is a three piston volumetric pump that
                supplies fuel at high pressure to both the fuel rails. The HPFP is mounted in the rear valley on top of
                the engine and driven by the camshaft.
                <revst/>
                <revend/>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Internal Transfer Pump (ITP)</title>The ITP is part of the HPFP assembly and driven off the same
                shaft as the HPFP assembly. The ITP supplies fuel at a slightly higher pressure and flow to the Fuel
                Volume Control Valve (FVCV). Cooling flow for the ITP is provided by routing fuel back to the suction
                side of the transfer pump. The discharge of the ITP has an orifice and check valve that also provides
                additional cooling for the ITP by routing flow to the fuel cooler.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel Volume Control Valve (FVCV)</title>The FVCV regulates the volume of flow sent to the HPFP.
                The FVCV is located in the HPFP assembly and controlled by the FRP via the ECM. The FVCV puts the
                necessary quantity of fuel under pressure to the HPFP.
            </para>
            <para>FVCV control depends on engine speed, injector quantity, fuel temperature, and the number of
                injections per cycle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel Pressure Control Valve (FPCV)</title>The FPCV controls the fuel pressure to the fuel rails.
                The FPCV is located in the HPFP assembly and is controlled by the FRP via the ECM. FPCV control depends
                on fuel pressure and fuel temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fuel Rail Pressure (FRP) sensor</title>The FRP monitors the fuel pressure in the fuel rails and
                sends a signal to the ECM. It is located in the right fuel rail. The FRP sensor harness is routed
                through the right Under Valve Cover (UVC) harness along with the fuel injector connections.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.3.1.4">
            <title>High-pressure Piezo Common Rail (HPCR) System</title>
            <para>The HPFP pumps fuel through separate tubes to each fuel rail. Each fuel rail has four fuel tubes, one
                for each injector, that maintain constant pressure from the high-pressure pump to each injector.
            </para>
            <para>The injectors operate in five cycles; two pre-injection cycles, a main-injection cycle, a
                post-injection cycle, and a late post-injection cycle. The pre-injection cycles and post-injection cycle
                reduce combustion noise, mechanical load, and exhaust emissions. The main-injection cycle injects and
                atomizes fuel in the combustion chambers for combustion. The late post-injection cycle adds fuel to the
                exhaust to regenerate the aftertreatment system.
            </para>
            <para>Each injector has an actuator that opens or closes the injector nozzle. Charging the actuator opens
                the nozzle. The nozzle is closed by discharging the actuator. The ECM charges and discharges each
                actuator by energizing the appropriate high side or low side output. The low side output supplies a
                return circuit for each actuator.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection/Management</title>The ECM can detect if the output is shorted to ground/battery
                detection, the output is open, or if the injector is shorted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.3.1.5">
            <title>Return Fuel System</title>
            <para>The return fuel system moves unused fuel from the fuel injectors to the fuel cooler. Excess fuel out
                of the FVCV and the FPCV mix with fuel from the fuel injectors on the way to the fuel cooler.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
