<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Rocker Arm Assembly, Camshaft
        Assembly, Tappets, and Push Rods - Clean, Inspect, Measure, and Test - Valve Lever and Rocker Arm Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s210010503.1" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Valve Lever and Rocker Arm Assembly</title>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010503.1.1">
            <title>Clean Valve Lever and Rocker Arm Assembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Immerse all components in suitable solvent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use filtered compressed air to dry components.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010503.1.2">
            <title>Inspect and Measure Rocker Shaft</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect rocker shaft for scoring, pitting, or wear steps. Replace rocker shaft if any of
                    these visual signs of wear are present.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To prevent possible engine damage, replace rocker shaft with like rocker shaft. If
                            replacing with new style rocker shaft all valve train components must be replaced.
                            Replacement of old style valve train components requires complete replacement of all valve
                            train components, including push rod assemblies, roller tappet assemblies, and rocker arm
                            assemblies.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is normal to see a slight polishing at lever contact area.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure rocker shaft in a non-contact area. Use an
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_X2100504.xml" xrefid="t210010504">Outside Micrometer</hotlnk>
                    . This dimension will be used as a baseline shaft diameter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010511" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8548.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Non-contact and arm contact area</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Non-contact area</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Arm contact area</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure each lever contact areas vertically.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010512" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8549.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Measure contact and non-contact areas vertically</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Subtract each twelve vertical measurements from baseline diameter. If difference is
                    greater than 0.025 mm (0.001 in), replace rocker shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify oil supply holes are open. Clean holes with small wire or other suitable tool if
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid possible engine failure, if replacing rocker shaft, all twelve valve levers must be
                        replaced. Reusing rocker arms on a new shaft will not allow for an adequate break-in period and
                        will cause premature failure of shaft and levers.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent possible engine damage, do not install new style valve train components in engines
                        produced with old style valve train components. Replacement of old style valve train components
                        requires complete replacement of all valve train components, including push rod assemblies,
                        roller tappet assemblies, and rocker arm assemblies.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>New valve levers may be installed on a used shaft.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Cup plugs at each end of shaft are replaceable. Do not disturb cup plugs unless damaged,
                        leaking hard part failure or contaminated oil. If replacement is required, pry damaged cup plug
                        out and press in new cup plug.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect cup plugs on each end of shaft for evidence of damage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cup plug(s) is damaged pry the damaged cup plug out.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area around the cup plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press in a new cup plug in the end of the shaft.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010503.1.3">
            <title>Inspect and Measure Valve Lever</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect rocker shaft for scoring, pitting, or signs of excessive wear. If valve lever
                    bore is visibly damaged, replace valve lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect lower half of valve lever. Most significant wear will occur at this location.
                    Valve levers may be reused in their original locations if phosphate coating is worn off and the
                    shaft is not replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Purpose of black phosphate coating on valve lever is to provide a break-in lubricant between
                        rocker shaft and valve lever bore. It is normal to see black phosphate coatings worn off of
                        bottom of lever arm in the shaft and bore contact area. Valve levers must be labeled and
                        installed in their original locations to maintain proper wear pattern.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure valve lever bore diameter at two locations with
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_X2100504.xml" xrefid="t210010504">Telescoping Gauge</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_X2100504.xml" xrefid="t210010504">Outside Micrometer</hotlnk>
                    . Measure diameter at A-B and C-D . If difference between diameters is greater than or equal to
                    0.025 mm (0.001 in), replace valve lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010513" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8547.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Measure valve lever bore</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect valve stem contact button on valve lever for scoring, pitting, or signs of
                    excessive wear. Replace valve lever if button is worn.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent possible engine damage, do not install new style valve train components in engines
                        produced with old style valve train components. Replacement of old style valve train components
                        requires complete replacement of all valve train components, including push rod assemblies,
                        roller tappet assemblies, and rocker arm assemblies.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f210010514" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8550.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Inspect valve stem contact button</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve lever</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Adjusting post</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Button</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect valve lash adjuster for signs of wear. Replace adjuster screw if excessive wear
                    is found.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect top oil feed hole in valve lever. Clean hole with small wire or other suitable
                    tool if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010515" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8562.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Inspect valve lever oil hole</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010503.1.4">
            <title>Inspect and Measure Shaft Springs</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect shaft springs for rust, pitting, and cracks. Replace as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010516" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8564.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Inspect valve lever components</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure shaft spring tension with
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_X2100504.xml" xrefid="t210010504">Valve and Clutch Spring Tester
                        (ZTSE2241)
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Measure free length (no load applied). Apply correct test load and measure test length.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace any shaft springs that do not meet "
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210010507.xml" xrefid="t210010501">Specifications</hotlnk>
                    ."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010517" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8561.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Measure shaft spring tension</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210010503.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_116.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
