<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Speed Control Command Switches (SCCS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="sccs" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Speed Control Command Switches (SCCS)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503086" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8880.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Cruise Control, PTO, Hand Throttle System Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cruise Control</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will control engine speed to maintain a constant road speed with cruise control. Depressing
                the set switch when the vehicle is at the desired speed with the Cruise button in the ON position
                activates the cruise control. Speed is increased or decreased by depressing Accel or Cruise buttons. The
                cruise control is deactivated by depressing the OFF switch, applying the brake pedal, clutch pedal, or
                on vehicles equipped with automatic transmissions, by placing the transmission in neutral.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Control</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Engine speed can be controlled by the SCCS switches if the PTO option has been programmed into the ECM
                and the vehicle is stationary. Variable as well as preset speeds are available depending on ECM
                programming. The PTO function is turned ON by switching the cruise button ON. Depressing the Set/Cruise
                or Resume/Accel button will increase or decrease engine speed depending on PTO programming.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The ECM does not monitor the SCCS system for faults. There are no Diagnostic Trouble Codes for this
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostics</title>
            <para>If the engine does not respond to the cruise control switches, use the cab electronics diagnostic
                software to monitor cruise switch input to the ESC. If the switch state does not change when the
                steering wheel cruise controls are depressed, diagnose the cruise switch circuits using the S08250 -
                Electrical Troubleshooting Guide - 4200/4300/4400. If the ESC is receiving the cruise switch input, use
                the electronic engine diagnostic software (Master Diagnostics) to view the cruise switch state. If the
                switch state does not change as the switch is depressed, verify communication exists between the ECM and
                the ESC (does the ECM respond to other ESC inputs). If the switch state does change, verify that other
                conditions do not exist that would stop or delay the reaction to the input. Examples include:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>RPM below minimum</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>RPM above maximum</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Road speed below minimum / Road speed above maximum</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake pedal depressed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch / driveline disengaged</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cruise Control</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Cruise control allows the ECM to control the engines power delivery to maintain a constant vehicle
                speed. The speed set point is determined by the driver, however high and low set points are programmed
                in the ECM. These are the cruise high set limit and cruise low set limit. Also the minimum engine speed
                at which the cruise control can be engaged is programmed in the ECM. See Cruise Control, Body Builder
                Connections Circuit Diagram .
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Operate cruise using the following switch functions:</emph>
            </para>
            <table id="te17503030.5">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.51*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.49*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Cruise ON/OFF button:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>ON enables and OFF disables the Cruise Control functions.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="1">
                                <para>SET/CRUISE:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>If the cruise is active but a speed is not set, depressing the SET switch will
                                    select the current vehicle speed as the set speed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>If the cruise is active an a speed is set, depressing the SET switch will cause
                                    the vehicle speed to decrease.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="1">
                                <para>RESUME/ACCEL:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>If the cruise is ON, but has been deactivated by application of the brake or
                                    clutch pedal, depressing the RESUME switch will cause the vehicle speed to resume to
                                    the last set speed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>If the cruise is ON and active, depressing the RESUME switch will cause the
                                    vehicle speed to increase.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Depressing the OFF switch, brake, clutch or placing the automatic transmission in neutral will
                deactivate the cruise control. Cruise control will not be functional if the VSS signal is in fault.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO (engine Speed) Control</emph>
            </para>
            <para>PTO speed control allows an operator to set a fixed engine speed, either in the cab or remotely.
                In-cab PTO uses the same switches on the steering wheel as are used for cruise control. Remote PTO uses
                switches that are installed by a body builder and are wired to the vehicle's wiring harness at the "body
                builder's connections." There are two features that utilize the PTO speed controls. Remote Accelerator
                Pedal and Electronic Pressure Governing. See RPS and EPG in this section of manual.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In-Cab PTO</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In-Cab PTO has three different modes of operation. These modes are selected by programming the ECM
                In-Cab PTO Mode. These modes are:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>In-Cab Preset</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>In-Cab Variable</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>In-Cab Mobile</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In-Cab Preset</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In-Cab Preset is selected by programming the ECM programmable parameters for In-Cab Mode to In-Cab
                Preset. This allows the operator to select one of two programmed values for engine speed. To operate,
                turn the ON/OFF switch to the ON position. Then depress either the Set or Resume switch. This will cause
                the engine speed to run at the value programmed into PTO Set Speed.
            </para>
            <para>Depressing the OFF switch, brake pedal, clutch pedal, placing the automatic transmission in gear, or a
                signal from the VSS (unless programmed for Mobile operation), will deactivate the PTO speed control. PTO
                speed control will not be functional if the VSS or Brake signal is in fault.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In-Cab Variable</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In-Cab Variable is selected by programming the ECM Programmable Parameters for In-Cab Mode to In-Cab
                Variable. This option allows the driver to set the engine speed to a desired value. The control module
                will then maintain this speed over varying load conditions up to the engines rated power in the selected
                speed range.
            </para>
            <para>To enable, turn the ON/OFF switch to the ON position. Speed may be adjusted two ways. First the
                operator may adjust the engine speed with the accelerator and then depress the Set switch. Second, the
                operator may depress the Resume/Accel to increase engine speed incrementally or depress the Set/Cruise
                switch to decrease the engine speed.
            </para>
            <para>Engine set speed will be limited to the value programmed in the ECM for Maximum PTO speed.</para>
            <para>Depressing the OFF switch, brake pedal, clutch pedal, placing the automatic transmission in gear, or a
                signal from the VSS, (unless programmed for Mobile operation), will deactivate the PTO speed control.
                PTO speed control will not be functional if the VSS or Brake signal is in fault.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In-Cab Mobile</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In-Cab Mobile is selected by programming the ECM programmable parameters for the In-Cab mode to In-Cab
                Mobile. This allows the operator to use the engine speed control the same as In-Cab Variable, however,
                in this mode the vehicle can be moving while the mode is active. See In-Cab Variable for more details.
                The maximum speed of the vehicle is programmable up to 20 m.p.h. This mode is the same as In-Cab
                Variable, however, a speed signal will not disable the speed control until the programmed maximum speed
                is exceeded.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Remote PTO</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Remote PTO can be enabled by two means, Remote Preset and Remote Variable. Operation of the speed
                control depends on which signal is enabled.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Remote Preset</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When in the preset mode, the set switch will cause the engine to run at the programmed set speed. The
                resume switch will allow the engine to run at the programmed resume speed.
            </para>
            <para>With the remote preset enabled, the speed is adjusted as with In-Cab preset. See In-Cab preset for
                more details.
            </para>
            <para>Turning the ON/OFF switch OFF, depressing the brake pedal, clutch pedal, placing the automatic
                transmission in gear, or a signal from the VSS will deactivate the PTO speed control. However, the
                programmed option of PTO Operation Disable will prevent the clutch and brake signals from interrupting
                the PTO speed control, as well as cause the APS to be inoperative. PTO speed control will not be
                functional if the VSS or Brake signal is in fault.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Remote Variable</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Enabling the remote variable signal allows for the engine speed to be adjusted to the desired level.
                Depressing the Resume /Accel switch will cause the engine speed to increase, depressing the Set/Cruise
                switch will cause the engine speed to decrease.
            </para>
            <para>With remote variable enabled the speed is adjusted as with In-Cab Variable.</para>
            <para>Opening the switch to pin 36, depressing the ON/OFF switch to OFF, depressing the brake or clutch
                pedal or placing the automatic transmission in gear, or a signal from the VSS will deactivate the PTO
                speed control. However the programmed option of PTO Operation Disable will prevent the clutch and brake
                signals from interrupting the PTO speed control, as well as cause the APS to be inoperative. PTO speed
                control will not be functional if the VSS or Brake signal is in fault.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Speed Ramp Rate</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The rate at which the speed of the engine will change will depend on load conditions and on a
                programmed value called PTO speed ramp rate. A higher value will cause the engine to change speed more
                quickly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Troubleshooting</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The EST can be used to monitor the status of the PTO controls. Comparing the data list reading to
                actual operation will indicate if the controls are operating properly. Using the menu option of
                programmable parameters the programming can be verified to be sure the ECM is programmed properly for
                the application. Also the data list can be used to monitor the parameters that cause interruption of PTO
                speed control.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_104.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_106.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
