<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Engine Service Manual - Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) -
        Description - Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s05.1.2" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Operation</title>
        <para>The VGT is a closed loop system that uses the Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor to provide feedback to
            the Electronic Control Module (ECM). The ECM uses the EBP sensor to continuously monitor the EBP and adjust
            the duty cycle to the VGT to match engine requirements.
        </para>
        <para>The VGT increases power output by supplying compressed air to the engine. The internal components are oil
            and air cooled. Engine oil is circulated through the housing, which acts as a heat barrier between the hot
            turbine and the cold compressor. Sleeve bearings are lubricated by engine oil. Oil is pumped directly from
            the oil filter base, circulates to the VGT housing, and returns to the sump through an oil drain in the VGT
            center housing.
        </para>
        <para>Expanding exhaust gases drive the turbine shaft assembly to speeds over 100,000 rpm. Filtered air entering
            the compressor side of the VGT is compressed and delivered through a charge air cooler (CAC). Hot compressed
            air is cooled, filling the intake manifold at a pressure higher than atmospheric pressure. Because
            considerably more air is forced into the intake manifold, the results are increased power, fuel efficiency
            and the ability to maintain power at higher altitudes.
        </para>
        <para>The VGT actuator, a variable position actuator, controls turbocharger turbine vane position. The VGT
            actuator is part of the turbocharger assembly, and is controlled by the controlled area network signals from
            the ECM in response to engine speed, required fuel quantity, boost, exhaust back pressure, and altitude. The
            VGT actuator controls the movement of the vanes linked by an adjusting ring in the turbine housing. Turbine
            exhaust gas flow and resulting VGT boost are modified by vane position.
        </para>
        <para>The key feature of the VGT is actuated vanes in the turbine housing. The vanes modify the flow
            characteristics of the exhaust gases through the turbine housing. This controls boost pressure needed for
            various engine speeds and load conditions. An additional benefit is lower exhaust emissions.
        </para>
        <para>Actuated vanes are mounted around the inside circumference of the turbine housing. An adjusting ring links
            all the vanes. When the adjusting ring moves, all vanes move to the same position. Adjusting ring movement
            occurs when the VGT actuator receives a controlled area network signal for a required position.
        </para>
        <para>Exhaust gas flow can be regulated depending on the required exhaust back pressure for engine speed and
            load. As power demands increase, exhaust gas velocity increases in direct relation, as does intake manifold
            boost pressure. Conversely, as the flow of exhaust gas diminishes, intake manifold boost pressure is also
            reduced at the same rate.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_108.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_110.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
