<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT and BEARINGS, CAMSHAFT and BUSHINGS -
        Cleaning, Inspection, and Testing - Camshaft
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s26508.2.4" svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Camshaft</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect camshaft. If any lobes are scuffed, scored or cracked, replace camshaft.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This engine uses hydraulic valve tappets with roller followers; therefore, a roller follower
                        guide is needed to maintain correct orientation of roller to cam lobe. Normal clearance between
                        the valve tappet roller and guide allows for slight tracking of roller across cam lobe.
                    </para>
                    <para>Tracking of the roller is normal when the roller accelerates and decelerates during engine
                        operation. Consequently, a typical wear pattern on cam lobes will exhibit tracks from side to
                        side, have wide and narrow areas from the loading, and unloading of the follower. The wear
                        pattern (tracking) is normal and the camshaft does not require replacement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After inspection, evaluate camshaft main journal and lobe condition as follows:</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When measuring the camshaft with a micrometer, always take two measurements 90&#176; apart.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f2650828" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd03/d0308.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Measurement for camshaft bearing journal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a 2-3 inch micrometer to measure journal diameter of camshaft bearing.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If bearing journals are worn beyond limits, install new camshaft.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <figure id="f2650829" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figd03/d0312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Measurement for camshaft intake and exhaust lobes</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft assembly</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Micrometer</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">To check camshaft intake and exhaust lobes, measure across (A to C) and across (B to D).
                    Subtract (B to D) from (A to C). This will give cam lobe lift. Replace camshaft if cam lobe wear
                    exceeds specifications .
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect thrust plate for wear, cracks or distortion. Use a micrometer to measure thrust
                plate thickness . Replace thrust plate if worn or damaged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect camshaft drive gear for worn or damaged teeth.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wash camshaft in cleaning solvent with a soft brush.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes. Limit
                    compressed air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dry with filtered compressed air.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_161.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_163.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
