<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Systems -
        Cooling System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Cooling System</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Cooling System Components and Coolant Flow</title>
            <figure id="f2700134" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH05/H05001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Engine cooling system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder head assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water outlet tube assembly (thermostat outlet)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Thermostat assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air compressor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water return from cylinder head to crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder sleeve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler return tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water outlet from crankcase to front cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water inlet to crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler supply tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil module assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water inlet to front cover and water pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water supply from front cover to crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water pump impeller assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water inlet elbow</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Cooling System Flow</title>
            </para>
            <para>The cooling system keeps the engine within a designated temperature range. The major components of the
                cooling system include the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Radiator and fan combination (chassis components)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Water pump assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Thermostat assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil system module assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR cooler assembly</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A belt-driven centrifugal water pump is set into the front cover. The front cover has three related
                passages. One passage channels coolant from the water pump to the crankcase, the second returns coolant
                to the water pump, and the third (a bypass) channels coolant back to the water pump when the thermostat
                is closed.
            </para>
            <para>Incoming coolant flows from the bottom of the radiator through a water inlet elbow to the front cover
                and water pump. Coolant is pumped to the crankcase through a passage in the front cover and crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>Water jackets in the crankcase direct coolant from front to rear, distributing coolant evenly to the
                lower sections of the cylinder sleeves. Coolant flow is directed tangent to each cylinder sleeve,
                causing a swirling motion up to the cylinder head. The swirling action improves heat absorption.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows from the cylinder sleeve areas in three ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant flows into the oil system module assembly through the right side of the crankcase,
                        passes through the oil system module, and returns through a tube to the front cover.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant is routed through hoses to and from the air compressor on the left side of the
                        crankcase.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant exits the crankcase at the upper end of each cylinder sleeve bore and is distributed
                        evenly through metering holes in the cylinder head gasket. Coolant then flows through the
                        cylinder head (back to front) to the thermostat.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The EGR cooler receives coolant from the front cover. Coolant flows from the front of the cooler and
                exits the rear of the cooler into the rear of the cylinder head. A deaeration port is on top of the EGR
                cooler.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Thermostat Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The thermostat has two outlets. One directs coolant to the radiator when the engine is at operating
                temperature. The other directs coolant to the water pump until the engine reaches operating temperature.
                The thermostat begins to open at 88 &#176;C (190 &#176;F) and is fully open at 96 &#176;C (205 &#176;F).
            </para>
            <figure id="f2700135" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH05/H05008.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Thermostat closed</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant flow to heater port</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant in from engine</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Bypass to water pump</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When engine coolant is below the 88 &#176;C (190 &#176;F) the thermostat is closed, blocking flow to
                the radiator. Coolant is forced to flow through a bypass port back to the water pump.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2700136" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH05/H05009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Thermostat open</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant out to radiator</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant flow to heater port</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant in from engine</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When coolant temperature reaches the nominal opening temperature (88 &#176;C [190 &#176;F]) the
                thermostat opens allowing some coolant to flow to the radiator. When coolant temperature exceeds 96
                &#176;C (205 &#176;F), the lower seat blocks the bypass port directing full coolant flow to the
                radiator.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
