<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Brake Switch Circuits (Brake)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Brake Switch Circuits (Brake)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503024" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1218A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Service Brake Circuit Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The service brake circuit function is to signal the ECM when the brakes are applied. This information
                is used to disengage the Cruise control and PTO functions. This signal is also used for ECM control of
                the Vehicle Retarder and exhaust brake enabling. The brake signal will also interrupt the Cold Ambient
                Protection feature and will reset the time interval for the Idle Shut Down feature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Service Brake Switch Input</emph>
                - The service brake switch is monitored by the Electrical System Controller (ESC). When the switch
                changes state, the change is detected by the ESC and relayed over the Drive Train Data Link to the ECM.
                Stuck, open, or shorted brake switches will be detected by the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostics</emph>
                - If a function that requires a brake switch input does not respond correctly, use Cab Electronics
                Diagnostic software to monitor brake switch input to the ESC. If the switch does not change when the
                pedal is depressed, diagnose the brake switch circuits using the S08250 - Electrical Troubleshooting
                Guide - 4200/4300/4400. If the ESC is receiving the brake switch input, use the electronic engine
                diagnostics software (Master Diagnostics) to view the brake switch state. If the switch state does not
                change, verify communications exist between the ECM and the ESC (does ECM respond to other ESC inputs).
                If the switch state does change, verify other conditions do not exist that would stop or delay the
                reaction to the brake switch status.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08250 - Electrical Troubleshooting Guide - 4200/4300/4400.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_80.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_S1750208.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
