<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Remote Accelerator Pedal Sensor (RPS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="rps" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Remote Accelerator Pedal Sensor (RPS)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503078" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1247.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>RPS Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The RPS, the ON/OFF switch, and the circuit are supplied by the body builder.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The purpose of the remote accelerator pedal sensor (RPS) is to allow an operator to adjust engine
                speed from a remote location. The RPS functions similar to the accelerator position sensor. The RPS
                sensor is a potentiometer that sends a variable analog voltage signal to the ECM that indicates a
                desired speed. In order for the RPS to function, the control module must be programmed for remote RPS
                enable. To activate the RPS the remote variable terminal of the ECM must receive a 12V signal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pedal Operation</title>
            <para>The pedal receives a 5V reference signal and a signal return from the ECM through the body builder
                connections. By depressing the pedal the RPS signal voltage increases indicating a request to increase
                engine speed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The ECM monitors the voltage at the RPS terminal for voltage to determine if the signal is in range. A
                minimum voltage level is established to verify that the circuit is not open and a maximum voltage level
                is established to verify that the signal is not shorted to a voltage source. When the ECM detects a
                voltage Out of Range, the pedal will be disabled and Diagnostic Trouble Code 213 for Out of Range LOW or
                code 214 for Out of Range HIGH will be set.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503079" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8826.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Remote Accelerator Pedal Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector always check for damaged pins, corrosion, and loose terminals.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503029" frame="all">
                <title>Remote Accelerator Pedal Sensor Circuit Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="52.25*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="51.15*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="292.60*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remote Pedal Sensor Connector Voltage Checks</emph>(check with
                                    remote pedal sensor disconnected and ignition key ON)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A positive voltage reading indicates a short to another circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A positive voltage reading indicates a short to another circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage out of specification indicates; an open circuit, short to ground, or short
                                    to B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(2) to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ON/OFF switch voltage when switch is in the ON position.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remote Pedal Sensor Connector Resistance Checks</emph>
                                    (check with remote pedal sensor disconnected, ignition key OFF and all accessories
                                    off)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 1k&#x2126; indicates a short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 5&#x2126; indicates circuit is open.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 1k&#x2126; indicates a short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(1) to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 1k&#x2126; indicates a short to ground with switch closed and fuse
                                    removed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Checks</emph>(check with breakout box installed
                                    on chassis harness only &#38; sensor connector disconnected)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5 to C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 5&#x2126; indicates a high resistance or an open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6 to B</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 5&#x2126; indicates a high resistance or an open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 5&#x2126; indicates a high resistance or an open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>36 to (1)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 5&#x2126; indicates a high resistance or an open circuit with switch closed and
                                    fuse removed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Continued on Next Page</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operational Voltage Checks</emph>(check with breakout box
                                    installed &#38; RPS sensor connected to connector)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to 6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.5 to 4V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage should be low at idle position and should increase by depressing the
                                    pedal. Voltage reading should change smoothly and there should be no position that
                                    causes a sudden increase or decrease in voltage.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>36 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V or 0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ON/OFF switch voltage: 12V when ON, 0V when OFF.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>213 = RPS Signal was &#60;0.49V. Circuit open or shorted to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>214 = RPS Signal was >3.91V. Sensor shorted internally or short to V
                                    <subscript>BAT</subscript>
                                    or V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The RPS is used for engine speed control outside of the vehicle cab. As part of the PTO engine speed
                control, connections for the RPS are supplied through the body builder's connections.
            </para>
            <para>To operate the RPS, a 5V reference voltage is supplied by the ECM from pin 5 through the body
                builder's connections circuit K97DD. Signal return for the RPS is supplied by a dedicated terminal
                number 6 through the body builder's connections circuit K97HM. The remote pedal sensor is a
                potentiometer that uses the 5V reference voltage and signal return to supply an analog voltage to
                terminal 30 through the body builder's connections circuit K99F. In the idle position, the voltage
                signal from the RPS is low. As the pedal is depressed, the voltage increases, indicating an increase in
                demand for speed from the operator.
            </para>
            <para>Before the RPS is operational the ECM must first have a 12V signal at pin 36. This is supplied through
                the body builder's connections circuit K97CC to enable the operation of the RPS.
            </para>
            <para>PTO speed control operation interruption will occur:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the remote variable circuit is opened. The engine will return to idle.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the brake or clutch pedal is depressed or with an automatic transmission, the transmission
                        is placed in gear. The engine will return to idle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the ECM receives a signal from the vehicle speed sensor (VSS) the engine will return to
                        idle. Remote PTO speed control will not function if the brake or VSS circuits are in fault and
                        the RPS will not operate if the RPS system has an active Diagnostic Trouble Code present.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the option has been programmed in the ECM for PTO Operation. The brake, clutch or
                        transmission will not interrupt the PTO speed control.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Programming</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM must be programmed to enable the RPS. From the programmable parameters menu under the option
                PTO controls, select RPS and program for "enable." If it is desired that the cab controls (APS brake and
                clutch) do not impede the operation of the PTO speed control, select the option PTO Operation. Disable,
                and select "enable." PTO mode must be programmed to remote. If the RPS is enabled and there is no pedal
                signal present, the ECM will log a Diagnostic Trouble Code. The PTO maximum engine speed will allow
                programming for the maximum engine speed allowed when in PTO mode.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM Diagnostics</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the voltage at the RPS terminal to determine if the signal is within range. A minimum
                voltage level is established to verify that the circuit is not open and a maximum voltage level is
                established to verify that the signal is not shorted to a voltage source. When the ECM sees the voltage
                Out of Range the pedal will be disabled and a Diagnostic Trouble Code 213 for Out of Range LOW or 214
                for Out of Range HIGH will be set. If the ignition is shut off a Diagnostic Trouble Code will be
                recorded as an inactive code.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc213">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 213</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 29, FMI 4</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Remote Throttle Signal Out of Range LOW</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 213 indicates that ECM pin 30 voltage was less than 0.25V. This indicates an
                open or shorted circuit for the V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                supply from ECM pin 5 or an open or shorted RPS signal circuit to pin 30 from the RPS. It may also
                result from a defective (open or shorted) remote pedal sensor.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc214">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 214</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 29, FMI 3</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Remote Throttle Signal Out of Range HIGH</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 214 indicates that ECM pin 30 voltage was greater than 4.5V. This indicates a
                possible open circuit in RPS return to pin 6 or a short circuit to another voltage supply on the RPS
                signal circuit. It may also result from a defective (shorted) remote pedal sensor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Troubleshooting</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The EST can be used to monitor the status of the PTO controls. Comparing the switch reading to actual
                operation will indicate if the controls are operating properly. Using the menu option of programmable
                parameters, the programming can verify that the ECM is programmed properly for that specific
                application. Also the data list can be used to monitor the parameters that cause the interruption of PTO
                speed control. Use the diagnostic code menu to read the Diagnostic Trouble Codes.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503080.5" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8806.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Electronic Engine Controls, Cruise Control Connections with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_102.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_104.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
