<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Systems - Fuel Supply System -
        Fuel Flow Schematic
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Fuel Flow Schematic</title>
        <figure id="f2700126" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
            <caption>Fuel flow</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The fuel filter housing includes the following components:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>150 micron fuel strainer</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>300W fuel heating element (optional)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Primer pump assembly</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fuel filtering element</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Water separator</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Water In Fuel (WIF) sensor</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Water drain valve</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fuel pressure regulator</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor (optional)</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fuel Flow</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The low-pressure fuel supply pump draws fuel from the fuel tank through a 150 micron strainer in the fuel
            filter assembly.
        </para>
        <para>An optional electric heating element in the fuel filter housing warms incoming fuel to prevent waxing.
        </para>
        <para>If water is in the fuel, the filter element repels water molecules, water collects at the bottom of the
            element cavity in the fuel filter housing, and a Water In Fuel (WIF) sensor in the element cavity detects
            water in the fuel. When enough water accumulates in the element cavity, the WIF sensor sends a signal to the
            Electronic Control Module (ECM); the ECM illuminates the amber WATER IN FUEL lamp on the instrument panel. A
            fuel drain valve handle on the housing can be opened to drain contaminants (usually water) from the fuel
            filter housing. Another drain valve in the bottom of the housing drains strainer cavity.
        </para>
        <para>A built-in fuel regulator valve, calibrated to open at about 414 - 482 kPa (60 - 70 psi), regulates and
            relieves excessive pressure. During idle and light engine loads, when injector demand is low, most of the
            fuel is cycled between the fuel filter housing and low-pressure fuel pump. When engine demand increases,
            engine fuel consumption increases resulting in less fuel cycling. Under heavy loads fuel flows through the
            filter with little or no cycling.
        </para>
        <para>Fuel is conditioned as it flows through a main filter and central post. The post prevents fuel from
            draining from the fuel rail during servicing.
        </para>
        <para>An optional Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor detects low pressure caused by high fuel filter restriction
            and sends a signal to the ECM; the ECM illuminates the amber FUEL FILTER lamp on the instrument panel.
        </para>
        <para>Fuel flows from the filter header assembly under low pressure - less than 482 kPa (70 psi) - into the
            low-pressure fuel rail for distribution to the fuel injectors. Fuel flows from the fuel filter housing into
            the fuel rail, through the fuel rail into six drilled holes (one for each injector) to each injector.
        </para>
        <para>When the fuel injectors are activated, fuel flows (from fuel rail) into four inlets in each injector.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
