<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYMPTOMS DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - Low Oil Pressure
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Low Oil Pressure</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Instrument panel gauge error</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low oil level: oil leak, oil consumption or incorrect servicing</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High oil level: incorrect servicing, fuel in oil or coolant in oil</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Incorrect oil viscosity</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel in oil</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Stuck oil pressure regulator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Scored/damaged oil pump</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) sensor biased</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Missing oil gallery plugs (front or rear)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Broken, missing or loose piston cooling tube(s)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Missing, damaged or worn bearing inserts or camshaft bushings</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Lifter missing (will also have performance problems)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Aeration (cracked pickup tube, missing O-ring)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Oil Pressure Diagnostics</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify oil level in engine by using oil level gauge while vehicle is parked on level
                    ground. Check to see if oil is contaminated with fuel or coolant.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Engine oil level will vary depending on temperature of engine</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If oil is contaminated, go to Fuel in Lube Oil or Coolant in Lube Oil test procedures
                            located in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400421" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400409.5" filename="../figd31/d31151.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         box="no"/>
                <caption>Lube Oil Pressure Test Port</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure test port</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle -
                        comply with the following;
                    </para>
                    <para>When routing test line , do not crimp the line, run the line too close to moving parts, or let
                        the line touch hot engine surfaces.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle -
                        comply with the following;
                    </para>
                    <para>When running the engine in the service bay, make sure the parking brake is set, the
                        transmission is in neutral, and the wheels are blocked.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify oil pressure using a known good mechanical gauge installed at the lube oil
                    pressure test port at the front of the engine. Measure pressure at both low and high idle no load.
                    Engine must be at operating temperature.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If oil pressure reads within specification listed in Appendix A in this Manual, compare
                            mechanical gauge readings with instrument panel gauge and Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) value on
                            the Electronic Service Tool (EST).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If mechanical gauge and EST read values with a difference greater than +/- 14 kPa (+/-2
                            psi) perform Electronic Control Systems Diagnostics for the EOP circuit as described in
                            Section 7 in this Manual.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If instrument panel engine oil pressure gauge reads a different value than the EST and
                            mechanical gauge refer to the Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide for the model and year
                            of vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If oil pressure does not read within the specification listed in Appendix A in this
                            Manual, continue to step 3.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and inspect the lube oil pump as described in the Engine Service Manual.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect the lube oil pump housing and cover for gouging or deep scratches.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect the gerotor gears for excessive wear or damage.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If no excessive damage is found continue to step 4.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400422" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400410.5" filename="../figd13/d1367.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         box="yes"/>
                <caption>Oil Pressure Regulator Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">End cap and O-ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure regulator spring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and inspect oil pressure regulator as described in the Engine Service Manual.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The oil pressure regulator piston should move freely in its bore in the front cover.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If oil pressure regulator is functional and passes visual inspection, reinstall regulator,
                            gerotor gears, pump cover, and damper following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual.
                            Retest following the Low Oil Pressure Diagnostics procedures in step 2. If oil pressure
                            remains low, do step 5.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain oil from engine using a clean catch basin. Inspect oil drain plug magnet, drained
                    oil and oil filter for foreign debris.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>An oil sample should be taken to determine level of engine wear metals and contaminants in
                            the oil.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400423" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400414" filename="../figd06/d0617.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Piston Cooling Tube</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Mounting bolt</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston cooling tube</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both the upper and lower oil pans as described in the Engine Service Manual.
                    Inspect for missing, loose or damaged oil pickup tube, O-ring, piston cooling tubes, bearing
                    inserts, and cam bushings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall oil filter cap without oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel/oil pressure test coupler to a regulated shop air line.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400424" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400477" filename="../figd31/d31151.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Lube Oil Pressure Test Port</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure test port</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect to lube oil pressure test port and apply 345 kPa (50 psi).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for gross leaks.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a major leak is observed from the front cover area, go to step 11.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a major leak is observed from the rear cover area, go to step 13.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a major leak is not observed, remove engine from vehicle. Disassemble engine and
                            perform full inspection of all components following procedures in the Engine Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the front cover from the engine following procedures in the Engine Service Manual
                    and complete inspection of the lube oil pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400425" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400413.5" filename="../figd06/d0645.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Main Oil Gallery Cup Plug Locations</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With front cover removed from the engine, verify that the main oil gallery cup plugs are
                    in position and not damaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, the
                        engine must be supported before removing rear cover or engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine from vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2400426" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f2400415.5" filename="../figd06/d0646.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Rear Main Oil Gallery Cup Plug Locations</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rear cover from the engine as described in the Engine Service Manual. Verify
                    the rear main oil gallery cup plugs are in position and not damaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_66.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_68.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
