<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Power Cylinders - Clean, Inspect,
        and Measure - Bearing Fitting Procedures
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="measure" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Bearing Fitting Procedures</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not attempt to reduce journal-to-bearing running clearance by
                        reworking the connecting rod bearing cap or the bearings. Grind the crankshaft to the next
                        available under size or replace the crankshaft.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f3350015465" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/eg9127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Effects of bearing crush</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Diameter at open ends after bearing crush load</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Diameter at open ends before bearing crush load</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Connecting rod bearings must fit tightly in the connecting rod bore. When bearings are
                        inserted in the connecting rod and cap, they protrude slightly above the parting surface. This
                        protrusion is required to achieve bearing crush. Bearing crush forces the ends inward at the
                        parting line when a load is applied by tightening the bolts. Some snap may be lost in normal
                        use, but bearing replacement is not required because of a nominal loss of snap.
                    </para>
                    <para>When the connecting rod bearing is installed and the connecting rod cap bolts are tightened,
                        the bearing is compressed, ensuring a positive contact between the backside of the bearing and
                        the machined surface of the connecting rod bore.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measure Bearing Running Clearance</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new bearings in the connecting rod and cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, correct mating of connecting rod and cap are required to prevent
                        damage to connecting rod fractured surface.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not torque-to-yield connecting rod cap bolts while doing this
                        measurement procedure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, when torquing connecting rod bolts use a torque wrench that is known
                        to be accurate. Correct torque of connecting rod cap bolts is important.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Match serial numbers on the connecting rod and rod cap (on same side of fractured rod)
                    and install the connecting rod and cap on the crankshaft. See
                    <hotlnk document="eges3351_387.xml" xrefid="s1523">Piston and Connecting Rod Assembly</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="s1523"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the connecting rod cap. Wipe the oil from the face of the bearings in the cap and
                    the exposed portion of the crankshaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a piece of undamaged Plastigage&#174; across the full width of the connecting rod
                    bearing, about 6 mm (0.25 in) from the center of the connecting rod cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the connecting rod cap and tighten the bolts to 109 N&#183;m (80 lbf&#183;ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not turn the crankshaft. This will smear the Plastigage&#174; making it unusable.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f3350015466" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8578.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Plastigage&#174; Measurement</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the connecting rod cap. The Plastigage&#174; material will adhere to either the
                    connecting rod bearing or the crankshaft. Do not remove the Plastigage&#174;.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the Plastigage&#174; paper scale to measure the widest point of the flattened
                    material. The numbers in the graduated marks on the wrapper scale indicate the running clearance in
                    thousandths of an inch or millimeters.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare Plastigage&#174; measurements with connecting rod bearing running clearance
                    <hotlnk document="eges3351_T335001501.xml" xrefid="t335001501">Specifications</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t335001501"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If running clearance is not within specifications grinding the crankshaft and using undersized
                        bearings may be necessary. Remeasure running clearance before condemning the crankshaft.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the Plastigage&#174; material. Repeat the test for each connecting rod bearing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measure Connecting Rod Side Clearance</title>
            <figure id="f3350015467" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH04/H04013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Connecting rod side clearance measurement</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a
                    <hotlnk document="eges3351_394.xml" xrefid="t335001503">feeler gauge</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t335001503"/>
                    between the connecting rod and crankshaft journal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the connecting rod side clearance is not in
                    <hotlnk document="eges3351_T335001501.xml" xrefid="t335001501">Specification</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t335001501"/>, replace the connecting rod.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If there is too little side clearance, the connecting rod may be damaged or the bearing may be
                        out of position. If there is too much clearance, the connecting rod or crankshaft may be
                        damaged.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_378.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_380.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
