<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Front Cover and Related Components -
        Checking Gear Train Timing Without Removing Front Cover - DT 466 Engines Only
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DT 466 Engines Only</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Method One - Using a Feeler Gauge</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the engine to approximately TDC (Top Dead Center) compression on No. 1 cylinder
                    (no valves open). Set the lash on the No. 1 intake valve to the nominal lash setting of 0.48 mm
                    (0.019 in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="fig8-3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figfig/fig8-3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Checking Engine Gear Train Timing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Straight line dimension</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Radial distance dimension</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Scribe mark</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Damper timing notch</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Scribe a mark on the damper pulley at a radial distance of 82.5 mm (3.25 in) or a
                    straight line distance of 81 mm (3.188 in) clockwise from the timing notch as viewed from the front
                    of the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a 0.28 mm (0.011 in) feeler gauge between the rocker arm and the valve bridge of
                    the No. 1 intake valve. Slowly rotate the engine forward (clockwise) until the intake valve starts
                    to lift and the feeler gauge becomes tight. The mark should line up with the TDC arrow on the front
                    cover or be within 3.5 crankshaft degrees of it. 3.5 degrees is equivalent to a radial (or straight)
                    line distance of 6.8 mm (0.27 in) at the damper pulley.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>One tooth "out of time" on the gear train equals approximately 11 degrees of movement or 21.4
                        mm (27/32 in) of radial distance of damper pulley.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the timing on the No.1 valve is within specifications, the other valves, barring
                    extreme camshaft lobe wear or poor adjustment, will also be in time. If timing is found to be
                    incorrect, removal of the front cover is required to inspect the punch marks on the gear train.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Method Two - Using a Dial Indicator</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the No.1 intake valve with the No.1 piston set at TDC (Top Dead Center)
                    compression stroke to 0.48 mm (0.019 in). Install a 0.28 mm (0.011 in) feeler gauge between the
                    rocker arm and the valve bridge of the No.1 intake valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the magnetic base dial indicator on the valve cover fence of the cylinder head
                    rail with the indicator tip on the No.1 intake rocker arm tip.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Zero the dial indicator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the engine approximately one full revolution in either direction to a position
                    360 degrees from starting point.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The dial indicator should read within the range of 0.13-0.25 mm (0.005-0.010 in) from
                    the starting position for proper gear train timing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If dial indicator readings are found to be outside of this range, removal of the front
                    cover is required to inspect the punch marks on the gear train.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_111.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_113.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
