<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Change Oil Display
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Change Oil Display</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503032.1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/EG9054.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for Change Oil Message</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Change Oil message will be displayed when a customer programmable service interval has been
                exceeded. These limits may be set for vehicle miles, hours, or calculated fuel consumption. These
                service interval limits may be adjusted or the Change Oil message feature may be turned on or off using
                the EST tool.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>There is no fault detection for the Change Oil message feature.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reset Change Oil Message</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After changing the engine oil, if the vehicle utilizes the Change Oil Message feature, reset
                        the system as follows:
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake (required for correct ESC signal).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key switch to the IGN/ON position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress and release both the Cruise On and Resume/Accel buttons simultaneously
                    <emph type="bold">four times (4)</emph>
                    times. This step 3 sequence must be performed within a
                    <emph type="bold">six (6)</emph>
                    second interval.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress and hold both the
                    <emph type="bold">CRUISE ON</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">RESUME/ACCEL</emph>
                    buttons simultaneously for
                    <emph type="bold">three (3)</emph>
                    seconds
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release both Cruise buttons.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The entire sequence MUST BE completed within twelve (12) seconds. The Change Oil Message will
                        now turn off and will reactivate when the next oil change is due.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Service Interval Limits</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This group of parameters customizes the Service Interval feature. Service Interval allows the vehicle
                owner to customize when his vehicle requires servicing as in changing oil. When the programmed distance
                or engine hour has been reached, the Change Oil Message will be displayed to indicate its time for
                maintenance and service.
            </para>
            <para>The limits listed below are the maximum and default values for the service internal function. Through
                the use of the EST tool these limits can be adjusted downward for specific customer needs, but not above
                the recommended factory service interval.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Service Interval Mode</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if this vehicle has the service interval
                        feature.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Fuel Interval</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter allows the customer to program the amount of fuel used since the last service
                        before displaying the Change Oil Message.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Hour Interval</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter allows the customer to program the amount of Engine Hours since the last
                        service before displaying the Change Oil Message.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Distance Interval</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter allows the customer to program the amount of Distance miles/kilometers since
                        the last service before displaying the Change Oil Message.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Fuel Used Starting Value</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates when the last service was performed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Engine Hour Starting Value</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates when the last service was performed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Vehicle Distance Starting Value</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates when the last service was performed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Service Soon Percent</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates at what percentage of the service intervals should the Change Oil
                        Message begin to flash as a warning.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Change Oil Message On Mode</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates if the Change Oil Message is to be always ON after an engine start.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Change Oil Message ON Mode</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates how long to activate the Change Oil Message after an engine start if
                        it is not always ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Service Interval Reset Request</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if the vehicle has been serviced and the
                        starting values are to be reset.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_S1750208.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_84.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
