<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT, CONNECTING
        RODS AND PISTONS - Connecting Rods, Pistons and Piston Rings - Bearing Fitting Procedure
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Bearing Fitting Procedure</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, do not attempt to reduce journal-to-bearing running clearances by
                    reworking the bearing cap and/or the bearings. Regrind or replace the crankshaft only.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1200733" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg9/eg9127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Effects of Bearing Crush</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Diameter at Open Ends Before Bearing Crush Load</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Diameter at Open Ends After Bearing Crush Load</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Bearing shells must fit tightly in the bore. When bearing shells are inserted into the connecting rod and
            cap, they protrude slightly above the parting surface. This protrusion is required to achieve a
            <emph type="bold">bearing crush</emph>.
        </para>
        <para>Across the open ends, bearing shells are slightly larger than the diameter of the connecting rod bore into
            which they are assembled. This condition is designed into the bearing shell, causing it to spread outward at
            the parting line when a bearing crush load is applied by tightening the nuts. Some snap may be lost in
            normal use, but bearing replacement is not required because of a nominal loss of snap.
        </para>
        <para>When the assembly is drawn up tight, the bearing is compressed, ensuring a positive contact between the
            backside of the bearing and the machined surface of the connecting rod bore.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install new bearing shells in the connecting rod and in the bearing cap. Lubricate each
                shell with clean engine oil.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the connecting rod on the crankshaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing cap on the connecting rod. Tighten the nuts on the bearing cap
                alternately and evenly to the special torque value.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1200734" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1926.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Measuring Bearing Running Clearance With Plastigage</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Connecting Rod</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Plastigage Wrapper/Scale</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft Connecting Rod Bearing Journal</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Flattened Plastigage</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the bearing running clearance as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the bearing cap. Wipe the oil from the face of the bearing shell in the bearing
                    cap and the exposed portion of the crankshaft.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place a piece of undamaged Plastigage&#174; across the full width of the bearing shell
                    about 6 mm (0.25 in) from the center of the bearing cap.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the bearing cap and tighten the nuts alternately and evenly to the special
                    torque value.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not turn the crankshaft. This will smear the Plastigage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the bearing cap. The Plastigage material will adhere to either the bearing shell
                    or the crankshaft . Do not remove the Plastigage.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use the Plastigage scale to measure the widest point of the flattened material. The
                    numbers within the graduated marks on the wrapper/scale indicate the running clearance in
                    thousandths of an inch or millimeters. See the specifications for the correct running clearance.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the Plastigage material. Repeat the test for each connecting rod bearing.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>With the use of precision bearings, few problems should be encountered. However, if proper running
                    clearance is not achieved, a problem with the crankshaft may still exist. Regrinding the crankshaft
                    and using undersize bearings are probably necessary.
                </para>
                <para>Also, the bearing cap bolt torque is very important. Use a torque wrench that is known to be
                    accurate. Repeat the running clearance check procedure before condemning the crankshaft.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1200735" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1927.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Checking the Connecting Rod Side Clearance with a Feeler Gauge</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Feeler Gauge</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Connecting Rod Bearing Cap</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the connecting rod side clearance using one of the following tests:</para>
            <para>
                <title>Feeler Gauge Test</title>Pry two adjacent connecting rods apart and use a feeler gauge to measure
                the clearance between them. Refer to the specifications and repeat for all connecting rods.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Dial Indicator Test</title>
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place the tip of the dial indicator on the connecting rod bearing cap.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Pry the two connecting rods apart with a screwdriver or prying tool. Then zero the dial
                    indicator.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Pry the connecting rod in toward the dial indicator while recording the connecting rod
                    side clearance. Refer to the specifications and repeat for all connecting rods.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Lack of side clearance could indicate a damaged rod or a bearing that is out of position. Too much
                    clearance may require replacement of the rods or crankshaft.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_181.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_183.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
