<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL&#174; VT 365 DIESEL ENGINE - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Engine Systems - Air Management System (AMS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Air Management System (AMS)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f235in11" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd31/D3108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Air management system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intake manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Left cylinder head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Left exhaust manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Shielded tube exhaust assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger assembly with mounting bracket</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air inlet duct</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Right cylinder head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Right exhaust manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust tube assembly, right</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>
                    <emph type="bold">The Air Management system includes the following:</emph>
                </title>
                <item>
                    <para>Air filter assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Closed crankcase breather</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chassis mounted Charged Air Cooler (CAC)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake manifold</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) system</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust system</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Catalytic converter- dependent on application</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Catalyzed Diesel Particulate Filter (CDPF) - dependent on application</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f2400112" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D31169.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Air flow diagram</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Induction System</title>
            <para>Ambient air is drawn into the air cleaner assembly and passes through a paper element filter. A filter
                minder monitors air filter restriction and is calibrated to warn when it needs servicing. As filtered
                air approaches the turbocharger, it passes over the pitot tube creating a vacuum and draws engine
                blow-by gases through a breather element located under the left side valve cover. Air entering the
                turbocharger inlet is then pressurized and directed to the charge air cooler.
            </para>
            <para>Air from the turbocharger is pushed through a network of heat exchanging tubes prior to entering the
                intake manifold. Outside air flowing over the tubes and fins serves to cool the charge air. The
                resulting cooler intake air is denser than heated air, allowing for an improved fuel/air ratio during
                combustion. This results in improved emission control and power output.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</title>
            <figure id="f235in11.3" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd15/D1531.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. VGT</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Actuator</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Control valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Unison ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Vanes</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The key feature of the Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) is the introduction of adjustable vanes
                within the turbine housing to modify the flow characteristics of exhaust gases onto the turbine wheel.
                The net benefit is to provide optimized boost pressure to accommodate all engine speed and load
                conditions. An additional benefit is lower emissions. The VGT relies on electronic feedback loops
                provided by the Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor via the Electronic Control Module (ECM).
            </para>
            <para>The turbocharger assembly contains a series of actuated vanes, a unison ring, and piston. The vanes
                regulate the flow of exhaust gases across the turbine. The only serviceable item on the turbocharger
                assembly is the control valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust</title>
            <para>The exhaust system includes the following components:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust valves</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust manifold</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turbine side of the turbocharger</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust piping</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Exhaust gas from combustion passes around two exhaust valves, through the exhaust manifold and is
                directed through pipes to the turbocharger exhaust inlet. As hot expanding exhaust gases flow into the
                turbocharger, they pass over the turbine wheel, causing it to spin in direct relation with the amount of
                exhaust gases being produced. The right side cylinders also provide a portion of their exhaust gases to
                supply the exhaust gas recirculation system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) Valve</title>
            <para>The EGR system includes:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cooler assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR valve actuator / Pintle position sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) reduces peak combustion temperatures and oxides of nitrogen (NO
                <subscript>X</subscript>).
            </para>
            <para>NO
                <subscript>X</subscript>
                formation in diesel engines is the result of combustion in the presence of oxygen. In the diesel engine,
                combustion starts when fuel is injected into the cylinder just prior to or slightly after the piston
                reaches top-dead-center.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The EGR Cooler</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With EGR, a portion of the engine's exhaust gases are cooled and then recirculated back into the inlet
                air stream. This increases the engine's tolerance for EGR and reduces the amount of smoke formed by
                exhaust gas dilution of the mixture.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The EGR Valve Actuator / Pintle Position Sensor</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The EGR valve is an electromechanical device that uses a linear actuator to control the relative
                position of the valve's pintle. This device also has a built-in pintle position sensor that functions to
                provide the ECM with a feedback signal. This output signal provides information on valve position
                relative to its seat. The advantage of this "closed loop" feedback is the ability to continuously vary
                exhaust gas flow to match operating conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The EGR valve uses a position feedback sensor to provide pintle position data to the ECM. The signal,
                based on a 5 volt (V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>) is directly proportional to the valve opening.
            </para>
            <para>The exhaust enters the valve assembly between the two pintle heads and exits through each pintle and
                seat interface when the valve is actuated. The valve group moves outward from its fail-safe closed
                position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f235in11.5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D31171A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Exhaust gas flow</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Actuator coil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve head (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Common shaft</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
