<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS DT 466 and
        DT 530 - PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTICS - Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="te17502027" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="left">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">11. Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load)</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>See figure
                                    <emph type="bold">J</emph>on back of form.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Measure fuel pressure at fuel filter bleeder.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Measure pressure at full load, rated speed.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Instrument</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>0-160 psi gauge</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 psi min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If pressure is low, replace fuel filter, clean fuel strainer and retest.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If pressure is still low, go to Test 3.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if the fuel system is supplying the engine with the proper fuel quantity and pressure at
                full load conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, be certain that the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is
                        applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to starting engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the fuel filter has a water-in-fuel probe, ask the vehicle operator if the water-in-fuel
                        lamp (yellow) is illuminated during vehicle operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If pressure gauge is not connected to fuel system in Test 2, remove air bleed valve on
                    fuel filter header. Install 1/8 in (3 mm) pipe fitting in place of the bleed valve .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a line from the fitting to the 0-160 psi gauge of the Gauge Bar. See Measuring
                    Fuel Pressure with Gauge Bar . Start engine and run at low idle to check for fuel leaks in-line to
                    pressure gauge.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Bleed air from the fuel line to insure an accurate reading.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive vehicle on road till engine reaches operating temperature. Find an open section of
                    road and select a suitable gear. Depress the accelerator pedal (full depression) to the floor and
                    accelerate to rated speed and 100% load.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Drive the vehicle uphill or fully loaded to reach the correct engine loading at rated
                            engine speed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure fuel pressure and record on Mechanical Diagnostics form EGED-220. If pressure is
                    not within specifications, replace fuel filter, clean fuel strainer, and recheck fuel pressure. If
                    fuel pressure remains low after replacing the filter, perform Transfer Pump Restriction Test 3 .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Several crank cycles may be required to purge the air from the fuel system after replacing the
                        fuel filter.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes:</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A clogged fuel filter or fuel strainer could cause high restriction and low fuel pressure.
                        Replace fuel filter, clean strainer, and retest.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Debris in the fuel regulator valve will cause low fuel pressure, see Test 3 .</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A kinked or severely bent fuel supply line, or blockage at the pickup tube could cause
                        restriction and low fuel pressure, see Test 3 .
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A loose fuel line on the suction side of the fuel system could cause air to be ingested into
                        the system and cause low fuel pressure, see Test 3 .
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The fuel pump could have internal damage, e.g. seized plunger or leaking check valves.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A restriction from the transfer pump inlet to the fuel tank can cause low fuel pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A restriction between the fuel inlet fitting, strainer and transfer pump inlet can cause low
                        fuel pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Gauge Bar (PS94-831-3) and appropriate line with 1/8 in NPT fitting</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_57.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_59.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
