<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Diamond Logic&#174;
        Brake System - Engine Brake System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Engine Brake System</title>
        <para>The engine brake is a compression release brake system that provides enhanced braking performance. The
            exhaust brake is an integrated engine brake system component. However, the exhaust brake can not be used
            independently.
        </para>
        <para>The operator can enable the brake function by toggling a dash mounted switch to ON or OFF and selecting a
            desired level. There are three brake level choices that accommodate terrain, driving conditions, or driver
            preference.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Operation</title>
        </para>
        <para>The engine brake system retards vehicle speed during deceleration or braking. During engine brake
            operation, high-pressure oil is used to force the exhaust valves partially open. An integrated high-pressure
            oil manifold and brake shut-off valve distribute high-pressure oil to each brake piston. These brake pistons
            hold the exhaust valves open.
        </para>
        <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk35/K35163.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Brake shut-off valve and brake actuator- OFF</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil manifold</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Injector oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake shut-off valve assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake actuator piston assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust valve bridge</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Valve lash (actuator retracted)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil inlet</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>During normal engine operation, oil in the high-pressure manifold goes to the fuel injectors only. A brake
            shut-off valve, mounted in the high-pressure oil manifold, is closed to prevent oil from entering the brake
            gallery.
        </para>
        <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk35/K35164.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Brake shut-off valve and brake actuator- ON</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil manifold</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil flow to brake oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake shut-off valve assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Brake actuator piston assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust valve bridge</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Valve lash (actuator deployed)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Normal oil seepage</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil inlet</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The ECM monitors the following criteria to make sure certain conditions are met.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>ABS (inactive)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>RPM (greater than 1200)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>APS (less than 5%)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Idle validation</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EOT (greater than or equal to 60 &#176;C [140 &#176;F])</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Operator input switches (On/Off) (power selection - Low, Med, High)</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If On is selected, and the preceding criteria is met, the engine brake will activate.</para>
        <para>When the engine brake is activated, the ECM provides the power to activate the brake shut-off valve to
            allow oil from the injector oil gallery to flow to the brake oil gallery. High oil pressure activates the
            brake actuator pistons to open the exhaust valves.
        </para>
        <para>The VGT vanes also move to restrict exhaust air flow. The combination of the compression release and
            exhaust restriction absorbs vehicle momentum.
        </para>
        <para>During an ABS event, the engine brake is deactivated. The engine brake is reactivated once the ABS event
            is over.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM removes the power source from the brake shut-off valve to deactivate the engine brake. Residual
            brake gallery pressure initially bleeds from the actuator bore. When brake gallery pressure bleeds down to
            6895 kPa (1000 psi), the brake pressure relief valve opens, and oil drains back to sump.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_E3350002.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
