<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEMS DIAGNOSTICS - Circuit Diagnostics -
        Electronic Control Module Power (ECM PWR)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Electronic Control Module Power (ECM PWR)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3324" filename="../figd33/d3324.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for the Electronic Control Module Power (ECM PWR)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Function Diagram for ECM PWR includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Battery</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Ignition switch or power relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuses</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) requires a 12V power source to function correctly. The operating
                power is received directly from the vehicle batteries through the ECM relay contacts each time the
                ignition key switch is turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>Turning the ignition key switch ON causes the ECM to provide an internal ground to the coil side of
                the ECM relay. This causes the relay to close its contacts and provide the ECM with the power necessary
                to perform its various functions.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM PWR Circuit Operation</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3325" filename="../figd33/d3325.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>ECM PWR Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECM is grounded directly to the battery negative terminal through ECM terminals X3-6 and X3-7.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM receives V
                <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                power at terminal X3-3. The power signals the ECM to provide a ground path to switch the ECM power relay
                from terminal X3-5 to 85. Switching the ECM relay provides power directly from the battery positive
                terminal through 2 fuses and relay contacts 30 and 87 to terminals X4-1 and X4-2. See truck Chassis
                Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for circuit numbers, connector and fuse locations.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM internally monitors battery voltage. When the ECM continuously receives less than 7V or more
                than 23V a Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC) will be set.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM PWR Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTCs are read using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by counting the flashes from the amber and
                red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc112">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 112</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Internal voltage power out of range high</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 112 is set when the ECM detects an alternator output greater than 23V at pin X3-3 for more
                        than 0.5 sec.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 112 can be set when jump starting the engine and additional voltage is introduced.
                        Incorrect external battery connections can cause the voltage increase.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the condition causing DTC 112 is intermittent, the code will change from active to inactive
                        status. DTC 112 will not cause the amber ENGINE lamp to turn on.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc113">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 113</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Internal voltage power out of range low</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 113 is set when the ECM detects less than 7.0V at pin X3-3 for more than 0.5 sec.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 113 can be set by a defective alternator or ECM power relay, discharged batteries, or
                        increased resistance in the battery feed circuits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the condition causing DTC 113 is intermittent, the code will change from active to inactive
                        status. DTC 113 will not cause the amber ENGINE lamp to turn on.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM monitors voltage on V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        A and will adjust signal values for the sensors that use V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        A for operation. If a sensor or circuit pulls V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        lower than 5V, the ECM may set out of range high DTCs for the sensors that operate on V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        B (APS, BAP, B+, and VSS).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc626">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 626</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Unexpected reset fault</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 626 is set when power is interrupted to the ECM. Loose or dirty connections at battery or
                        ground cables can cause the ECM to power down.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After circuit becomes intact, the ECM will reboot. Erratic engine performance can occur.
                        Turning engine ignition key OFF and then ON will cause the code to change from active to
                        inactive status.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 626 is active, monitor the voltage at ECM pins X4-1 and X4-2. Examine for
                        intermittent connections in the power feed wiring. The EST can be used to indicate DTCs and
                        display the V
                        <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                        voltage measured by the ECM to pin X3-3.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 626 will not turn the amber ENGINE lamp on.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When DTC 112 or 113 is active, see truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for circuit
                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Tools</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Service Tool (EST) with Master Diagnostics software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>International&#174; EZ-Tech Interface Cable</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Relay Breakout harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout box</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Terminal Test Adapter Kit</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM PWR Pin Point Diagnostics</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3325" filename="../figd33/d3325.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>ECM PWR Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECM PWR circuit requires the use of vehicle circuit diagrams. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit
                Diagram manual for circuit numbers, connector and fuse locations.
            </para>
            <table id="te24007025" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="bottom">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <caution>
                                    <para>To avoid damage to engine, before unplugging IDM connectors and relay, turn
                                        ignition key OFF. Failure to turn ignition key OFF will create a voltage spike
                                        and damage electrical components.
                                    </para>
                                </caution>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Key ON Engine OFF - Voltage Checks at ECM Power Relay Socket
                                    </emph>
                                    (Follow tests in order. Check with ECM relay and breakout harness installed,
                                    ignition Key ON Engine OFF. Inspect for bent pins or corrosion.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177;1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Continuous voltage. If no voltage, check power circuits from batteries through
                                    fuse. If fuse is blown, check for short to ground. If fuse is good, check for open
                                    between PIN 30 and B+. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay
                                    and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Continuous voltage. If no voltage, check fuses. If fuse is blown, check for short
                                    to ground. If fuse is good, check for open between PIN 30 and B+. See truck Chassis
                                    Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for fuse and relay locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0.06 to 2V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >2V is present, check for open circuit between PIN X3-5 to PIN 85 on relay or V
                                    <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                                    circuit. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse
                                    locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>87 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177;1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Continuous voltage. If no voltage, replace relay.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3325" filename="../figd33/d3325.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>ECM PWR Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te24007026" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="bottom">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <caution>
                                    <para>To avoid damage to engine, before unplugging IDM connectors and relay, turn
                                        ignition key OFF. Failure to turn ignition key OFF will create a voltage spike
                                        and damage electrical components.
                                    </para>
                                </caution>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Key ON Engine OFF - Voltage Checks at ECM</emph>
                                    (Follow tests in order. Check with breakout box installed between chassis harness
                                    and ECM. Inspect for bent pins and corrosion.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-3 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177;1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Power from ignition switch to ECM. If no voltage, see truck Chassis Electrical
                                    Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-6 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery. If voltage is present
                                    check for open or high resistance between battery (-) and ECM pins.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-7 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery. If voltage is present
                                    check for open or high resistance between battery (-) and ECM pins.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-5 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0.06-2V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>ECM grounds relay through internal transistor. If >2V is present, replace ECM.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X4-1 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177;1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Power from relay to ECM. If no voltage, check for open between X4-1 and 87 on ECM
                                    relay. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse
                                    locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X4-2 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12V &#177;1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Power from relay to ECM. If no voltage, check for open between X4-2 and 87 on ECM
                                    relay. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse
                                    locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3325" filename="../figd33/d3325.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>ECM PWR Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te24007027" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="bottom">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <warning>
                                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or
                                        vehicle, always disconnect main negative battery cable first. Always connect the
                                        main negative battery cable last.
                                    </para>
                                </warning>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <caution>
                                    <para>To avoid damage to engine, before unplugging IDM connectors and relay, turn
                                        ignition key OFF. Failure to turn ignition key OFF will create a voltage spike
                                        and damage electrical components.
                                    </para>
                                </caution>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Checks</emph>
                                    (Check with Key OFF. Disconnect negative battery cable. Inspect for bent pins or
                                    corrosion. Install relay breakout harness and breakout box to X3 and X4 chassis
                                    harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-5 to 85 (ECM relay)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections for open between ECM and relay. See truck Chassis
                                    Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X4-1 to 87 (ECM relay)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections for open between ECM and relay. See truck Chassis
                                    Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X4-2 to 87 (ECM relay)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections for open between ECM and relay. See truck Chassis
                                    Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>30 (ECM relay) to B+ cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections for open between relay and positive battery
                                    cable. Check fuses. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay
                                    and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>86 (ECM relay) to B+ cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections for open between relay and positive battery
                                    cable. Check fuse. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and
                                    fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-6 to neg bat cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections to battery ground. See truck Chassis Electrical
                                    Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-7 to neg bat cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections to battery ground. See truck Chassis Electrical
                                    Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-3 to V
                                    <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                                    (power relay)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, check connections or open between ECM and V
                                    <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                                    power relay. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual for relay and fuse
                                    locations.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECM PWR Diagnostic Trouble Code</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 112 = Internal voltage power out of range high >23V</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 113 = Internal voltage power out of range low &#60;7V</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 626 = Unexpected reset fault</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_137.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_139.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
