<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW - VEHICLE
        FEATURES - Standard Features
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Standard Features</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Governor Control</title>
            <para>DT 466E and INTERNATIONAL&#174; 530E engines are electronically controlled for all operating ranges.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>American Trucking Association Data Link Provisions</title>
            <para>Vehicles are equipped with the American Trucking Association (ATA) data link connector for
                communication between the ECM and the Electronic Service Tool (EST).
            </para>
            <para>The ATA data link provides data for the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission of engine parameter data</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics and troubleshooting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Customer programming</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Production line programming of vehicle features</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Field programming</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Diagnostics</title>
            <para>The Electronic Service Tool (EST) provides diagnostic information using the ATA data link.</para>
            <para>
                <title>Diagnostics Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes for sensors, actuators, electronic components, and engine systems are
                detected and stored in the ECM. The ECM transmits Diagnostic Trouble Codes to the EST to indicate
                correct diagnostic action. The ECM also provides service diagnostic information, via flash codes emitted
                by the engine warning lamp located on the dash of the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Speedometer and Tachometer</title>
            <para>The engine control system calibrates vehicle speed to 157,157 pulses/mile. The new speed calibration
                information must be programmed with an Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
            <para>The tachometer signal is generated by the ECM by computing the Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP) signal.
                The signal is transmitted to the instrument dash cluster and the Electronic Service Tool (EST) by the
                ATA data Link.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Over Temperature Protection System (Coolant Temperature Compensation)</title>
            <para>Coolant Temperature Compensation reduces fuel delivery if engine coolant temperature is above the
                cooling system specifications. Fueling is reduced proportionally to the design limit exceeded. Fuel
                reduction is calibrated to a maximum of 40% before standard engine warning or optional warning/shutdown
                is engaged. If warning, shutdown, or Coolant Temperature Compensation (CTC) occurs, a Diagnostic Trouble
                Code is stored in the ECM memory.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Coolant Temperature Compensation may be omitted on emergency vehicles that require 100% power
                        on demand.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Event Logging System</title>
            <para>The event logging system records engine operation above maximum rpm (overspeed), high coolant
                temperature, low coolant level, or low oil pressure. This information and readings for the odometer /
                hourmeter are stored in the ECM memory and may be accessed using the EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Crank Inhibit</title>
            <para>Engine Crank Inhibit will not allow the starting motor to crank if the engine is running or the
                automatic transmission is in gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Accelerator Pedal</title>
            <para>The Electronic Accelerator Pedal eliminates the mechanical linkage used with conventional accelerator
                pedals. An accelerator position sensor, part of the accelerator pedal assembly, provides the ECM with an
                analog voltage signal representing the driver's demand for power.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750125" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG1/EG1279A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Electronic Accelerator Pedal System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cold Ambient Protection (CAP)</title>
            <para>The Cold Ambient Protection system safeguards the engine from damage caused by prolonged periods of
                idle at no load during cold weather conditions. CAP will also improve cab warm up.
            </para>
            <para>CAP maintains engine coolant temperature by increasing the engine rpm to a programmed value when the
                Ambient Air Temperature is below 32&#176;F (0&#176;C), the Engine Coolant Temperature is below 149&#176;F
                (65&#176;C), and the engine has been idling with no load for more than 5 minutes.
            </para>
            <para>CAP is standard on all trucks without an Idle Shutdown Timer, with a clutch switch (manual
                transmission), or a neutral safety switch (automatic transmission).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Oil Lamp (COL)</title>
            <para>The change oil lamp interval can be programmed with the Electronic Service Tool (EST) for milage,
                hours, or gallons of fuel used.
            </para>
            <para>The change oil lamp timer can be reset with the Engine Diagnostics switch. Set the COL timer as
                follows:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition key on.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress and release the Engine Diagnostics switch twice.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress and hold the Engine Diagnostics switch for three seconds.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the Engine Diagnostics switch.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The procedure must be done within 10 seconds.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
