<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Symptoms
        Diagnostics - Problems and Conditions - ECM Reset / IDM Reset (intermittent engine stumble)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM Reset / IDM Reset (intermittent engine stumble)</title>
        <para>
            <title id="s27004002">Symptom</title>
        </para>
        <para>An Electronic Control Module (ECM) reset occurs when the ECM momentarily reboots or is turned OFF and ON
            while the engine is operating. Symptoms of this include the following:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Wait to start lamp cycles ON while engine running</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine stumbles and may die</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Loss of accelerator pedal authority</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Miles driven are not logged if ECM reset occurs during current key cycle</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If a reset occurs, the engine will momentarily stumble and the ECM will go through a normal KEY ON cycle.
            This includes the following:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Illuminate the WAIT TO START lamp</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Validate the accelerator pedal position</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If the pedal is not at idle position when the reset occurs, a DTC is set and engine speed goes to low
            idle. The ECM will not allow accelerator pedal authority until the Accelerator Pedal Sensor (APS) is
            released.
        </para>
        <para>An Injector Drive Module (IDM) reset will occur if power is lost to the circuits for IDM Logic or IDM Main
            Power while the engine is operating. If power is lost, the engine will miss and recover or stall. The APS
            will not be affected by this fault.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Cause</title>
        </para>
        <para>Momentary loss of power to the ECM or IDM may be caused by the following:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Failed fuses</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Intermittent open circuit</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Failed battery power feed harness</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Poor ground connection</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Failed power relay</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Shorted or open harness</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the EST, check for DTCs for both the engine and chassis modules.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If DTC 626 (unexpected reset fault) or 534 (IDM relay voltage low) are present as active or
                        inactive codes, continue with next step.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If any other engine DTCs are active, perform appropriate diagnostics and repairs before
                        continuing with these procedures.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If any chassis DTCs are active when checking the Electronic System Controller (ESC), perform
                        appropriate diagnostics and repairs before continuing.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>See Section 7 in this manual, the Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual and Electrical System
                    Troubleshooting Guidefor the model and year of the vehicle when performing the following steps.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check all ECM and IDM related fuses.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check all Battery, VIGNand ground connections for the ECM and IDM.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Monitor ECM powers and grounds with breakout box under operator complaint conditions.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Monitor IDM powers and grounds with 12-pin Breakout Harness under operator complaint
                conditions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If root cause has not been identified in previous steps, continue diagnosis by performing
                the remaining steps on the Performance Diagnostics form or Section 6 of this manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_65.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_67.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
