<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Crankcase, Crankshaft, Connecting
        Rods, And Pistons - Crankshaft and Main Bearings - Check Crankshaft Journals for Out-of-Round and Taper
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Check Crankshaft Journals for Out-of-Round and Taper</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To check for an out-of-round condition, measure each end of each journal at two points, 90&#176;
                apart from each other (4 measurements total).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When taking crankshaft measurements, it is important to keep the micrometer clear of the
                        crankshaft fillet radius.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Take the first two measurements taken in the same position (one measurement at each end
                    of the journal) and record the average.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Again, take the second set of measurements taken in the other position (at 90&#176; to
                    the first set, one measurement at each end of the journal) and record the average.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Subtract the smaller averaged value from the larger averaged value. This will yield the
                    amount of out-of-round.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To determine journal taper, use the measurements taken in Step 1.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Record the average of two measurements taken at one end of the journal.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Record the average of the other two measurements at the other side of the journal.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Subtract the smaller averaged value from the larger averaged value. This will yield the
                    amount of taper from one end of the journal to the other.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If any journals exceed either the maximum out-of-round or maximum taper specifications, the
                    crankshaft must be replaced or reground and undersize bearings installed. Failure to do so may
                    result in engine damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_189.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_191.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
