<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Power Cylinders - Remove -
        Piston and Rod Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s210010602.1" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Piston and Rod Assembly</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>There are two types of connecting rods used on this engine for model years 2000 through 2003. The
                connecting rods are easily identified by the way the connecting rod caps are secured to the connecting
                rods.
            </para>
            <table id="t01001" type="simple" frame="none">
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Forged steel connecting rods are secured to the connecting rod with bolts and
                                    nuts.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Powdered metal forged steel connecting rods are secured with bolts that thread
                                    into the connecting rod (no nuts used).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>The connecting rod is constructed of forged steel. It is attached to the crankshaft, one per journal.
                The pistons are cast aluminum alloy or steel crown with an aluminum skirt. All pistons are fitted with
                two compression rings and one oil ring. The piston pin is a free floating type, permitting the pin to
                move or float freely in the piston and connecting rod, and is held in place with pin retaining rings.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010602.1.1">
            <title>Forged Connecting Rods</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                        safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                        sure the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before doing
                        diagnostic or service procedures on engine or vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, if a carbon ridge has developed at top of cylinder sleeve, use a razor
                        knife to scrape it off before removing piston assemblies. Care must be taken not to damage
                        sleeve bore surface when removing carbon.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>Mark each connecting rod cap and reassemble to its respective connecting rod upon removal.
                        Also, mark location of each connecting rod in crankcase.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para id="s210010602.1.1" count="1">Use razor knife to scrape carbon ridge from top of cylinder
                    sleeve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen connecting rod bolts using a socket and breaker bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010602" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8576.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Remove connecting rod bolts</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts by hand.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bolts should turn out of connecting rod freely. If binding exists, check thread condition
                        carefully.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove connecting rod cap and bearing insert.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010603" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8648.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Remove connecting rod bearing cap</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate engine to vertical position (front end up).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use hammer with plastic or wooden handle or non-marring punch to push piston out of
                    cylinder sleeve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once piston rings are free of cylinder bore, assembly can be removed from top of
                    crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010604" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg5/eg5335.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Remove piston and connecting rod assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Match connecting rod and piston assemblies upon removal so they can be installed in
                    their respective cylinder bores.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010602.1.2">
            <title>Fractured Connecting Rods</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, keep fractured mating surfaces of connecting rod and cap clean and
                        free of lint and debris. Do not allow mating surfaces to rest on any surface. Do not bump mating
                        surfaces or drop connecting rod or cap. This could cause chipping and wear on mating surface,
                        resulting in improper mating during installation and possible engine damage.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, if carbon ridge has developed at top of cylinder sleeve, use a razor
                        knife to scrape it off before removing piston assemblies. Care must be taken not to damage
                        sleeve bore surface when removing carbon.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>For removing fractured connecting rods use the following procedures to avoid damaging mating
                        surfaces.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen both connecting rod bolts two turns.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use brass hammer to tap on bolt heads until cap comes loose from connecting rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010605" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figf04/f0405.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Remove connecting rod cap</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both bolts and cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate engine to vertical position (front end up).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to the engine, do not force the piston out of the engine by pushing on the rod
                        fracture surface.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f210010606" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh04/h04023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Push piston and connecting rod assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not push on rod fractured surface. Use hammer with plastic or wooden handle or
                    non-marring punch to push piston out of cylinder sleeve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once piston rings are free of cylinder bore, assembly can be removed from top of
                    crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010607" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg5/eg5335.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Remove piston and connecting rod assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Match connecting rod and piston assemblies upon removal so they can be installed in
                    their respective cylinder bores.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cap can be pulled away from connecting rod, proceed with assembly procedure in this
                    manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If cap cannot be pulled away from connecting rod, place connecting rod on a work bench
                    with cap extending over edge of work bench.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010608" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figf04/f0404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Split fractured connecting rod</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grasp connecting rod with one hand and cap outer half with other. Press down on cap to
                    break it away from connecting rod half.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210010602.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_137.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
