<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS DT 466 and
        DT 530 - PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTICS - Transfer Pump Restriction Test
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" id="E1750206" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Transfer Pump Restriction Test</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="te17502019" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC6" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">3. Transfer Pump Restriction Test</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>Perform this test only if fuel pressure is low. See figure
                                    <emph type="bold">K</emph>on back of form.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Measure restriction at fuel filter inlet @ high idle.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Instrument</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>0-30 in Hg vacuum Gauge</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 8 in Hg</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If restriction is high, check for blockage between fuel pump and tank.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If restriction is &#60; 8 in Hg, see EGES-215.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if low fuel pressure is caused by excessive restriction in the fuel supply line from the
                fuel tank to the transfer pump inlet.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a Tee between the fuel filter inlet and fuel supply line. Connect a line from
                    the Tee to a 0-30 in Hg vacuum gauge on Gauge Bar. See measuring Transfer Pump Restriction with
                    Gauge Bar .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Transfer pump restriction test will only detect a restriction in the fuel line (filter
                            header to tank) or tank pickup. Restriction between the transfer pump and the strainer will
                            not be detected by this test.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f1750238" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6819.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                    <caption>Measuring Transfer Pump Restriction with Gauge Bar</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure fuel inlet restriction at high idle and record reading on diagnostic form.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If restriction exceeds 8 in Hg, locate the restriction on the suction side of the fuel
                    system and correct. If restriction is within specifications or very low, check for air ingestion
                    between fuel inlet and the transfer pump inlet by performing the following.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove fuel supply line. Connect a clear plastic line to the fuel inlet fitting and
                        connect the fuel supply line to clear plastic line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check for air bubbles in the clear plastic line while engine is running at high
                        idle. If air bubbles are seen, inspect fuel system for suction leaks. Repair system, if
                        necessary. If air bubbles were not present, remove clear plastic line.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>To avoid personal injury, be certain that the transmission is in neutral, parking
                                brake is applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to starting engine.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install plug to seal off the fuel inlet. Start engine and run at high idle. Vacuum
                        reading should be greater than 22 in Hg. If less, check for air ingestion from the vacuum gauge
                        to the transfer pump. If no leak is found, replace transfer pump.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If no leaks are found on the inlet side of the fuel system, while the transfer pump is
                                providing > 22 in Hg. vacuum, replace fuel return valve. Recheck fuel pressure to verify
                                the valve was defective.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A fuel filter could cause high restriction and low fuel pressure because of dirt or fuel
                        jelling in cold ambient temperatures. Change filter and retest.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Primary fuel filter or fuel/water separator clogged.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A kinked or severely bent fuel supply line or blockage at the pickup tube could cause
                        restriction and therefore low fuel pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A loose fuel line on the suction side of the fuel system could cause air to be ingested into
                        the system and cause low fuel pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Primary fuel filter or fuel/water separator may be ingesting air into fuel system via loose
                        connections etc.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel return valve defective or stuck open due to debris.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective fuel transfer pump.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Gauge Bar (PS94-831-3)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tee or reworked hollow screw fitting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>NPT pipe adapter and appropriate fuel lines</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_49.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_51.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
