<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Water Pump and Thermostat -
        Remove
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="s210011002">
        <title>Remove</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo id="s210011002.1">
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                        safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                        sure the transmission is in neutral or park, parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before
                        doing diagnostic or service procedures on engine or vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death from hot coolant or steam scalding, use the following
                        procedure to remove the pressure cap from the cooling system. Allow the engine to cool. Wrap a
                        thick cloth around the cap. Unscrew cap slowly, then pause to allow pressure to release.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>Before removing water pump, coolant filter header, or water inlet elbow, first drain coolant
                        from engine.
                    </para>
                    <para>Coolant filter header must be removed prior to mounting engine on an engine stand.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc graphiccount="0">
            <title>Remove Pressure Cap from Deaeration Tank</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow the engine to cool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wrap a thick, heavy cloth around the cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the cap slowly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pause for a moment to allow the pressure and or steam to escape. This will avoid
                    possible scalding by hot water or steam.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue to turn the cap and remove it.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210011001.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_253.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
