<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Cylinder Head And Valves - Valve
        Seats - Resurfacing
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="recondition" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Resurfacing</title>
        <figure id="f1200498" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg9/eg9155.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Installing a Pilot in the Valve Guide</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Pilot</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lightly lubricate and install the correct size pilot into the valve guide bore.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1200497" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg9/eg9051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
            <caption>Using a Grinding Stone</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Choose the correct angle grinding stone and dress the stone.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the grinding stone over the pilot.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the grinding head over the pilot shank until the wheel contacts the valve seat. Turn
                on the power and gently apply the wheel to the valve seat with hardly any pressure other than weight of
                the grinding wheel itself.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the wheel frequently to prevent overheating.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Grind the seat to a smooth even finish.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After grinding, use a caliper to check the width of the valve seat. If the valve seat widths
                are excessive, they may be corrected by grinding with a 15&#176; or less angled stone.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a new valve does not correct an excessive recession condition, replace the cylinder head. If
                    the valve face protrudes above the deck, the valve seat must be ground deeper into the cylinder
                    head. After grinding a valve seat, check the seat width and confirm valve seat contact by using
                    Prussian Blue&#8482;.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After grinding the valve seat, use a depth gauge and micrometer to check the valve
                recession. Valve recession should not exceed specifications.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the valves have been resurfaced and the valve guides have been cleaned, insert the
                valves into the clean valve guide. Check the contact between the valve face and valve seat using
                Prussian Blue&#8482; or equivalent as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Spread a thin film of Prussian Blue on the valve face. Insert the valve into its
                    guide.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply pressure on the center of the valve head while making a quarter turn into the
                    valve seat.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the valve. Inspect the impression made on the valve seat and the valve face.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">A blue line should appear around the entire contact surface of the valve seat and an
                    impression on the blue film of the valve face should be centered. Check several times to prevent
                    error. If acceptable, proceed with valve installation.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For proof of results of refacing and to test seating operations, recheck the valve
                recession. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Inspection, Check Valve Recession</emph>
                in this section.
            </para>
            <para>A poor quality grind cannot be corrected by lapping. Inspect each valve for seat dimensions and make
                any necessary corrections. Corrections should always be made on the seat, not the valve face. If the
                recession is excessive, install a new cylinder head. If the valve protrudes above the deck, grind the
                valve seat.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_78.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_80.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
