<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Fuel Supply System - Fuel Flow</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Fuel Flow</title>
        <para>The fuel pump draws fuel from the fuel tank(s). Fuel passes through an 80 micron strainer on the pump. The
            fuel pump pressurizes and transfers fuel to the base of the fuel filter housing.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The fuel filter housing regulates fuel pressure and relieves excessive pressure back to the fuel
                    tank(s) through a fuel line connected to the top of the fuel filter housing. The fuel pressure
                    regulator is calibrated to open at 345 kPa (50 psi) but at high rpm, low load pressure could reach
                    more than 517 kPa (75 psi).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The fuel is conditioned as it passes through a 10 micron filter to a standpipe in the center of
                    the fuel filter housing.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>An optional electric heating element in the fuel filter housing warms the fuel to prevent
                    waxing.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A sensor in the base of the fuel housing detects water in the fuel. When enough water accumulates
                    in the bottom of the housing, the sensor sends a signal to light the optional Water In Fuel (WIF)
                    lamp on the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A fuel drain valve on the housing is used to eliminate contaminants (usually water) from the fuel
                    housing.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Filtered fuel flows from the fuel filter housing to both cylinder heads through fuel lines.</para>
                <para></para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Fuel flows past check valves through passages in the cylinder heads that intersect with the fuel
            injectors.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
