<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Fuel Management System - Fuel Injectors</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Fuel Injectors</title>
        <figure id="f2400124" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd11/D1117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Fuel Injector</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">CLOSE coil</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Control valve body</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Intensifier piston</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Piston return spring</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Plunger</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Valve opening pressure spring</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Needle</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">OPEN coil</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Spool valve (control valve)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Casenut</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel strainer (3)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Nozzle assembly</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Fuel injector features</title>
        </para>
        <para>Two 48 volt 20 amp coils control a spool valve that directs oil flow in and out of the injector. The
            injector coils are turned on for approximately 800 (micro second or millionth of a second). Each injector
            has a single four pin connector that passes through the rocker arm carrier
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Injector coils and spool valve</title>
        </para>
        <para>An OPEN coil and a CLOSE coil on the injector move the spool from side to side using magnetic force. The
            spool has two positions:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>When the spool valve is open oil flows into the injector from the high pressure oil rail.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When the spool valve is closed oil drains back to the crankcase.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Intensifier piston</title>
        </para>
        <para>When the spool valve is open high pressure oil enters the injector, pushing down the intensifier piston
            and plunger. Since the intensifier piston is 7.1 times greater in surface area than the plunger, the
            injection force is also 7.1 times greater than ICP pressure on the plunger.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Plunger and barrel</title>
        </para>
        <para>Fuel pressure builds between the plunger and the barrel. When the intensifier piston pushes the plunger
            down, the plunger increases fuel pressure in the barrel 7.1 times greater than ICP. The plunger has tungsten
            carbide coating to reduce scuffing and poor performance.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Injector needle</title>
        </para>
        <para>The injector needle opens inward, off its seat when fuel pressure overcomes the Valve Opening Pressure
            (VOP) - approximately 21 MPa (3100 psi). Fuel is atomized at high pressure through the nozzle tip.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Fuel injector operation</title>
        </para>
        <para>The injection operation has three stages:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Fill stage</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Main injection</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>End of main injection</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Fill stage</title>
        </para>
        <para>During the fill stage both coils are de-energized and the spool valve is closed. High pressure oil from
            the high pressure oil rail is dead headed at the spool valve.
        </para>
        <para>Low pressure fuel fills the port below the plunger. The needle control spring holds the needle on its seat
            to prevent fuel from entering the combustion chamber.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Main injection (Step 1)</title>
        </para>
        <para>A pulse width current energizes the OPEN coil. Magnetic force moves the spool open. High pressure oil
            flows past the spool valve into the intensifier piston chamber. Oil pressure overcomes the force of the
            intensifier piston spring and the intensifier starts to move. An increase in fuel pressure under the plunger
            seats the fuel inlet check ball. Fuel pressure starts to build once the plunger passes the fuel spill port
            of the barrel. Force on the needle begins to build.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Main injection (Step 2)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The pulse width controlled current to the OPEN coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains open. High
            pressure oil from high pressure oil rail continues to flow past the spool valve. The intensifier piston and
            plunger continue to move and fuel pressure increases in the barrel. When fuel pressure rises above the VOP -
            about 21 MPa (3100 psi) - the needle lifts of its seat and injection begins.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>End of main injection (Step 1)</title>
        </para>
        <para>When the Injector Drive Module (IDM) determines that the correct injector On Time has been reached
            (meaning the correct amount of fuel has been delivered), the IDM sends pulse width controlled current to the
            CLOSE coil of the injector. The current energizes the CLOSE coil and magnetic force closes the spool valve.
            High pressure oil is dead headed against the spool valve.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>End of main injection (Step 2)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The pulse width controlled current to the CLOSE coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains closed. The
            intensifier piston and plunger return to their initial position. Oil above the intensifier piston flows past
            the spool valve through the exhaust ports. Fuel pressure decreases until the needle control spring forces
            the needle back onto its seat.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
