<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS DT 466 and
        DT 530 - HARD START / NO START DIAGNOSTICS - EST Data List
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EST Data List</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="te1750211" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">9. EST Data List</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>Do tests 10, 11, 12 if EST is not available.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Enter data in the
                                    <emph type="bold">Actual</emph>
                                    column below.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Monitor DATA for 20 seconds or more while cranking engine.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>PID</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Battery Voltage</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7 Volts min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>130 rpm min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ICP Pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>500 psi min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If voltage is low, see ECM Diagnostics.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If no rpm is noted, check DTC's.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If ICP is low, do Test 13.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if systems needed for starting meet operating specifications.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Test must be done with fully charged batteries.</emph>
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, do not under any circumstances allow smoking, an electric spark or
                        open flame near the battery or explosion may occur.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, be certain that the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is
                        applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to cranking engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>To measure battery voltage, engine cranking rpm, and Injection Control Pressure (ICP), read Electronic
                Service Tool (EST) data, while cranking the engine for a minimum of 20 seconds.
            </para>
            <para>If an EST is not available, use a Digital Multimeter (DMM) as an alternative to perform the following
                tests:
            </para>
            <para>Connect the EST tool to the American Trucking Association (ATA) diagnostic connector. The connector is
                on the underside of the dash panel (left side) inside the cab in most applications. Use Master
                Diagnostics to view Battery Voltage, Engine rpm, and ICP pressure while cranking .
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch ON.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Crank the engine and read data on the screen. The data will be displayed when the engine
                    begins to crank. The battery voltage must be 7 or more volts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If voltage to the Electronic Control Module (ECM) drops below 7 volts, the ECM will not
                    remain powered up. If the ECM does not get power through the ECM relay, the engine will not start.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine cranking speed must generate the required ICP to operate the fuel injectors and
                    create the required compression to ignite the fuel. If the EST shows
                    <emph type="bold">0</emph>
                    rpm during engine cranking, the ECM may not be receiving a signal from the Camshaft Position (CMP)
                    sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the CMP sensor is not functioning, it must be replaced. The ECM will not allow the
                    Injector Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve to fully activate without a CMP signal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the EST indicates low or no injection control pressure, check oil level in oil
                    reservoir (on front cover). Remove the engine harness connector from the Engine Oil Temperature
                    (EOT) sensor. Remove the EOT sensor from the front cover. Oil should drain from the internal
                    reservoir. If oil does not drain from the sensor hole continue to crank the engine.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Proceed with caution when removing sensor. Do not completely remove if oil is present.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the oil reservoir level continues to fall, the primary lube oil pump may be
                    inadequate in its duty to supply oil to the reservoir. See Low ICP Pressure Test 13 .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Low battery voltage - Failed batteries, high resistance at battery cable connections, or in
                        wiring to the ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective ECM power relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blown 40A in-line fuse (in battery box) which supplies voltage to the ECM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low cranking rpm - Can be caused by electrical system malfunctions, incorrect oil viscosity,
                        or long oil change intervals in cold ambient temperatures.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No engine rpm indication on EST while cranking the engine. - This can be caused by a faulty
                        CMP sensor or faulty circuitry to the ECM. Recheck for DTC's after cranking engine. See EST,
                        Diagnostic Trouble Codes or Diagnostic Trouble Code Access (DTC) .
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low ICP Pressure - This could indicate a leak in the high pressure oil system or a defective
                        ICP sensor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A defective high pressure oil pump, pump drive, defective Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR),
                        or electronic controls for the regulator could also cause low injection control pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <para>Electronic Service Tool (EST) with Master Diagnostics software</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supplemental Diagnostics</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If DTC's are set, see DTC column on Engine Diagnostic Trouble Codes .</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">To troubleshoot low voltage at ECM Power Supply see:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module Power Supply Diagram</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module Power Supply Circuit</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ECM PWR Circuit Diagnostics</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">No engine rpm indication during cranking - See CMP sensor diagnostics</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position Sensor Functions</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position Sensor Circuit Diagram</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position Sensor and Circuit Diagnostics</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">No Injection Control Pressure - See Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor
                    diagnostics
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Circuit Diagram Using a Breakout Tee</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Voltage Checks</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Troubleshooting Flowchart</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Circuit Specifications</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">No or low injection control pressure and no electronic DTC's</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>See Test 13 - Low ICP Pressure Test</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_X1750210.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_X1750204.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
