<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diagnostic Tools and
        Accessories - Tools and Accessories - Slack Tube Manometer
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Slack Tube Manometer</title>
        <figure id="f2700823" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEG7/EG7725.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>ZTSE2217A</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The Slack Tube Manometer is a U-shaped tube with a scale mounted between the legs of the tube. When the
            portability of the gauge bar tool is not required, this manometer is used to measure low vacuum for intake
            restriction or low pressure for crankcase.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Filling</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Fill the manometer with water before checking pressure. Use only distilled water. Add some colored water
            vegetable dye so the scale can be read more easily. With both legs of the manometer open to the atmosphere,
            fill the tube until the top of the fluid column is near the zero mark on the scale. Shake the tube to
            eliminate any air bubbles.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Installing, Reading, and Cleaning</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the manometer vertically. Make sure the fluid level is in line with the zero
                indicator on the graduated scale.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect one leg of the manometer to the source of the pressure or vacuum. Leave the other
                leg open to atmospheric pressure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and allow it to reach normal operating temperature. Then run the engine to
                high idle. The manometer can be read after 10 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Record the average position of the fluid level when it is above and below the zero
                indicator. Add the two figures together. The sum of the two is the total column of fluid (distance A).
                This represents the crankcase pressure in inches of water (in H
                <subscript>2</subscript>O).
            </para>
            <para>At times, both columns of the manometer will not travel the same distance. This is no concern if the
                leg not connected to the pressure or vacuum source is open to the atmosphere.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Compare the manometer reading with engine specifications.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the test is done, clean the tube thoroughly using soap and water. Avoid liquid soaps
                and solvents.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_190.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_192.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
