<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Introduction - Air Induction and
        Exhaust Systems - Air Flow
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Air Flow</title>
        <para>The intake system consists of an air cleaner, air to air cooler, the compressor side of the turbocharger,
            valve cover and intake manifold and intake valves. During start up, the air is forced through the air
            cleaner by atmospheric pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The turbocharger is used to increase engine power output by increasing air supply to the engine. It
            provides uniform performance at various operating altitudes. It is an exhaust driven centrifugal air
            compressor; that allows filtered air to enter at the center of the compressor housing and forced under
            pressure to the combustion chamber. After combustion, hot and expanding exhaust gases move through the
            turbine housing causing the turbine wheel to spin. The turbine wheel drives the compressor wheel through a
            common shaft. The turbocharger responds directly to engine loads. During heavy load, increased flow of
            exhaust gases turn the turbine wheel faster causing the compressor impeller to turn faster and supply more
            air (greater boost) to the intake manifold. Conversely, with light engine load, flow of exhaust gases
            decreases and less air is pumped into the intake manifold.
        </para>
        <para>The air is cooled by a charge air cooler prior to entering the intake manifold. Air then flows into the
            combustion chamber where the proper amount of fuel is injected causing combustion to occur. Exhaust gases
            leave the cylinders through exhaust ports and the exhaust manifold. From the exhaust manifold, the expansion
            of exhaust gases on the exhaust turbine drive the turbocharger and are released through the exhaust pipe to
            the atmosphere.
        </para>
        <para>The exhaust system includes exhaust valves, exhaust manifold, exhaust piping and muffler. The turbocharger
            compressor side is part of the intake system and turbine side is part of the exhaust system.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
