<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS - HARD START / NO
        START DIAGNOSTICS - Engine Systems Check
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Engine Systems Check</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f175205" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG9/EG9062.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To check engine systems for hard or no start conditions.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Read all safety instructions in this manual before doing this procedure.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect fuel tank and lines for damage and leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check oil line from high pressure pump to oil supply manifold for oil leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect entire cooling system for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check air induction system for leaks.
                    <hotlnk xrefid="p1750202">See
                        <emph type="bold">Air Induction System Inspection</emph>
                        <xref refid="p1750202"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect engine wiring harness for correct routing and protection against rubbing or
                    chaffing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The engine will not start with the IPR or CMP disconnected.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check sensor, relay, and control module connections. All connections must be seated, in
                    good condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect battery cable and fuse connections for corrosion. All connections must be
                    seated, in good condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
                </para>
                <specpara></specpara>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM harness connections must be torqued to 35 in&#183;lb (4 N&#183;m).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title id="p1750202">Air Induction System Inspection</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner housing for damage or distortion that could allow unfiltered air
                    into the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for end seal movement inside the housing. End seal movement is indicated if the
                    seal contact area is polished. A polished contact area indicates that unfiltered air has passed by
                    the filter element and into the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner element for end cap dents, holes, damaged seals, and soot.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air intake hoses and clamps for tightness and positioning over sealing beads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the chassis mounted charge air cooler and piping.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Induction System Pressure Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mask the outer diameter of air cleaner element air inlet with duct tape and plug air
                    cleaner canister drain.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air cleaner restriction indicator or tubing to the air cleaner. Install a
                    plug to seal opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f175206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1177.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Regulated air supply</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Find cold air discharge pipe containing a plug. Remove plug and connect a manually
                    regulated air supply with pressure gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 5-8 psi of air pressure to the air induction system. A constant air supply is
                    needed to replace air lost through opened intake valves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat areas (
                    <emph type="bold">a</emph>
                    through
                    <emph type="bold">f</emph>
                    - below) with a soap solution and check for leaks.
                </para>
                <figure id="f175207" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1181.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Checking for leakage</caption>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air cleaner body surface around the outlet pipe.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air cleaner outlet pipe to air cleaner body junction.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">All clamped hose and gasket connections between air cleaner outlet and intake
                        manifold. This includes turbocharger connections.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Surface of all air induction piping and hoses between air cleaner and intake
                        manifold.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air compressor air inlet piping from the air cleaner tube to and including the
                        fitting and the gasket.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Piping to the air charge cooler.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leakage is not permitted between air cleaner and turbocharger (suction side). If leaks
                    are found, tighten hose clamps. If leaks continue, replace necessary parts. Retest corrected area.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Air induction leaks can indicate dirt in the engine. Dirt can cause piston rings to wear
                            or break causing high oil consumption and excessive blue smoke and pitting or erosion of the
                            turbocharger compressor wheel. If leaks are found, test crankcase pressure.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection Lamp</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air Pressure Regulator</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
