<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - SUPPLEMENTAL DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS -
        DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS PROCEDURES - Coolant in Lubricating Oil or Lubricating Oil in Coolant
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Coolant in Lubricating Oil or Lubricating Oil in Coolant</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Oil Cooler Pressure Check</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use oil cooler test plate (ZTSE4376). See engine service manual. Possible locations of leakage include:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Lube oil cooler bundle (cracked / loose tubes or cut O-rings).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cylinder sleeve cavitation.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Blown air compressor head gasket.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cracked or porous cylinder head (top deck, injector sleeve, or defective head gasket).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Porous or cracked crankcase (in main bearing crankcase webbing).</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Pressure Leakage Test for Engine Crankcase</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If oil cooler is okay, perform pressure test.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Drain all lube oil and coolant from engine and radiator.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect the radiator from the engine and cap off all engine connections (with plugs and hose
                    clamps).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect cab heater connections at the engine and cap engine openings.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect air compressor coolant supply / discharge lines, then cap lines at engine.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect oil supply line from air compressor and cap.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Remove the intake manifold / valve cover, lube oil pan, and drain plug from the lube oil cooler.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fill the engine with water and attach an air line connection coupled with a regulator assembly to
                    the water drain in the cylinder block.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pressurize the crankcase cooling system to 30 psi (207 kPa). Maintain pressure to find leakage
                    (overnight, if necessary) to locate porous castings or tiny cracks.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All points of leakage must be found before tear down and repair.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>No external or internal leakage is allowable. After leaks are found and repaired, clean the
                    contaminated engine.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_137.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_139.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
