<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic
        Control System - Engine and Vehicle Sensors
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="6">
        <title>Engine and Vehicle Sensors</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermistor Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35156.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Thermistor</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A thermistor sensor changes electrical resistance with changes in temperature. Resistance in the
                thermistor decreases as temperature increases, and increases as temperature decreases. Thermistors work
                with a resistor that limits current in the ECM to a voltage signal matched with a temperature value.
            </para>
            <para>The top half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor inside the ECM. A thermistor
                sensor has two electrical connectors, signal return and ground. The output of a thermistor sensor is a
                nonlinear analog signal.
            </para>
            <para>Thermistor type sensors include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Aftertreatment temperature sensors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inlet Air Temperature (IAT) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT) sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Aftertreatment Sensors</title>
            </para>
            <para>Three sensors used in the Aftertreatment System include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Temperature (EGT) 1 sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGT 2 sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGT 3 sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The EGT 1 sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC)
                inlet temperature. The EGT 1 sensor is the first temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and
                just before the DOC.
            </para>
            <para>The EGT 2 sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF)
                inlet temperature. The EGT 2 sensor is the second temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and
                just after the DOC.
            </para>
            <para>The EGT 3 sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating DPF outlet temperature. The EGT 3
                sensor is the third temperature sensor installed past the turbocharger and just after the DPF.
            </para>
            <para>During a catalyst regeneration, the ECM will monitor all three sensors along with the Exhaust Gas
                Recirculation (EGR) System and Intake Throttle Valve (ITV).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECT Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the ECT signal and uses this information for the instrument panel temperature gauge,
                coolant compensation, Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS), and IAH operation. The ECT is a backup,
                if the EOT is out-of-range. The ECT sensor is installed in the water supply housing (Freon&#174;
                compressor bracket), to the right of the flat idler pulley assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EOT Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the EOT signal and uses this information to control fuel quantity and timing when
                operating the engine. The EOT signal allows the ECM to compensate for differences in oil viscosity for
                temperature changes. The EOT sensor is located in the rear of the front cover, to the left of the
                high-pressure pump assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>IAT Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the IAT signal to control injector timing and fuel rate during cold starts. The ECM
                also uses the IAT signal to control EGR position and intake throttle control. The IAT sensor is
                installed in the air filter housing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MAT Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the MAT signal for EGR operation. The MAT sensor is located in the intake manifold,
                to the right of the MAP sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Variable Capacitance Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35157.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Variable capacitance sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors measure pressure. The pressure measured is applied to a ceramic material.
                The pressure forces the ceramic material closer to a thin metal disk. This action changes the
                capacitance of the sensor.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor is connected to the ECM by the VREF, signal, and signal ground wires.</para>
            <para>The sensor receives the VREF and returns an analog signal voltage to the ECM. The ECM compares the
                voltage with pre-programmed values to determine pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The operational range of a variable capacitance sensor is linked to the thickness of the ceramic disk.
                The thicker the ceramic disk the more pressure the sensor can measure.
            </para>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Differential Pressure (EGDP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>EGDP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EGDP sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating the pressure difference between the
                inlet and outlet of the particulate filter. During a catalyst regeneration, the ECM will monitor this
                sensor along with three Aftertreatment System thermistor sensors, the EGR System, and the Intake
                Throttle Valve (ITV).
            </para>
            <para>The EGDP sensor is a differential pressure sensor with two tap-offs installed past the turbocharger. A
                tap-off is located before and after the DPF.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EFP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM uses the EFP sensor signal to monitor engine fuel pressure and give an indication when the
                fuel filter needs to be changed. The EFP sensor is installed in the fuel filter housing on the left side
                of the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EOP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the EOP signal, and uses this information for the instrument panel pressure gauge and
                EWPS. The EOP sensor is installed in the left side of the crankcase, below the left side of the fuel
                filter housing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EBP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the exhaust pressure so that the ECM can control the VGT, EGR, and intake throttle
                systems. The sensor provides feedback to the ECM for closed loop control of the Variable Geometry
                Turbocharger (VGT). The EBP sensor is installed in a bracket mounted on the water supply housing (Freon&#174;
                compressor bracket).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>MAP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the MAP signal to determine intake manifold pressure (boost). This information is
                used to control the turbocharger boost. The MAP sensor is installed in the intake manifold, left of the
                MAT sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Magnetic Pickup Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35159.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Magnetic pickup sensors</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A magnetic pickup sensor contains a permanent magnet core that is surrounded by a coil of wire. The
                sensor generates a voltage signal through the collapse of a magnetic field that is created by a moving
                metal trigger. The movement of the trigger then creates an AC voltage in the sensor coil.
            </para>
            <para>Magnetic pickup sensors used include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Crankshaft Position (CKP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>CKP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The CKP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that indicates crankshaft speed and position. As the
                crankshaft turns, the CKP sensor detects a 60 tooth timing disk on the crankshaft. Teeth 59 and 60 are
                missing. By comparing the CKP signal with the CMP signal, the ECM calculates engine rpm and timing
                requirements. The CKP sensor is installed in the top left side of the flywheel housing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>CMP Sensor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The CMP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that indicates camshaft position. As the cam rotates,
                the sensor identifies the position of the cam by locating a peg on the cam. The CMP sensor is installed
                in the front cover, above and to the right of the water pump pulley.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VSS</title>
            </para>
            <para>The VSS provides the ECM with transmission tail shaft speed by sensing the rotation of a 16 tooth gear
                on the rear of the transmission. The detected sine wave signal (AC), received by the ECM, is used with
                tire size and axle ratio to calculate vehicle speed. The VSS is on the left side of the transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) Sensors</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35158.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>MSG sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) sensor measures pressure. Pressure to be measured exerts force on a
                pressure vessel that stretches and compresses to change resistance of strain gauges bonded to the
                surface of the pressure vessel. Internal sensor electronics convert the changes in resistance to a
                ratiometric voltage output.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor is connected to the ECM by the VREF, signal, and signal ground wires.</para>
            <para>The sensor is powered by VREF received from the ECM and is grounded through the ECM to a common sensor
                ground. The ECM compares the voltage with pre-programmed values to determine pressure.
            </para>
            <para>Inline six engine micro strain gauge type sensors include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Brake Control Pressure (BCP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>BCP</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the BCP signal to determine the oil pressure in the brake gallery of the
                high-pressure oil manifold. The BCP sensor is under the valve cover, forward of the No. 2 fuel injector
                in the high-pressure oil manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ICP</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the ICP signal to determine injection control pressure for engine operation. The ICP
                signal is used to control the IPR valve. The ICP sensor provides feedback to the ECM for Closed Loop IPR
                control. The ICP sensor is under the valve cover, forward of the No. 6 fuel injector in the
                high-pressure oil manifold.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Potentiometer</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35160.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Potentiometer</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A potentiometer is a variable voltage divider that senses the position of a mechanical component. A
                reference voltage is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical rotary or linear motion moves
                the wiper along the resistance material, changing voltage at each point along the resistive material.
                Voltage is proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
            </para>
            <para>The engine has one potentiometer, the Accelerator Position Sensor (APS).</para>
            <para>
                <title>APS</title>The APS provides the ECM with a feedback signal (linear analog voltage) that indicates
                the operator's demand for power. The APS is installed in the cab on the accelerator pedal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Switches</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35161.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Switch</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Switch sensors indicate position, level, or status. They operate open or closed, regulating the flow
                of current. A switch sensor can be a voltage input switch or a grounding switch. A voltage input switch
                supplies the ECM with a voltage when it is closed. A grounding switch grounds the circuit when closed,
                causing a zero voltage signal. Grounding switches are usually installed in series with a current
                limiting resistor.
            </para>
            <para>Switches include the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Water In Fuel (WIF)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>DDS</title>
            </para>
            <para>The DDS determines if a vehicle is in gear. For manual transmissions, the clutch switch serves as the
                DDS. For automatic transmissions, the neutral indicator switch or datalink communication functions as
                the DDS.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECL</title>
            </para>
            <para>ECL is part of the Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS). The ECL switch is used in plastic
                deaeration tanks. When a magnetic switch is open, the tank is full.
            </para>
            <para>If engine coolant is low, the switch closes and the red ENGINE lamp on the instrument panel is
                illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>IVS</title>
            </para>
            <para>The IVS is a redundant switch that provides the ECM with a signal that verifies when the APS is in the
                idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>WIF</title>
            </para>
            <para>A Water In Fuel (WIF) sensor in the element cavity of the fuel filter housing detects water. When
                enough water accumulates in the element cavity, the WIF sensor signal changes to the Electronic Control
                Module (ECM). The ECM sends a message to illuminate the amber water and fuel lamp, alerting the
                operator. The WIF is installed in the base of the fuel filter housing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
