<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Power Cylinders - Installation -
        Piston and Connecting Rod Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Piston and Connecting Rod Assembly</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, do not allow the connecting rod or connecting rod cap fractured mating
                    surfaces to contact any surface other then its matched fractured surface. Contacting any other
                    surface can cause misalignment of the mating surface, resulting in connecting rod bearing and engine
                    failure.
                </para>
            </caution>
            <note>
                <para>Turn crankshaft so connecting rod journals 1 and 6 are at Bottom Dead Center (BDC). Install piston
                    and connecting rod assemblies 1 and 6 first. Then repeat the procedure for piston and connecting rod
                    assemblies 2 and 5. Finish with piston and connecting rod assemblies 3 and 4.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install connecting rod bearings into connecting rods and connecting rod caps dry (without
                oil).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para id="s1523" count="1">Lubricate piston rings with clean engine oil. Stagger piston ring gaps
                approximately 120 degrees from each other.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate inside diameter of the cylinder sleeve with clean engine oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, install each piston with the arrow to the front of the engine and the
                    "camside" mark toward the cam side of the engine.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully install the piston and connecting rod assembly into the cylinder sleeve with the
                arrow on the piston crown pointing to the front of the engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f3350015488" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh04/H04018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Piston Ring Compressor Tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_394.xml" xrefid="t335001503">Piston Ring Compressor Tool</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001503"/>
                over the piston rings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f3350015489" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh04/H04019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Piston and connecting rod assembly installation</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the piston and connecting rod assembly into the cylinder sleeve using a wooden or
                plastic handle. Carefully guide the connecting rod over the crankshaft connecting rod journal. Do not
                touch the crankshaft journal with the fractured mating surface of the connecting rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f3350015490" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk04/K04005.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Connecting rod and cap serial number locations</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, each connecting rod cap serial number must be assembled on the same side
                    as its connecting rod serial number (they must match). If the rod cap is reversed when assembled on
                    the connecting rod or a rod cap is not installed on its original matching connecting rod, the
                    fractured mating surfaces will be ruined. The entire connecting rod assembly must then be replaced.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f3350015491" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk04/K04007.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Incorrect connecting rod cap orientation</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the connecting rod cap is reversed during assembly, an obvious offset will be seen at the rod
                    mating surfaces. If the connecting rod cap is installed in the reverse orientation, the connecting
                    rod must be replaced. Also check the crankshaft journal for damage.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Each connecting rod cap mark must point toward the front of the engine.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the connecting rod bearing inside diameter with clean engine oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f3350015492" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh04/H04021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Connecting rod cap installation</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully install connecting rod cap and two new rod bolts over the crankshaft journal and
                finger tighten rod bolts into connecting rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect connecting rod caps and determine if engine has
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_S1525.xml" xrefid="f3350015504">connecting rods with M12 bolts</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f3350015504"/>
                or
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_S1526.xml" xrefid="f3350015505">connecting rods with M11 bolts</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f3350015505"/>
                . Follow the appropriate torque procedure for the connecting rods installed in engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_386.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_S1525.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
