<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Electronic Control Systems Diagnostics - Pin-Point Diagnostics</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="s305010705">
        <title>Pin-Point Diagnostics</title>
        <svcproc id="s305010705.1" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Voltage Checks - Connectors</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The ECM harness connectors must be properly seated and the connector latched to avoid possible
                        driveability or no-start conditions. Installing ECM connectors on an angle may cause an improper
                        connection, misdiagnosis, and damaged components. Install the connector until the lever pivots
                        and seats. Apply light pressure to position the connector on the ECM and then fully seat
                        connector.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to ON (do not crank the engine).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug correct breakout harness into the harness connector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure voltage at each pin with a DMM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare sensor or actuator voltage readings with the expected voltages listed in the
                    diagnostic table in this section for circuits being tested, this test will verify circuit integrity.
                </para>
                <para>If a breakout harness is not available, use the correct tool from Terminal Test Adapter Kit. Do
                    not directly probe the connector terminals with the DMM leads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition switch to OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>For circuits without an expected voltage, this test will determine if that circuit is shorted or
                miss-wired to V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>, B+ or other voltage sources.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_120.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_122.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
