<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Variable Geometry Turbocharger
        (VGT) - Removal
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Removal</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information"
                        section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, allow engine to cool before working with components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, disconnect ground (-) cable from battery before doing
                        service or diagnostic procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, inspect turbocharger with engine off, and turbocharger
                        not spinning. Turbocharger components may be extremely hot. Turbocharger wheels are very sharp
                        and spin at high speeds.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields. Limit compressed
                        air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, support turbocharger assembly during removal and
                        installation.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not let engine fluids stay on your skin. Clean skin
                        and nails using hand cleaner and wash with soap and water. Wash or discard clothing and rags
                        contaminated with engine fluids.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <regulation>
                    <para>Engine fluids (oil, fuel, and coolant) may be a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose
                        of engine fluids and filters according to applicable regulations. Never put engine fluids in the
                        trash, on the ground, in sewers, or bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </regulation>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="disconnect" graphiccount="1">
            <title>VGT Actuator Connector</title>
            <figure id="f3350004126" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figK09/K09013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>VGT actuator connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lock tab (up to unlock)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Release tab (push to release)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VGT actuator</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push lock tab up to unlock VGT actuator connector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press the release tab and pull sensor harness connector out of VGT actuator connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_108.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_110.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
