<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - DIAGNOSTIC PROCEDURES FOR THE ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM - Actuator and Sensor Diagnostic Procedure
        Without Master Diagnostics
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="svcproc" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Actuator and Sensor Diagnostic Procedure Without Master Diagnostics</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Connector Voltage Checks</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Turn the ignition key on. Plug the breakout tee into the harness and measure voltage at each pin with a
            digital multimeter (DMM). Compare meter readings with the expected voltages listed in the diagnostic
            section. If the tee is not available, use the appropriate tool from the terminal test adapter kit
            (ZTSE4435). Do not probe the connector terminals with the DMM leads directly. This test will determine if
            that circuit is shorted or incorrectly wired to V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>, B+, or other voltage sources.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Signal return circuits will measure 0 - 0.25V on a "Pull Down" sensor circuit or close to 5V or
                    12V for a "Pull Up" circuit.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Actuator circuits may be either ON/OFF or pulse width modulated (PWM). If the actuator has an
                    ON/OFF circuit, the ECM controls the voltage or the ground. When pulse width modulated (PWM), the
                    ECM controls the duty cycle or on time of the power or ground.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    should measure 5 &#177; 0.5V (4.5 - 5.5 V) with the sensor disconnected. If the voltage reading is
                    lower than expected, disconnect the sensors that operate on that V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    circuit (V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>-D: EOP, MAP, CMP, ICP; V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    - B: APS/IVS, BAP; V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    - C body builder accessories) one at a time while observing V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>. If V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    returns after disconnecting a sensor, that sensor is shorting V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    to ground, refer to Measuring Voltage Reference, .
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f17503008.6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8836.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Measuring Vref Voltage with ZTSE4486</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. DMM Probe (red)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. Vref, Pin B (blue)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. DMM Probe (to engine ground)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Connector Checks To Ground</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Turn the ignition switch off. Disconnect the positive battery cable. Using the breakout tee, measure the
            resistance from the lead of the tee to the negative battery terminal. Sensor signal ground circuits should
            measure less than 5 ohms. V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            and signal circuits should measure greater than 1000 ohms. The control side of an actuator will measure
            greater than 1000 ohms, but the expected reading on the other circuit of the actuator will depend upon what
            the control side was switching, power or ground. If the ECM was switching the ground, "low side driver,"
            then the other circuit of the actuator should measure greater than 1000 ohms from the connector terminal to
            battery ground. If the ECM is switching the B+ side, "high side driver," the ground circuit will measure
            less than 5 ohms from terminal to battery ground, .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17503008.7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8838.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Measuring Resistance to Ground with ZTSE4486</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. DMM Probe (red)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CMP Ground, Pin A, (black)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. DMM Probe to Engine Ground (black)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Tests</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Harness resistance is checked when a circuit is suspected of having high resistance or being open. Perform
            this test by connecting a breakout box to the ECM end of the harness and measuring resistance from the pin
            of the breakout tee to the pin on the breakout box. Circuit wires should have a resistance of less than 5
            ohms.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_74.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_76.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
