<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYMPTOMS DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - Rough Idle
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Rough Idle</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine oil (aerated, incorrect grade, low oil level, extended drain interval)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor fuel quality</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low fuel pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Aerated fuel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic control system faults (ECM and IDM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system problems</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel injectors not working properly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve stuck open</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Power cylinder problems</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Valve train problems</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine or flywheel balance problems</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust system to cab/chassis ground out</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose/worn engine mounts</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostics for Verifying Rough Idle</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify complaint. Confirm conditions when complaint is present.</para>
                <para>When does engine rough idle occur?</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Hot - operating temperature</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Cold</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After high speed operation</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Over entire engine speed range</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Combination of the above conditions</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Is there chassis vibration or any other conditions/observations present when engine idles
                            rough.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect exhaust system for contact with cab, frame or body of vehicle.</para>
                <para>Engine exhaust pipe contact with cab may transmit engine vibrations to cab, especially on
                    acceleration or engine shifts. This condition may be incorrectly diagnosed as a rough idle
                    complaint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Complete the following tests on the Performance Diagnostic form EGED-250. See Section 6 in this manual
                for specific details on each test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 1 (Engine Oil) on form EGED-250. Check engine oil level. Verify correct oil
                    grade for ambient temperature. Refer to the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Engine
                    Lubrication Requirements section. Confirm oil meets correct API specification for your model and
                    year of engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 2 (Fuel) on form EGED-250. Verify quality and quantity of diesel fuel. Poor
                    quality fuel or low cetane rating can cause white smoking, engine misfire, and low power. Refer to
                    the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Fuel Requirements section for your model and year of
                    engine to determine minimum necessary fuel grade and cetane rating.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 3 (Fuel Pressure) on form EGED-250. Measure transfer pump pressure. Low fuel
                    pressure will cause the engine to misfire and will cause a loss of power.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If fuel pressure is low, remove canister mounted on fuel pump and remove any debris on
                            fuel inlet screen.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 4 (Fuel Inlet Restriction) on form EGED-250 using the fuel inlet restriction
                    adapter.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove fuel pressure regulator from side of fuel filter housing and inspect valve and
                            spring for damage. Inspect the rubber seat on the valve for tearing or swelling. Remove any
                            foreign material found.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 5 (Diagnostic Trouble Codes) on form EGED-250. Intermittent sensor, injector or
                    wiring harness faults can affect engine idle conditions. The ECM may have detected and recorded
                    these conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 6 (Key On Engine Off Standard Test) on form EGED-250. The KOEO Standard Test
                    will verify electrical operation of all sensors and actuators.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 7 (Key On Engine Off Injector Test) on form EGED-250. This test will verify that
                    the injectors are working electronically.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do air in fuel and fuel return flow test. Install a clear line on the return fuel line
                    and check to see if air bubbles are present while engine is running. An excessive amount of air
                    indicates a suction side air leak or damaged injector gasket. These problems will cause rough idle
                    and/or poor performance. If there is a question about what is excessive air, locate a good running
                    vehicle and compare fuel flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 12 (Key On Engine Running Standard Test) on form EGED-250. This test will verify
                    the functionality of the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system. The engine must be at operating
                    temperature 70&#176;C (158&#176;F) to do this test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 16 (Injection Control Pressure) on form EGED-250. This test will confirm if the
                    Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system is functioning properly and verify ICP stability.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 17 (Crankcase Pressure) on form EGED-250. This test will determine the condition
                    of the power cylinders and base engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 18 (Injector Disable) on form EGED-250. The primary function of this test is to
                    show the contributions of the individual power cylinders. The test will detect a weak cylinder which
                    could be the result of an injector or base engine problem.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Test 18 is used in conjunction with Test 19 (Relative Compression) to distinguish between
                            an injector or mechanical problem.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 19 (Relative Compression) on form EGED-250. This will verify base engine
                    compression.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Test 19 is used in conjunction with Test 18 (Injector Disable) to distinguish between an
                            injector or mechanical problem.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for engine and flywheel balance. Engine roughness at idle that gets worse with a
                    no load acceleration may be caused by an out of balance condition.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle,
                            support the vibration damper during mounting bolt removal. The damper can slide off the nose
                            of the crankshaft very easily.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To prevent engine damage, you must always replace all four bolts when installing the
                            vibration damper.
                        </para>
                        <para>Do not use anti-seize compounds, grease, or any lubricants whatsoever. Lubricants have an
                            adverse effect on torque results.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual remove the vibration damper and
                            inspect the elastomer layer for cracks and misalignment. If no problem is found, reinstall
                            vibration damper following the exact assembly procedures found in the Engine Service Manual.
                            Verify that locating dowel at the end of the crankshaft is aligned with locating hole in the
                            balancer for proper installation.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Isolate the engine from transmission by removing the transmission, clutch and pressure
                            plate or torque converter. Start the engine and evaluate for roughness. If the engine runs
                            smooth, replace the torque converter or replace clutch and pressure plate.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the flywheel and verify
                            proper orientation. If orientation is correct, replace or rebalance flywheel. When
                            removing/installing the flywheel, ensure that the locating dowel is in the right place and
                            that the flywheel is located properly on the dowel.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Following the procedures in the Engine Service Manual, remove the lower and upper oil pan
                            and inspect the crankshaft counterweights to ensure balance holes exist.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_68.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_70.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
