<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - INTRODUCTION - Engine Description
        - Cooling System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Cooling System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f120in14" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg3/EG3507.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Engine Coolant Flow Diagram (1994 Model Year)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Thermostat</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Outlet Tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front Cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder Head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lube Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water Pump Inlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant Filter Header</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant Filter</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f120in30" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8042.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Engine Coolant Flow Diagram (1995 through 1997 Model Year)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Thermostat</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Outlet Tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front Cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder Head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lube Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water Pump Inlet</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The function of the cooling system is to keep the engine within a designated temperature range. Major
                components of most cooling systems include a radiator and fan combination with a water pump, thermostat,
                oil cooler, and coolant filter. The water pump is a belt-driven centrifugal type, which is set into the
                front cover.
            </para>
            <para>The front cover incorporates two separate passages. One passage channels coolant from the water pump
                to the crankcase. The other passage is a bypass that routes coolant back to the water pump when the
                thermostat is closed. For 1994 model year engines, the thermostat starts to open at 82&#176;C (179&#176;F)
                and is fully open at 100&#176;C (212&#176;F). For 1995-1997 model year engines, the thermostat starts to
                open at 89&#176;C (192&#176;F) and is fully open at 104&#176;C (219&#176;F).
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows from the bottom of the radiator into the inlet tube of the water pump, and into the
                front cover. Coolant is pushed by the impeller in the water pump, through an internal passage in the
                front cover, and out into the crankcase. Coolant flows through the crankcase, evenly distributed around
                the cylinders, then up through multiple passages into the cylinder heads.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <title>Coolant leaves the cylinder head in the following two ways:</title>
                <item>
                    <para>The coolant is directed, via an internal passage in the crankcase, to the oil cooler header.
                        Coolant flows through passages in the oil cooler and exists at the water pump, to be mixed with
                        incoming coolant from the radiator.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant exists from the cylinder head, flows through an internal passage in the crankcase, and
                        into the front cover. It is then directed to the water pump passage containing the thermostat.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostat Operation</title>
            <para>The thermostat incorporates two outlets that work independently to channel coolant to two different
                parts of the engine. One outlet carries coolant to the radiator, the other outlet directs coolant back
                to the water pump.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine coolant temperature is below the specified thermostat opening temperature, the outlet
                to the radiator is thermally blocked. This blockage forces coolant to flow through the bypass passage
                back into the water pump. As the engine approaches its normal operating temperature, the thermostat
                opens, closing off the bypass passage and allowing coolant to flow towards the radiator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
