<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System - Engine and Vehicle Sensors
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.4" graphiccount="9">
        <title>Engine and Vehicle Sensors</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f3050145" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Engine and vehicle sensors</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermistor Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050146" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Thermistor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Four thermistor type sensors used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>ECT</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EOT</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>MAT</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IAT</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A thermistor sensor changes its electrical resistance with changes in temperature. Resistance in the
                thermistor decreases as temperature increases, and increases as temperature decreases. Thermistors work
                with a resistor that limits current in the ECM to form a voltage signal matched with a temperature
                value.
            </para>
            <para>The top half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor inside the ECM. A thermistor
                sensor has two electrical connectors, signal return and ground. The output of a thermistor sensor is a
                nonlinear analog signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT)</title>The ECM monitors the ECT signal and uses this information
                for the instrument panel temperature gauge, coolant compensation, Engine Warning Protection System
                (EWPS), and glow plug operation. The ECT is a backup, if the EOT is out of range. The ECT sensor is
                installed in the left side of the front cover assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</title>The ECM monitors the EOT signal to control fuel quantity,
                inlet air heater operation, and timing during operation of the engine. The EOT signal allows the ECM and
                IDM to compensate for differences in oil viscosity for temperature changes. This ensures that power and
                torque are available for all operating conditions. The EOT sensor is installed in the oil filter base.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</title>The ECM monitors the MAT signal for EGR operation. The MAT
                sensor is installed in the left side of the intake manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the IAT signal to control timing and fuel rate during cold starts. The IAT sensor is
                mounted with the MAF sensor in the air flow between the inlet of the turbocharger and the air filter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hot Wire Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050147" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31055.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Hot wire sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>One hot wire type sensor used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>MAF</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Mass Air Flow (MAF)</title>The MAF sensor is mounted in the air flow between the inlet of the
                turbocharger and the air filter.
            </para>
            <figure id="f3050148" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31261.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>MAF/IAT sensor unit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The MAF sensor is an flow meter that operates on the principle of hot-film anemometry. A heated
                element is placed within the airflow stream, and maintained at a constant temperature differential above
                the air temperature. The amount of electrical power required to maintain the heated element at the
                proper temperature is a direct function of the mass flow rate of the air past the element.
            </para>
            <para>As the flow rate increases, more heat is transferred to the air, and the electrical power required to
                maintain the desired operating temperature increases. Conversely, a decrease in airflow results in a
                decrease in the power required to maintain the proper operating temperature.
            </para>
            <para>The power required to maintain constant temperature is converted to a digital signal.</para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the MAF signal to control EGR operation. The ECM also uses the MAF signal to control
                timing and fuel rate during cold starts and limits smoke emissions during normal operations.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Variable Capacitance Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050149" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Variable capacitance sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Two variable capacitance sensors used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>BAP</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>MAP</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Variable capacitance sensors measure pressure. The pressure measured is applied to a ceramic material.
                The pressure forces the ceramic material closer to a thin metal disk. This action changes the
                capacitance of the sensor.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal ground</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The sensor receives the V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                and returns an analog signal voltage to the ECM. The ECM compares the voltage with pre-programmed values
                to determine pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The operational range of a variable capacitance sensor is linked to the thickness of the ceramic disk.
                The thicker the ceramic disk the more pressure the sensor can measure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)</title>The ECM monitors the BAP signal to determine altitude,
                adjust timing, fuel quantity, glow plug, and air heater operation. The BAP sensor is in the cab.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</title>The ECM monitors the MAP signal to determine intake
                manifold pressure (boost). This information is used to control the Boost Control Solenoid (BCS). The MAP
                sensor is installed to the right of the intake air elbow in the intake manifold.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050150" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31034.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>MSG sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>One micro strain gauge type sensor used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A Micro Strain Gauge (MSG) sensor measures pressure. Pressure to be measured exerts force on a
                pressure vessel that stretches and compresses to change resistance of strain gauges bonded to the
                surface of the pressure vessel. Internal sensor electronics convert the changes in resistance to a
                ratiometric voltage output.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Signal ground</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The sensor is powered by V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                received from the ECM and is grounded through the ECM to a common sensor ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</title>The ECM monitors the ICP signal to determine the
                injection control pressure for engine operation. The ECM monitors the ICP signal to determine the
                injection control pressure for engine operation. The ICP signal is used to control the IPR valve. The
                ICP sensor provides feedback to the ECM for Closed Loop ICP control. The ICP sensor is installed through
                the right side valve cover in the oil rail.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Magnetic Pickup Sensor</title>
            <figure id="f3050151" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31035.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Magnetic pickup</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Two magnetic pickup type sensors used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>CKP</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CMP</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A magnetic pickup sensor generates an alternating frequency that indicates speed. Magnetic pickups
                have a two wire connection for signal and ground. This sensor has a permanent magnetic core surrounded
                by a wire coil. The signal frequency is generated by the rotation of gear teeth that disturb the
                magnetic field.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Crankshaft Position (CKP) sensor</title>The CKP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that
                indicates crankshaft speed and position. As the crankshaft turns the CKP sensor detects a 60 tooth
                timing disk on the crankshaft. Teeth 59 and 60 are missing. By comparing the CKP signal with the CMP
                signal, the ECM calculates engine rpm and timing requirements. The CKP is installed in the front right
                side of the lower crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Camshaft Position (CMP)</title>The CMP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that indicates
                camshaft position. As the cam rotates, the sensor identifies the position of the cam by locating a peg
                on the cam. The CMP is installed in the front left side of the lower crankcase.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Potentiometer</title>
            <figure id="f3050152" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31036.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Potentiometer</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>One potentiometer used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>APS</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A potentiometer is a variable voltage divider that senses the position of a mechanical component. A
                reference voltage is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical rotary or linear motion moves
                the wiper along the resistance material, changing voltage at each point along the resistive material.
                Voltage is proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</title>The APS provides the ECM with a feedback signal (linear
                analog voltage) that indicates the operator's demand for power. The APS is mounted in the accelerator
                pedal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Switch</title>
            <figure id="f3050153" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31037.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Switch</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Five switches used</title>
                <item>
                    <para>DDS (transmission select)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IVS</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>WIF</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EOP</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ECL</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Switches indicate position or condition. They operate open or closed, allowing or preventing the flow
                of current. A switch can be a voltage input switch or a grounding switch. A voltage input switch
                supplies the ECM with a voltage when it is closed. A grounding switch grounds the circuit when closed,
                causing a zero voltage signal. Grounding switches are usually installed in series with a current
                limiting resistor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</title>The Transmission Control Module (TCM) monitors the
                transmission shifter position. A signal from the TCM functions as the DDS signal to the ECM. A manual
                transmission application will have a clutch switch for the DDS signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>The IVS is a redundant switch that provides the ECM with a
                signal that verifies when the APS is in the idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Water In Fuel (WIF)</title>
                A WIF switch detects water in the fuel filter of the HFCM. When enough water accumulates in the filter
                housing, the WIF switch sends a signal to the ECM. The ECM sets a Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC) and
                illuminates the amber Water In Fuel lamp (fuel pump next to a fuel tank) on the right side of the
                instrument panel. The WIF switch is in the base unit of the HFCM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP) Switch</title>The ECM monitors the EOP signal for reference only. The
                ECM uses the EOP signal to control the instrument panel oil pressure gauge and for EWPS warning, lights
                the Warn Engine Lamp (WEL) for low oil pressure. The EOP switch closes a circuit to ground after the
                engine oil pressure reaches 34 to 48 kPa (5 to 7 psi). When the pressure is above 48 kPa (7 psi) the
                gauge reads normal. If the oil pressure drops below 41 kPa (6 psi) the gauge reads 0 kPa (0 psi). The
                EOP switch is in the oil filter base assembly.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</title>
            </para>
            <para>ECL is part of the Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS). The ECL switch is used in plastic
                deaeration tanks. When a magnetic switch is open, the tank is full.
            </para>
            <para>If engine coolant is low, the red Oil/Water Lamp (OWL) on the instrument panel is illuminated.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
