<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Air Compressor and Power Steering
        Pump - Description
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Description</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>The optional air compressor is gear driven from the lower idler gear located in the engine front
                cover.
            </para>
            <para>Lubrication oil for the air compressor is provided through a hose connected to the engine oil pressure
                sensor tee. Oil drains back to the crankcase through a hose on the bottom of the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>Filtered air for the air compressor is drawn through an air hose connected to the air cleaner
                assembly. Air is compressed and delivered to an air tank. When the air tank is full, excess compressed
                air is vented to the atmosphere.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant for the air compressor is supplied and returned through two hoses connected to the intake side
                of the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>The optional power steering pump assembly is mounted in one of two configurations:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Without an air compressor, the power steering pump is mounted on the front cover and driven by
                        the lower idler gear.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With an air compressor, the power steering pump is mounted to the air compressor. The
                        compressor is driven by the lower idler gear and torque is transferred to the power steering
                        pump through the compressor crankshaft.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For individual component service procedures other than removal and installation refer to the
                        International Service Information Solutions - ISIS&#174; web site and then select the
                        "Suppliers" link.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_213.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_215.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
