<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Injection Pressure Regulation System (IPR_SYS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Injection Pressure Regulation System (IPR_SYS)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503069" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1244.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Injection Control Pressure Regulation System</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Injection Control Pressure System consists of the low pressure oil lubrication system, passages in
                the front cover and reservoir, high pressure oil pump, high pressure oil line as well as the high
                pressure oil rail mounted on the side of the cylinder head. The injection control pressure system also
                includes the injectors (and their respective sealing O-rings), the IPR valve (injection pressure
                regulator) and the ICP (injection control pressure) sensor and associated wiring.
            </para>
            <para>The function of this system is to develop, maintain and control the high pressure injection control
                pressure to provide the force to actuate the injectors and provide fuel to the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The Diagnostic Trouble Codes associated with this system may indicate an electrical or electronic
                control system failure, but
                <emph type="bold">most likely will indicate a mechanical or hydraulic problem with the injection control
                    pressure system.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM constantly monitors the injection control pressure in the system to assure the control system
                is providing the proper control pressure at all times. If the oil pressure feedback provided by the ICP
                sensor does not meet the ECM's desired values, the ECM will set a Diagnostic Trouble Code, illuminate
                the amber ENGINE lamp and control the operation of the injection control system by calculating the
                correct oil pressure for all engine operating conditions until the system is diagnosed and repaired.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM also monitors the injection control pressure developed while cranking the engine. If pressure
                does not develop within the ECM's expected time limit, it will set an appropriate Diagnostic Trouble
                Code which will aid the technician in diagnosing the no start or hard start condition.
            </para>
            <para>The EST may be used by the technician to command the ECM to perform an engine running test on the
                Injection Control Pressure system. The ECM controls the pressure regulator in a programmed sequence to
                evaluate system performance. At the end of the test, the ECM will transmit the appropriate Diagnostic
                Trouble Code(s) if system performance is unsatisfactory.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Diagnostics</title>
            <para id="f175fc333">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 333</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 164, FMI 10</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure above/below Desired Level</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When code 333 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated and the odometer displays the message
                WARN ENG.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 333 may be set during normal engine operation through the continuous monitor
                function or during the Engine Running Standard Test. It indicates that the measured pressure does not
                match the pressure that the ECM expects. Code 333 will be set if the measured value is less than or
                greater than 362 psi (2.5 MPa) of desired injection control pressure for a period greater than 7
                seconds. When this code is active, the ECM will ignore feedback from the ICP sensor and control the IPR
                valve from programmed default values.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 333 is usually associated with poor engine performance. Symptoms include slow
                acceleration time, low power at full load and possible engine under run.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the
                Diagnostic Trouble Code flashes from the amber and red ENGINE lamps, see .
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Possible Causes:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Low oil level, contaminated or aerated engine oil.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trapped air in the ICP system (particularly after an injector or high pressure pump
                        replacement).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective or stuck injection pressure regulator.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent IPR valve wiring connection. Spread IPR harness terminals at valve, poorly
                        crimped terminals or pulled back pins.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Leaking injector O rings.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Problem with ICP sensor and/or sensor circuit, incorrect sensor, system biased high or low.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High pressure pump.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>See Diagnostic Trouble Code 333 Recommended Actions .</para>
            <table id="te17503023" frame="all">
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code 333 Recommended Actions</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="130.66*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="265.34*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Recommended Actions:</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Test</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Comments</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check repair history - (Determine if air entrapment could be caused by ICP system
                                    disassembly)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If system was disassembled assure vehicle is operated 15 to 20 miles after
                                    injection control system has been serviced
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and quality</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and for contamination and correct API classification</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check active and inactive Diagnostic Trouble Codes</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair any ICP sensor codes first</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform a Key-ON Engine-OFF Standard Test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test will verify IPR circuit continuity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform a Key-ON Engine-Running test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ICP step test will verify a gross ICP system failure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform Key On Engine Running Continuous Monitor Test (intermittent Diagnostic
                                    Trouble Code detection)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>When running the Key On Engine Running Continuous Monitor Test, pull / wiggle
                                    wires on ICP sensor and IPR valve as well as all pass through connectors. If
                                    Diagnostic Trouble Code is set or engine dies, inspect wires at point of connection,
                                    check codes.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform ICP Pressure test - Performance Diagnostic Form (Oil aeration)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Will verify if oil is aerated at high idle Step #9 on the Performance Form</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test high pressure (injection control pressure system) for leaks</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>See ICP Leakage tests in Section 2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para id="f175fc334">
                <emph type="bold">DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODE 334</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 164, FMI 7</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Unable to Reach Set Point - Poor Performance</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The purpose of Diagnostic Trouble Code 334 is to determine if a rapid increase in injection control
                pressure can be developed when commanded by the operator while the engine is running. Diagnostic Trouble
                Code 334 is an ICP system response time Diagnostic Trouble Code that compares measured injection control
                pressure to desired injection control pressure and looks for a large pressure difference, 1300 psi (9
                MPa) for a short period of time (3 seconds). Its primary function is to detect injection control
                pressure system Diagnostic Trouble Codes. When this code is active the ECM will ignore the ICP sensor
                and control IPR valve operation from programmed default values.
            </para>
            <para>An active 334 code is usually associated with poor engine performance conditions including slow
                acceleration times and lower power concerns.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Possible Causes:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Low oil level, contaminated or aerated engine oil.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trapped air in the ICP system particularly after an injector or high pressure pump
                        replacement.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective or stuck injection pressure regulator.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent IPR valve wiring connection. Spread IPR harness terminals at valve, poorly
                        crimped terminals or pulled back pins.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Leaking injector O rings.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Problem with ICP sensor and/or sensor circuit, incorrect sensor, system biased high or low.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>See Diagnostic Trouble Code 334 Recommended Actions .</para>
            <table id="te17503024" frame="all">
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code 334 Recommended Actions</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="130.16*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="265.84*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Recommended Actions:</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Test</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Comments</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check repair history - (Determine if air entrapment could be caused by ICP system
                                    disassembly)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If the ICP system was disassembled, assure vehicle is operated 15 to 20 miles
                                    after injection control system has been serviced
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and quality</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and for contamination and correct API classification</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check active and inactive diagnostic trouble codes</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair any ICP sensor codes first</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform a Key ON Engine OFF Standard Test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test will verify IPR valve circuit continuity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform a Key ON Engine Running test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ICP step test will verify a gross ICP system failure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform Key ON Engine Running Continuous Monitor test</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>When engine is running enable test, pull/wiggle wires on ICP sensor and IPR valve
                                    as well as all pass through connectors. If diagnostic trouble code is set or engine
                                    dies, inspect wires at point of connection, check codes.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform ICP Pressure test - Performance Diagnostic form (Oil aeration)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Will verify if oil is aerated at high idle Step #9 on the Performance form</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test high pressure (injection control pressure system) for leaks</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>See ICP Leakage Tests in Section 2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 331</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 164, FMI 0</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure (ICP) above Working System Range</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When code 331 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated and the odometer displays the message
                WARN ENG.
            </para>
            <para>The purpose of Diagnostic Trouble Code 331 is to detect when the injection control pressure is above
                its normal working range, 3675 psi (25 MPa). This code may indicate a mechanical injection control
                pressure system problem, wiring, or ICP sensor problem. When code 331 is active the ECM ignores the ICP
                sensor signal and uses estimated ICP values to operate the engine.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the engine still performs well when this code is set, the problem is more likely in the ICP
                        sensor circuit.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Possible Causes:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Contaminated or improper grade of engine oil</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective or stuck injection pressure regulator (IPR) valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Improperly matched parts (IPR valve, ICP sensor, high pressure pump, front cover)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Grounded IPR control wire</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Problems with ICP sensor or circuit causing signal to be biased high</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para id="f175fc335">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 335</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 164, FMI 1</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Unable to Build Pressure During Cranking</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The purpose of Diagnostic Trouble Code 335 is to determine if injection control pressure is being
                developed during engine cranking. It is an ICP system check and will be set after 8 to 10 seconds of
                engine cranking with less than 725 psi (5 MPa) of detected injection control pressure. The period of
                engine cranking time before Diagnostic Trouble Code 335 is set varies with engine temperature. Engine
                cranking speed must be greater than 130 rpm before Diagnostic Trouble Code detection can begin.
            </para>
            <para>An active code 335 is normally associated with a no start condition or lengthy starting period.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Possible Causes:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Lack of or insufficient quantity of engine oil in the crankcase</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air in the injection control pressure system, particularly after an injector or high pressure
                        pump replacement
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective or stuck injection pressure regulator.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Leaking injector O-rings</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose high pressure pump gear</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective high pressure pump</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>See Diagnostic Trouble Code 335 Recommended Actions .</para>
            <table id="te17503025" frame="all">
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code 335 Recommended Actions</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="130.05*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="265.95*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Recommended Actions:</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Test</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Comments</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Visual Inspection</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check to see if IPR regulator and ICP sensor wiring is connected. Check for oil
                                    leaks, and see if injection control system has recently been disassembled (air
                                    entrapment). Ensure that the vehicle is operated at least a minimum of 15 to 20
                                    miles if the symptom is hard starting with evidence of recent ICP system
                                    disassembly.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and pressure.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check oil level and for contamination, check for oil in the oil reservoir (remove
                                    EOT sensor, oil should flow out) , verify lube oil pressure during engine cranking.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check active and inactive diagnostic trouble codes.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair any ICP and CMP sensor codes first.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform a Key ON Engine OFF Standard Test.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test will verify IPR valve circuit continuity.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform Key ON Engine Running Continuous Monitor Test.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>When engine is running enable test, pull / wiggle wires on ICP sensor and IPR
                                    valve as well as all pass through connectors. If diagnostic trouble code is set or
                                    engine dies inspect wires at point of connection, check for codes.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform ICP Pressure test - No Hard/No Start Diagnostic form.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Will verify if oil is aerated at high idle Step #9 on the Performance form.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test high pressure (injection control pressure system) for leaks.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>See ICP Leakage tests in Section 2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_98.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_100.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
