<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Cleaning</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With valves installed to protect seats, use a scraper and wire brush to remove deposits and
                gasket material from valve heads and gasket surface. Do not damage gasket surface of cylinder head.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a suitable solvent to remove dirt, grease, and deposits from removed parts.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields to protect eyes. Limit
                    compressed air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi).
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all bolt holes, Make sure gasket surfaces, oil return, and coolant passages are clean.
                After rinsing thoroughly with hot water, dry with filtered compressed air. .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, new head bolts and a new cylinder head gasket must be used when
                    installing the cylinder head. Even if one bolt was removed, a new cylinder head gasket and new bolts
                    are required.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all bolts (except head bolts) with a suitable solvent and dry thoroughly. New head
                bolts must be installed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean crankcase threads.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Dirt in threads or damaged threads may cause binding, resulting in a false torque reading.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f2650451" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd06/d0648.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Figure 131. Bottoming tap</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a Bottoming Tap (metric) to clean each tapped hole in crankcase top deck. Remove debris
                with filtered compressed air.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, always replace head bolts when installing the cylinder head. Even if you
                    are removing only one bolt, it will be necessary to replace the cylinder head gasket and all
                    cylinder head bolts.
                </para>
                <para>Do not use antiseize compound, grease, or any other lubricant except clean engine oil. Other
                    lubricants have an adverse effect on torque results.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thoroughly clean each push rod using a suitable solvent. Dry using filtered compressed air
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_52.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352_54.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2352.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
