<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS DT 466 and
        DT 530 - PERFORMANCE DIAGNOSTICS - ICP Pressure Test
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="Proctype" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ICP Pressure Test</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="te17502028" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="100.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="1.23in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.01in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">12. ICP Pressure Test</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Monitor ICP pressure and engine rpm. Use EST data list or breakout tee and
                                    DMM. See figure
                                    <emph type="bold">G</emph>
                                    on back of form.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; See EGES-215 for specifications.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>PID</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low Idle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>psi/volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>High Idle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>psi/volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Full Load</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>psi/volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If ICP is low or unstable, disconnect ICP sensor and retest.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If problem is resolved, see ICP diagnostics.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If pressure is still low or unstable, replace IPR and retest.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if the high pressure lube oil system is providing sufficient hydraulic pressure to
                operate the injectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <para>Test should be performed at full load in conjunction with Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load) Test 11 , and
                Boost Pressure Test 13 .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Turn all accessories and the ignition off, before connecting Electronic Service Tool (EST)
                        tool to American Trucking Association (ATA) diagnostic connector.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EST to the ATA data link connector. See ATA Connector Location .</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para id="P1750207" count="1">Start Master Diagnostics and select the pre-configured session entitled
                    Road Performance. Drive vehicle on road until engine reaches operating temperature. Find an open
                    section of road and select a suitable gear. Depress the accelerator pedal (full depression) to the
                    floor and accelerate to rated speed and 100% load.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Drive the vehicle uphill or fully loaded to reach the correct engine load at rated engine
                            speed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read maximum pressure for ICP pressure and record on Electronic Control System
                    Diagnostic form EGED-220.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Stop the vehicle, read psi for low and high idle ICP pressures, and record on Electronic
                    Control System Diagnostic form EGED-220.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternate Method for Measuring ICP Using (Breakout Tee)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine harness connector from ICP sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect ICP Breakout Tee to the removed engine harness connector and the ICP sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a DMM in cab of vehicle and connect a long set of leads (+Green, -Black) to the
                    Breakout Tee utilizing the connection points as shown in Measuring Injection Control Pressure Using
                    Breakout Tee .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate vehicle under load as described in Test Procedure Step 2 .</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <para>Low voltage for injection control pressure indicates insufficient oil pressure to operate the fuel
                injectors (perform ICP Leakage Test). This may be caused by:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Defective IPR valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective High Pressure Pump</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure system leakage</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ECM commanding the IPR valve to reduce injection control pressure due to:</para>
                    <seqlist style="alphalc">
                        <item>
                            <para>Low Boost Pressure</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Incorrect signal from Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Incorrect signal from ICP sensor or wrong ICP sensor</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ICP Oil Aeration Test</emph>
            </para>
            <para>High-pressure oil supplies the mechanical force needed to push fuel into the cylinder for combustion.
                Aerated oil can retard the timing of fuel injection into the cylinder. When aerated oil is suspected,
                perform the following steps.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, be certain that the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is
                        applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to starting engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>ICP Oil Aeration Test</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and bring to normal operating temperature.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise engine speed to high idle. Note ICP value (ICP will rise when the engine goes to
                    high idle and then settle to a lower value within a few seconds. Record the lower value).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold engine speed at high idle for 2 minutes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Watch the ICP value during this time period. Compare with the initial value. If ICP
                    rises and continues to increase in value, the lube oil is being aerated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Possible causes of oil aeration include overfilled sump, cracked pickup tube, and missing or faulty
                pickup tube gasket.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Service Tool (EST) with Master Diagnostics software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DMM (ZTSE4357) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Breakout Tee (ZTSE4347) (optional)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supplemental Diagnostics</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If DTC's are set, see DTC column on Engine Diagnostic Trouble Codes .</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">See ICP diagnostics in Electronic Control System Diagnostics, Section 3</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Circuit Diagram Using a Breakout Tee</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Voltage Test</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Troubleshooting Flowchart</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ICP Sensor Circuit Specifications</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">See IPR diagnostics in Electronic Control System Diagnostics, Section 3</emph>:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator Circuit Diagrams</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator and Circuit Diagnostics</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_58.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_60.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
