<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - TOOLS - DWYER SLACK
        TUBE MANOMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DWYER SLACK TUBE MANOMETER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <figure id="f17505004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG7/EG7725.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Slack Tube Manometer, Dwyer No. 1211-48</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The manometer is a
                <emph type="bold">U</emph>
                shaped tube with a scale mounted between the legs of the U. When portability of the Model 200 Pressure
                Test Kit is not required, this manometer can be used to measure either low pressure or vacuum (intake
                restriction, crankcase pressure or exhaust back pressure) and must be filled with water.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Filling the Manometer</title>
            <para>Fill the manometer with only good drinking water without additives, except for some colored water
                vegetable dye that enables the tester to read the scale easier. With both legs of the manometer open to
                the atmosphere, fill the tube until the top of the fluid column is near the zero mark on the scale.
                Shake the tube to eliminate any air bubbles.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not use antifreeze solutions, soda pop, tonic, etc. to fill manometer. Increased density
                        will cause false readings.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installing and Reading the Manometer</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support the manometer vertically. Be sure the fluid level line is in line with the zero
                    indicator on the graduated scale.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect one leg of the manometer to the pressure source or vacuum. The Leave the other
                    leg open to atmospheric pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After starting the engine, allow the engine to reach normal operating temperature and
                    set the engine to
                    <emph type="bold">High Idle</emph>. After approximately
                    <emph type="bold">10 seconds</emph>
                    check the manometer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the average position of the fluid level when it is above and below the zero
                    indicator. Add the two figures. The sum equals the total column of fluid and represents the
                    crankcase pressure in inches of water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare manometer reading with engine specifications.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>At times both columns of the manometer will not travel the same distance. This is of no
                        concern to the tester as long as the leg not connected to the pressure or vacuum source is open
                        to the atmosphere.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cleaning</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash the tube thoroughly using a little pure soap and water. Avoid liquid soaps and
                    solvents.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_150.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_152.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
