<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Electronic Control Module Power Supply (ECM PWR)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Electronic Control Module Power Supply (ECM PWR)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Circuit Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503043" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1226.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Electronic Control Module Power Supply Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module requires a 12V source of power in order to perform its functions. It
                receives this operating power directly from the vehicle batteries via the ECM relay contacts each time
                the ignition key switch is turned to the ON position. Turning the ignition key switch ON causes the ECM
                to provide an internal ground to the coil side of the ECM relay. This causes the relay to close its
                contacts and provide the ECM with the power necessary to perform its various functions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The ECM internally monitors battery voltage. If the ECM continuously receives less than 6.5V or more
                than 18V a Diagnostic Trouble Code will be set. The Diagnostic Trouble Code will not cause the Warning
                lamp to be turned ON. If the condition is intermittent, the code will be logged as an inactive code. The
                ECM will not operate at voltages continuously below 6.5 or above 18V.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503044" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/EG9029.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>ECM Power Supply Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector always check for damaged pins, corrosion, and loose terminals.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Make sure batteries are fully charged and terminals are clean and tight.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503011" frame="all">
                <title>ECM PWR Circuit Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="55.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="48.40*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="292.60*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Key On Engine Off - Voltage Checks at ECM Power Relay Socket
                                        (check with ECM relay removed breakout tee installed, ignition key ON, engine
                                        OFF).
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>+Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage present at all times. If no voltage, check ground and power circuits from
                                    chassis connections.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage present at all times. If no voltage, check ground and power circuits to
                                    battery circuits.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 to 0.25V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No voltage expected.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>87 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No voltage present when relay is removed.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Continued on Next Page</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Key ON Engine OFF - Voltage Checks at ECM (check with breakout box
                                        installed, ECM power relay installed, and ignition key ON).
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>+Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>24 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power from ignition switch to ECM.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>21 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power from relay to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>22 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power from relay to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>41 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power from relay to ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>25 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.6 to 2V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ECM grounds relay through internal transistor. Expect 1.2V with Key ON.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>23 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>42 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ground - voltage reading indicates poor ground to battery.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Circuit Resistance Checks (check with breakout box installed, ECM
                                        power relay installed and ignition key OFF).
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>+Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1, 2, 23, 42 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance from ECM grounds to battery grounds.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>F11 to 25</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>60 - 120&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Measure resistance across relay coil - Remove fuse F11 to test.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to B+</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power from battery to relay (remove relay to test &#38; test at location 30 in
                                    relay socket).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>112 = Internal ECM voltage was detected above 18V.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>113 = Internal ECM voltage was detected below 6.5V.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>626 = ECM detected intermittent power loss through ECM relay.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>Refer to ECM Power and Ground System Circuit Diagram for the following discussion .</para>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) receives its power directly from the vehicle batteries when the
                ECM power relay is energized. This allows maximum power transfer from the batteries to the ECM with a
                minimum amount of power loss. The wire harness that supplies the ECM power is fused at the battery to
                protect it from short circuits.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is turned ON, ignition power from fuse in the Power Distribution Center (5 A) is
                supplied to Pin 24 of the ECM through the engine dash connector. This indicates to the ECM that the
                ignition switch is ON and it is time to enable the ECM power relay.
            </para>
            <para>Power to the ECM Power Relay control coil (terminal 85) is provided by circuit 97CT from the battery
                feed stud through the engine dash connector. The ECM will enable the ECM power relay by completing the
                ground circuit (internally) for the relay at ECM pin 25.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM Power Relay is enabled power at terminal 30 from the vehicle batteries is switched
                directly to the ECM from terminal 87 of the relay to pins 21, 22 and 41 of the ECM. The vehicle battery
                power for this relay to switch is supplied directly from the battery through connectors 4105, 6323,
                9261, and the ECM feed fuse.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Diagnostics</title>
            <para>If the ECM detects more than 18V at pins 21, 22 and 41 it will set Diagnostic Trouble Code 112. A
                voltage of less than 6.5V detected by the ECM will set Diagnostic Trouble Code 113. The ECM is capable
                of detecting an intermittent interruption of power or ground circuits. Diagnostic Trouble Code 626 will
                be set indicating an unexpected reset has occurred.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the
                Diagnostic Trouble Code flashes from the amber and red ENGINE lamps, see .
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc112">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 112</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 168, FMI 35</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM: Internal voltage power Out of Range HIGH</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 112 can be caused by:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Defective alternator causing an alternator output voltage in excess of 18V.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Additional voltage provided while attempting to jump start engine or improper external
                    battery connections that could cause the voltage increase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the condition causing code 112 is intermittent, the code will change from active to inactive
                status. Diagnostic Trouble Code 112 will
                <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                cause the amber ENGINE lamp to turn ON.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc113">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 113</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 168, FMI 36</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM: Internal voltage power Out of Range LOW</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 113 can be caused by consistently less than 6.5V being applied to ECM pins 21,
                22 and 41. This can be caused by a defective alternator, ECM power relay, discharged batteries, and/or
                increased resistance in the battery feed circuits. Diagnostic Trouble Code 113 will
                <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                turn the amber ENGINE lamp ON. If the condition causing Diagnostic Trouble Code 113 to set is an
                intermittent condition when the condition is no longer present, the code status will go from active to
                inactive.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc626">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 626</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 254, FMI 56</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM: Unexpected Reset Diagnostic Trouble Code</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Any time power is interrupted to the ECM due to intermittent power feed circuits caused by loose or
                dirty connections at the batteries or at ground cables, the ECM may "power down." When the power or
                ground circuit becomes intact again the ECM will "reboot" itself. This may cause erratic engine
                operation. Diagnostic Trouble Code 626 will be set anytime the flow of power is interrupted to the ECM.
                Turning the ignition key OFF and then ON again causes the code to change from active to inactive status.
                Diagnostic Trouble Code 626 will
                <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                cause the amber ENGINE lamp to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <para>If either Diagnostic Trouble Code 112 or 113 is active, see S08250 - Electrical Troubleshooting Guide
                - 4200/4300/4400. If Diagnostic Trouble Code 626 is active, the voltage at pins 21, 22 and 41 of the ECM
                should be monitored while looking for an intermittent connection in the power feed wiring. The EST may
                be used to indicate Diagnostic Trouble Codes to display the V
                <subscript>IGN</subscript>
                voltage that the ECM measures to Pin 24.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503045" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8804.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>ECM Power and Ground System Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_88.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_90.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
