<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS -
        Circuit Function And Diagnostics - Engine Coolant Level System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Engine Coolant Level System</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Function</title>
            <figure id="f17503039" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1224B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Engine Coolant Level system function</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The engine coolant level system monitors the level of coolant in the cooling system. The Electronic
                Control Module (ECM) can be programmed to shut down the engine to prevent engine damage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Coolant Level Sensors</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Magnetic Switch</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The magnetic switch sensor is used in plastic surge tanks. The magnetic switch is open when the
                coolant level in the tank is full.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Conductive Probe</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The conductive probe sensor is used in steel surge tanks. The conductive probe is grounded when the
                coolant level in the tank is full.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>There are no ECM diagnostics for the Engine Coolant Level system. Diagnostic Trouble Code 236 will be
                active when a low coolant situation is present and the Electronic Service Tool (EST) will indicate
                Engine Coolant Level Below Warning/Critical level. After the coolant has been restored to proper levels,
                Diagnostic Trouble Code 323 will remain as an inactive code and the ECM will log the engine hours of the
                occurrence.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503040" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1225B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Circuit Diagram for Engine Coolant Level Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te17503009" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="all">
                <title>Engine Coolant Level System Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="51.51*"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="52.52*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="291.98*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">All tests performed with coolant level full, (plastic or steel
                                        tank connector voltage checks)
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Coolant Level Sensor connector (400) removed and Ignition switch
                                        ON
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Open circuit 34B or defective ECM.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Circuit 34G shorted to another circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>(A) to (B)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Open ground circuit 34G, 11GJ or 11GS. Open in 34B</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Connector Resistance Checks (coolant level sensor connector (400)
                                        removed, measure across sensor)
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">PLASTIC TANK</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>(A) to (B)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>1000 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low coolant, defective sensor or shorted sensor harness.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">SteeL TANK</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>(A) to (B)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Low coolant, defective sensor or open sensor harness.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECM Chassis Connector (black) Voltage Checks (Check with breakout
                                        box installed, ignition switch ON, and sensor connected.)
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">PLASTIC TANK</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>10 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage should be >4.3V w/tank full. Voltage should be &#60;3.4V w/tank empty.
                                    (Use breakout box.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">SteeL TANK</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>10 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0V to &#177; 0.5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5 Volts indicates low coolant level or open in circuit 34B.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Reference</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>236 = ECM has detected an open or shorted circuit on the ECL circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>323 = The 12V circuit at pin 10 of the ECM has been pulled to ground indicating
                                    low coolant. Check cooling system.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The Engine Coolant Level sensor is used with the optional engine warning and protection feature. The
                Coolant Level system monitors coolant level in the surge tank to protect the engine from damage due to
                operating the engine when the coolant level is low. Since this is an optional feature, the system
                functions by programming three way warning or three way engine shutdown in the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>In either mode when the feature has been enabled and the engine is running, the ECM will cause the red
                Oil/Water warning light to illuminate and the warning buzzer to sound if the coolant level is below the
                level of the sender in the surge tank. If the system is programmed for engine shut down, the ECM will
                cause the engine to stop running after the coolant level has been depleted below the coolant level
                sensor and the preprogrammed warning time has expired. If the engine stops running in this condition, it
                can be restarted and run again for the warning time period, provided it is capable of restarting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Coolant Level Sensors</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Magnetic Switch</para>
            </step1>
            <para>The magnetic switch sensor is used in plastic surge tanks. The magnetic switch is open when the
                coolant level in the tank is full.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Conductive Probe</para>
            </step1>
            <para>The conductive probe sensor is used in steel surge tanks. The conductive probe is grounded when the
                coolant level in the tank is full.
            </para>
            <figure id="f175327" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG7/EG7292B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px" box="no"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Plastic Surge Tanks</title>
            <para>Plastic surge tanks use a floating ball with a magnet and magnetic switch. With the coolant level
                full, the float will raise and the magnet will pull the level switch open. This will allow for 5V to be
                present at pin 10 of the ECM. If the level should go low, the switch will close and pin 10 of the ECM
                would go to 0V. The ECM must be programmed for a plastic tank for this coolant level switch to operate
                properly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Steel Surge Tanks</title>
            <para>Steel surge tanks use a conductive probe that allows the probe to be grounded when the coolant level
                is full. This causes the voltage at pin 10 to be 0V. If the coolant level is low the probe circuit is
                open and a 5V signal is present at pin 10 of the ECM. If using a steel surge tank, it is necessary for
                the ECM to be programmed for a steel tank.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Programming</title>
            <para>Coolant level monitoring is a customer programmable feature that may be programmed by the Electronic
                Service Tool (EST) using the customer password. The coolant level feature is operational if programmed
                for three way warning or three way shutdown, however, if not preprogrammed for three way shut down at
                the factory it will not be possible to enable the shutdown feature. Contact Technical Services or your
                International&#174; dealer for programming this feature.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc236">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 236</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code PID 111 FMI 33</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Coolant Level Switch Circuit Diagnostic Trouble Code</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 236 will be
                <emph type="bold">active</emph>
                when the ECM detects an
                <emph type="bold">in-range</emph>
                voltage error in the Engine Coolant Level (ECL) circuit. This condition is usually caused by a high
                resistance connection or intermittent short to ground in the circuit.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc323">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 323</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code PID 111 FMI 33</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Coolant Below Warning/Critical Level</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 323 will be active when the coolant level is low, and the EST will show
                COOLANT LOW. When the coolant level is corrected, Diagnostic Trouble Code 323 will change to inactive
                and the ECM will log the engine hours and odometer reading.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the batteries are fully charged. If batteries are
                    not fully charged, voltage tests will give misleading readings. Check battery connections and
                    grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting a circuit, inspect connectors for pushed back, loose or damaged
                    (spread or bent) terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. Wires and connections must be free of
                    damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must
                    be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before troubleshooting, inspect suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections
                    free of damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <para>Use the EST to monitor the coolant level on the data list or to retrieve Diagnostic Trouble Codes from
                the Diagnostic Trouble Code list. Also prior engine events can be retrieved using the EST in the
                calibration data screen under the Event Log. This will display the total number of times the event has
                taken place, the engine hours, the odometer reading at which the last two events have taken place.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTES</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_106.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_108.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
