<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Introduction - Fuel System -
        Description
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Description</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The fuel system provides filtered fuel to the fuel injectors at a regulated pressure. The system also
                returns warm fuel to the fuel tank during normal engine operation.
            </para>
            <para>Since fuel temperature is dependent on engine temperature, fuel is not warm when the engine is cold.
            </para>
            <para>As fuel travels through the fuel system, it will be under negative pressure (vacuum), supply pump
                pressure and high-pressure (injection pressure).
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Negative Pressure (Vacuum)</title>
            <para>When the priming pump is pushed down, the check ball is seated on the fuel strainer. Releasing the
                priming pump unseats the check ball, draws fuel from the fuel tank to the inlet port of the fuel filter
                header and into the fuel strainer assembly. Fuel exits the strainer, flows through the internal passage
                of the fuel filter header, via a fuel line to the fuel supply pump.
            </para>
            <para>Once the engine has been primed, the fuel supply pump keeps the fuel supply header under pressure and
                the fuel supply line under negative pressure for a constant supply of fuel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Supply Pump Pressure</title>
            <para>The supply pump produces a regulated pressure of fuel. Fuel flows from the supply pump to the fuel
                filter header. Fuel then travels through an internal passage into the fuel filter. Fuel passes through
                the fuel filter, from the outside of the filter element to the filter header spud. Fuel then flows from
                the filter header through an external hose or line to the fuel supply manifold.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supply Manifold</title>
            <para>Fuel in the supply manifold is delivered to drilling in the cylinder head leading to the injector
                bores. The fuel is then pressurized by the injectors. Any excess fuel is piped from the rear of the
                supply manifold to the fuel tank.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</title>
            <figure id="f2100214" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8593.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>ICP System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Reservoir</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ICP Sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Supply Manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure Hose</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The system utilizes hydraulically actuated, electronically controlled injectors to deliver fuel to
                each cylinder. Engine oil is used as hydraulic fluid to actuate the injectors.
            </para>
            <para>Oil is drawn from the oil pan through the pickup tube by the engine oil pump. The engine oil pump is a
                gerotor type pump driven by the crankshaft. Oil is fed through passages in the front cover to the oil
                reservoir.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir makes available a constant supply of oil to a high-pressure hydraulic pump mounted to
                the front cover. The high-pressure pump is a gear driven swash plate pump. High-pressure oil is
                delivered by the high-pressure pump to the supply manifold and into oil passages machined into the
                cylinder head.
            </para>
            <para>When an injector is energized, a poppet valve is opened by an electronic solenoid mounted on the
                injector. Oil pressure is allowed to flow into the injector and act on the amplifier piston. When the
                solenoid is disengaged the oil pressure on top of the amplifier piston is vented by the poppet valve
                through the top portion of the injector.
            </para>
            <para>Pressure control in the Injection Control Pressure System is a closed loop system. It is controlled by
                the Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve, the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor and the
                strategy in the Electronic Control Module (ECM).
            </para>
            <para>ICP pressure ranges from 3.5 to 21 MPa (500 to 3000 psi). The regulator valve is mounted in the
                high-pressure pump and achieves injection control pressure regulation by dumping excess oil into the
                front cover and back to sump.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2100215" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6947.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Electronic Control Module (ECM) system (engine mounted)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel Injector</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">IPR</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">ICP Sensor</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>For engine mounted ECM systems , the ECM controls the IPR valve. Desired pressure control is a
                variable function of the engine control strategy and the calibration that has been programmed into the
                ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ICP sensor is mounted on the supply manifold and provides the feedback signal for the closed loop
                control system. The ICP sensor is a ceramic disk type pressure sensor that converts pressure into a 0 to
                5 volt analog signal that the ECM uses to determine ICP pressure.
            </para>
            <para>A spring and piston pop-off valve is installed internal to the high-pressure pump and is set to dump
                oil pressure into the front cover in the event ICP pressure exceeds 27.6 MPa (4000 psi).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
