<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Service Manual - Mounting Engine on Stand - Mounting Engine on Stand - Service Procedure
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s26501.1.1" svcproctype="mount" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Service Procedure</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main battery negative terminal
                    before disconnecting or connecting any electrical components. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="safety">"Safety Information</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, do not tug on any sensor wiring harnesses while trying to remove them.
                    If resistance is felt, find the source of resistance and free any connectors or clips that are
                    caught before proceeding.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death: Do not allow used engine fluids to stay on
                    your skin. Clean your skin and nails with soap and water, or a good hand cleaner. Wash or properly
                    throw away clothing or rags containing used engine fluids. Used engine fluids contain certain
                    elements that may be unhealthy for skin and could even cause cancer. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="safety">"Safety Information</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, make sure that the engine has cooled down
                    sufficiently before attempting to remove any components. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="safety">"Safety Information</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </warning>
            <note>
                <para>Engine fluids, oil, fuel, and coolant can be a threat to the environment. Never dispose of engine
                    fluids by putting them in the trash, pouring them on the ground, in the sewers, in streams, or
                    bodies of water.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Refer to the manufacturer's instructions (included with engine stand and engine stand bracket) for
                    specific directions on their safe use.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="e3000201" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ11/J11023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Removing the oil filter cap</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the starter if not done during engine removal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove oil filter cap from filter housing to allow oil to drain back into the oil pan. This
                must be done before removing the oil drain plug.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="e3000202" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ10/J10002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Removing the oil drain plug</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove oil pan drain plug and drain oil into a suitable container.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="e3000203" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd06/D0602.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Location of left side coolant drain plug</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust manifold</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant drain plug</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="e3000204" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ10/J10001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Location of right side coolant drain plug</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant drain plug</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust manifold</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain coolant from crankcase into a suitable container by removing the two coolant drain
                plugs. The coolant drain plugs are located at the rear of the crankcase on each side of the engine, just
                below the exhaust manifolds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After all fluids are drained from the engine, install drain plugs into crankcase and oil
                pan. Tighten oil pan drain plug tothe
                <hotlnk document="eges3001_33.xml" xrefid="E30002B">Special Torque</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="e3000205" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ10/J10003.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Disconnecting the CKP harness connector</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the CKP harness connector from the sensor on the right side of engine.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, attach the hoist hook lifting bracket to the
                    engine lifting eyes before lifting the engine. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="safety">"Safety Information</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach hoist to the engine lifting eyes. Use safety catches on the hoist hooks when lifting
                engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, use only grade 8 bolts when mounting engine to
                    stand. Other grade bolts may shear, allowing the engine to fall off the engine stand.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use the Engine Stand Mounting Bracket when mounting an engine to the stand. See
                    <hotlnk document="eges3001_34.xml" xrefid="E30002C">Special Service Tools</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="e3000206" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ10/J10004.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Torquing Engine Stand Mounting Bracket to engine</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="e3000207" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ10/J10005.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Engine stand mounting bracket</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine stand bracket grade 8 mounting bolts (4)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position engine stand mounting bracket on right side of engine. Secure bracket plate with
                four grade 8 mounting bolts and washers. Tighten four mounting bolts to the
                <hotlnk document="eges3001_311.xml" xrefid="S300GTG">Standard Torque</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount engine with mounting bracket on the engine stand using four grade 8 mounting bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten engine stand bolts to the
                <hotlnk document="eges3001_311.xml" xrefid="S300GTG">Standard Torque</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_S3000201.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
