<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Air Management
        System - Air Management Components
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="8">
        <title>Air Management Components</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Charge Air Cooler (CAC)</title>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figd15/D1530.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>CAC</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air outlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">CAC</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air inlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Radiator</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The chassis mounted CAC is mounted on top of the radiator. Air from the turbocharger passes through a
                network of heat exchanger tubes before entering the engine intake system. Outside air flowing over the
                heat exchanger tube fins cools the charge air. Cooling the charge air increases the density and improves
                the air to fuel ratio during combustion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System</title>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35171.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px" box="no"/>
                <caption>EGR system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust side EGR cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intake side EGR cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR coolant return tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR valve manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant crossover tube assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR metering tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR coolant supply tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust manifold</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para id="s0110">The EGR system includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust manifold</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR exhaust side cooler</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust gas crossover tube</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electrical control system</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR control valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR intake side cooler</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR mixer duct</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake manifold</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The EGR system reduces Nitrogen Oxide (NO
                <subscript>X</subscript>) engine emissions. NO
                <subscript>X</subscript>
                forms during a reaction between nitrogen and oxygen at high temperatures during combustion. Combustion
                starts when fuel is injected into the compressed combustion chamber.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EGR Flow</title>
            </para>
            <para>Metered exhaust gas from the exhaust manifold flows into the exhaust side EGR cooler. Cooled exhaust
                gas flows through the exhaust tube assembly to the EGR control valve.
            </para>
            <para>When the EGR is commanded, the EGR control valve opens and allows cooled exhaust gas to enter the
                intake side EGR cooler for further cooling. This exhaust gas is directed into the EGR mixer duct where
                it is mixed with filtered intake air.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EGR Control Valve</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35119.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px" box="no"/>
                <caption>EGR control valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The EGR valve consists of three major components, a valve, an actuator motor, and an Integrated
                Circuit (IC).
            </para>
            <para>The EGR valve is installed in the EGR valve manifold on the top front of the engine.</para>
            <para>The EGR valve uses a DC motor to control position of the valve assembly. The motor pushes directly on
                the valve stem to open. The valve is shut by a spring. The valve assembly has two poppet valves on a
                common shaft.
            </para>
            <para>The IC has three hall effect position sensors to monitor valve movement.</para>
            <para>
                <title>EGR Closed Loop System</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35120.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>EGR closed loop system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECM commands the EGR control valve position based on engine speed and load conditions. The EGR
                control valve provides feedback to the ECM on current valve position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35121.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>EGR control</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</title>
            <figure id="f3700001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk15/K15010.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="no"/>
                <caption>VGT components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">M10 nut (4)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbo mounting gasket</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Compressor outlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil supply port</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbine inlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil drain port</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VGT actuator</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Compressor inlet</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VGT actuator harness</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VGT actuator linkage</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">M6 serrated lock nut (4)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">E-clip</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbine outlet</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para id="s0111">The VGT responds to engine load. During heavy load, an increased flow of exhaust gases
                turns the turbine wheel faster. The increased speed turns the compressor impeller faster and supplies
                greater air quantity and boost pressure to the intake manifold. When engine load is light, the flow of
                exhaust gases decreases which causes reduction in air volume and boost pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The VGT has actuated vanes in the turbine housing. These vanes modify flow characteristics of the
                exhaust gases through the VGT to further control boost pressures for various engine speeds and load
                conditions.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VGT Closed Loop System</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>VGT closed loop system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The VGT is a closed loop system that uses the EBP sensor to provide feedback to the ECM. The EBP
                sensor continuously monitors exhaust system back pressure while the ECM adjusts VGT position to match
                engine requirements.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VGT Control</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35118.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>VGT control</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The VGT actuator is a control module located below the turbocharger. The internal microchip controls a
                DC motor which rotates a crank lever that adjusts vane position in the turbine housing. The position of
                the vanes is based on the VGT signal sent from the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>Moveable vanes are mounted around the inside circumference of the turbine housing. A unison ring links
                all the vanes together. When the unison ring moves, all vanes will move to the same position. Unison
                ring movement occurs when the crank lever in the VGT actuator moves.
            </para>
            <para>Exhaust gas flow can be regulated, depending on required exhaust system back-pressure, to match engine
                speed and load. As demand for exhaust system back-pressure increases, the ECM increases the VGT signal
                to the VGT actuator. When exhaust system back-pressure demand is reduced, the ECM decreases the VGT
                signal to the VGT actuator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Aftertreatment (AFT) System</title>
            <para>The AFT System, part of the larger exhaust system, processes engine exhaust to meet emissions
                requirements. The AFT system traps particulate matter (soot) and prevents it from leaving the tailpipe.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>AFT Control System</title>
            </para>
            <para>The control system performs the following functions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Monitors exhaust gases, the aftertreatment system, and controls engine operating parameters
                        for emission processing and failure recognition
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cancels regeneration in the event of catalyst or sensor failure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Monitors the level of soot accumulation in the Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) and adapts
                        engine operating characteristics to compensate for increased back pressure
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Controls engine operating parameters to make regeneration automatic.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maintains vehicle and engine performance during regeneration</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Sensors</title>
            </para>
            <para>Sensors produce an electronic signal based on temperature and pressure. It is used by the control
                system to regulate the aftertreatment function.
            </para>
            <para>The sensors measure the temperature and pressure at the center of the exhaust flow.</para>
            <para>
                <title>Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC)</title>
            </para>
            <para>The DOC does the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Oxidizes hydrocarbons and carbon monoxide (CO) in exhaust stream</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Provides heat for exhaust system warm-up</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Aids in system temperature management for the DPF</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oxidizes NO into NO2 for passive DPF regeneration</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF)</title>
            </para>
            <para>The DPF does the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Captures and temporarily stores carbon-based particulates in a filter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Allows for oxidation (regeneration) of stored particulates once loading gets to a particular
                        level (pressure drop)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Provides the required exhaust back pressure drop for engine performance</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Stores noncombustible ash</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>AFT Conditions and Responses</title>
            </para>
            <para>The operator is alerted audibly or with instrument panel indicators of system status. Automatic or
                manual regeneration is required when levels of soot exceed acceptable limits. For additional information
                see the applicable vehicle Operator's Manual and the vehicle visor placard.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
