<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Symptoms
        Diagnostics - Problems and Conditions - Smoke
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Smoke</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Two types of smoke conditions can occur, black and white. Dark-gray smoke is considered black smoke.
                Light-blue smoke is considered white smoke.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the following corresponding smoke condition for symptom, cause, and diagnostic procedure.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Black Smoke</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Cause</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Air intake or exhaust restriction</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turbocharger failure, turbocharger blade damage or turbocharger wheel stuck</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose or failed injector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Altitude (black smoke on hard acceleration or snap acceleration may be more pronounced at
                        higher elevations)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Failed Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Failed Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Failed Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Procedure</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine has fuel knock or there is evidence of fuel in the exhaust, remove exhaust
                    manifolds and inspect for fuel in the exhaust ports. (Suspect loose injectors, missing or damaged
                    O-ring and gasket on bottom of injector).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air inlet system and exhaust system for possible sources of restriction.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect turbocharger for oil leakage or failure of blades.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 7 (Intake Restriction) on Performance Diagnostics form or in Section 6 of this
                    manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 8 (Exhaust Restriction) on Performance Diagnostics form or in Section 6 of this
                    manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>White Smoke</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Cause</title>
                <item>
                    <para id="whitesmoke">Cold engine</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No Intake Air Heater (IAH) operation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor quality fuel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR stuck open on startup</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR cooler leaking coolant into exhaust</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose or failed injector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Bent connecting rods</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn piston rings</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low compression</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant leaking into the intake manifold through the cylinder head cup plugs</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant leaking into combustion chamber</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Aerated fuel</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Procedure</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">In cold ambient temperatures, some white smoke is normal until the engine is up to
                    operating temperature.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Ensure that engine is up to operating temperature 88 &#176;C (190 &#176;F) prior to
                            verifying a white smoke complaint.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the engine is unable to obtain operating temperature during a road test, verify
                            thermostat opening temperature 88 &#176;C (190 &#176;F).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 15 (Inlet Air Heater System) on Hard Start and No Start Diagnostics form to
                    verify inlet air heater operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 5 (Fuel) on Performance Diagnostics form. Verify quality and quantity of diesel
                    fuel. Poor quality fuel or low cetane rating can cause white smoking, engine misfire and low power.
                    SeeEngine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Fuel Requirements section for model and year of engine
                    to determine minimum necessary fuel grade and cetane rating.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 6 (Fuel Pressure and Aerated Fuel) on Performance Diagnostics form to verify
                    aerated fuel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 11 (Injector Disable) and Test 12 (Relative Compression) on Performance
                    Diagnostics form to identify failed injector or weak power cylinder.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 16 (Crankcase Pressure) to measure condition of power cylinders.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is coolant loss without engine overheating, check for coolant in exhaust.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant is leaking from exhaust or can be smelled in the exhaust, go to
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_69.xml" xrefid="s27004023">"Coolant Leak to Exhaust"</hotlnk>
                            in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine has fuel knock or evidence of fuel in exhaust, remove exhaust manifolds and
                    inspect for fuel in the exhaust ports. (Suspect loose injectors, missing or damaged O-ring and
                    copper gasket on bottom of injector).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air induction system for evidence of water ingestion or evidence of unfiltered
                    air entering the engine.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Water ingestion could have caused a hydraulic lock and bent connecting rods. If water
                            ingestion is suspected, identify smoking cylinders by removing exhaust manifolds and running
                            engine.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Unfiltered air entering the engine can cause excessive power cylinder wear and
                            turbocharger compressor blade damage. If power cylinder wear is suspected, identify smoking
                            cylinder(s) by removing exhaust manifolds and running engine.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant is found in the intake manifold, check cylinder head cup plugs and intake
                            manifold. Go to
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_69.xml" xrefid="s27004023">"Coolant Leak to Exhaust"</hotlnk>
                            in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine is overheating with coolant loss, and cylinder head gasket or injector sleeve
                    is suspected for leaking, go to
                    <hotlnk document="eges270_63.xml" xrefid="s27004027">"Combustion Leaks to Coolant"</hotlnk>
                    in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_75.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_77.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
