<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS DT 466 and
        DT 530 - DIAGNOSTIC FORMS - Introduction,
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="svcproc" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Introduction,</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two Types of Forms</title>
            <para>The purpose of engine diagnostic forms is to provide the customer with satisfaction as well as assist
                the technician in troubleshooting DT 466 and DT 530 diesel engines. Diagnostic forms provide a guide to
                finding problems quickly and easily and to avoid unnecessary repairs and expense. Diagnostic forms
                should be taken to the job and used to provide a systematic and time saving method of diagnosing engine
                problems.
            </para>
            <para>Engine diagnostic forms begin with the basics progressing to the tests that are more difficult. This
                leads the technician in a path of diagnosis to check the more common problems first and proceed to the
                less likely. The form should be followed in sequence, starting at test number one (1) and continuing
                through to the final test. The order of the tests should be followed because some components depend on
                the function of other components for proper operation. Performing the tests out of order could cause an
                incorrect conclusion.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Two diagnostic forms are required to properly diagnose the DT 466 and DT 530 diesel
                    engines.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Hard Start / No Start and Performance Engine Diagnostics, EGED-220</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The left front side of form EGED-220 is used to diagnose hard start or no start conditions.
                        Hard Start/No Start and Performance Engine Diagnostics, guides the technician through Hard Start
                        or No Start conditions in which the engine does not start or is difficult to start. The
                        Procedures must be done in sequence; performing the tests out of order could cause incorrect
                        results. See Section 2, Hard Start / No Start and Performance Engine Diagnostics for detailed
                        instructions.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The right front side of form EGED-220 is used to diagnose engine performance concerns while
                        the engine is running. The Performance Engine Diagnostics portion guides the technician through
                        conditions in which the engine is running with some type of performance problem. An example
                        would be a low power complaint. The tests must be done in sequence; Performing the tests out of
                        order could cause incorrect results. See figures on the rear side of the form for part location,
                        test and hookup points. See Section 2, Performance Engine Diagnostics for detailed instructions.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The reverse side of the form is a series of illustrations. They show the location of test
                        points and how to hook up test equipment at each test point described on the front side of the
                        form (when applicable) .
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Electronic Control System Diagnostics, EGED-225</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The front side of this form EGED-225 contains two tables and an engine electrical diagram.
                        They cover Signal Values associated with each of the ECM pin connections for the engine, and
                        chassis components of the vehicle. The electrical diagram covers the engine mounted components,
                        ECM pin connections and related wire numbering .
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The rear side of the form contains an electrical diagram covering all the electronic chassis
                        mounted components, ECM pin connections and related wire numbering .
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Information relating to this form is discussed and located in Section 3.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Information</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>BEFORE ATTEMPTING TO PERFORM ANY OF THE DIAGNOSTIC PROCEDURES, IT IS IMPORTANT TO FILL IN THE
                        INFORMATION REQUESTED AT THE TOP OF THE DIAGNOSTIC FORM(S). PROPER INFORMATION IS REQUIRED.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The DATE, MILES and HOURS are important information for warranty purposes.</para>
            <para>The ENGINE SERIAL NUMBER AND VEHICLE IDENTIFICATION NUMBER (VIN) are important information for
                ordering parts and referencing service information. The ENGINE SERIAL NUMBER is located on a machined
                pad next to the rear of fuel filter on left side of engine block. The VIN is located on the driver's
                side door jamb.
            </para>
            <para>The ENGINE HORSEPOWER / EMISSIONS INFORMATION and ENGINE FAMILY RATING CODE (EFRC) is important
                information to determine if the engine is the correct horsepower for the application and if the ECM is
                calibrated to the correct horsepower and emissions level. The ENGINE HORSEPOWER/EMISSIONS INFORMATION is
                located on the emission label located on the intake manifold/valve cover. The ENGINE FAMILY RATING CODE
                can only be accessed with the EST (Electronic Service Tool).
            </para>
            <para>The TECHNICIAN and UNIT number is useful information for reference only .</para>
            <table id="te1750201">
                <title>Table 1 Diagnostic Form Required Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="7" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="12.13*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="14.22*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="12.46*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="16.87*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="17.75*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col6" colwidth="4.19*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col7" colwidth="22.38*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col6" nameend="col7" spanname="6to7"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col3" spanname="2to3"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col5" nameend="col7" spanname="5to7"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col4" nameend="col5" spanname="4to5"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Date:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Miles:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Hours:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="justify">
                                <para>Technician:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injector P/N:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="6to7">
                                <para>Turbocharger P/N:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Eng. Sn.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="2to3">
                                <para>VIN:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Unit #</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="5to7">
                                <para>Engine Family Rating Code:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Eng. HP:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="2to3">
                                <para>Ambient Temp.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="4to5">
                                <para>Coolant Temp:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="6to7">
                                <para>Complaint:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Instructions for Engine Diagnostic Forms</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Information obtained during Hard Start / No Start or Performance Diagnosis should be recorded
                        in the appropriate box of the Hard Start / No Start or Performance Diagnostic form . If there
                        are any differences between the "Specification" box and the recorded data, correct as necessary
                        and repeat the checks. Retain this information for future operating analysis.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Diagnostic form EGED-220 is available in 50 sheet pads from:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation</line>
                <line>Printing, Procurement and Distribution</line>
                <line>4956 Wayne Road</line>
                <line>Battle Creek, Michigan 49015</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>The following pages have supporting information and instructions for the combined Mechanical
                Diagnostic form EGED-220.
            </para>
            <table id="te1750202">
                <title>Table 2 Mechanical Diagnostic Form Sample from EGED-220</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">9. EST Data List</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Do Tests 10,11 and 12 if EST is not available</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; Monitor DATA for 20 seconds or more while cranking</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>PID</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Actual</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Battery Voltage</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7 Volts min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Engine rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>130 rpm min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ICP Pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>500 psi min.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If voltage is low, see ECM diagnostics</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If no rpm is noted, check DTC's</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>&#8226; If ICP pressure is low, do Test 13</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para></para>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="f1750202" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8755C.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Hard Start / No Start Engine Diagnostics form EGED-220 Front Side</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1750202.1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/EG9003A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Hard Start / No Start Engine Diagnostics form EGED-220 Rear Side</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
