<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="Sec-7-175-1" svcsectype="enginesec" division="engine" date="10-02">
        <title>GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Actuator-</emph>
                A device that performs work in response to an input signal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog -</emph>
                A continuously variable voltage.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog to Digital Converter (A/D) -</emph>
                A circuit in the processing section of the ECM that takes an analog signal (either DC or AC) and
                converts it into a usable digital signal for the microprocessor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analog Multimeter -</emph>A meter that uses a needle to point to a number on a scale
                of numbers to indicate a measured value (volts, ohms, amperes). Not recommended for use on
                microprocessor systems because of the possibility of excessive current due to the low impedance of the
                meter.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">APS, Accelerator Position Sensor -</emph>
                A potentiometer sensor that indicates the throttle pedal position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Data Link -</emph>
                A serial data link specified by the American Trucking Association and the SAE.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Background Manager -</emph>The portion of the computer that performs "housekeeping
                duties." The Background Manager typically controls low priority items or items that occur at a slower
                rate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">BAP, Barometric Absolute Pressure -</emph>
                A variable capacitance sensor that, when supplied with a 5 volt reference signal from the ECM, produces
                a linear analog voltage signal indicating atmospheric pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">BNO, Brake Normally Open -</emph>
                An on/off switch style sensor used to indicate if the brake is applied. Normal primary function is to
                disengage cruise control (normally open).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Calibration -</emph>
                The data values used by the strategy to solve equations and make decisions. Calibration values are
                stored in the ROM. Calibration values are put into the processor during programming to allow the engine
                to operate within certain parameters.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CLS, Coolant Level Switch -</emph>
                A switch sensor used to indicate coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CMP, Camshaft Position Sensor -</emph>
                A Hall effect sensor used to indicate engine speed and camshaft position. Speed is indicated by the rate
                vanes pass the sensor. Camshaft position is indicated by a single narrow vane that indicates No. 1
                cylinder position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Continuous Test -</emph>
                A function of the ECM in which the inputs and outputs of the ECM are continuously monitored to assure
                that the readings are within set limits.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DDS, Driveline Disengagement Switch -</emph>
                A switch indicating when the driveline is disengaged from the engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Disable -</emph>
                A computer decision which results in a system being deactivated and not allowed to operate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Driver -</emph>
                A transistor in the output section of the ECM used to turn on or off various actuators in the system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Drive Train Data Link J1939 -</emph>
                Drive Train Data Link J1939 is the primary communication link for the ECM, ESC, and the instrument
                cluster.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DTC, Diagnostic Trouble Code -</emph>
                formerly referred to as Fault Code or Flash Code. The DTC is a 3 digit numeric code.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Duty Cycle Signal -</emph>
                A control signal that has a controlled on/off time measured from 0% to 100%. Normally used to control
                solenoids.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DMM, Digital Multimeter-</emph>
                An Electronic meter that uses a digital display to indicate a measured value (Volts, Ohms, and Amperes).
                They are preferred for use on microprocessor systems, because a DMM has a very high internal impedance
                and will not load the circuit being measured.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECI, Engine Crank Inhibit -</emph>
                An output of the ECM that controls the ECI relay and controls when the starter motor is allowed to
                operate and crank the engine over.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM, Electronic Control Module -</emph>
                The housing that contains the micro computer, V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                regulator, input conditioners and output drivers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM Power Relay -</emph>An ECM controlled relay that supplies or removes power to the
                ECM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECT, Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor -</emph>
                A thermistor type sensor that indicates engine coolant temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EFRC, Engine Family Rating Code -</emph>
                A code readable in the calibration list of the electronic service tool (EST) that identifies the
                horsepower and emission calibration of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Off Tests -</emph>Tests that are performed with the ignition switch ON and the
                engine OFF. See KOEO (Key ON Engine OFF)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Running Tests -</emph>Tests that are performed with the engine running. See
                KOER (Key ON Engine RUNNING)
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP, Engine Oil Pressure Sensor -</emph>
                A variable capacitance sensor used to indicate oil pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOT, Engine Oil Temperature Sensor-</emph>
                A thermistor sensor that senses engine oil temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EST, Electronic Service Tool -</emph>A computer diagnostic and programming tool for
                the ECM and ESC. The hardware is typically a laptop or notebook computer. The diagnostic and programming
                software consists of the International Master Diagnostics program, ISIS on-line documentation, and NETS
                for factory programming.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EWL-</emph>
                Engine Warning Light Circuit
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EWPS -</emph>Engine Warning and Protection
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FMEM, Failure Modes Effects Management-</emph>An alternate control strategy devised to
                reduce the adverse effects that can be caused by system failure. Should a sensor fail, the ECM
                substitutes a good sensor signal or assumed sensor value in its place. The ENGINE WARN Lamp is then lit
                to alert the driver to take the vehicle in for service.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Foreground Manager -</emph>
                The portion of the computer that manages the primary engine control functions. The foreground manager
                responds to external events quickly to maintain correct engine performance under a variety of
                conditions. The foreground manager typically controls high priority items.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Hall Effect Sensor -</emph>
                A Hall Effect sensor generates a digital on/off signal that indicates speed or timing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">HEUI - Hydraulically actuated Electronically controlled Unit Injector -</emph>
                The electronically controlled high pressure fuel injector used in INTERNATIONAL&#8482; diesel engines.
                This injector uses high pressure oil acting on an amplifier piston to achieve fuel injection pressures
                of up to 21,000 psi.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High Speed Digital Inputs -</emph>
                Inputs to the ECM that are from a sensor that generates varying frequencies. Examples of high speed
                digital input sensors are engine speed and vehicle speed sensors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IAT, Intake Air Temperature Sensor -</emph>A thermistor sensor used to indicate intake
                air temperature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ICP, Injector Control Pressure Sensor -</emph>
                A variable capacitance sensor used to indicate Injection Control Pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Impedance -</emph>
                A form of opposition to AC current flow measured in Ohms (&#x2126;).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure -</emph>
                High pressure lube oil generated by a high pressure pump/pressure regulator used to hydraulically
                actuate the fuel injectors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Input Conditioner -</emph>
                A device or circuit that conditions or prepares an input signal for use by the microprocessor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IPR, Injection Control Pressure Regulator -</emph>An ECM controlled pulse width
                modulated regulator valve that regulates injection control oil pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IVS, Idle Validation Switch -</emph>An on/off switch sensor that indicates when the
                accelerator pedal is in the idle/ off idle position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KOEO</emph>- Key ON Engine OFF
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KOER</emph>- Key ON Engine RUNNING
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low Speed Digital Inputs -</emph>
                Switched sensor inputs that generate an on/off (high/low) signal to the ECM. The input supplied to the
                ECM from the sensor could be from a high input source switch (usually 12 or 5 volts) or could be from a
                grounding type switch that grounds the signal from a current limiting resistor inside the ECM, creating
                a low signal (0 volts).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">MAP, Manifold Absolute Pressure -</emph>
                A MAP sensor is a variable capacitance sensor used to indicate intake manifold pressure (boost).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Microprocessor-</emph>
                An integrated circuit in a microcomputer that controls information flow in that computer.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normally Closed -</emph>Refers to a switch that remains closed when no control force
                is acting on it.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normally Open -</emph>Refers to a switch that remains open when no control force is
                acting on it.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">On Demand Test -</emph>
                A self test that the technician initiates, and is run from a program in the processor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OCC, Output Circuit Check -</emph>An "On Demand" test performed during an "Engine Off"
                self test that tests the continuity of selected actuators.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Output State Check -</emph>An "On Demand" test selected by the technician that forces
                the processor to activate actuators "High or Low" for additional diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OWL -</emph>Oil/Water Light and Alarm
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PID -</emph>Parameter Identifier
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Potentiometer -</emph>
                An electro-mechanical device (variable voltage divider) that senses the position of a mechanical
                component. Mechanical motion connected to the wiper causes it to move along the resistance material in a
                rotary fashion. The voltage on the wiper changes at each point along the resistive material and is
                proportional to the amount of mechanical movement. Potentiometers have three connections; V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>, signal out (wiper), and ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PROM -</emph>Programmable Read Only Memory
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO, Power Takeoff -</emph>
                Accessory output, usually from the transmission that is used to power a hydraulic pump for garbage
                packing, lift equipment, etc.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Pulse Width -</emph>
                The length of time an actuator, such as an injector remains energized.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RAM, Random Access Memory -</emph>A memory used to store information. Information can
                be written to and read from the RAM. Input information such as current engine speed or temperature would
                be stored here to be compared to values stored in the ROM. All memory in the RAM is lost when the
                ignition switch is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Read -</emph>
                A computer operation where information is retrieved from the memory.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">RFI -</emph>
                Radio Frequency Interference
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ROM, Read Only Memory -</emph>
                A memory used to store information permanently. Information cannot be written to the ROM memory.
                Operating strategies and calibration tables are the type of information most commonly stored in the ROM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SCCS, Speed Control Command Switches -</emph>
                A set of switches used for cruise control, PTO and the remote hand throttle system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SID -Sub-System Identifier</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SIG GRD, Signal Ground -</emph>The common ground wire to the ECM for the sensors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Strategy -</emph>
                A plan or set of operating instructions that the microprocessor follows in order to achieve a desired
                goal. Strategy is the computer program itself, including all equations and decision making logic.
                Strategy is always stored in the ROM and thus cannot be changed during calibration.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Switch Sensors -</emph>Switch sensors indicate position, level or pressure. The signal
                of a switch sensor is a digital signal created by either opening or closing a switch. The on or off
                signal can indicate position as in the case of a clutch switch, level as in the case of a coolant level
                switch, or pressure as in the case of a oil pressure switch. A switch sensor normally has two
                connectors; signal return (grd), and the signal. A switch sensor is considered a low speed digital
                signal input.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TAC, Tachometer Output Signal -</emph>Engine speed signal used for remote tachometers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Thermistor -</emph>Sensor used to determine temperature. A thermistor changes its
                resistance value in relation to temperature. Increasing temperature results in decreasing resistance,
                decreasing temperature results in increasing resistance. The thermistor in conjunction with a current
                limiting resistor in the ECM forms a voltage divider that provides a voltage signal that indicates
                temperature. Since the top half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor and is inside
                the ECM, a thermistor sensor only has two connections: signal return, and ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Transition -</emph>Changing from one value or condition to another, such as from
                positive to negative in an electronic circuit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TTS -</emph>Transmission Tailshaft Speed
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VEPS, Vehicle Electronic Programming System -</emph>
                The computer system used to program electronically controlled vehicles.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">V
                    <subscript>IGN</subscript>, Voltage Ignition -
                </emph>
                Voltage supplied by the ignition switch when the key is in the "ON" position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VRE, Vehicle Retarder Enable -</emph>Output from the ECM to control a vehicle
                retarder.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>, Reference Voltage -
                </emph>
                A five volt reference supplied by the ECM to operate sensors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">V
                    <subscript>BAT</subscript>
                    -
                </emph>
                Battery voltage
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">VSS, Vehicle Speed Sensor -</emph>Normally a magnetic pickup style sensor that is
                mounted in the tailshaft housing of the transmission to indicate ground speed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WARN ENGINE Lamp</emph>
                <emph type="bold">-</emph>Lamp in the dash that comes on when selected Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)
                are set or when the ECM is utilizing FMEM strategy. Fault codes in some vehicles can be read as flash
                codes through the WARN ENGINE Lamp. To access the flash codes, the switch STI (Self Test Input "Engine
                Diagnostics" switch) is depressed and held momentarily while the ignition switch is placed in the "ON"
                position. This will cause the WARN ENGINE lamp to flash any fault codes which were stored while
                operating the vehicle
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WTEC-</emph>
                World Transmission, electronically controlled automatic transmissions (Allison).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_198.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_200.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
