<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS -
        Circuit Function And Diagnostics - Engine Crank Inhibit System (ECI)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Engine Crank Inhibit System (ECI)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Function</title>
            <figure id="f17503036" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1222.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for Engine Crank Inhibit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit function of the ECM controls cranking motor operation. The ECM prevents the
                cranking motor from being engaged when the engine is running. The transmission neutral safety switch or
                clutch switch will prevent the cranking motor from being engaged when the transmission is in gear or
                when the clutch pedal is not depressed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>The ECM prevents the engine from being cranked if the engine is running, by not enabeling the Engine
                Crank Inhibit relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Crank Inhibit Relay</title>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit relay controls the start relay. The Crank Inhibit relay receives signals from
                the ignition switch and ECM to close the relay. Current to the relay is supplied from the neutral safety
                switch on an automatic transmission or clutch pedal switch on a manual transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Start Relay</title>
            <para>The start relay sends battery voltage to the crank motor solenoid when the crank inhibit relay is
                energized. The start relay is protected and controlled by an overcrank thermocouple, if equipped.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Switch</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with manual transmissions, the clutch switch supplies power to the Engine Crank
                Inhibit (ECI) relay and provides a signal to the ECM that indicates the driveline is disengaged. For
                vehicles programmed for manual transmissions, a 0V signal on the DDS circuit indicates that the clutch
                is disengaged (clutch pedal down). A 12V signal indicates that the clutch is engaged (clutch pedal up).
                When the clutch pedal is up no power is available to the ECI relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Neutral Switch</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with mechanical automatic transmissions (Allison AT/MT), the neutral position
                switch is used to supply power to the ECI relay and provides a signal to the ECM that indicates the
                driveline is disengaged. For vehicles programmed for Allison AT/MT transmissions, a 12V signal on the
                DDS circuit indicates that the transmission is out of gear. A 0V signal indicates that the transmission
                is in gear. When the transmission is in gear no power is available to the ECI relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WTEC VIM Relay</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with the Allison MD World Transmission Electronically Controlled transmission
                (WTEC), the transmission controller provides a signal to a relay in the VIM module to supply power to
                the ECI relay and a signal to the ECM to indicate that the driveline is disengaged. For vehicles
                programmed for Allison MD transmissions, a 12V signal on the DDS circuit indicates that the transmission
                is out of gear. An 0V signal indicates that the transmission is in gear. When the transmission is in
                gear no power is available to the ECI relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The ECM does not monitor cranking system circuits. Diagnostic Trouble Codes are not used for this
                system.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503037" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1223A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Circuit Diagram for Engine Crank Inhibit</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before testing Engine Crank Inhibit or cranking circuits, check battery for full charge. Check
                        battery connections at the battery, frame, and starter. See CTS 5000 for battery and starter
                        test procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503008" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="all">
                <title>Engine Crank Inhibit System Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="43.45*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="36.73*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="315.82*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Start Relay Voltage and Resistance Checks - With Starter Relay
                                        Removed
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check with relay unplugged and starter switch (key or button) engaged. If no
                                    voltage is present, troubleshoot clutch or trans switch. ECI circuit or ignition
                                    crank circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>An open to ground will cause the relay not to energize (check thermal overcrank
                                    switch, if equipped).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Crank Circuit Test</emph>
                                    - With the trans out of gear and the clutch depressed with wheels safely blocked,
                                    momentarily insert a jumper wire between socket pins No.30 and No.87 of the Start
                                    Relay.
                                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: If the cranking circuit is functional, the starter will
                                        energize.
                                    </emph>
                                    If the engine cranks and voltage is present at 86 and ground at 85 the relay is bad.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Relay Voltage and Resistance Checks - With ECI Relay
                                        Removed.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check with relay unplugged &#38; starter switch (key or button) engaged. If no
                                    voltage present, troubleshoot ignition crank circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If no voltage is present when clutch is depressed or auto. transmission in
                                    neutral, troubleshoot clutch switch or neutral safety switch circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4V to 5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ECM will pull circuit up to 4V to 5V with key ON and will go to 0V when the clutch
                                    is depressed or transmission is in neutral.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Circuit Test</emph>- With the trans out of gear and the clutch
                                    depressed with wheels safely blocked, insert a jumper wire between socket pins No.85
                                    and No.87 of the ECI Relay. If the engine cranks, when the start switch is engaged
                                    either the ECI relay is bad or there is a problem with the ECM or ECM wiring
                                    harness.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>Contiued on next page</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECM Chassis (Black) Circuit Checks - Check with All Relays
                                        Installed and Breakout Box Connected.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>DDS (+26) to (-23)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0V or 12V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Manual Trans</emph>
                                    - 0V with clutch pedal down, 12V clutch pedal up
                                    <emph type="bold">Automatic Trans</emph>
                                    - 12V with trans in neutral, 0V trans in gear.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI</emph>
                                    +46 to -23
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">At crank w/clutch up or auto trans in gear</emph>, if 12V present
                                    ckt good cranking inhibited.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0V to 0.6V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">At crank w/clutch down or auto trans in neutral,</emph>
                                    if ECM pin No.26 is at 12V and pin No.46 is not at 0V to 0.6V, check ECM
                                    programming. Cranking allowed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>4V to 5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pull up voltage from ECM with /key ON,
                                    <emph type="bold">engine OFF or running</emph>: trans in gear or clutch up.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The engine starting system is controlled by the Electronic Control Module (ECM). The ECM also prevents
                cranking motor operation, while the engine is running, that could cause damage to the starter pinion and
                ring gear.
            </para>
            <para>A clutch switch or transmission neutral switch is in series with the Engine Crank Inhibit relay. Both
                switches prevent the cranking motor from being engaged unless the transmission is in neutral or the
                clutch is disengaged.
            </para>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit system includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Ignition switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Push button start switch (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine crank inhibit relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crank motor and solenoid</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Batteries and cables</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Neutral safety switch (with AT/MT automatic transmission)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch switch (with manual transmission)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VIM relay module (with MD automatic transmission)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Operation</title>
            <para>See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f17503038">Cranking System Circuit Diagram
                    <xref refid="f17503038"/>
                </hotlnk>
                for the following description.
            </para>
            <para>When the ignition is turned on and the push button start switch is depressed, current flows to the
                Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) relay. The relay is enabled when the ECM supplies the ground circuit.
            </para>
            <para>Closing this relay allows current to pass from the ignition switch through fuse F17 through the
                neutral safety switch (jumped if manual trans), and through the clutch switch normally closed (jumped if
                auto trans). With the relay closed current then passes through the relay and will energize the start
                relay. The ground circuit for the start relay is through the overcrank protection fuse in the crank
                motor or directly to ground if not equipped with overcrank protection. When the relay is closed the
                current can pass from the crank motor battery terminal through the relay and to the crank motor
                solenoid, start terminal. This closes the crank solenoid to engage the starter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>When the ECM recognizes that the engine is not running, the ECM will ground terminal 46 providing DDS
                status is correct. This provides the current path for the Engine Crank Inhibit Relay to close when the
                Start switch is engaged or the starter button is depressed. When the ECM recognizes that the engine is
                running the ECM will open terminal 46. This will prevent the Engine Crank Inhibit relay from closing
                thus preventing the starter motor from engaging.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Crank Inhibit Relay (ECI)</title>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit relay controls the current to the start relay. Turning the ignition key to
                the START, supplies current to the relay at terminal 85. If the engine is not running ECM terminal 46
                will enable the relay by supplying a ground circuit to terminal 86. Current for the start relay is
                supplied through the neutral safety switch if the transmission is in neutral with an automatic
                transmission to terminal 30. Or if the truck is equipped with a manual transmission, current will be
                supplied to the relay through the clutch switch if the clutch pedal is depressed. With the relay closed
                current can pass through the relay to terminal 86 to power the start relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Start Relay</title>
            <para>The start relay switches battery power to the crank motor solenoid when the crank inhibit relay is
                energized. When the engine crank inhibit relay is closed, current is supplied to the start relay
                terminal to energize the relay. The start relay control is grounded through the starter thermal
                overcrank protection thermocouple if equipped. Or if not, the relay is grounded directly to the ground
                stud on the starter. With the start relay energized, battery voltage is supplied to the start relay and
                then switched to the crank motor solenoid to crank the engine.
            </para>
            <para>Before troubleshooting, make certain batteries are fully charged. Voltage readings will not be
                accurate if the batteries are not fully charged Check battery cables and grounds for clean and tight
                connections free of damage.
            </para>
            <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose or damaged (spread or bent)
                terminals, or wires with cut strands etc. Wires and connections must be free of damage or corrosion.
                When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must be removed.
            </para>
            <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect the suspect circuit ground for clean, tight connections, free of an
                damage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503038" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figeg7/EG7291.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Cranking System Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>*See Publication CTS 5122V Electrical Circuit Diagrams</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTES</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_108.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_110.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
