<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Cooling System - Cooling System Components and Flow</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010106.1" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Cooling System Components and Flow</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010106.1.1">
            <figure id="f305010140" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31138.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="490px"/>
                <caption>Cooling system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intake manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder head (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Thermostat assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant return (from heater)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front cover assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant inlet (from radiator)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water pump assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant outlet (to radiator)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant supply (to heater)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The cooling system keeps the engine within a designated temperature range.</para>
            <para>The centrifugal water pump (hub and impeller) is mounted in the pump housing of the front cover. The
                water pump has a built in reservoir to catch small amounts of coolant that may seep past the seal.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010106.1.2">
            <title>Front Cover Housing Flow</title>
            <para>The water pump draws coolant from the radiator through inlet of the front cover housing. Coolant flows
                from the water pump through three passages in the front cover.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Two passages (left and right) direct coolant into the crankcase (front to rear) to cool the
                        cylinder walls and the cylinder heads.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The third passage directs coolant through a passage in the crankcase to the oil cooler
                        cover.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an oil cooler seal is damaged, weep holes in the oil filter base allow coolant to seep from
                        the cooler cover.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Coolant returns through two front cover passages.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A single return passage in top of the front cover.</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Two opening (left and right) from the crankcase to this return passage.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>A third opening directs coolant from the intake manifold to this return passage.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>This return passage supplies coolant to the cab heater.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A second passage directs coolant from the cab heater to the front cover</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Return coolant is directed to the thermostat in the front cover.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the thermostat is open, coolant flows to the radiator and is blocked to the pump.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the thermostat is closed, coolant returns to the water pump and the radiator outlet is
                        blocked.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>As the engine reaches operating temperatures, the thermostat slowly opens and directs coolant to the
                radiator and blocks passage to the water pump. There is a small stop check valve through the thermostat
                disc that allows warming and equalizing flow across the thermostat.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010106.1.3">
            <title>Crankcase and Cylinder Head Flow</title>
            <para>Coolant flows through passages in the front cover to the left and right sides of the crankcase.
                Coolant flows through the front of both sides of the crankcase, evenly distributing coolant around the
                cylinders, and exits the rear of the crankcase flowing up to the cylinder heads.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows from the rear of the cylinder heads to the front of the cylinder heads, exits down a
                passage in the crankcase, and returns to the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>An optional coolant heater is installed in the crankcase for use in extremely cold weather. The
                coolant heater can be connected by a dealer.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Cooler and EGR Cooler Flow</title>
            <para>The front cover directs coolant to a passage in the crankcase. Coolant flows from the crankcase to the
                front of the oil cooler cover. The oil cooler and the oil filter base direct coolant to the front of the
                oil cooler.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows through the oil cooler from the front to rear and exits through the EGR cooler supply
                port.
            </para>
            <para>Coolant flows from the rear of the EGR cooler to the front returning to the front cover though a
                passage in the intake manifold.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The deaeration port is on top of the intake manifold.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostat Operation</title>
            <para>The thermostat has two outlets. One directs coolant to the radiator when the engine is at operating
                temperature. The other directs coolant to the water pump until the engine reaches operating temperature.
                The thermostat begins to open at 88 &#176;C (190 &#176;F) and is fully open at 96 &#176;C (205 &#176;F).
            </para>
            <figure id="f3050141" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31241.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Coolant flow - thermostat closed</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When engine coolant is below the nominal operating temperature the thermostat is closed, blocking flow
                to the radiator. Coolant is forced to flow through a bypass port back to the water pump.
            </para>
            <figure id="f3050142" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31242.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Coolant flow - thermostat open</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>As coolant temperature reaches the nominal opening temperature the thermostat starts to open allowing
                some coolant to flow to the radiator. When coolant temperature reaches normal operating temperature, the
                lower seat blocks the water pump port directing full coolant flow to the radiator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_S305010106.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_S3050107.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
