<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - DIGITAL
        MULTIMETER USE - ELECTRONIC CIRCUIT TESTING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
        <title>ELECTRONIC CIRCUIT TESTING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Some of the devices in an electronic control system are not capable of carrying any appreciable amount
                of current. Therefore the test equipment used to troubleshoot an electronic system must be designed not
                to damage any part of it. Because most analog meters use too much current to test an electronic control
                system, it is recommended that they not be used, unless specified.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1750541" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6133.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Typical Meters, Digital and Analog</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Only high impedance DMMs should be used when troubleshooting an electronic circuit. The use of any
                kind of battery powered test light is not recommended when troubleshooting an electronic circuit. This
                can damage an electronic control circuit.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Jumper Wires</title>
            <para>Jumper wires allow jumping across a suspected open or break in a circuit.</para>
            <figure id="ef1750542" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6134.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Troubleshooting Using Jumper Wires</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the circuit works properly with the jumper wire in place, but does not work when the jumper
                        wire is removed, the circuit is open.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A circuit without any opens or breaks has continuity (which means continuous) and needs no
                        further testing.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Jumper wires are fitted with several types of wire tips. It will be helpful to have several jumper
                wires available with different tips .
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1750543" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6135.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Jumper Wires</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>In the illustration Troubleshooting Using Jumper Wires , an open in the ground circuit exists when:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Switch is closed and light does not illuminate.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jumping the switch does not illuminate the light.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jumping the light to the ground causes the light to illuminate.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The jumper wire can be used to check for open relay contacts, wire breaks, and poor ground
                connections.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_158.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_SEC-6-NGV.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
