<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Systems - Air
        Management System - Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) System</title>
        <para>The EGR system includes the following:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>EGR control valve</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EGR cooler</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Air intake manifold</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Inlet and EGR mixer duct</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Exhaust manifold</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Exhaust gas crossover</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) system reduces Nitrogen Oxide (NOx) emissions.</para>
        <para>NO
            <subscript>X</subscript>
            forms during a reaction between nitrogen and oxygen at high temperature during combustion. Combustion starts
            when fuel is injected into the cylinder before or slightly after the piston reaches top-dead-center.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EGR Flow</title>
        </para>
        <para>Some exhaust from the exhaust manifold flows into the EGR cooler. Exhaust from the EGR cooler flows
            through the exhaust gas crossover to the EGR valve.
        </para>
        <para>When EGR is commanded, the EGR control valve opens allowing cooled exhaust gases to enter the EGR mixer
            duct to be mixed with filtered intake air.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EGR Control Valve</title>
        </para>
        <figure id="f2700117" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH15/H15016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>EGR control valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Connector</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">DC motor with position sensor</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Valve assembly</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The EGR valve uses a DC motor to control the position of the valve assembly. The motor pushes directly on
            the valve assembly. The valve assembly has two valve heads on a common shaft.
        </para>
        <para>The EGR actuator consists of three major components, a valve, an actuator motor, and Integrated Circuit
            (IC). The IC has three Hall effect position sensors to monitor valve movement. The EGR actuator is located
            at the front of the engine on the intake manifold.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EGR Closed Loop System and Control</title>
        </para>
        <figure id="f2700118" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>EGR closed loop operation with fault management</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The EGR drive module controls the EGR actuator and is located on the left side of the engine on the ECM
            and Injector Driver Module (IDM).
        </para>
        <para>The EGR drive module receives the desired EGR actuator position from the ECM across the CAN 2 datalink to
            activate the valve for exhaust gas recirculation. The EGR drive module provides feedback to the ECM on the
            valve position. The EGR drive module interprets the ECM command and sends the command using three
            pulse-width modulated signals to the valve actuator.
        </para>
        <para>The system is closed loop control using the EGR position signals.</para>
        <figure id="f2700119" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31194.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>EGR control</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_S265INTRO01.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
