<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Air Management System -
        Aftertreatment (AFT) System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Aftertreatment (AFT) System</title>
        <para>The AFT System processes engine exhaust to meet emissions requirements. The aftertreatment system consists
            of the Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC), Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF), three Exhaust Gas Temperature (EGT)
            sensors, and a Exhaust Gas Differential Pressure (EGDP) sensor. The Electronic Control Module (ECM) monitors
            aftertreatment and engine sensors to control AFT regeneration cycles. During a regeneration cycle the
            exhaust is heated to clear soot accumulation.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>AFT Control System</title>
        </para>
        <para>The control system performs the following functions:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Monitors exhaust gases, the aftertreatment system, and controls engine operating parameters for
                    emission processing and failure recognition
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cancels regeneration in the event of catalyst or sensor failure</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Monitors the level of soot accumulation in the Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) and adapts engine
                    operating characteristics to compensate for increased back pressure
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Controls engine operating parameters to make regeneration automatic.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Maintains vehicle and engine performance during regeneration</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The DOC does the following:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Oxidizes hydrocarbons and carbon monoxide (CO)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Provides heat for exhaust system warm-up</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Aids in system temperature management for the DPF</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Oxidizes NO into NO2 for passive DPF regeneration</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The DPF does the following:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Captures and temporarily stores carbon-based particulates in a filter</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Allows for oxidation (regeneration) of stored particulates once loading gets to a particular level
                    (pressure drop)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Stores noncombustible ash</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Sensors</title>
        </para>
        <para>Sensors produce an electronic signal based on temperature and pressure and are used by the ECM to monitor
            aftertreatment function and control regeneration.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>AFT Conditions and Responses</title>
        </para>
        <para>The operator is alerted audibly or with instrument panel indicators of AFT system status. Automatic or
            manual regeneration is required when levels of soot exceed acceptable limits. For additional information see
            the applicable vehicle Operator's Manual and the vehicle visor placard.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_S305010104.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
