<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Valve Train: Push Rods, Hydraulic
        Valve Lifters And Camshaft - Push Rods and Hydraulic Valve Lifters
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Push Rods and Hydraulic Valve Lifters</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Operation</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>As a general rule, hydraulic valve lifters should not require any service if they are
                        operating quietly and functioning satisfactorily.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1200602" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figcg1/cg11079.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Valve Lifter Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Lifter Body with Roller</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Spring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Plunger</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Plunger Body</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Metering Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Push Rod Seat</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Retainer</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Lube oil from the oil gallery is supplied to the lifters through a hole in the side of the lifter body
                that indexes with a groove and hole in the lifter plunger. Oil is then metered past the oil metering
                valve, up through the push rods and onto the valve levers.
            </para>
            <para>When the lifter begins to roll up the cam lobe, the metering valve is held against its seat in the
                plunger body by the spring. This action traps the oil in the base of the lifter body below the plunger.
                The plunger body and lifter body then rise as a unit, pushing the push rod up in order to open the
                valve. The spring force exerted on the plunger through the valve lever and push rod causes a slight
                amount of leakage between the plunger and lifter body.
            </para>
            <para>"Leak down" is the term used to describe this leakage. Leak down allows a slow escape of trapped oil
                in the base of the lifter body. As the lifter rides down the other side of the cam lobe and reaches the
                base circle or "valve closed" position, the plunger spring quickly moves the plunger back up to its
                original position. This movement causes the check valve to open against the check valve spring and
                allows oil to be replenished from the oil gallery. This restores the lifter to zero lash.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_SECTION6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_134.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
