<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System - Injection Drive Module
        (IDM)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.3" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Injection Drive Module (IDM)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f3050144" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Injection Drive Module (IDM)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The IDM has three functions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic distributor for injectors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Power source for injectors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IDM and injector diagnostics</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Electronic distributor for injectors</title>The IDM distributes current to the injectors. The IDM
                controls fueling to the engine by sending high voltage pulses to the OPEN and CLOSE coils of the
                injector. The IDM uses information from the ECM to determine the timing and quantity of fuel for each
                injector.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM uses CMP and CKP input signals to calculate engine speed and position. The ECM conditions both
                input signals and supplies the IDM with CMP and CKP output signals. The IDM uses CMP and CKP output
                signals to determine the correct sequence for injector firing.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends information (fuel volume, EOT, and ICP) through the CAN2 datalink to the IDM. The IDM
                uses this information to calculate the injection cycle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injector power source</title>The IDM creates a constant 48 volt (DC) supply to all injectors by
                making and breaking a 12 volt source across a coil in the IDM. The 48 volts created by the collapsed
                field is stored in capacitors until used by the injectors.
            </para>
            <para>The IDM controls when the injector is turned on and how long the injector is active. The IDM first
                energizes the OPEN coil, then the CLOSE coil. The low side driver supplies a return circuit to the IDM
                for each injector coil (open and close). The high side driver controls the power supply to the injector.
                During each injection event, the low and high side drivers are switched on and off for each coil.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>IDM and injector diagnostics</title>The IDM determines if an injector is drawing enough current.
                The IDM sends a fault to the ECM, indicating potential problems in the wiring harness or injector, and
                the ECM sets a DTC. The IDM also does self-diagnostic checks and will send a fault to the ECM. The ECM
                will set a DTC to indicate a fault from the IDM.
            </para>
            <para>On demand tests can be done using the Electronic Service Tool (EST). The EST sends a request to the
                ECM and the ECM sends a request to the IDM to do a test. Some tests set a DTC when a problem exists.
                Other tests require the technician to evaluate parameters, if a problem exists.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
