<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Air Compressor and Power Steering Pump
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="EGES-265-Section15" svcsectype="enginesec" division="engine" date="03/25/04">
        <title>Air Compressor and Power Steering Pump</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The air compressor and power steering pump assemblies are optional components on International&#174;
                    engines. They can be configured individually or together depending on vehicle application
                    requirements.
                </para>
                <para>Air for braking is supplied by an air compressor mounted on the lower left side of the engine. It
                    is gear driven from the lower idler gear located within the front engine cover.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Lubrication of the compressor is provided by a hose connected at the engine oil pressure
                            sensor port with oil draining back to the crankcase through an elbow at the bottom of the
                            compressor.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Filtered air is furnished through an air hose connected to the air cleaner assembly, and
                            compressed into a supply tank. When the air supply tank is full, compressed air is simply
                            vented to the atmosphere.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Coolant to the compressor is supplied and returned through two hoses to ports located on
                            the left side of the engine crankcase.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>The power steering pump assembly is mounted in one of two following configurations:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Without</emph>
                            an air compressor, the power steering pump is mounted onto the front cover and is driven by
                            the lower idler gear that would normally drive the air compressor.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">With</emph>
                            an air compressor, the power steering pump is mounted to the air compressor. The compressor
                            is driven by the lower idler gear and power is transferred through the compressor crankshaft
                            to drive the power steering pump.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For component service procedures other than removal and installation refer to the
                            <emph type="bold">International Service Information Solutions - ISIS&#174;</emph>
                            and then select manufacturer from suppliers tab.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_286.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_288.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
