<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Electrical - Removal - Injector
        Wiring Harness
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="1">
        <title>Injector Wiring Harness</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, disconnect
                    the main negative battery terminal before removing or installing any electrical components.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, make sure the key is in the OFF position before unplugging the connector
                    or relay for the ECM, IDM, and EGR drive module. Failure to turn the key to the OFF position will
                    cause a voltage spike and damage the electrical components.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, do not tug on any wiring harnesses while trying to remove them. If
                    resistance is felt, find the source of resistance and free up any connectors or clips that are
                    caught before proceeding. If necessary, remove the valve cover to gain clearance for injector
                    harness.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f2651131" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh09/H09023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Disconnecting the No. 6 fuel injector connector</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect six, four wire injector connectors from valve cover gasket.</para>
        </step1>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>If only removing the injector harness, separate it from the sensor harness and remove from various
                    tie down locations.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>If removing both the sensor and injector harnesses together, it is assumed the sensor harness
                    removal procedure was followed by removing both harnesses at the various tie down locations.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_SVCPROC1101.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_225.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
