<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Air Management
        System - Air Flow
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Air Flow</title>
        <para>Air flows through the air filter assembly and enters the VGT. The VGT compressor increases the pressure,
            temperature, and density of the intake air before it enters the CAC. Cooled compressed air flows from the
            CAC into the inlet throttle valve and EGR mixer duct.
        </para>
        <para>If the EGR control valve is open, exhaust gas will pass through the EGR system and mix with the filtered
            intake air. This mixture flows through the inlet air heater and into the intake manifold.
        </para>
        <para>If the EGR control valve is closed, only filtered intake air will flow through the inlet air heater and
            into the intake manifold.
        </para>
        <para>After combustion gases exit through the exhaust valves and ports, the gas is forced through the exhaust
            manifold to the EGR system and VGT.
        </para>
        <para>Some gas flows through the EGR system, which is controlled by the EGR valve. The remaining gas flows to
            the VGT turbine.
        </para>
        <para>The turbo vanes control flow and pressure of exhaust gas. This controls the speed of the compressor wheel,
            which is connected to the turbine wheel by a shaft. The VGT compressor wheel compresses the filtered air.
        </para>
        <para>Exhaust gases exit the turbocharger, flow into the exhaust piping to the aftertreatment system, and are
            released from the exhaust tail pipe.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
