<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Electronic Control System</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Electronic Control System</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <figure id="f2400133" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D31188.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="yes"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Operation and function</title>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) monitors and controls engine
                performance to ensure maximum performance and adherence to emissions standards. The ECM has four primary
                functions:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Provides Reference Voltage (V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Conditions input signals</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Processes and stores control strategies</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Controls actuators</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>1. Reference voltage (V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>)
                </title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM supplies a 5 volt V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                signal to input sensors in the electronic control system. By comparing the 5 volt V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                signal sent to the sensors with their respective returned signals, the ECM determines pressures,
                positions, and other variables important to engine and vehicle functions.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM supplies two independent circuits for V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        A supplies 5 volts to engine sensors
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        B supplies 5 volts to vehicle sensors
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>2. Signal conditioner</title>
            </para>
            <para>The signal conditioner in the internal microprocessor converts analog signals to digital signals,
                squares up sine wave signals, or amplifies low intensity signals to a level that the ECM microprocessor
                can process.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>3. Microprocessor</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM internal microprocessor stores operating instructions (control strategies) and value tables
                (calibration parameters). The ECM compares stored instructions and values with conditioned input values
                to determine the correct operating strategy for all engine operations.
            </para>
            <para>Continuous calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds: Foreground and
                Background.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Foreground calculations are much faster than background calculations and are normally more
                        critical for engine operation. Engine speed control is an example.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Background calculations are normally variables that change at a slower rates. Engine
                        temperature is an example.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs) are generated by the microprocessor, if inputs or conditions do not
                comply with expected values.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic strategies are also programmed into the ECM. Some strategies monitor inputs continuously
                and command the necessary outputs to achieve the correct performance of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Microprocessor memory</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM microprocessor includes Read Only Memory (ROM) and Random Access Memory (RAM).
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ROM</title>
            </para>
            <para>ROM stores permanent information for calibration tables and operating strategies. Permanently stored
                information cannot be changed or lost by turning the ignition key OFF or when ECM power is interrupted.
                ROM information includes the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle configuration, modes of operation, and options</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine warning and protection modes</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>RAM</title>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold"></emph>
            </para>
            <para>RAM stores temporary information for current conditions. Temporary information in RAM is lost when the
                ignition key is turned OFF or when ECM power is interrupted. RAM information includes the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine rpm</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator pedal position</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>4. Actuator control</title>The ECM controls the actuators by applying a low level signal (low
                side driver) or a high level signal (high side driver). When switched on, these drivers complete a
                ground or power circuit to an actuator.
            </para>
            <para>Actuators are controlled in three ways (determined by the kind of actuator):</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A duty cycle (percent time on/off)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A controlled pulse width</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Switched on or off</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>ECM Control of Engine Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM controls engine operation with the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>EVRT&#8482; control valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>IPR valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Glow plug relay</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Electronic Variable Response Turbocharger (EVRT&#8482;) control valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EVRT&#8482; control valve is an actuator on top of the EVRT&#8482;. The EVRT&#8482; control valve
                is a variable position valve that controls vane position in the turbine housing. The valve position is
                controlled by a switching voltage source in the ECM. The ground circuit is supplied directly from the
                battery ground at all times.
            </para>
            <para>The actuator control is achieved by setting a pulse width modulated signal in response to engine
                speed, desired fuel quantity, boost or exhaust back pressure and altitude.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EGR valve controls the flow of exhaust gases into the intake manifold. The EGR valve has an
                actuator to control the valve position and a position sensor to provide a feedback signal to the ECM.
                The valve position is controlled by switching the ground circuit in the ECM. The voltage source is
                supplied by the ECM power relay. The actuator control is achieved by setting a pulse width modulated
                signal in response to engine speed, desired fuel quantity, boost or exhaust back pressure and altitude.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</title>
            </para>
            <para>The IPR valve controls pressure in the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system. The IPR valve is a
                variable position valve controlled by the ECM. This regulated pressure actuates the fuel injectors. The
                valve position is controlled by switching the ground circuit in the ECM. The voltage source is supplied
                by the ignition switch.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Glow plug relay</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM activates the glow plug relay. The relay delivers V
                <subscript>BAT</subscript>to the glow plugs for up to 120 seconds, depending on ambient temperature and
                altitude. The ground cicuit is supplied directly from the battery ground at all times. Relay is
                controlled by switching on a voltage source from the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
