<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Diamond Logic&#174;
        Brake System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Diamond Logic&#174; Brake System</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para id="s0139">The Diamond Logic&#174; brake system is available for all engine displacements.</para>
            <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figk35/K35139.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Diamond Logic&#174; brake system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Electronic Control Module (ECM)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Brake pressure relief valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure oil manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Brake Shut-off Valve (BSV) assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front of engine</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">VGT control module</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>BCP</title>
            </para>
            <para id="s0146">The BCP sensor provides a feedback signal to the ECM indicating brake control pressure. The
                ECM monitors the BCP signal during engine normal and braking operation to determine if the engine brake
                system is working without fault. The BCP sensor is installed in the high-pressure oil manifold, under
                the valve cover.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>BSV</title>
            </para>
            <para>The BSV controls pressure entering the brake oil gallery from the high-pressure oil manifold gallery.
                This activates the brake actuator pistons and opens the exhaust valves. The BSV is located in the center
                of the high-pressure oil manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Brake Pressure Relief Valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>The brake pressure relief valve vents excess pressure under the valve cover. The ECM deactivates the
                engine brake by shutting off power to the BSV. Residual brake gallery pressure initially bleeds from the
                actuator bore. When brake gallery pressure reaches a set point, the brake pressure relief valve opens
                and oil drains back to the sump.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EBP</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EBP sensor measures exhaust back pressure. The ECM monitors the exhaust back pressure signal and
                commands the VGT and EGR systems to open or close to most restrictive position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>High-Pressure Oil Manifold</title>The high-pressure oil manifold has two internal separated oil
                galleries. The manifold supplies high-pressure oil to each fuel injector during normal operation.
                High-pressure oil is directed to the brake pistons during engine brake operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>VGT</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM commands the VGT vanes to the closed (most restrictive) position during exhaust and engine
                brake operation. This exhaust restriction increases exhaust back pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
