<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Electronic Control System - Engine and Vehicle
        Sensors
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Engine and Vehicle Sensors</title>
        <figure id="f2400135" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D31357.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Engine and Vehicle Sensors</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Electronic Control Module (ECM)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Oil Pressure (EOP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft Position (CMP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft Position (CKP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) drive module</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">EGR valve</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f2400136" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Thermistor</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Thermistors</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>ECT</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EOT</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>IAT</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MAT</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>A thermistor sensor changes electrical resistance as temperature changes. Resistance in the thermistor
            decreases as temperature increases, and increases as temperature decreases. Thermistors work with a resistor
            that limits current in the ECM to form a voltage signal matched with a temperature value.
        </para>
        <para>The top half of the voltage divider is the current limiting resistor that is internal to the ECM. A
            thermistor sensor has two electrical contacts: signal return and ground. The output of a thermistor sensor
            is a non-linear analog signal.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The ECT sensor detects engine coolant temperature.</para>
        <para>The ECT signal is monitored by the ECM for operation of the instrument panel temperature gauge, coolant
            temperature compensation, optional Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS), glow plugs, and the wait to
            start lamp. The ECM will use ECT sensor input as a backup, if EOT sensor values are out of range.
        </para>
        <para>The ECT sensor is installed in the left side of the front cover.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The EOT sensor detects engine oil temperature.</para>
        <para>The EOT signal is monitored by the ECM to control EGR, VGT, and for engine fueling calculations throughout
            the operating range of the engine. The EOT signal allows the ECM and IDM to compensate for differences in
            oil viscosity, due to temperature changes.
        </para>
        <para>The EOT sensor is installed in the oil filter base.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The IAT signal is monitored by the ECM to control timing and fuel rate during cold starts.</para>
        <para>The IAT sensor is chassis mounted in the air filter housing.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The MAT sensor detects intake manifold air temperature.</para>
        <para>The MAT signal is monitored by the ECM for EGR operation.</para>
        <para>The MAT sensor is installed in the right front of the intake manifold.</para>
        <figure id="f2400137" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Variable capacitance sensor</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Variable capacitance sensors</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>BAP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EBP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EOP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ICP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MAP</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Variable capacitance sensors measure pressure. The pressure measured is applied to a ceramic material. The
            pressure forces the ceramic material closer to a thin metal disk. This action changes the capacitance of the
            sensor.
        </para>
        <para>The sensor is connected to the ECM by three wires:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Signal return</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Signal ground</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The sensor receives the V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            and returns an analog signal voltage to the ECM. The ECM compares the voltage with pre-programmed values to
            determine pressure.
        </para>
        <para>The operational range of a variable capacitance sensor is linked to the thickness of the ceramic disk. The
            thicker the ceramic disk the more pressure the sensor can measure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The BAP sensor detects altitude.</para>
        <para>The BAP sensor provides information to the ECM for control of fuel quantity, fuel timing, glow plug
            operation, and adjustment of the VGT to compensate for density changes.
        </para>
        <para>The BAP sensor is mounted behind the instrument panel.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The EOP sensor detects engine oil pressure.</para>
        <para>The EOP signal is monitored by the ECM for operation of the instrument panel pressure gauge and optional
            EWPS.
        </para>
        <para>The EOP sensor is installed in the oil filter base.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The EBP sensor measures exhaust back pressure before the turbocharger.</para>
        <para>The EBP sensor provides feedback to the ECM for closed loop control of the VGT and for EGR position
            calculations.
        </para>
        <para>The EBP sensor is mounted on a bracket on the left side of the engine below the ECM.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The ICP sensor, a micro-strain gauge sensor, measures injection control pressure.</para>
        <para>The ICP signal is monitored by the ECM for closed loop control of the IPR valve. The ICP signal is also
            used by the IDM for engine fueling calculations.
        </para>
        <para>The ICP sensor is installed in the right high-pressure oil rail.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The MAP sensor detects intake manifold boost pressure.</para>
        <para>The MAP signal is monitored by the ECM for EGR position and engine fueling calculations.</para>
        <para>The MAP sensor is installed in the top front of the intake manifold.</para>
        <figure id="f2400138" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD33/D3385.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Magnetic pickups</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Magnetic pickup sensors</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>CKP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CMP</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>VSS</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>A magnetic pickup sensor generates an alternating frequency that indicates rotational speed. Magnetic
            pickup sensors have a two wire connection for signal and ground. The sensor has a permanent magnet core
            surrounded by a wire coil. The signal frequency is generated by the rotation of gear teeth that disturb the
            magnetic field.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Crankshaft Position (CKP) sensor</title>
        </para>
        <para>The CKP sensor indicates crankshaft speed and position.</para>
        <para>The CKP sensor provides the ECM with a signal that indicates crankshaft speed and position. As the
            crankshaft turns the CKP sensor detects a 60 tooth timing disk on the crankshaft. Teeth 59 and 60 are
            missing. By comparing the CKP signal with the CMP signal, the ECM calculates engine rpm and timing
            requirements.
        </para>
        <para>The CKP is installed in the front right side of the lower crankcase.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Camshaft Position (CMP)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The CMP sensor indicates camshaft speed and position.</para>
        <para>The CMP sensor sends a pulsed signal to the ECM when a single peg on the camshaft rotates past the CMP
            sensor once during each revolution of the camshaft. The ECM calculates camshaft speed and position from CMP
            signal frequency.
        </para>
        <para>The CMP sensor is installed in the front left side of the crankcase.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The VSS provides the ECM with transmission tail shaft speed by sensing the rotation of a 16 tooth gear on
            the rear of the transmission. The detected sine wave signal (AC), received by the ECM, is used with tire
            size and axle ratio to calculate vehicle speed.
        </para>
        <para>The VSS is installed in left side of the transmission.</para>
        <figure id="f2400139" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ31/J31036.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Potentiometer</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Potentiometers</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>APS</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>A potentiometer is a variable voltage divider that senses the position of a mechanical component. A
            reference voltage is applied to one end of the potentiometer. Mechanical rotary or linear motion moves the
            wiper along the resistance material, changing voltage at each point along the resistive material. Voltage is
            proportional to the amount of mechanical movement.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The APS provides the ECM with a feedback signal (linear analog voltage) that indicates the operator's
            demand for power. The APS is mounted in the accelerator pedal. In the same application, a remote accelerator
            or throttle device can be used in addition to the accelerator pedal.
        </para>
        <para></para>
        <figure id="f2400140" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD33/D3387.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Switch</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Switches</title>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>DDS</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ECL</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>IVS</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Switch sensors indicate position. They operate open or closed, allowing or preventing the flow of current.
            A switch sensor can be a voltage input switch or a grounding switch. A voltage input switch supplies the ECM
            with a voltage when it is closed. A grounding switch grounds the circuit closed, causing a zero voltage
            signal. Grounding switches are usually installed in series with a current limiting resistor.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The DDS determines if a vehicle is in gear. For manual transmissions, the clutch switch serves as the DDS.
            For automatic transmissions, the neutral switch functions as the DDS.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The ECL switch is used in plastic deaeration tanks. When the magnetic switch is open, the tank is full.
        </para>
        <para>The ECL lamp on the instrument panel signals the operator if engine coolant is low. ECL is part of the
            Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS)
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>
        </para>
        <para>The IVS is a redundant switch that provides the ECM with a signal that verifies when the APS is in the
            idle position.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
