<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Idle Shutdown Timer (IST)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Idle Shutdown Timer (IST)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503070" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1295.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Idle Shutdown Timer Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Idle Shutdown feature is an optional feature that allows the ECM to shut off the engine if an idle
                condition has been detected for more than the customer specified programmed period (2 to 120 minutes).
                Prior to engine shutdown the red Engine lamp illuminates and causes the message
                <emph type="bold">OIL/WATER</emph>
                to be displayed on the odometer. The lamp will flash for 30 seconds to warn the driver of the pending
                shutdown. The idle time is measured from the last clutch or break pedal transition. The engine must be
                out of gear for the idle shutdown timer to be initiated. This feature can be programmed to operate only
                at specific ambient air temperatures to allow prolonged engine operation in cold or hot weather
                operation. For PTO applications this feature can also be programmed not to be turned on under specific
                load levels or when the PTO switches are on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 324</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Idle Shutdown feature is internal to the ECM. All subsystems that input the idle shutdown strategy
                have their own Diagnostic Trouble Code detection and management strategy (e.g. IAT temperature sensor
                circuit). A Diagnostic Trouble Code will be set if the idle shutdown timer has been activated.
                <emph type="bold">This is not a system Diagnostic Trouble Code. Its only purpose is to indicate to the
                    owner, driver or technician that the idle shutdown timer has been activated and that the engine has
                    been shut down.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 324</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This Diagnostic Trouble Code does not indicate any system or circuit faults, no diagnostics
                        are necessary. If the (IST) programming parameters need to be changed, see the following
                        Extended Description.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The following list of parameters are essential to setting the IST function to meet the customer's
                needs and expectations. They are accessible by using the EST.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Idle Shutdown Control Parameters</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This group of parameters customizes the prolonged engine idle automatic shutdown feature. The purpose
                of this feature is to shut down the engine after a programmable period of idle time has been exceeded.
                This allows fuel conservation, a reduction of engine wear and emissions. Thirty (30.0) seconds prior to
                an automatic engine shutdown, the operator will be warned via the red ENGINE lamp and causes the message
                <emph type="bold">OIL/WATER</emph>
                message being displayed on the odometer. This lamp will begin flashing until the engine is shut down.
                The operator may override the electronics at any time. After an engine shutdown occurs, the red ENGINE
                lamp will stop flashing and a Diagnostic Trouble Code (324) will be recorded. The Diagnostic Trouble
                Code is recorded to assist in diagnosing possible service complaints of the engine shutting down.
            </para>
            <para>Currently, there are four states of electronic operation:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Timer</emph>
                    -This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if this vehicle has the Idle Shutdown timer
                    feature.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">OFF</emph>- Feature is turned off at all times.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">PTO Available</emph>- Feature will allow prolonged engine idle shutdown only
                        when the engine is in the low idle no load condition and PTO operation is off.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">No Engine Load</emph>- Feature allows prolonged engine idle shutdown when the
                        engine is in the low idle no load condition.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Tamper Proof</emph>- Feature is tamper proof from operator over ride.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Time</emph>
                    -This parameter indicates the length of engine idle time before the engine may be shut down.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Maximum Intake Ambient Air Temperature (IAT) for Idle Shutdown</emph>- This
                    parameter indicates the maximum ambient intake air temperature that the on-board electronics may
                    shut down during prolonged idling engine. This temperature is used to circumvent the shutting down
                    of an engine when it is running because the air conditioning may be turned on.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Minimum Intake Ambient Air Temperature (IAT) for Idle Shutdown</emph>- This
                    parameter indicates the minimum ambient intake air temperature that the on-board electronics may
                    shut down during prolonged idle time. This temperature is used to circumvent engine shut down when
                    it is running because of cold ambient temperature.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para id="f175fc324">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 324</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 71, FMI 14</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Timer Enabled Engine Shutdown</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This Diagnostic Trouble Code is set when the engine has been shut off by the ECM because the
                programmed idle time criteria has been exceeded. The idle shutdown feature must be turned on for this
                Diagnostic Trouble Code to be displayed. This Diagnostic Trouble Code can be cleared using the EST.
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_99.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_101.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
