<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Performance Diagnostics
        - Test Procedures - 18. Valve Lash and Brake Lash
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="8">
        <title>18. Valve Lash and Brake Lash</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f27006091" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31269.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If Tests 1-17 meet specifications, engine operation is good: Test 18 is not necessary.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f27006092" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31154.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Purpose</title>
                <item>
                    <para>To check or adjust valve lash for intake and exhaust valves</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To check or adjust actuator lash for Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Feeler gauge</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Straight-blade screwdriver</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Open end wrench (two sizes)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque wrench</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crows foot (two sizes)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                        safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Valve Lash for Intake and Exhaust Valves</title>
            </para>
            <para>During the procedure to adjust valve lash, the crankshaft is rotated two times:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Six valve adjustments are made when piston 1 is at Top Dead Center (TDC) compression.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Six valve adjustments are made when piston 6 is at Top Dead Center (TDC) compression.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the engine is equipped with the Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake, corresponding brake actuator lash
                can be adjusted before rotating the crankshaft the second time.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjusting Valve Lash</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve cover following procedure in Engine Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn crankshaft in the direction of engine rotation to remove gear lash from gear train
                    and align the timing mark on the damper pulley with the TDC mark on the front cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Confirm that piston 1 is at TDC compression by turning both push rods by hand to verify
                    that valves are closed.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If push rods are loose and turn easily, piston 1 is at TDC compression and valves are
                            closed. If piston 1 is at TDC compression, see and do steps 4, 5, and 6.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If push rods will not turn easily for cylinder 1, piston 6 is at TDC compression. Confirm
                            that valves are closed by making sure that push rods for cylinder 6 are loose and turn
                            easily. If piston 6 is at TDC compression, see and do steps 4, 5, and 6.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27006093" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08044.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Valve lash adjustments with piston 1 at TDC compression</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f27006094" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08045.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Valve lash adjustments with piston 6 at TDC compression</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f27006095" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08043.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Valve lash adjustment</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f27006096" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08098.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Feeler gauge between the pivot foot and valve bridge</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check cold valve lash with a (0.019 in) feeler gauge between the pivot foot and valve
                    bridge. If adjustment is required, loosen the locknut and turn the valve adjustment screw until a
                    light drag is felt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once valve adjustment is set, tighten the locknut to 27 N&#183;m (20 lbf&#183;ft) and
                    remove the feeler gauge. Recheck for light drag on feeler gauge. If drag is too tight or loose,
                    repeat steps 4 and 5.
                </para>
                <para>If engine is equipped with the Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake, corresponding brake actuator lash
                    can be adjusted before rotating the crankshaft. See "Brake Actuator Lash" in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn crankshaft 360&#176; in the direction of engine rotation to remove gear lash from
                    gear train and realign the timing mark on the damper pulley with the TDC mark on the front cover.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If first adjustments were with piston 1 at TDC compression, cylinder 6 should be at TDC
                            compression. Confirm that valves are closed by making sure that push rods for cylinder 6 are
                            loose and turn easily. If piston 6 is at TDC compression, see and do steps 4 and 5.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If first adjustments were with piston 6 at TDC compression, cylinder 1 should be at TDC
                            compression. Confirm that valves are closed by making sure that push rods for cylinder 1 are
                            loose and turn easily. If piston 1 is at TDC compression, see and do steps 4 and 5.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>Before doing step 7, If engine is equipped with the Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake corresponding
                    brake actuator lash can be adjusted. See "Brake Actuator Lash" in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve cover following procedure inEngine Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Lash</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Three actuators are adjusted when piston 1 is at Top Dead Center (TDC) compression.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Three actuators are adjusted when piston 6 is at Top Dead Center (TDC) compression.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Corresponding intake and exhaust valve lash should be adjusted before rotating the crankshaft.</para>
            <para></para>
            <figure id="f27006097" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08048.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake lash adjustment</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f27006098" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08050.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Feeler gauge between the valve bridge and brake actuator</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check cold brake lash with a (0.019 in) feeler gauge between the actuator and valve
                    bridge. If adjustment is required, loosen the locknut and turn the actuator adjustment screw until a
                    light drag is felt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once brake lash is set, tighten the locknut to 27 N&#183;m (20 lbf&#183;ft) and remove
                    the feeler gauge. Recheck for light drag on feeler gauge. If drag is too tight or loose, repeat
                    steps 1 and 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Possible Causes</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn valve train</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn valve seat or valve face</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn actuator in Diamond Logic&#174; engine brake</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_114.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_E2700107.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
