<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE OPERATION - Key-On Engine Running Standard Test
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="1">
        <title>Key-On Engine Running Standard Test</title>
        <para>The ECM evaluates the hydraulic performance of the injection control pressure system. The ECM monitors the
            signal values for the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor and compares them with the expected values.
            When the Key-On Engine Running Standard Test is over, the ECM returns the engine to normal operation and
            sends Diagnostic Trouble Codes to the EST.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before doing this test:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure engine coolant temperature is above 170&#176; degrees.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure battery voltage is 12.5 volts or higher.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure the signal for the Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) is not on.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check for active Diagnostic Trouble Codes. If active DTCs are displayed, correct the
                            causes and clear all DTCs.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
        </para>
        <figure id="f17530" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEG8/EG8712C.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Key-On Engine Running Standard Test</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine Running Standard Test from the Diagnostics Drop-Down Menu.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The ECM increases engine idle speed to a set value.</para>
            <para>The ECM signals the IPR valve to set the injection control pressure to rated speed pressure. If IPR
                performance is acceptable, the ECM will command the IPR valve to reduce the pressure in steps, while
                continuing to monitor the performance of the injection control pressure system.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_32.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
