<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Crankcase, Crankshaft, Connecting
        Rods, And Pistons - Connecting Rods, Pistons and Piston Rings - Check Piston Protrusion
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="f04019" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Check Piston Protrusion</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Lack of protrusion could indicate a damaged rod or a rod bearing out of position. Excessive
                    protrusion may require replacement of rods or crankshaft. To avoid engine damage correct as
                    required.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before removing any piston and connecting rod assemblies, it is recommended that piston protrusion
                    be evaluated. This will help identify bent or twisted connecting rods.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check piston protrusion above crankcase as follows:</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the crankshaft so the piston is just below crankcase deck surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place and zero a dial indicator gauge on crankcase deck surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position tip of dial indicator gauge onto the piston head at the 3 o'clock position.
                (Positioning the dial indicator tip at 12 o'clock or 6 o'clock will not yield an accurate measurement).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the crankshaft so the piston is at the highest point of its stroke and record the
                reading.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the crankshaft to reposition the piston to just below the crankcase surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reposition dial indicator tip onto piston head at the 9 o'clock position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the crankshaft so the piston is at the highest point of its stroke and record the
                reading. Then average the two readings.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_166.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_168.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
