<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - TOOLS - DWYER
        SLACK TUBE MANOMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DWYER SLACK TUBE MANOMETER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <figure id="f17505004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figcg7/CG7725.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Slack Tube Manometer, Dwyer No. 1211-48</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The manometer is a "U" shaped tube with a scale mounted between the legs of the U. Where the
                portability of the Model 200 Pressure Test Kit is not required, this manometer can be used to measure
                either low pressure or vacuum (intake restriction, crankcase pressure or exhaust back pressure) and must
                be filled with water. Refer to Dwyer Slack Tube Manometer .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Filling</title>
            <para>The manometer must be filled with water before checking any pressure.</para>
            <para>When filling with water, use only good drinking water without additives, except for some colored water
                vegetable dye, which enables the tester to read the scale easier. With both legs of the manometer open
                to the atmosphere, fill the tube until the top of the fluid column is near the zero mark on the scale.
                Shake the tube to eliminate any air bubbles.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>NEVER USE AN ANTIFREEZE SOLUTION, SODA POP, TONIC, ETC. TO FILL MANOMETER. THE INCREASE IN
                        DENSITY CAUSES FALSE READINGS.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installing and Reading</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support the manometer in a vertical position. Be sure the fluid level line is in line
                    with the zero indicator on the graduated scale.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect one leg of the manometer to the source of the pressure or vacuum. The other leg
                    is left open to atmospheric pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After starting the engine and allowing it to reach its normal operating temperature, it
                    can be set to
                    <emph type="bold">High Idle</emph>. After approximately
                    <emph type="bold">10 seconds</emph>
                    the manometer can be observed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the average position of the fluid level when it is above and below the zero
                    indicator. Add the two figures together. The sum of the two is the total column of fluid and
                    represents the crankcase pressure in inches of water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare manometer reading with engine specifications.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>At times both columns of the manometer will not travel the same distance. This is of no
                        concern to the tester as long as the leg not connected to the pressure or vacuum source is open
                        to the atmosphere.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cleaning</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash the tube thoroughly using a little pure soap and water. Avoid liquid soaps and
                    solvents.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_129.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_131.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
