<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Engine Crank Inhibit System (ECI)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Engine Crank Inhibit System (ECI)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503036" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8839.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Engine Crank Inhibit Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Crank Inhibit Functions</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit feature of the ECM is used to control the operation of the cranking motor.
                The ECM prevents the cranking motor from being engaged when the engine is running. The transmission
                neutral safety switch or clutch switch will prevent the cranking motor from being engaged when the
                transmission is in gear or when the clutch pedal is not depressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Crank Inhibit Relay</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The engine starter relay is used to relay battery voltage to the crank motor solenoid. The relay is
                also controlled by an over crank thermocouple, if so equipped.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fault Detection / Management</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM does not monitor the cranking system circuits. There are no Diagnostic Trouble Codes for this
                system.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503037" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8840.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Engine Crank Inhibit Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector always check for damaged pins, corrosion, and loose terminals.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before testing starter relay or cranking circuits, verify that the batteries are fully
                        charged. Check battery connections at the battery, frame and starter. See S08256 for battery and
                        starter test procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503008" frame="all">
                <title>Starter Relay Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="77.83*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="54.38*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="263.79*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Relay Voltage and Resistance Checks - With ECI Relay
                                        Removed.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check with relay unplugged &#38; starter switch (key or button) engaged. If no
                                    voltage present, troubleshoot ignition crank circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If no voltage is present, troubleshoot battery wiring.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4V to 5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ECM will pull circuit up to 4V to 5V with key ON and will go to 0V when the clutch
                                    is depressed or transmission is in neutral.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Circuit Test</emph>- With the trans out of gear and the clutch
                                    depressed with wheels safely blocked, insert a jumper wire between socket pins #86
                                    and #87 of the starter relay. If the engine cranks, when the start switch is engaged
                                    either the ECI relay is bad or there is a problem with the ECM or ECM wiring
                                    harness.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Continued on Next Page</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECM Chassis (Black) Circuit Checks - Check With All Relays
                                        Installed and breakout Box Connected
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DDS (+26) to (-23)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V or 12V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Manual Trans</emph>
                                    - 12V with clutch pedal down, 0V clutch pedal up;
                                    <emph type="bold">Automatic Trans</emph>
                                    - 12V with trans in neutral, 0V trans in gear.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="2">
                                <para>ECI (+46) to (-23)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">At crank w/clutch up or auto trans in gear</emph>, if 12V is
                                    present circuit is good, cranking inhibited.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V to 0.6V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">At crank w/clutch down or auto trans in neutral,</emph>
                                    if ECM pin #26 is at 12V and pin #46 is not at 0V to 0.6V, check ECM programming.
                                    Cranking allowed.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4V to 5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pull up voltage from ECM w/key ON,
                                    <emph type="bold">engine OFF or running</emph>: trans in gear or clutch up.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The engine starting system is controlled by the Electronic Control Module (ECM). This is to prevent
                cranking motor operation while the engine is running, causing damage to the starter pinion and ring
                gear. Input from the clutch switch or transmission neutral switch. These switches prevent the cranking
                motor from being engaged unless the transmission is in neutral or the clutch is depressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Start Relay</emph>
                - The engine starter relay controls the current to the starter motor. Turning the ignition key to the
                start position supplies current to energize the relay at terminal 85. If the engine is not running and
                the driveline is not engaged the ECM terminal 46 will enable the relay by supplying a ground circuit to
                terminal 85 of the relay. With the relay closed current can then pass through the relay to terminals the
                cranking motor solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for pushed back, loose or damaged (spread or bent)
                terminals, or wires with cut strands etc. Wires and connections must be free of damage or corrosion.
                When some connectors corrode, a light white residue will be present that must be removed.
                <emph type="bold">Make certain that the batteries are fully charged.</emph>
                Check battery cables and grounds for clean and tight connections free of damage. Voltage readings will
                not be accurate if the batteries are not fully charged.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Clutch Switch</emph>- On vehicles equipped with a manual transmission, the clutch
                switch is used to supply a signal to the ECM that indicates the driveline is disengaged. A 12V signal on
                the DDS circuit indicates that the clutch is disengaged (clutch pedal down), a 0V signal indicates that
                the clutch is engaged (clutch pedal up).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Neutral Switch (Allison 2000 Series Transmissions)</emph>
                - On vehicles equipped with Allison LCT transmissions (2000 series), the neutral position switch is used
                to supply switched power to the starter relay and provides a signal to the ECM that indicates the
                driveline is disengaged. On vehicles programmed for Allison AT/MT transmissions, a 12V signal on the DDS
                circuit indicates that the transmission is out of gear, a 0V signal indicates that the transmission is
                in gear. When the transmission is in gear no power is available to the ECI relay.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WTEC MD W/Auto Neutral</emph>
                - On vehicles equipped with Allison MD World Transmission Electronically Controlled transmission (WTEC)
                w/optional Auto Neutral, the crank inhibit system has an additional relay that inhibits cranking. The
                additional relay is used to inhibit cranking when the transmission is in auto neutral. PIN 6 of the
                transmission ECU controls 12 volts to pin 86 of the crank inhibit relay. When PIN 86 receives power and
                the relay closes, IGN voltage is supplied to PIN 86 of the starter relay. PIN 26 of the ECM receives 12
                volts from the WTEC Auto Neutral relay whenever the transmission is either shifted in neutral or auto
                neutral. Without the additional relay the Driveline Disengagement input (PIN 26) would allow cranking in
                auto neutral.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Electronic Control Module (ECM)</emph>
                - When the ECM recognizes that the engine is not running and the driveline is not engaged the ECM will
                ground terminal 46. This provides the current path for the Engine Crank Inhibit relay to close when the
                Start switch is engaged or the starter button is depressed. When the ECM recognizes that the engine is
                running or the driveline is engaged the ECM will open terminal 46. This will prevent the Engine Crank
                Inhibit relay from closing thus preventing the starter motor from engaging.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Components of the ECI System are:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Ignition Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Push Button Start Switch (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Starter Relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crank Motor and Solenoid</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Batteries and Cables</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Neutral Safety Switch (with Allison 2000 Series Transmissions)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Switch (with Manual Transmission)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Crank Inhibit Relay (Allison MD WTEC w/Auto Neutral)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f17503038.5" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8847.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Cranking Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f17503038.61" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/eg9012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Cranking Circuit Connections with Manual Transmission</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f17503038.6" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8993.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Allison LCT Transmission Driveline Disengagement Input</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f17503038.7" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8994.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Driveline Disengagement Input WTEC MD or HD w/Auto Neutral</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f17503038.8" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8995.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Allison MD Transmission Driveline Disengagement Input</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_85.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_87.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
