<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - INTRODUCTION - Engine Description
        - Air Induction and Exhaust System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Air Induction and Exhaust System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f120in16" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg3/EG3506.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Air Induction/Exhaust System Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Charge Air Cooling Tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Air Inlet Assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Compressor Assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Center Housing</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Turbine Housing</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Muffler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Right Hand Exhaust Manifold</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Left Hand Exhaust Manifold</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The intake and exhaust systems consist of those components that contain the flow of filtered air into
                the engine cylinders and exhaust gases to the atmosphere.
            </para>
            <para>The turbocharger is used to increase engine power output by increasing the air supply to the engine,
                resulting in more uniform performance at various operating altitudes. The turbocharger incorporates an
                exhaust driven air compressor that allows filtered air to enter the center of the air compressor where
                it undergoes an increase in pressure from "atmospheric" to "boost" as it flows into the combustion
                chambers. After combustion, hot and expanding exhaust gases move out of the cylinders and into the
                turbine housing driving the turbine wheel. The turbine wheel drives the compressor wheel through a solid
                common shaft allowing the engine to respond directly to changing engine loads. During heavy loads, an
                increased flow of exhaust gas spins the turbine wheel faster causing the compressor impeller to spin in
                direct relation, supplying greater volumes of air (boost) into the intake manifold and cylinders.
                Conversely, with lighter engine loads, the flow of exhaust gas decreases as does the volume of air being
                compressed into the intake manifold and cylinders.
            </para>
            <para>Some engines are equipped with an optional exhaust back pressure device to allow for a faster warm-up
                of the engine and passenger compartment when heat is needed. This device increases heat production. It
                uses a butterfly valve located in the exhaust side of the turbocharger housing. When the valve is
                restricted, exhaust back pressure increases, forcing the engine to work harder to expel the exhausted
                gases. When the valve is open, exhaust gases flow out freely.
            </para>
            <para>The hot boost air from the compressor is cooled by a charge air cooler before entering the intake
                manifold. Air then flows into the combustion chamber where the required quantity of fuel is injected,
                igniting the combustion phase. Exhaust gases leave the cylinders through exhaust ports and the exhaust
                manifold. From the exhaust manifold, the expansion of exhaust gases on the exhaust turbine drive the
                turbocharger and are released through an exhaust pipe into the atmosphere.
            </para>
            <para>The exhaust system includes exhaust valves, an exhaust manifold, exhaust piping and a muffler. The
                turbocharger turbine side is also an integral part of the exhaust system. The compressor side is a
                component of the induction or intake system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
