<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM DIAGNOSTICS -
        Circuit Function And Diagnostics - Idle Shutdown Timer (IST)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Idle Shutdown Timer (IST)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Function</title>
            <para>See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f17503070">Idle Shutdown Timer Function Diagram
                    <xref refid="f17503070"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503070" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG1/EG1295A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for Idle Shutdown Timer</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Idle Shutdown feature is a customer optional feature that allows the ECM to shut off the engine if
                an idle condition has been detected for more than the customer specified programmed period (2 to 120
                minutes). Before engine shutdown the Oil / Water Lamp (red) will flash for 30 seconds to warn the driver
                of the pending shutdown. The idle time is measured from the last clutch or break pedal transition. The
                engine must be out of gear for the idle shutdown timer to be initiated. This feature can be programmed
                to operate at specific ambient air temperatures to allow prolonged engine operation in cold or hot
                weather operation. For PTO applications this feature can also be programmed not to be turned on under
                specific load levels or when the PTO switches are on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>The Idle Shutdown feature is internal to the ECM. All subsystems that are inputs for the idle shutdown
                strategy have their own Diagnostic Trouble Code detection and management strategy (e.g. IAT temperature
                sensor circuit). A Diagnostic Trouble Code will be set if the idle shutdown timer has been activated.
                This is not a system Diagnostic Trouble Code. It only indicates that the idle shutdown timer has been
                activated and that the engine has been shut down.
            </para>
            <table id="te17503026" tblwidth="col-wide" frame="all">
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code 324</title>
                <tgroup cols="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="100.00*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Reference</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>324 = Idle shutdown time has been exceeded and the engine has been shut down.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This Diagnostic Trouble Code does not indicate any system or circuit faults; no diagnostics
                        are necessary. If the (IST) programming parameters need to be changed, see the following
                        Extended Description.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>The following list of parameters are essential to setting the IST function to meet the customer's
                needs and expectations. They are accessible by using the EST.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Idle Shutdown Control Parameters</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This group of parameters customizes the prolonged engine idle automatic shutdown feature. The purpose
                of this feature is to shut the engine down after a programmable period of idle time has been exceeded.
                This allows fuel conservation, a reduction of engine wear and emissions. Thirty (30.0) seconds before an
                automatic engine shutdown, the operator will be warned via the red Oil / Water Lamp. This lamp will
                begin flashing until the engine is shut down. The operator may over ride the electronics at any time.
                After an engine shutdown occurs, the Oil / Water Lamp will stop flashing and a diagnostic code (324)
                will be recorded. The diagnostic code is recorded to assist in diagnosing possible service complaints of
                the engine shutting down.
            </para>
            <para>Currently, there are four states of electronic operation.
                <emph type="bold">1. Off 2. PTO available 3. No engine load 4. Tamper proof.</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Timer</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if this vehicle has the Idle Shutdown timer
                feature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OFF:</emph>
                Feature is turned off at all times.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Available</emph>: Feature allows prolonged engine idle shutdown only when the
                engine is in the low idle no load condition and PTO operation is off.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">No Engine Load</emph>: Feature allows prolonged engine idle shutdown when the engine
                is in the low idle no load condition.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Tamper Proof</emph>: Feature is tamper proof from operator over ride.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Time</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>This parameter indicates the length of engine idle time before the engine may be shut down.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Maximum Intake Ambient Air Temperature (IAT) for Idle Shutdown</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>This parameter indicates the maximum ambient intake air temperature that the on-board electronics may
                shut down during prolonged engine idling. This temperature is used to circumvent the shutting down of an
                engine when it is running because the air conditioning may be turned on.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Minimum Intake Ambient Air Temperature</emph>(
                    <emph type="bold">IAT</emph>)
                    <emph type="bold">for Idle Shutdown</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>This parameter indicates the minimum ambient intake air temperature that the on-board electronics may
                shut down during prolonged engine idling. This temperature is used to circumvent the shutting down of an
                engine when it is running because of cold ambient temperature.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc324">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 324</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code PID 71 FMI 14</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Idle Shutdown Timer Enabled Engine shutdown</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This Diagnostic Trouble Code is set when the engine has been shut off by the ECM because the idle time
                criteria has been exceeded. The idle shutdown feature should be turned on for this Diagnostic Trouble
                Code to be displayed. Diagnostic Trouble Code 324 can be cleared using the EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_114.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_116.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
