<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS AND ACCESSORIES - Electronic Circuit Testing -
        Electrical Theory
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Electrical Theory</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltage</title>
            <para>Voltage is electrical pressure or force that pushes current through a circuit. The pressure is
                measured in volts. The symbol V (for example, 12V) is used in circuit diagrams to denote voltage. The
                letter E (Electromotive force) is also used for voltage. Voltage can be compared to the pressure
                necessary to push water through a metering valve.
            </para>
            <para>Low voltage to a lamp will cause the lamp to glow dimly. This can be caused by low source voltage
                (discharged battery or low alternator output) or by high circuit resistance resulting from a poor
                connection. Resistance from a poor connection or poor ground is an additional load in the circuit. The
                additional load reduces voltage available to push current through the load device. Before making any
                meter measurements, review Ohm's Law.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ohm's Law</title>
            <para>Ohm's Law describes the relationship between current, voltage, and resistance in an electrical
                circuit. Ohm's Law also provides the basic formula for calculations.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750534" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8530.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Ohm's Law</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Memorize the formula in the circle. Cover the letter with a finger for the desired formula. For
                example, I is covered, the formula is I = E &#247; R.
            </para>
            <para>If two values are known for a given circuit, the missing one can be found by substituting the values
                in amperes, volts, or ohms.
            </para>
            <para>The three basic formulas for Ohm's Law are as follows:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>I = Current (amperes)</line>
                <line>E = Voltage (volts)</line>
                <line>R = Resistance (ohms)</line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>I = E &#247; R</para>
                    <para>This formula states that the current flow (I) in the circuit equals the voltage (E) applied to
                        the circuit divided by the total resistance (R) in the circuit. This shows that an increase in
                        voltage or a decrease in resistance increases the current flow.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>E = I &#215; R</para>
                    <para>This formula states that the voltage (E) applied to the circuit equals the current flow (I) in
                        the circuit multiplied by the total resistance (R) in the circuit. The voltage drop is caused by
                        resistance across a particular load device in a series of load devices.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>R = E &#247; l</para>
                    <para>This formula states that the total resistance (R) in the circuit equals the voltage (E)
                        applied to the circuit divided by the current flow (I) in the circuit. Resistance can be
                        calculated for a specific current flow when a specific voltage is applied.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f2400835" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6124.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Simple Electrical Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>In a typical circuit, battery voltage is applied to a bulb through a 10 amp fuse and a switch. Closing
                the switch turns on the bulb.
            </para>
            <para>To find the current flow, use the formula I = E &#247; R:</para>
            <para>Fill in the numbers for the formula:</para>
            <para>I = 12V &#247; 2 ohms</para>
            <para>I = 6 amps</para>
            <para>The bulb in this circuit operates at 6 amps and is rated at 6 amps. With 12 volts applied, the bulb
                will glow at the rated output level (candlepower rating). However,
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>if the voltage applied is low (low battery), the value of E is lower, current flow will be
                        less, and the bulb will glow less brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>if connections are loose or the switch is corroded, the circuit resistance will be greater
                        (value of R will be larger), the current flow will be reduced, and the bulb will glow less
                        brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Voltage drops are important for the following reasons:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>High voltage drops indicate excessive resistance. For example, if a blower motor runs too
                        slowly or a light glows too dimly, the circuit may have excessive resistance. Voltage drop
                        readings can isolate problems in parts of a circuit (corroded or loose terminals, for example).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Too low of a voltage drop indicates low resistance. For example, if a blower motor runs too
                        fast, the problem could be low resistance in a resistor pack.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maximum allowable voltage drop under load is critical, especially for more than one high
                        resistance problem. All voltage drops in a circuit are cumulative. Corroded terminals, loose
                        connections, damaged wires or other similar conditions create undesirable voltage drops that
                        decrease the voltage available across the key components in the circuit. Increased resistance
                        will decrease current flow in the circuit, preventing other components from operating at peak
                        efficiency. A small drop across wires (conductors), connectors, switches, etc., is normal
                        because all conductors have some resistance, but the total should be less than 10% of the total
                        voltage drop in the circuit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_200.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
