<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Engine Lubrication System -
        Oil Cooler and Filter Assemblies
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Oil Cooler and Filter Assemblies</title>
        <figure id="f305010138" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figJ13/J13035.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Oil cooler cover and oil filter base</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Unfiltered oil flow from pump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler outlet (oil)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Filtered oil to reservoir</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure test port fitting</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant inlet</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler bypass valve</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Filtered oil to crankcase galleries</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Unfiltered oil inlet</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil temperature sensor port</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger oil supply port</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure sensor port</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil filter drain to sump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant outlet</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler inlet (oil)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil drain to sump</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Pressurized oil from the oil pump flows through a passage in the front cover, through a passage in the
            upper crankcase, to the oil cooler cover. Passages in the oil cooler cover direct lube oil and coolant. Oil
            flows through plates in the oil cooler from the back to the front, cools, and flows back to the oil cooler
            cover.
        </para>
        <para>If the oil cooler is restricted, a bypass valve in the oil filter base opens, oil bypasses the oil cooler,
            and flows to the oil filter base.
        </para>
        <para>Oil flows through the oil filter base to the oil filter element outside to inside, up the outside of the
            filter stand pipe and down the inside of the stand pipe, and back to the oil filter base. If the oil filter
            element is restricted, a bypass valve in the oil filter return line opens, oil bypasses the oil filter
            element, and flows to the oil filter base.
        </para>
        <para>Both bypass valves ensure full flow of oil to the engine, if the filter or cooler is restricted.</para>
        <para>The oil filter base directs filtered oil to the turbocharger oil supply tube, EOP switch, EOT sensor,
            diagnostic port, and to the oil cooler cover. Lubricating oil from the turbocharger drains back to the oil
            pan through the high-pressure oil pump cover.
        </para>
        <para>When the oil filter is removed, oil flows from a drain valve in the oil filter base back to the oil pan.
        </para>
        <figure id="f3050139" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj13/J13043.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Oil reservoir in crankcase</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil feed to high-pressure oil pump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil filter drain to pan</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil feed to left side of main lube oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil feed to oil cooler cover</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil feed to right side of main lube oil gallery</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant feed to oil cooler</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The oil cooler cover and oil cooler base direct filtered oil in three ways:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>One passage supplies oil to the reservoir in the crankcase for the high-pressure oil pump and ICP
                    system. A screen in the oil reservoir catches debris before oil goes to the high-pressure oil pump.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>One passage supplies filtered oil to the left side for the main lube oil gallery, push rod and
                    rocker arms, piston cooling tubes, and lifters.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>One passage supplies filtered oil to the right side for the main lube oil gallery, push rods and
                    rocker arms, piston cooling tubes, camshaft bushings, crankshaft main bearings, connecting rod
                    bearings, primary balancer shaft bushings, and lifters.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_S305010106.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
