<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC SOFTWARE SELF TEST OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostics Overview</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750130" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8793.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Diagnostic Trouble Code Detection</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code Access Procedure</title>
            </para>
            <para>To display ECM Diagnostic Trouble Codes using the EST refer to Diagnostic Testing in Section 5 .
            </para>
            <para>To display ECM Diagnostic Trouble Codes when the EST is not available use the following procedure:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Set the parking brake and turn the Ignition Key ON.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Press and release the
                        <emph type="bold">CRUISE ON</emph>
                        button and the
                        <emph type="bold">RESUME/ACCEL</emph>
                        button simultaneously. If no faults are present, the cluster odometer will display NO FAULTS. If
                        codes are present they will be flashed out using the red and amber ENGINE lamps on the gauge
                        cluster.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>To read the Diagnostic Trouble Codes, count each time the amber
                <emph type="bold">ENGINE</emph>
                lamp flashes, continue with the following sequence below. This sequence occurs each time the Cruise
                Control buttons are depressed together to access the Diagnostic Trouble Codes.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The red ENGINE lamp will flash once to indicate the beginning of
                        <emph type="bold">ACTIVE</emph>
                        DTC's.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The amber ENGINE lamp will flash repeatedly signaling the Active DTC's.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE - All DTC's are three digits. Code 111 indicates no Diagnostic Trouble
                            Codes have been detected.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Count the flashes in sequence. After each digit of the code a short pause will occur. Three
                        flashes and a pause would indicate number 3. Two flashes, a pause, three flashes, a pause, and
                        two flashes and a pause would indicate Diagnostic Trouble Code 232. If there is more than one
                        DTC, the red ENGINE lamp will flash once indicating the beginning of another active DTC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>After all active DTC's have flashed, the red ENGINE lamp will flash twice to indicate the start of
                <emph type="bold">INACTIVE</emph>
                DTC's. Count the flashes from the amber ENGINE lamp. If there is more than one inactive code, the red
                ENGINE lamp will flash once between each DTC.
            </para>
            <para>After all DTC's have been sent, the red ENGINE lamp will flash three times indicating END OF
                MESSAGE.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To repeat DTC transmission, repeat the above procedure by depressing both Cruise Control
                        buttons. The ECM will once again send the stored DTC's.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Clearing Inactive Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Set park brake (required for correct ESC signal and to clear codes).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn key switch to the IGN/ON position.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Depress and hold the CRUISE ON and RESUME/ACCEL buttons simultaneously.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Continue holding the Cruise Control buttons. Depress and release the accelerator pedal three
                        (3) times within a six (6) second interval.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Release the Cruise Control buttons.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inactive codes will be cleared.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
