<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Engine Identification -
        Engine Description
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s01.1.4" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Engine Description</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s01.1.4.1">
            <table id="t3500001004" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Features and Specifications</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.20*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" valign="bottom">
                                <para>Engine configuration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" valign="bottom">
                                <para>4 stroke, V8 diesel</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Displacement</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>6.4 liters (389 in
                                    <supscript>3</supscript>)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Bore (sleeve diameter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>98.2 mm (3.87 in.)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Stroke</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>105 mm (4.134 in.)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Compression ratio</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>17.5:1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Aspiration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) and Charge Air Cooled (CAC)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Rated power @ rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>230 hp @ 2300 rpm
                                    <ftnote id="fn3050101">Initial rating at the time of manual printing, ratings are
                                        subject to change for various application. See EPA emission label for the exact
                                        rating for a particular engine.
                                    </ftnote>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Peak torque @ rpm</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>620 ft&#183;lbs @ 1500 rpm
                                    <ftnref xrefid="fn3050101"/>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Engine rotation (facing flywheel)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Counterclockwise</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Combustion system</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Direct injection, turbocharged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Fuel system</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Direct injection common rail</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Cooling system capacity (engine only)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>10.23 liters (10.8 quarts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Lube system capacity (including filter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>17 liters (18 quarts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Lube system capacity (overhaul only, with filter)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>18.9 liters (19 quarts US)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Firing order</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1-2-7-3-4-5-6-8</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s01.1.4.2">
            <title>Standard Features</title>
            <para>The International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 is a V8 engine with a displacement of 6.4 liters (389 cubic
                inches).
            </para>
            <para>The electronic governor controls the engine's rpm within a safe and stable operating range for ideal
                performance. Low idle governor prevents the engine rpm from dropping below a stable speed to prevent
                stalling when various loads are demanded on the engine. High idle governor prevents the engine rpm from
                going above a safe speed that would cause internal damage to the engine.
            </para>
            <para>The cylinder heads have four valves per cylinder. Each fuel injector is centrally located between the
                four valves and directs fuel over the piston bowl for improved performance and reduced emissions.
            </para>
            <para>The camshaft is supported by four bushings pressed into the crankcase. The camshaft is crankshaft
                driven and thrust is controlled by a plate mounted behind the fourth cam journal.
            </para>
            <para>The overhead valve train includes hydraulic roller cam followers, push rods, rocker arms, and valve
                bridges to open the dual intake and exhaust valves.
            </para>
            <para>The crankcase is comprised of two major matching components. The upper crankcase half houses the
                cylinders, main bearing saddles, with oil and coolant passages either cast or machined. The lower
                crankcase consists of a structural plate with the main bearing caps machined into it for improved load
                retention and alignment.
            </para>
            <para>The crankshaft is supported by five main bearings with fore and aft thrust controlled at the upper
                half of the second main bearing. Two connecting rods are attached to each crankshaft rod journal and are
                offset to minimize vibration. Piston pins are free floating, allowing the pins free lateral movement
                within the connecting rod as well as the piston. Piston pins are held in place with retaining rings.
            </para>
            <para>One piece aluminum-alloy pistons are fitted with one keystone ring, one rectangular intermediate
                compression ring, and a two piece oil control ring. The combustion bowl is located in the piston crown
                to reduce emissions. All pistons are mated to fractured cap joint connecting rods.
            </para>
            <para>The Crankshaft Position (CKP) sensor and Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor are used by the Electronic
                Control Module (ECM) to calculate rpm, fuel timing, fuel quantity, and duration of fuel injection.
            </para>
            <para>The Exhaust Gas Recirculating (EGR) system includes an EGR valve and an intake throttle valve. The EGR
                valve is mounted in an EGR mixer elbow that is part of the EGR valve elbow housing. The intake throttle
                valve is mounted on the other side of the EGR valve elbow housing in the air stream from the CAC.
            </para>
            <para>A gerotor lube oil pump is mounted in the front cover and is driven by the crankshaft. Pressurized oil
                is supplied to engine components. All MaxxForce&#8482; 7 engines use an engine oil cooler and engine oil
                filter.
            </para>
            <para>A closed crankcase breather system draws crankcase vapors through a breather element. The breather
                element separates the vapor and sends it to the air intake and returns the oil to the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>The low-pressure fuel pump draws fuel from the fuel tank(s) through the primary fuel filter. The
                primary fuel filter assembly includes a Water in Fuel (WIF) sensor and an optional fuel heater. Water
                and solids are separated from the fuel and the water is collected in the water separator bowl. The
                instrument panel WIF lamp is illuminated when water needs to be drained. A drain valve in the water
                separator bowl drains water out. Fuel is discharged to the secondary fuel filter. The secondary fuel
                filter assembly is pressure regulated and incorporates an air bleed orifice allowing air to be
                automatically purged if it has been introduced to the system.
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure fuel system includes a High-pressure Fuel Pump (HPFP), high-pressure common rails,
                and fuel injectors. The ECM electronically controls the injectors allowing multiple injections and more
                precise fuel delivery to improve combustion, emissions, and cold start performance.
            </para>
            <para>A hand operated primer pump is mounted on the right valve cover. The manual priming pump draws fuel
                from the fuel tank(s) through the primary filter after filter replacement or when system has run out of
                fuel. This primes the fuel system to minimize the amount of air injected into the system on initial
                startup.
            </para>
            <para>The Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) has actuated vanes in the turbine housing. These vanes modify
                exhaust gas flow through the VGT. The ECM commands the VGT to control boost pressure for various engine
                speeds and load conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The Exhaust Gas Recirculating (EGR) system circulates cooled exhaust into the intake air stream in the
                intake manifold. This cools the combustion process and reduces the formation of NOX engine emissions.
            </para>
            <para>Diamond Logic&#174; engine control is a single electronic control unit that monitors and controls the
                engine and chassis components.
            </para>
            <para>The glow plug relay controls the eight glow plugs, one for each cylinder. The glow plugs warm the
                cylinders during start-up.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Optional Features</title>An air compressor is available for applications that require air brakes
                or air suspension.
            </para>
            <para>A coolant heater is available to raise the temperature of the coolant surrounding the cylinders for
                improved performance during cold weather startups.
            </para>
            <para>A fuel heater is available and installed in the primary fuel filter assembly and warms the supply
                fuel. Warmed supply fuel prevents waxing, and improves performance and fuel economy during cold weather
                start-up.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Chassis Mounted Features</title>A Charge Air Cooler (CAC) is an air-to-air heat exchanger which
                increases the density of the air charge.
            </para>
            <para>The Aftertreatment System processes engine exhaust so that it meets emissions requirements at the
                tailpipe.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The oxidation catalyst burns oxygen and hydrocarbons in the exhaust stream.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The DPF captures and burns particulates in the exhaust stream.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
