<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Symptoms
        Diagnostics - Problems and Conditions - Low Power (Turbocharger Assembly and Actuator)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Low Power (Turbocharger Assembly and Actuator)</title>
        <para>
            <title>Symptom</title>
        </para>
        <para>Excessive low power on take-off or intermittent low power from drive cycle to drive cycle</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Cause</title>
            <item>
                <para>Electrical power or ground issue</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Inoperative turbocharger assembly</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Failed turbocharger actuator</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Tools</title>
            <item>
                <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Turbo Breakout Harness</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>12-pin Breakout Harness</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch to OFF.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Move turbocharger linkage through its full range of motion by hand. Linkage should move
                    smoothly and not chatter or hesitate.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Do a bounce test by moving turbocharger linkage all the way out towards frame rail and
                    let it go. Linkage should move towards engine, bounce, and stay there.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If linkage moves smoothly, do step 2.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If linkage does not move smoothly, remove turbocharger actuator and move linkage through
                            its full range of motion.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>If linkage moves smoothly, replace turbocharger actuator.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If linkage does not move smoothly, replace turbocharger assembly.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch to ON. Watch turbocharger linkage during pre-cycle movement.
                Linkage should move all the way out towards frame rail, move all the way back in towards engine, and
                move back out about half way.
            </para>
            <para>Check pre-cycle three times with at least three seconds of key-off time between tests. Linkage should
                move through pre-cycle smoothly and not chatter, vibrate, hesitate or slow down during pre-cycle. Each
                pre-cycle should be completed in less than one second.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When pre-cycle is complete with key-on engine-off, the linkage should not move by hand.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If pre-cycle fails, do step 3.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If pre-cycle passes, the turbocharger or actuator may not be cause of low power.</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Verify that all tests on Performance Diagnostic form do not indicate another cause.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If the low power complaint is intermittent, and all tests on Performance Diagnostic
                                form do not indicate another cause, do step 3.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect turbocharger breakout harness between engine harness and actuator harness. Measure
                voltage between actuator power and ground terminals with key-on engine-off.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If pre-cycle fails, and voltage is 10 V or more, replace the actuator.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If low power complaint is intermittent, and voltage is 10 V or more, inspect turbocharger
                        power and ground wires for corroded or loose connections.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>If power and ground wires are properly connected, not corroded, and performance
                                diagnostic tests do not indicate another cause of low power, replace the actuator.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If voltage is low, repair low voltage problem. See
                        <hotlnk document="eges270_161.xml" xrefid="s27005028">"VGT Actuator"</hotlnk>
                        in Section 7 .
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Go to step 2 and test again.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The turbocharger actuator can be tested again with a known good power and ground supplied
                        directly through turbocharger actuator breakout harness.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_76.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_E2700105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
