<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diagnostic Software
        Operation - Diagnostic Tests - Relative Compression
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Relative Compression</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>During this test the IDM shuts off the injectors so no fueling occurs.</para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>The Relative Compression test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is
                    required.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>This test is used in conjunction with the Injector Disable test to distinguish between an injector
                    problem or a mechanical problem.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The Relative Compression test provides the difference between the fastest and slowest crankshaft speed
            during the power stroke of each cylinder.
        </para>
        <para>As the engine is cranked, the IDM uses the CMP and CKP sensor signals to measure crankshaft speed, as
            piston reaches two points: Top Dead Center (TDC) compression and about 30 degrees after TDC compression.
        </para>
        <para>When the piston approaches TDC, crankshaft speed should be slower because of compression resistance. As
            the piston passes TDC, compression resistance dissipates and crankshaft speed increases.
        </para>
        <para>At TDC compression, the cylinder reaches its highest compression and resistance to crankshaft rotation -
            Crankshaft speed is the slowest. A cylinder with low compression will have less resistance to crankshaft
            rotation. Crankshaft speed will be faster than normal.
        </para>
        <para>About 30 degrees after TDC, crankshaft speed should be fastest because compression has dissipated. On a
            cylinder that has low compression, crankshaft speed will be close to, or less than crankshaft speed at TDC.
        </para>
        <para>At TDC of each power cylinder, and about 30 degrees past TDC, the IDM collects data for crankshaft
            speed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If not cranked long enough to collect data, the EST will display 255. 255 represents an erroneous
                    rpm value
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The TDC value is subtracted from the value about 30 degrees after TDC and is recorded for each cylinder.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>
        </para>
        <para>200 rpm (30 degrees after TDC) - 180 rpm (TDC) = 20 rpm</para>
        <para>The EZ-Tech&#174; will display a value on the screen for each cylinder.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f27003048" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31310.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>Compare the compression values of each cylinder with the other cylinder values. A cylinder with
            compression lower than the other cylinders indicates a suspect cylinder. Test value of 18 for cylinder one
            indicates a suspect cylinder.
        </para>
        <para>If a cylinder value is zero or a much lower than other cylinders and this cylinder is a non-contributor
            (identified in the Injector Disable Test), check for a mechanical problem.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f27003049" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>If TDC rpm is greater than rpm 30 degrees after TDC, the EST will display 0.</para>
        <para>If the test value for a power cylinder is 0, the cylinder is suspect.</para>
        <para>If the test value for a power cylinder is significantly below 15 rpm, the cylinder is suspect.</para>
        <para>Test value 5 for cylinder 1 indicates a suspect cylinder. Test value 0 for cylinder 6 indicates a suspect
            cylinder.
        </para>
        <para>When the Relative Compression test is done, the EST indicates, stop cranking the engine, and will display
            test values.
        </para>
        <para>Test data displayed in this test should be compared with data collected from the Injector Disable test.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                    safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Batteries must be fully charged before doing this test. Use battery charger during this test, if
                    multiple tests are needed; battery drain can be extensive.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>Read and be familiar with all steps and time limits in this procedure before starting.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f27003050" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh31/H31236.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Relative Compression test</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select Relative Compression Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Follow the messages at the bottom of the window.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Turn the ignition switch to ON.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Select Run.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, after clicking
                        Run, turn the ignition switch, within 5 seconds, to crank the engine; if not done in 5 seconds,
                        the IDM will cancel the test and the engine will start.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Within 5 seconds of selecting run, crank engine for 15 seconds. Another message will read Stop
                        Cranking within 5 seconds.
                        <emph type="bold">Do not turn the ignition switch to OFF</emph>.
                        <emph type="bold">If the ignition switch is turned to OFF, test results will be lost</emph>.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If test results are identical to previous test results, the current test failed and the
                        previous results were displayed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Interpret results.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If a Relative Compression test and Injector Disable test identify a suspect cylinder, check
                        for a mechanical problem.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a Relative Compression test does not identify a suspect cylinder, but the Injector Disable
                        test does, replace suspect injector(s).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_58.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_60.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
