<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System - Actuators</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.2" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Actuators</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s3050107.2.1">
            <table id="t305010111" frame="topbot">
                <title>The ECM controls engine operation with the following:</title>
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>EGR valve and drive module</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Intake air heater relay</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Glow plug relay</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Boost Control Solenoid (BCS)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>HFCM control</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para></para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.2">
            <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve and Drive Module</title>
            <para>The EGR valve controls the flow of exhaust gases to the intake manifold.</para>
            <para>The EGR drive module controls the EGR actuator.</para>
            <para>The EGR drive module receives the desired EGR valve position from the ECM across the CAN2 datalink to
                activate the valve for exhaust gas recirculation. The EGR drive module provides feedback to the ECM on
                the valve position.
            </para>
            <para>The EGR drive module constantly monitors the EGR valve position. When an EGR control error is
                detected, the EGR drive module sends a message to the ECM and a DTC is set.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.3">
            <title>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve</title>
            <para>The IPR valve controls pressure in the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system to actuate the fuel
                injectors. The IPR valve is a variable position valve controlled by switching the ground circuit in the
                ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.4">
            <title>Intake air heater relay</title>
            <para>The ECM activates the intake air heater relay. The relay delivers V
                <subscript>bat</subscript>
                to the intake air heater for up to 30 seconds, depending on engine oil temperature and altitude. The
                ground circuit is supplied directly from the battery ground at all times. Relay is controlled by
                switching on a voltage source from the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.5">
            <title>Glow plug relay</title>
            <para>The ECM activates the glow plug relay. The relay delivers V
                <subscript>bat</subscript>
                to the glow plugs for up to 120 seconds, depending on engine coolant temperature and altitude. The
                ground circuit is supplied directly from the battery ground at all times. Relay is controlled by
                switching on a voltage source from the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.6">
            <title>Boost Control Solenoid (BCS) Assembly</title>
            <para>The BCS controls boost pressure to the turbocharger pneumatic actuator. The BCS is a variable position
                valve controlled by switching the power circuit from the ECM. The pneumatic actuator control the
                turbocharger bypass valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s3050107.2.7">
            <title>Horizontal Fuel Conditioning Module (HFCM)</title>
            <para>The ECM sends a signal to the fuel pump relay that controls power to the HFCM fuel pump.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
