<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEMS DIAGNOSTICS - Circuit Diagnostics -
        Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) Actuator
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) Actuator</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>For 2004 Model Year EGR Diagnostics, see
                <exhotlnk document="../tsis/041210r.htm" bookname="tsi">TSI-04-12-10R</exhotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3302" filename="../figd33/d3302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for the Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) Actuator</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The Function Diagram for the EGR actuator includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) actuator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation Position (EGRP) sensor</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The EGR actuator consists of two components, a valve with actuator (solenoid) and a position sensor to
                monitor valve movement. The EGR is at the front of the engine on top of the intake manifold.
            </para>
            <para>The EGR actuator is a variable position valve that controls the amount of exhaust that enters the
                intake system. The EGR valve is controlled by the ECM using a pulse width modulated signal. The system
                is closed loop using the EGRP as input. Other inputs that are used to calculate the desired position of
                the EGR valve include BAP, EBP, MAT, VGT control, MAP, APS, and EOT.
            </para>
            <para>The EGRP sensor is a potentiometer sensor. When the EGRP receives a 5V reference signal and a ground
                from the ECM, a linear analog voltage signal from the sensor will indicate position of the EGR valve.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EGR Circuit Operation</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3301" filename="../figd33/d3301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>EGR Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The EGR actuator receives 12V to terminal E from ECM power relay. The ECM controls the EGR through
                terminal A by grounding terminal X2-19 with a pulse width modulated signal. Precise control is gained by
                varying the percentage of ON/OFF time of the EGR coil. A high duty cycle indicates more force on the
                valve to open . A low duty cycle indicates less force on the valve to open.
            </para>
            <para>The EGRP is supplied a 5 volt reference at terminal D from ECM terminal X1-14. The EGRP sensor is also
                supplied at terminal B from ECM terminal X1-6. The EGRP sensor sends a signal from terminal C of the
                sensor to ECM terminal to X2-9.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            </para>
            <para>An open or short to ground in the EGR control circuit can be detected by an on demand output circuit
                check during KOEO Standard test. If there is a circuit fault detected a DTC will be set.
            </para>
            <para>When the EGRP signal voltage is detected out of range high or low, the ECM will cause the engine to
                ignore the EGRP signal and the EGR valve will close and the amber ENGINE lamp will be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>The EGRP sensor is calibrated to zero position each time the key is cycled to allow compensation if
                carbon deposits develop on the valve. If the deposits get so heavy that the position is out of range to
                zero, a DTC will be set, the valve will close, and the amber ENGINE lamp will be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>The EGR actuator can also be tested for a stuck or sticking valve by performing an Output State Low
                Test while monitoring EGRP percentage. See Performance Diagnostic Section 6 for additional information.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>EGR Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTCs are read using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by counting the flashes from the amber and
                red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc163">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 163</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">EGRP signal out of range low</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 163 is set by the ECM the EGRP voltage is less than 0.3V for more than 0.35 second.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 163 can be set due to an open or short to ground on the signal circuit, a defective sensor
                        or an open V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        circuit or V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        short to ground.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 163 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc164">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 164</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">EGRP signal out of range high</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 164 is set by the ECM when the EGRP voltage is greater than 4.5V for more than 0.35
                        second.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 164 can be set due to an open or short to ground on the signal circuit, a defective sensor
                        or an open V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        circuit or V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        short to ground.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 164 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc264">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 264</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">EGR OCC self test failed</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 264 is set by the ECM when the OCC test fails after the Key ON Engine OFF Standard test
                        has been run.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 264 can be set due to open or shorts to ground, short to voltage source in the EGR control
                        circuit, or a defective coil.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Tools</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Service Tool (EST) with Master Diagnostics software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>International&#174; EZ-Tech Interface Cable</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Harness - 3-Banana and 500 ohm</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout box</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Terminal Test Adapter Kit</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EGR Operational Diagnostics</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3328" filename="../figd33/d3328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>EGR Circuit Diagram with Breakout harness</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle -
                        comply with the following:
                    </para>
                    <para>Be careful to avoid rotating parts (belts and fan) and hot engine surfaces.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using EST, open the continuous monitor session. To monitor signal voltage, run Key ON
                    Engine OFF continuous monitor test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monitor EGR signal volts. Verify an active DTC for the EGR circuit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If code is active, complete step 5 and do circuit check for the EGR sensor in table on
                    the following page.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If code is inactive, wiggle connectors and wires at all suspected problem locations. If
                    circuit continuity is interrupted, the EST will beep and display DTCs related to the condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install EGR breakout harness to engine harness only.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector, inspect for damaged pins, corrosion, or loose terminals. Repair as
                        required.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te24007047" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="topbot">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.18in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.93in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Circuit Checks for EGR Sensor</emph>
                                    (Use EST, DMM, breakout harness, and 500 ohm wire harness.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Checks</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Sensor disconnected</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If voltage >0.039V, check signal circuit for short to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Voltage from PIN D to ground with DMM.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>5V &#177;0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If voltage >5.5V, check V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    for short to B+. If voltage is &#60;4.5V, check V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    for open or short to ground. Remove the negative battery cable. Use breakout box and
                                    measure resistance from PIN D to X1-14 (spec &#60;5&#x2126;) to check for a short to
                                    ground or open in the harness.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>500 ohm harness installed between GREEN and BLUE wires of breakout harness.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>5V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If voltage &#60;4.55V, check signal circuit for open or short to ground. Remove
                                    negative battery cable. Measure resistance from PIN C to ground (spec >1k&#x2126;)
                                    to check for short to ground. Use a breakout box from PIN C to PIN X2-9 (spec &#60;5&#x2126;)
                                    to check for open in the harness.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Resistance from BLACK wire of breakout harness to chassis ground using DMM.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If resistance is >5&#x2126;, check for open or high resistance between ECM and
                                    sensor connector. Use a breakout box and measure resistance from between PIN B and
                                    PIN X1-6 (spec &#60;5&#x2126;).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine harness to sensor. Use the EST to clear DTCs. If an active code remains
                    after checking test conditions, replace the EGR valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EGR Pin Point Diagnostics</title>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3328" filename="../figd33/d3328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>EGR Circuit Diagram with Breakout harness</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te24007048" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="bottom">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.94in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <warning>
                                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or
                                        vehicle, always disconnect main negative battery cable first. Always connect the
                                        main negative battery cable last.
                                    </para>
                                </warning>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Connector Voltage Checks</emph>
                                    (Install EGR breakout harness between EGR valve and harness. Turn ignition key ON
                                    and engine OFF.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>2.0 to 10V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If not in spec, check for control circuit shorted to B+ or ground</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Signal ground (no voltage expected). If voltage is present, check for short to B+
                                    or V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;0.25V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >2.5V, signal circuit is shorted to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>D to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>5V &#177;0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If voltage not to spec, V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    circuit is shorted to gnd or B+
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>E to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>B+</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>EGR power from V
                                    <subscript>IGN</subscript>. If no voltage, check from EGR to voltage source. See
                                    truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram manual.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Resistance Checks to Chassis Ground</emph>
                                    (Install EGR breakout harness on engine harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If &#60;1k&#x2126;, control circuit short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, signal ground has open or high resistance.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If &#60;1k&#x2126;, EGRP signal short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>D to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>>500&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If &#60;500&#x2126;, V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    short to ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>E to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If &#60;1k&#x2126;, short to ground exists. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit
                                    Diagram manual.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Checks at EGR Valve Harness to Breakout Box
                                        ECM
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn ignition key OFF. Install breakout box and EGR breakout harness on engine
                                    harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A to X2-19</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, ground wire open.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>B to X1-6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    wire open.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>C to X2-9</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, EGRP signal wire open.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>D to X1-14</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    wire open.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>E to power relay</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If >5&#x2126;, open circuit to power relay.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">EGR Operational Voltage Checks</emph>
                                    (Check with breakout box installed to ECM and engine harness.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X2-9 to X1-6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0.6 - 1.2V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>EGR Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 163 = Signal voltage was &#60;0.3V for more than 0.35 second</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 164 = Signal voltage was >4.2V for more than 0.35 second</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>DTC 264 = EGR OCC self test failed</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_148.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_150.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
