<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Electronic Control
        Systems Diagnostics - Circuit Diagnostics - Brake Shut-off Valve
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Brake Shut-off Valve</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f27007026" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31326.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Function diagram for the Brake Shut-off Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para id="s27005012">The function diagram for the brake shut-off valve includes the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para id="bsv">Engine Oil Temperature (EOT) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Speed Control Command Switches (SCCS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine brake switches</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator Position / Idle Validation (APS/IVS) sensors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake pedal</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake shut-off valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) actuator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) actuator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ENGINE lamp (amber)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The brake shut-off valve controls pressure in the oil gallery of the high-pressure oil rail. When the
                engine brake is activated, the ECM provides power to activate the brake shut-off valve to allow oil from
                the injector oil gallery to flow to the brake oil gallery. High oil pressure activates the brake
                actuator pistons to open the exhaust valves.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM removes the power from the brake shut-off valve to deactivate the engine brake. Residual brake
                gallery pressure initially bleeds from the actuator bore. When brake gallery pressure reaches 1000 psi,
                the brake pressure relief valve opens, and oil drains back to sump.
            </para>
            <para>The brake shut-off valve consists of a solenoid and valve assembly and is located in the center of the
                high-pressure oil rail.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM monitors the following criteria to make sure certain conditions are met.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>ABS (inactive)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>RPM (greater than 1200)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APS (less than 5%)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EOT (greater than 60 &#176;C [140 &#176;F])</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle validation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Operator input switches (On/Off) (power selection - Low, Medium, High)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Shut-off Valve Circuit Operation</title>
            <figure id="f27007027" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The brake shut-off valve is supplied ground to Pin 1 from the battery through Pin 4 of the 12-pin
                connector and then through Pin A of the valve cover gasket. The ECM controls the engine brake by
                supplying 12 volts through Pin C of the valve cover gasket to Pin 2 of the brake shut-off valve.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            </para>
            <para>An open or short to ground in the brake shut-off valve control circuit can be detected by an on demand
                Output Circuit Check (OCC) during KOEO Standard Test. If there is a circuit fault detected a DTC will be
                set.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine is running, the ECM compares engine brake control pressure to injection control
                pressure and BCP desired. When the brake is activated, brake control pressure will equal injection
                control pressure.
            </para>
            <para>If the brake control pressure does not match injection control pressure, the ECM will disable the
                engine brake, a DTC will be set, and the amber ENGINE lamp will be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine brake is not active and the ECM detects an undesired value, the ECM will set a DTC and
                the amber ENGINE lamp will be illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>A bias BCP sensor can also cause the fault. The brake shut-off valve and the BCP sensor circuit should
                both be diagnosed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Brake Shut-off Valve Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTCs are read using the EST or by counting the flashes from the amber and red ENGINE lamp.</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 247</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine brake enable OCC self-test failed</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 247 is set by the ECM when the OCC test has failed after the KOEO Standard Test has been
                        run.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 247 can be set when a poor connection, an open or short to ground in the brake shut-off
                        valve control circuit, or a failed brake shut-off valve solenoid exists.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 247 is active the amber ENGINE lamp will be illuminated.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 546</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine brake control pressure below expected range</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 546 is set by the ECM when the brake control pressure is less than injection control
                        pressure 4 MPa (580 psi) for more than 3 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 546 can be set due to a bias low BCP sensor or a failed BCP sensor. See "Brake Control
                        Pressure (BCP) Sensor - Section 7.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 546 can be set due to an open control circuit (power or ground), a failed brake shut-off
                        valve, or a failed brake shut-off valve solenoid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 546 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 547</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine brake control pressure above expected range</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 547 is set by the ECM when the brake control pressure is greater than desired brake
                        control pressure by 4.5 MPa (653 psi) for more than 3 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 547 can be set due to an open signal ground, V
                        <subscript>REF</subscript>
                        shorted to a voltage source higher than 5.5 V, or a failed BCP sensor. See "Brake Control
                        Pressure (BCP) Sensor - Section 7.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 547 can be set due to a control circuit short to B+ or a brake shut-off valve stuck
                        open.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 547 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>EST with MasterDiagnostics&#174; software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EZ-Tech&#174; interface cable</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VC Gasket Breakout Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12-Pin Breakout Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>500 Ohm Resistor Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout Box</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Terminal Test Adapter Kit</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Shut-off Valve Pin-Point Diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket connector)</title>
            <figure id="f27007028" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te27007025" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1" align="center">
                                <note>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Complete all pin-point diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket
                                            connector) before removing valve cover for under-valve-cover diagnostics.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>Turn the ignition switch to OFF before disconnecting engine wiring
                                                harness connectors from components.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for circuit
                                                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Actuator Control Voltage Check at Valve Cover Gasket Connector
                                    </emph>
                                    (Disconnect engine harness from valve cover gasket. Inspect for bent pins or
                                    corrosion. Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to engine harness and valve cover
                                    gasket. Turn the ignition switch to ON.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, continue with next test point, C to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, control wire is shorted to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+, or an open ground, open control circuit, or open solenoid exists.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, ground wire is shorted to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Output State Test - Signal Check at Valve Cover Gasket Connector
                                    </emph>
                                    (Disconnect engine harness from valve cover gasket. Connect VC Gasket Breakout
                                    Harness to engine harness and valve cover gasket. Run the Output State Tests. For
                                    help, see
                                    <hotlnk document="eges270_51.xml" xrefid="s27007029">"Diagnostic Software
                                        Operation"
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    in Section 3 for procedure to run the Low and High Output State Tests.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test State/Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Setting/Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>KOEO</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, disconnect VC Gasket Breakout Harness from gasket. Connect 500 Ohm
                                    Resistor Harness between C and A and retest.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If > 0.25 V, run the Low and High Output State Test.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; 0.25 V, the concern is the valve cover gasket, UVC wiring, or
                                            brake shut-off valve.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - Low</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, disconnect VC Gasket Breakout Harness from gasket. Connect 500 Ohm
                                    Resistor Harness between C and A and retest Output State Test - Low.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If > 0.25 V the concern is the engine harness or ECM, check for a short to
                                            B+ or V
                                            <subscript>REF</subscript>.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; 0.25 V, the concern is the valve cover gasket, UVC wiring, or
                                            Brake Shut-off Valve.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - High</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B+ &#177; 0.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; B+, disconnect VC Gasket Breakout Harness from gasket. Connect 500 Ohm
                                    Resistor Harness between C and A and retest and retest Output State Test - High.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If equal to B+ the concern is the valve cover gasket, UVC wiring, or Brake
                                            Shut-off Valve. Check for short to ground or open on control circuit, or
                                            open ground circuit.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; B+ the concern is the engine harness or ECM. Check the ECM
                                            programming and check for a short to ground or open control circuit. Do the
                                            <hotlnk xrefid="BSV3">Actuator Control Voltage Check at ECM</hotlnk>
                                            and
                                            <hotlnk xrefid="BSV1">Harness Resistance Checks</hotlnk>
                                            .
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <figure id="f27007029" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te27007026" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.76*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <note>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Complete all pin-point diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket
                                            connector) before removing valve cover for under-valve-cover diagnostics.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>Turn the ignition switch to OFF before disconnecting engine wiring
                                                harness connectors from components.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for circuit
                                                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para id="BSV3">
                                    <emph type="bold">Actuator Control Voltage Check at ECM</emph>
                                    (Connect breakout box [X2 only] to ECM and engine harness. Engine harness is not
                                    connected to valve cover gasket. Connect 500 Ohm Resistor Harness to X2-18 and
                                    ground. Turn the ignition switch to ON. Run Low and High Output State Test. For
                                    help, see
                                    <hotlnk document="eges270_51.xml" xrefid="s27007029">"Diagnostic Software
                                        Operation"
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    in Section 3 for procedure to run the Low and High Output State Tests. Measure
                                    across X2-18 and ground.)
                                </para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test State/Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Setting/Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>KOEO</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>X2 - 18 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, disconnect engine harness from breakout box harness and retest.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If > 0.25 V, run the Low and High Output State Tests.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; 0.25 V, diagnose engine wiring harness. Check for short to V
                                            <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                            or B+.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - Low</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>X2 - 18 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, disconnect engine harness from breakout box harness and retest.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; 0.25 V, diagnose engine wiring harness. Check for short to V
                                            <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                            or B+.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If > 0.25 V with breakout box connected only to ECM, replace ECM.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - High</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>X2 - 18 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B+ &#177; 0.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; B+, disconnect engine harness from breakout box harness and retest.
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If equal to B+, diagnose engine wiring harness. Do
                                            <hotlnk xrefid="BSV1">Harness Resistance Checks</hotlnk>
                                            . Check for short to ground or open circuit.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; B+ with breakout box connected only to ECM, replace the ECM.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <figure id="f27007030" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te27007027" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.56*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.35*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.09*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <note>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Complete all pin-point diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket
                                            connector) before removing valve cover for under-valve-cover diagnostics.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>Turn the ignition switch to OFF before disconnecting engine wiring
                                                harness connectors from components.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for circuit
                                                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para id="bsv1">
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket Connector to ECM
                                        Chassis Ground
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnote id="f1">Connector 9260 is a 2-wire connector usually located in the battery
                                        box. Pin A is the ground connection for the ECM and IDM. See truck Chassis
                                        Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for complete chassis side ECM and IDM ground
                                        circuit information.</ftnote>. Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to engine
                                    wiring harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to Pin A (9260)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for an open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to Pin A (9260)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 1 k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 1 k&#x2126;, check for short to ground within wiring harness.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <warning>
                                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or
                                        vehicle, always disconnect main negative battery cable first. Always connect the
                                        main negative battery cable last.
                                    </para>
                                </warning>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket Connector to Chassis
                                        Ground
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnref xrefid="f1"/>. Disconnect negative battery cable. Disconnect harness from
                                    valve cover gasket. Use disconnected negative battery cable for ground test point.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 500 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 500 &#x2126;, check for short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 1 k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 1 k&#x2126;, check for short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - 12-Pin Connector to ECM Chassis
                                        Ground
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Connect 12-pin Breakout Harness to chassis wiring
                                    harness only. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnref xrefid="f1"/>.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4 to Pin A (9260)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for open in chassis wiring harness ground circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - 12-Pin Connector to Chassis Ground
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnref xrefid="f1"/>. Disconnect negative battery cable. Disconnect 12-pin
                                    connector and use chassis side for test point. Use disconnected negative battery
                                    cable for ground test point.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4 to gnd cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 500 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 500 &#x2126;, check for short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket Connector to 12-Pin
                                        Connector
                                    </emph>
                                    (Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to engine wiring harness only. Connect 12-Pin
                                    Breakout Harness to engine wiring harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to 4
                                    <ftnref xrefid="V-DC"/>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for open in actuator ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket Connector to ECM
                                    </emph>
                                    (Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to engine wiring harness only. Connect breakout
                                    box X2 to engine wiring harness only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to X2-18</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for open in control wire.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket, UVC Wiring, and Brake
                                        Shut-off Valve/Solenoid
                                    </emph>
                                    (Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to valve cover gasket only.)
                                </para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>10 &#x2126; &#177; 2 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If > 12 &#x2126;, the concern is the valve cover gasket, UVC wiring, or
                                            brake shut-off valve/solenoid. Do
                                            <hotlnk xrefid="BSV2">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket
                                                Connector to UVC Connector
                                            </hotlnk>
                                            and
                                            <hotlnk xrefid="BSV2">Solenoid Resistance Check - Brake Shut-off Valve
                                            </hotlnk>
                                            .
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If &#60; 8 &#x2126;, a short to ground exists. The concern is the valve
                                            cover gasket, UVC wiring, or brake shut-off valve/solenoid.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Shut-off Valve Pin-Point Diagnostics (ECM to brake valve - valve cover removed)</title>
            <figure id="f27007031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te27007028" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1" align="center">
                                <note>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Complete all pin-point diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket
                                            connector) before removing valve cover for under-valve-cover diagnostics.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>Turn the ignition switch to OFF before disconnecting engine wiring
                                                harness connectors from components.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for circuit
                                                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Actuator Control Voltage Check at UVC Connector</emph>
                                    (Remove valve cover following procedure in the Engine Service Manual. Disconnect UVC
                                    connector from valve. Use the Terminal Test Adapter Kit to connect the 500 Ohm
                                    Resistor harness to the UVC connector Pin 2 and ground. Turn the ignition switch to
                                    ON.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, continue with next test point, 2 to chassis ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to chassis gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, control wire is shorted to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 to chassis gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, ground wire is shorted to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Output State Test - Signal Check at UVC Connector</emph>
                                    (Disconnect UVC connector from valve. Use the Terminal Test Adapter Kit to connect
                                    the 500 Ohm Resistor harness to the UVC connector Pin 2 and ground. Run the Output
                                    State Tests. For help, see
                                    <hotlnk document="eges270_51.xml" xrefid="s27007029">"Diagnostic Software
                                        Operation"
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    in Section 3 for procedure to run the Low and High Output State Tests. Measure
                                    across adapter and ground.)
                                </para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test State/Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Setting/Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - Low</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0 V to 0.25 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 0.25 V, and all pin-point diagnostic tests (ECM to valve cover gasket) were
                                    in spec, the valve cover gasket or UVC wiring are suspect. Check for short to V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    or B+.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Output State Test - High</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>DMM set to V - DC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Toggling between the Low and High Output State Tests can be done during this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B+ &#177; 0.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; B+, and all pin-point diagnostic tests (ECM to valve cover gasket) were
                                    in spec, the valve cover gasket or UVC wiring are suspect. Check for short to
                                    ground, open control wire, or open ground wire. Do
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="BSV2">Harness Resistance Checks</hotlnk>
                                    .
                                </para>
                                <para>If equal to B+, and all pin-point diagnostic tests (ECM to valve cover gasket)
                                    were in spec, do
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="BSV2">Solenoid Resistance Check - Brake Shut-off Valve</hotlnk>
                                    .
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <figure id="f27007032" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Brake Shut-off Valve circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <table id="te2700128" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot" numbered="no">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.53*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.35*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.12*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <note>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Complete all pin-point diagnostics (ECM to valve cover gasket
                                            connector) before removing valve cover for under-valve-cover diagnostics.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>Turn the ignition switch to OFF before disconnecting engine wiring
                                                harness connectors from components.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for circuit
                                                numbers, connector and fuse locations.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para id="BSV2">
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - UVC Connector to ECM Chassis Ground
                                    </emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnote id="f1">Connector 9260 is a 2-wire connector usually located in the battery
                                        box. Pin A is the ground connection for the ECM and IDM. See truck Chassis
                                        Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual for complete chassis side ECM and IDM ground
                                        circuit information.</ftnote>.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 to Pin A (9260)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for an open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to Pin A (9260)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 1 k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 1 k&#x2126;, check for short to ground within wiring harness.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - UVC Connector to Chassis Ground</emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to OFF. Disconnect chassis connector 9260
                                    <ftnref xrefid="f1"/>. Disconnect negative battery cable. Disconnect harness from
                                    valve. Use disconnected negative battery cable for ground test point.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 to gnd cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 500 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 500 &#x2126;, check for short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to gnd cable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>> 1 k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; 1 k&#x2126;, check for short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Check - Valve Cover Gasket Connector to UVC
                                        Connector
                                    </emph>
                                    (Connect VC Gasket Breakout Harness to valve cover gasket only.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for open in actuator ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to 2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 5 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If > 5 &#x2126;, check for open in control wire.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Solenoid Resistance Check - Brake Shut-off Valve</emph>
                                    (Measure across terminals of solenoid.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2 to 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>10 &#x2126; &#177; 2 &#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If not to specification, replace brake shut-off valve.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_129.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_131.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
