<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYMPTOMS DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - Smoke</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Smoke</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Black Smoke Diagnostics</title>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Air intake or exhaust restriction</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turbocharger failure, turbocharger blade damage or turbocharger wheel stuck</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose injector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Altitude (black smoke on hard acceleration or snap acceleration may be pronounced at higher
                        elevations)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor defective</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Procedures</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine has fuel knock or there is evidence of fuel in the exhaust, remove exhaust
                    manifolds and inspect for fuel in the exhaust ports. (Suspect loose injectors, missing or damaged
                    O-ring and gasket on bottom of injector).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air inlet system and exhaust system for possible sources of restriction.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect turbocharger for oil leakage or failure of blades. Some oil carryover
                    is expected due to the closed crankcase ventilation system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 9 (Intake Restriction) on Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 or in Section 6
                    of this manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 11 (Exhaust Restriction) on form EGED-250 or in Section 6 of this manual.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>White Smoke Diagnostics</title>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cold engine</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No glow plug operation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor quality fuel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR stuck open on startup</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant leak to combustion from exhaust side</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose fuel injectors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective fuel injectors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Bent connecting rods</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn piston rings</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low compression</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant leaking into combustion chamber</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake manifold porosity</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Procedures</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">In cold ambient temperatures, some white smoke is normal until the engine is up to
                    operating temperature.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Ensure that engine is up to operating temperature 88&#176;C (190&#176;F) prior to
                            verifying a white smoke complaint.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the engine is unable to obtain operating temperature during a road test, verify
                            thermostat opening temperature 88&#176;C (190&#176;F).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On a cold engine, the glow plug system may remain on for up to two minutes after the
                    engine starts to assist in cold smoke cleanup. Do Tests 15A and 15B (Glow Plug System) on Hard Start
                    and No Start Diagnostics form EGED-245 to verify glow plug operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 2 (Fuel) on Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250. Verify quality and quantity
                    of diesel fuel. Poor quality fuel or low cetane rating can cause white smoking, engine misfire and
                    low power. Refer to the Engine Operation and Maintenance Manual, Fuel Requirements section for model
                    and year of engine to determine minimum necessary fuel grade and cetane rating.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 10 (EGR Position) on Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 if operator complaint
                    is white smoke on start-up only. Do test according to condition of operator complaint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is coolant loss without engine overheating, check for coolant in exhaust.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant is leaking from exhaust or can be smelled in the exhaust, refer to Coolant Leak
                            to Exhaust diagnostics in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine has fuel knock or evidence of fuel in exhaust, remove exhaust manifolds and
                    inspect for fuel in the exhaust ports. (Suspect loose injectors, missing or damaged O-ring and
                    copper gasket on bottom of injector).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect air induction system for evidence of water ingestion or evidence of unfiltered
                    air entering the engine.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Water ingestion could have caused a hydraulic lock and bent connecting rods. If water
                            ingestion is suspected, identify smoking cylinders by removing exhaust manifolds and running
                            engine.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Unfiltered air entering the engine can cause excessive power cylinder wear and
                            turbocharger compressor blade damage. If power cylinder wear is suspected, identify smoking
                            cylinder(s) by removing exhaust manifolds and running engine.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If coolant is found in the intake manifold, refer to Coolant Leak to Exhaust diagnostics
                            in this section.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do compression test on cylinders that are white smoking using the compression test
                    adapter. Inspect turbocharger for damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If engine is overheating with coolant loss, and cylinder head gasket, injector sleeve or
                    glow plug sleeve is suspected for leaking, refer to Combustion Leaks to Coolant Test using High
                    Pressure in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blue Smoke Diagnostics</title>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Excessive crankcase pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective turbocharger</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective fuel injector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Piston oil control ring stuck/damaged</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Leaking valve stem seals or worn valve guides</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Procedures</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do oil consumption test on engine. Verify high oil consumption.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do Test 17 (Crankcase Pressure) on Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 or Section 6 of
                    this manual.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If crankcase pressure is high and there is excessive oil consumption, investigate air
                            compressor, turbocharger, and power cylinder components.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If crankcase pressure is normal and there is excessive oil consumption continue with next
                            step.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove Charge Air Cooler (CAC) pipes and inspect CAC and intake system for excessive oil
                    carryover.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Oil in the air induction system is normal, since the engine has a closed breather.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect turbocharger for oil leak at both the compressor and turbine housings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove exhaust manifolds and inspect exhaust ports for oil residue to pinpoint possible
                    injector failure causing oil to mix with fuel injected into the power cylinder.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If crankcase pressure is normal and oil consumption is more than one quart per 500 miles,
                            replace fuel injector in cylinder where oil residue is identified.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_69.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_EGES240-SEC5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
