<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Cylinder Head Inspection - Valves Removed</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, wear safety glasses with side shields whenever
                    using compressed air for cleaning purposes. Limit the air pressure to 207 kPa (30 psi). See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="safety">"Safety Information</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Pressure testing the cylinder head will reveal cracks in ports or sleeve leakage which
                cannot be observed using dye penetrant. Pressure test the cylinder head as follows:
            </para>
            <figure id="e300551" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ08/J08058.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Cylinder Head Test Plate</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure gauge and regulator</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Mounting bolts (12 total)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pressure test plate</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fasten the Cylinder Head Pressure Test Plate tool, with rubber gasket attached, to
                    gasket side of cylinder head. Secure plate using eight (M14) bolts and four (M8) bolts. See
                    <hotlnk document="eges3001_116.xml" xrefid="E30005C">Special Service Tools</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install pressure test regulator and gauge assembly to cylinder head test plate.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Immerse cylinder head in water. Apply air pressure and adjust to 124 to 138 kPa (18 to
                    20 psi) and inspect for leaks at the following places. If any leaks are observed replace the
                    cylinder head:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Ports</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Upper cylinder head deck</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Lower cylinder head deck</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Nozzle sleeve area</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Glow plug sleeve area</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the valves removed from the cylinder head, clean all valve guides using a nylon brush,
                soap and water. Blow out any residue with filtered compressed air.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position an inspection light at the bottom of the valve guide bores and examine the walls
                for burning or cracking. Replace the cylinder head as necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="e300552" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd08/D0873.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Measuring the small hole gauge (valve guide ID)</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure each valve guide by using a 0-1 inch outside micrometer.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Record each valve guide inner diameter so valve-to-guide running clearance may be
                    determined.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If valve guide inner diameter exceeds specifications, replace cylinder head. See
                    <hotlnk document="eges3001_114.xml" xrefid="E30005A">Specifications</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean valve seat area using suitable solvent, prior to visual inspection.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the exhaust valve seats for burned or cracked conditions. If any of these conditions
                exist, replace cylinder head.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_91.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_93.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
