<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS AND ACCESSORIES - Electronic Circuit Testing -
        Using the Digital MultiMeter
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="10">
        <title>Using the Digital MultiMeter</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The following electrical test equipment should be available for testing electronic circuits:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Voltmeter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Ohmmeter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Ammeter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jumper wires</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Test lights</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Meters</title>
            <figure id="f2400836" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6133.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Typical Test Meters</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>All test meters come in a variety of models. Any working model will be adequate for simple tests.
                However, accurate readings are important. Make sure the test meter is of high quality. The Fluke 88&#8482;
                Digital Multimeter is recommended because it has very little current and a high impedance (resistance)
                of 10 megaohms (10 M&#x2126;).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use only high impedance digital multimeters when troubleshooting an electronic circuit. Do not
                        use any kind of battery powered test light. Battery test lights can damage an electronic control
                        circuit.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Some devices in an electronic control system are not capable of carrying an appreciable amount
                        of current. Therefore, test equipment must be designed to not damage any part the electronic
                        control system. Do not use analog meters unless specified. Analog meters use too much current to
                        test an electronic control system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Jumper Wires</title>
            <figure id="f2400837" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6135.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Jumper Wires</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Jumper wires allow a circuit to by-pass a suspected opening or break in a circuit. Use a jumper wire
                to check for open relay contacts, wire breaks and poor ground connections. Several jumper wires with
                different tips should be available.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400838" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6134.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Troubleshooting with Jumper Wires</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If the circuit works correctly with the jumper wire in place, but does not work when the jumper wire
                is removed, the circuit is open.
            </para>
            <para>A circuit with no openings or breaks has continuity (uninterrupted current flow) and needs no further
                testing.
            </para>
            <para>An opening in the ground circuit exists for the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A switch is closed but the light does not illuminate.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jumping the switch does not illuminate the light.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jumping the light to the ground causes the light to illuminate.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltmeter</title>
            <para>Use a voltmeter to answer the following questions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Does the circuit have voltage?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage reading?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage drop across a load device?</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f2400839" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6125.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Checking Power to a Load Device</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To check for voltage to a load device, connect the positive meter lead to the input connection of the
                device (positive side) and connect the negative meter lead to a good vehicle ground.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400840" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG9/EG9001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Checking Power to a Connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Voltage to a device can also be measured by disconnecting the harness connector and using the correct
                tool in the Terminal Test Adapter Kit.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400841" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Checking Voltage Drop</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To check the voltage drop across a load device, connect the positive lead of the voltmeter to the
                positive side of the device and the negative meter lead to the negative side of the device.
            </para>
            <para>With the device operating, this will measure the voltage drop across the device. With only one device,
                all of the voltage should be dropped at the device. In any circuit, the voltage applied will equal the
                voltage dropped in the circuit. If this circuit only dropped 9V across the load, it indicates the wires
                and connections dropped 3V, indicating excessive circuit resistance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ammeter</title>
            <para>An ammeter measures current flow (amperage) in a circuit. Amperes (or amps) are units of electron flow
                that indicate how many electrons are passing through the circuit. An amp is the unit of measurement for
                the current flow in the circuit.
            </para>
            <para>Ohm's Law states that the current flow is equal to the circuit voltage divided by the total circuit
                resistance (I = E &#247; R). Therefore, increasing the voltage also increases the current flow. Any
                decrease in resistance will also increase the current flow.
            </para>
            <para>At normal operating voltage, most circuits have a characteristic amount of current flow (current
                draw). Current draw can be measured with an ammeter. Valuable diagnostic information can be provided by
                referring to a specified current draw rating for a component (electrical device), measuring the current
                flow in the circuit, and then comparing the two measurements (the rating vs. the actual measurement).
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400842" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/eg6128.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Installing the Ammeter</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>An ammeter is connected in series with the load, switches, resistors, etc., so that all of the current
                flows through the meter. The ammeter measures current flow only when the circuit is powered up and
                operating. The DMM is fused to measure up to 10 amps using the 10A connection point.
            </para>
            <para>Before measuring current flow, determine approximately how many amps are in the circuit to correctly
                connect the ammeter. The estimate of current flow can easily be calculated. The resistance of the light
                bulb is 2 ohms. Applying Ohm's law, current flow will be 6 amps (6 amps = 12V &#247; 2 ohms). If the
                fuse is removed and an ammeter is installed with the switch closed, 6 amps of current will be measured
                flowing in the circuit. Notice that the ammeter is installed in series so that all the current in the
                circuit flows through it.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, always make sure the power is off before
                        cutting, soldering, removing circuit components or before inserting the digital multimeter for
                        current measurements. Even small amounts of current can be dangerous.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Excessive current draw means that more current is flowing in a circuit than the fuse and circuit were
                designed to handle. Excessive current draw will open fuses and circuit breakers, and will also quickly
                discharge batteries. An ammeter can diagnose these conditions.
            </para>
            <para>Reduced current draw will cause a device (an electric window motor, for example) to operate poorly.
                Increased circuit resistance will cause lower current flow (often due to loose or corroded connections).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ohmmeter</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent damage to the test meter, only use the ohmmeter on circuits when the power is OFF.
                        Power from 12-volt systems may damage the meter.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The ohmmeter measures resistance (ohms) in a circuit. Ohmmeters use a small battery to supply voltage
                and current flow through the circuit being tested. Based on Ohm's Law, the ohmmeter calculates
                resistance in the circuit by measuring the voltage of the meter battery and the amount of current flow
                in the circuit. With the DMM, range selection and meter adjustment are not necessary.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400843" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG6/EG6130.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Measuring Resistance</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Resistance measurements are used to determine the resistance of a load or conductors, the value of
                resistors and the operation of variable resistors.
            </para>
            <para>To measure the resistance of a component or a circuit, remove power from the circuit. Isolate the
                component or circuit from other components and circuits so that the meter current (from probe to probe)
                only flows through the selected component or circuit. When measuring the resistance of the load, most of
                the current flow from the meter will go through the indicator lamp because it has less resistance.
            </para>
            <para>Remove one connector to the load. It is not always apparent when a component must be isolated, so it
                is a good practice to isolate a component or circuit by disconnecting one circuit. Place the ohmmeter
                leads across the component or circuit to display the resistance in ohms. When checking a sensor or
                variable resistor such as the fuel level gauge, heating the element or moving the arm should move the
                meter through a range of resistance that can be compared to a specification.
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400844" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG6/EG6131.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Checking for Open Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Open electrical circuits can be diagnosed using an ohmmeter. Disconnect the power supply to the
                circuit and isolate the circuit from all other circuits. The circuit between the light and the ground is
                disconnected to prevent reading a circuit that may be shorted to ground ahead of the load device as a
                continuous circuit. Connect the ohmmeter to the open ends of the circuit. A high reading (infinity)
                indicates an open circuit. A reading near zero indicates a continuous circuit. With the Fluke 88&#8482;
                Digital Multimeter, an open circuit will read OL (over limit).
            </para>
            <figure id="f2400845" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG6/EG6132.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Checking for Short Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Checks for short circuits are similar to checks for open circuits. Isolate the circuit from the power
                source and the ground point. Connect the ohmmeter between an isolated circuit and a good ground point to
                check the circuit for a short to ground. A short to ground will be indicated by a reading near zero. A
                circuit that is not shorted to ground will cause a high meter reading.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_201.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_203.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
