<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diagnostic Software
        Operation - Diagnostic Tests - Key-On Engine-Off Tests
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="15">
        <title>Key-On Engine-Off Tests</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Test</title>
            <para>The KOEO Standard test is done by the ECM. The technician runs this test, using the EST or the CRUISE
                ON and RESUME/ACCEL switches.
            </para>
            <para>During the KOEO Standard test, the ECM does an internal test of its processing components and memory
                followed by an Output Circuit Check (OCC). The OCC evaluates the electrical condition of the circuits,
                not mechanical or hydraulic performance of the systems. By operating the ECM output circuits and
                measuring each response, the Standard test detects shorts or opens in the harnesses, actuators, and ECM.
                If a circuit fails the test, a fault is logged and a DTC is set.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM checks the following circuits:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake shutoff valve (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fan (EFAN) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Radiator Shutter Enable (RSE) (optional)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When the OCC is done, the DTC window will display DTCs, if there are problems.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Test Using EST</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake to ensure the correct signal from the Electronic System Controller
                    (ESC).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch to ON. (Do not crank the engine.)</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003007" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31145.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Standard test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Standard and Run to start the test.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Test Using Cruise Switches</title>
            <figure id="f27003008" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figD31/D3172.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Cruise Switches</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para id="s27005016">Read and be familiar with all steps and time limits in this procedure before
                        starting.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake to ensure the correct signal from the Electronic System Controller
                    (ESC).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch to ON. (Do not crank the engine.)</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press and release the CRUISE ON and RESUME/ACCEL switches at the same time, twice within
                    3 seconds of the ignition switch on.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The ECM will begin the Output Circuit Check (OCC).</para>
                        <para>When the OCC is done, the ECM will flash the red ENGINE and amber ENGINE lamps to signal
                            the DTCs.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>There could be as much as a 10 second delay from the time switches are pressed to the time
                        DTCs are flashed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Injector Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Injector test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.
                        The Standard test must be done before doing the Injector test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Injector test diagnoses electrical problems in IDM wiring or injectors.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before doing the Injector test, DTCs should be accessed, noted, and cleared. This allows DTCs
                        found to be displayed as Active DTCs.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>During the Injector test, the ECM requests the IDM actuate the injectors in numerical order (1 through
                6), not in firing order. The IDM monitors the electrical circuit for each injector, evaluates the
                performance of the injector coils, and checks the operation of the electrical circuit. If an electronic
                component in the injector drive circuit fails the expected parameters, the IDM sends a fault to the ECM.
                The ECM logs the fault, a DTC is set and sent to the EST.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The technician can monitor injector operation by listening to the sound of each injector when
                        activated by the IDM. During Hard Start and No Start conditions, when oil is very cold and
                        thick, injectors may be hard to hear.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The DTC window will display DTCs, if there are problems.</para>
            <figure id="f27003009" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31146.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Injector test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Injector and Run to start the test.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>During the Injector test, injector solenoids should click when actuated. If a series of clicks
                        are not heard for each injector, one or more injectors are not activating.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Continuous Monitor Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Continuous Monitor test troubleshoots intermittent connections between the ECM and sensors. The
                engine can be off or running.
            </para>
            <para>The EST monitors the following circuits:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Battery Voltage (VBatt)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake Control Pressure (BCP) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR Valve Position (EGRP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f27003010" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31240.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Continuous Monitor session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select D_ContinuousMonitor.ssn from the open session file window and select OPEN to open
                    the session.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003011" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31229.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Continuous Monitor test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Continuous Monitor and select Run to start the
                    test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, be
                        careful to avoid rotating parts (belts and fan) and hot engine surfaces.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wiggle connectors and wires at all suspected problem locations. If circuit continuity is
                    interrupted, the EST will display DTCs related to the condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Correct problem causing active DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003012" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Output State Low Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Output State Low test allows the technician to diagnose the operation of the output signals and
                actuators.
            </para>
            <para>In the Output State Low test mode, the ECM pulls down the output voltage to the low state. This
                grounds the low side driver circuits and actuates the output components controlled by the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>During Output State Low test, the output of the circuit in question can be monitored with a DMM. The
                DMM measures a low voltage state as the outputs are toggled. The actual voltage will vary with the
                circuit tested.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>A Breakout Box or Breakout Harness and a DMM are required to monitor the suspected
                                circuit or actuator.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>DTCs are not set by the ECM during this test.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following actuators are activated when toggled low during the test:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) (electrical circuit only)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fan (EFAN) relay (optional) (electrical circuit and inspect if clutch is engaged)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Radiator Shutter Enable (RSE) (optional) (electrical circuit, audible, and visual inspection
                        of shutter position)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR (audible and visual inspection only) continuous monitoring by EGR drive module</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VGT vanes full open (electrical circuit, audible, and visual inspection of actuator arm)
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f27003013" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/H31416.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Output State Test Session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select D_OutputStateTest.ssn from the open session file window.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003014" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31231.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Output State Low test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Output State Low and Run to start the test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Toggle between the Low and High tests in the Output State Test. Listen and observe
                    actuator control or circuit operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Output State High Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Output State High test allows the technician to diagnose the operation of the output signals and
                actuators.
            </para>
            <para>In the Output State High test mode, the ECM pulls up the output voltage to the high state. This
                energizes the control high side driver circuits and actuates the output components controlled by the
                ECM.
            </para>
            <para>During this test, the output of the circuit in question is monitored with a DMM. The DMM measures a
                high voltage state, as the outputs are toggled. The actual voltage will vary with the circuit tested.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>A Breakout Box or Breakout Harness and a DMM are required to monitor the suspected
                                circuit or actuator.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>DTCs are not set by the ECM during this test.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following actuators are activated when toggled high during the test:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>VGT vanes full closed (electrical circuit, audible, and visual inspection of actuator arm)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake Shutoff valve (optional) (electrical circuit only)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f27003016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/H31416.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Output State Test Session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select D_OutputStateTest.ssn from the open session file window.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31230.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Output State High test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Output State Test High and Run to start the
                    test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Toggle between the Output State Test Low and the Output State Test High. Listen and
                    observe actuator control or circuit operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Glow Plug/Inlet Air Heater Output State Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Glow Plug/Inlet Air Heater Output State test allows the technician to determine if the Inlet Air
                Heater System is operating correctly.
            </para>
            <para>The inlet air heater relay operation is activated for 30 seconds. A DMM and current clamp are used to
                measure the time the relay is on and the amperage that is drawn for the inlet air heater.
            </para>
            <figure id="f27003019" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/H31416.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Output State Test Session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select D_OutputStateTest.ssn from the open session file window.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31139.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Glow Plug/Inlet Air Heater Output State test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Off Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOEO Diagnostics menu, select Glow Plug/Inlet Air Heater and Run to start the
                    test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be run twice for each ignition switch cycle. Earlier calibration may not
                        allow the test to be run, contact International&#174; Technical Services.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f27003021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/J31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
