<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - MASTER
        DIAGNOSTICS (MD 32) - EST HELP
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCESS" graphiccount="3">
        <title>EST HELP</title>
        <para>This software release of Master Diagnostics has an extensive set of documentation loaded into the
            electronic help file. This section describes the organization and the layout of
            <emph type="bold">Help</emph>
            file.
        </para>
        <para>Select
            <emph type="bold">Help</emph>
            and then
            <emph type="bold">Contents</emph>
            .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505110.1" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8725.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Help</emph>
            section will appear .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505111" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8726.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Help</emph>
            file is arranged under the following headings:
            <emph type="bold">Company, Introduction, How to's, Programming, Menus Toolbar</emph>, and
            <emph type="bold">Trouble Codes (DLC)</emph>.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Introduction</emph>
            topic contains the software revision information. This topic documents the changes to individual software
            releases. Click on the topic titled
            <emph type="bold">Revision Information</emph>. It will display the software revision contained in this
            release.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">How to's</emph>
            topic describes the features of this software's usage, access, and examples. Double clicking on the heading
            labeled
            <emph type="bold">How to's</emph>
            will display more help functions.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Trouble Codes (DLC)</emph>topic contains service procedures and technical information on
            the International family of engines. Placing the mouse pointer over a Diagnostic Trouble Code number or the
            circuit index causes the pointer to change from the shape of an arrow to the shape of a hand indicating
            these topics can be hot linked .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17505114" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8729.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>: Double clicking on the Diagnostic Trouble Code brings up a detailed
            description of possible causes. This is normally displayed when double clicking the
            <emph type="bold">DTC</emph>
            in the
            <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code</emph>
            window .
        </para>
        <para>Clicking on a hot link in the circuit index will bring up a detailed description of the circuit involved
            with this Diagnostic Trouble Code as well as others. The circuit index is also organized under individual
            topics corresponding to their related Diagnostic Trouble Codes. Related circuit diagrams can be reviewed as
            well by clicking on the appropriate engine family hot link (V-8 or I-6 ) .
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Example</emph>: Clicking on Diagnostic Trouble Code 131, results in a window detailing
            more information about that particular diagnostic code . Clicking on the I-6 hot link opens up an electrical
            diagram and voltage / resistance checks for harnesses and connectors .
        </para>
        <para>Click on the tab label
            <emph type="bold">Index</emph>. This displays all EST HELP topic indexes. Double clicking on an index item
            causes the help information to be displayed.
        </para>
        <para>Click on the tab labeled
            <emph type="bold">Search</emph>. You can search help by using specific words or phrases. You can use the
            advanced search features by making conditional searches. Type in the words or phrases in the search box and
            click on the
            <emph type="bold">List Topics</emph>
            button. Select the topic and then click on the
            <emph type="bold">Display</emph>
            button to display the help information.
        </para>
        <para>Please check the Master Diagnostic software users manual for questions and additional information.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_152.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_154.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
