<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Remote PTO Speed Control (RPTO)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="rpto" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Remote PTO Speed Control (RPTO)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503082" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1297.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Remote PTO Speed Control Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The purpose of the remote power takeoff feature is to allow the control of engine speed via remote
                switches for the use of ancillary engine devices such as hydraulic pumps, lift gates, etc.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Mode Selection</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Variable speed or preset PTO control (up to two speeds selected) can be selected and programmed into
                the module via EST.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Speed Selection</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Variable PTO speed is either increased or decreased by depressing the momentary speed control switch
                to the Set or Resume position. The speed at which the engine accelerates is noted as the "ramp rate" or
                rpm per seconds of acceleration that the engine is allowed to accelerate. "Ramp rate" and maximum PTO
                speed are programmable by using the EST.
            </para>
            <para>In the preset PTO mode, the momentary speed control switch allows for two preset speeds to be
                selected. By momentarily depressing the switch in the preset #1 mode the first speed is selected, by
                momentarily depressing the switch in the preset #2 position a second speed can be selected. These speeds
                are programmable in the ECM by using the EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>Disagreements in speed selection states will be detected by the ECM and a Diagnostic Trouble Code will
                be set. The most common source of RPTO problems are blown fuses to the ON/OFF circuit, an incorrectly
                programmed ECM, or improper wiring of the body builder connectors and speed control switches.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503083" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8858.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Remote PTO Speed Control Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>See Body Builder Connections .</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector always check for damaged pins, corrosion, and loose terminals. Check
                        for blown fuses.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503030" frame="all">
                <title>Remote PTO Speed Control Circuit Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="43.40*"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="40.93*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="311.67*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Voltage Circuit Checks at ECM Connector</emph>
                                    (check with breakout box installed and ignition key ON)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">REMOTE PTO SPEED SELECTION SWITCH</emph>
                                    (TWO POSITION INTERMITTENT ROCKER SWITCH)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Set Switch Circuit</emph>
                                    (Speed #1 - preset PTO) (Deaccel - variable PTO)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>32 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch held in Set position - If no voltage, check switch and circuit for open or
                                    ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>32 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in Middle position - If voltage is present, switch or circuit is shorted to
                                    power.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Resume Switch Circuit</emph>(Speed #2 - preset PTO) (Accel -
                                    variable PTO)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>31 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch held in Resume position - If no voltage, circuit is open or shorted to
                                    ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>31 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in Middle position - If voltage is present, switch or circuit is shorted to
                                    power.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remote Variable PTO ON/OFF Switch - Switch must be ON for remote
                                        PTO to function.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>36 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in ON position - If no voltage, open circuit, switch or fuse from switch.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>36 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in OFF position - If voltage is present, switch or circuit is shorted to
                                    power.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remote Preset PTO ON/OFF Switch - Switch must be ON for remote PTO
                                        to function.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>37 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in ON position - If no voltage, open circuit, switch or fuse from switch.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>37 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch in OFF position - If voltage is present, switch or circuit is shorted to
                                    power.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Power Take Off Speed Control</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The purpose of the remote power takeoff feature is to allow the control of engine speed via remote
                switches for the use of ancillary engine devices such as hydraulic pumps, lift gates, etc.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Mode Selection</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Variable speed or preset PTO control (up to two speeds selected) can be selected and programmed into
                the module via EST.
            </para>
            <para>The mode, variable and/or preset PTO must be selected and "turned on" by the EST tool for this feature
                to function. On/off switches must also be installed to provide a 12V signal to the appropriate pin in
                the ECM. The Remote PTO feature will be disabled when vehicle speed is detected, the clutch pedal is
                depressed or if the engine is put into gear (automatic transmission only).
            </para>
            <para>Power Take Off (PTO) speed control provides a method for the operator to set and maintain a regulated
                engine speed, without using the accelerator pedal, for the purpose of operating auxiliary equipment. The
                power take off feature has a in-cab and a remote operator interface. Depending on configuration, the
                operator may turn on and activate PTO speed control while in the comfort of the cab or at the
                convenience of the remote interface. If both in-cab and remote operations are enabled, the on-board
                electronics senses which interface is active depending on operator actions. No active mobile PTO
                operation is possible when the PTO speed control is turned on using the remote interface.
            </para>
            <para>This feature also has the bump up and bump down functions. Where, the operator may bump up the rpm in
                25 rpm increments when the Resume/Accel button is momentarily pressed. The operator may bump down the
                rpm in 25 rpm increments when the Set/Cruise button is momentarily pressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Power Take Off</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if the vehicle has the Power Take Off speed
                control feature.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>PTO Programmable Features</title>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Disable</emph>: Feature is turned off at all times.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Remote Operation Only</emph>: Feature is enabled and may only be turned on and
                        activated using the remote PTO ON/OFF switches.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">In-Cab Operation Only</emph>: Feature is enabled and with use in-cab to PTO
                        speed control while in the in-cab operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Remote and In-Cab Operation</emph>: Feature is enabled and will allow both
                        remote and in-cab operations. However, the remote operation takes precedence over the in-cab
                        operations.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Max VS (vehicle speed)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the maximum road speed that the PTO speed control may be engaged while in
                Mobile PTO operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO In-Cab Mode</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates how the steering wheel mounted Cruise Control buttons are to be
                interpreted.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">None</emph>: The steering wheel mounted Cruise Control ON/OFF switch is
                        ignored.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Stationary Preset</emph>: The steering wheel mounted Cruise Control buttons
                        operate only in the
                        <emph type="bold">Preset</emph>
                        state of operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Stationary Variable</emph>: The steering wheel mounted Cruise Control buttons
                        operate in a variable state of operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Mobile Variable</emph>: The steering wheel mounted Cruise Control buttons
                        operate in a variable state of operation while allowing the vehicle to be mobile.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO In-Cab Interface</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics if PTO speed control is on and active the
                operator in-cab interfaces are ignored. These interfaces include accelerator pedal, driveline engagement
                signal, brake pedal and the steering wheel mounted Cruise Control buttons.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Enable</emph>: Continue to monitor in-cab operator interfaces.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Disable</emph>: Ignore in-cab operator interfaces.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Remote Pedal</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics that a remote throttle control is available for
                use to control the PTO rpm setting.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Disable</emph>: Remote throttle is not available.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Enable</emph>: Remote throttle is available.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Preset rpm 1</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rpm setting when the operator depresses the Set/Cruise button with the
                STATIONARY PRESET in-cab mode of operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Preset rpm 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rpm setting when the operator depresses the Resume/Accel button with the
                <emph type="bold">Stationary Preset</emph>
                in-cab mode of operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Preset rpm Ramp Rate</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rate that rpm is increased when the operator depresses and holds the
                Resume/Accel button.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PTO Max rpm</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the maximum rpm that the PTO speed control may be engaged.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Troubleshooting</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The EST can be used to monitor the status of the PTO controls. Comparing the data list reading to
                actual operation will indicate if the controls are operating properly. Using the menu of programmable
                parameters, the ECM programming can also be verified to insure that the ECM is properly programmed for
                PTO applications.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503083.1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8806.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>ECM Body Builder Connections Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_103.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
