<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Introduction - Lubrication
        System - Oil Pressure Regulator Valve and Oil Pressure Relief Valve
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Oil Pressure Regulator Valve and Oil Pressure Relief Valve</title>
        <para>The lubricating oil pressure relief valve, 552 kPa (80 psi) located in the front cover and the oil
            pressure regulating valve [345 kPa (50 psi)], located between the oil filter header and the crankcase,
            extends the life of the engine because they control the volume and pressure of oil supplied to the engine.
            The volume of oil supplied by the pump is always in excess of what is needed to lubricate the engine.
        </para>
        <para>The oil pressure relief valve is used to protect the oil cooler and oil filter from extremely
            high-pressures encountered during cold starts in cold weather. If oil pressure exceeds 552 kPa (80 psi) on
            the relief valve face, it moves the relief valve inward allowing oil to travel through the relief valve and
            back to the oil pan, relieving pressure in the lubrication system.
        </para>
        <para>When all points of lubrication within the engine are satisfied, restriction to flow causes pressure to
            build on the regulator valve causing it to move inward. This action allows excess oil to go directly back to
            the oil pan, through the ports uncovered by the movement of the regulator valve.
        </para>
        <figure id="f2100210" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg5/eg5329B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>High-pressure relief valve</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f2100211" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg3/eg3557.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Oil pressure regulating valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler Rear Header</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Pressure Regulating Valve</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
