<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Service Manual - Engine Electrical Components - Installation - Installing Engine Wiring
        Harnesses
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Installing Engine Wiring Harnesses</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Glow Plug Harness</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main battery negative
                        terminal before disconnecting or connecting any electrical components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not tug on any sensor wiring harnesses while trying to remove
                        them. If resistance is felt, find the source of resistance and free any connectors or clips that
                        are caught before proceeding.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use this procedure only if you are installing the glow plug wiring harness with the engine
                        sensor wiring harness.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="e3001144.3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ09/J09009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Using the Glow Plug Connector Removal and Installation tool</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Glow plug</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Glow plug harness connector</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Glow Plug Connector Remover/Installer tool</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace any cut, worn, or damaged O-rings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the Glow Plug Connector Remover / Installer tool, install left and right side glow
                    plug harnesses. See
                    <hotlnk document="eges3001_244.xml" xrefid="E30011C">Special Service Tools</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the glow plug wiring harness connector to the engine sensor wiring harness
                    connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Injector Wiring Harness</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main battery negative
                        terminal before disconnecting or connecting any electrical components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not tug on any sensor wiring harnesses while trying to remove
                        them. If resistance is felt, find the source of resistance and free any connectors or clips that
                        are caught before proceeding.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="e3001145" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figJ09/J09007.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Connecting Injector Wiring Harness onto the connectors</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector harness connector</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector connector</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect each injector wiring harness connector onto the injector connector.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Sensor Wiring Harness</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main battery negative
                        terminal before disconnecting or connecting any electrical components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not tug on any sensor wiring harnesses while trying to remove
                        them. If resistance is felt, find the source of resistance and free any connectors or clips that
                        are caught before proceeding.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully place the injector and engine sensor wiring harness (and glow plug harness, if
                    attached) over the engine and support bracket located by the intake air and glow plug relays. Use
                    the sensor and actuator location views at the front of this section to aid in the wiring harness
                    routing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Begin connecting the injector and engine sensor wiring harness by placing the drain wire
                        connection over the grounding terminal stud. Tighten nut to
                        <hotlnk document="eges3001_311.xml" xrefid="S300GTG">Standard Torque</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If installing the Glow Plug Harness only, refer to Installation - Glow Plug Harness in this
                        section for further information.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to Installation procedures for location photos of individual components.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect three IDM wiring harness connectors and four ECM wiring harness connectors (two
                    for engine and two for chassis) to the ECM/IDM modules.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the 8 and 12-pin wiring harness connectors.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Some stripped chassis applications may not require the 8-pin connector.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the glow plug relay. Refer to Installation - Glow Plug Relay in this section,
                    for connecting the wiring harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the intake air heater relay. Refer to Installation - Intake Air Heater Relay in
                    this section, for connecting the wiring harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect sensor harness connector to the ICP sensor, located in the right oil rail.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect starter motor to the sensor harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air conditioner clutch to the sensor harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the CKP sensor electrical connector located on the right side of the lower front
                    of the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If installing the complete wiring harness assembly (sensor and injector), connect injectors 1,
                        3, and 5 at this time. Refer to Installing - Injector Wiring Harness in this section for further
                        information.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the right side glow plug harness to the sensor harness. Refer to Installation -
                    Glow Plug Harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the alternator power electrical connector and the alternator sensor electrical
                    connection to the alternator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place electrical cable onto heater element and secure with a washer and nut (M5).
                    Tighten nut to the
                    <hotlnk document="eges3001_243.xml" xrefid="E30011B">Special Torque</hotlnk>. Pull rubber boot over
                    heater element threads and nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the MAP sensor electrical connector located next to air inlet on the front of
                    intake manifold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the BCS electrical connector located on the inlet elbow.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EGR valve electrical connector to the EGR valve, located directly behind the
                    intake manifold air inlet elbow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the left side glow plug harness to the sensor harness. Refer to Installation -
                    Glow Plug Harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the ECT sensor electrical connector located above water pump on the left side of
                    the engine front cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the MAT sensor electrical connector located in the left side of the intake
                    manifold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect EOT and EOP electrical connectors to their respective sensors located in the
                    center of the oil filter base assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If installing the complete wiring harness assembly (sensor and injector), connect the IDM
                        ground stud and injectors 2, 4, and 6 at this time. Refer to Installation - Installing Injector
                        Wiring Harness in this section for further information.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the wiring harness to the IDM ground stud.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect MAF/IAT sensor electrical connector located at the end of the air inlet duct
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the IPR valve installed into the top of the high-pressure pump, rotate the IPR
                    valve solenoid clockwise. Connect the IPR valve electrical connector to the valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the CMP sensor electrical connector located on lower left side of the engine
                    block near front cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Securing the wiring harness to the engine by connecting the harness to the engine clamps
                    and anchor points
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect main negative (-) battery cable to the battery.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_239.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001_241.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
