<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Fuel Management System -
        Fuel Injector Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Fuel Injector Assembly</title>
        <figure id="e3005105" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figd11/D1111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Fuel injector assembly</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Lower O-ring</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel inlet screens (3)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Upper O-ring</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Clamp alignment slot</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Harness connector</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Fuel Injector Features</title>
        </para>
        <para>Two 48 volt, 20 amp coils control a spool valve that directs oil flow in and out of the injector. The
            injector coils are turned on for approximately 800 &#181;s (microseconds). Each injector has a single four
            pin connector that couples to the engine sensor wiring harness through the rocker arm carrier.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Injector Coils and Spool Valve</title>
        </para>
        <para>An OPEN coil and a CLOSE coil on the injector move the spool valve from side to side using magnetic force.
            The spool has two positions:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>When the spool valve is open, oil flows into the injector from the high-pressure oil manifold.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When the spool valve is closed, oil exits from the top of the fuel injector and drains back to the
                    oil pan.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Intensifier Piston and Plunger</title>
        </para>
        <para>When the spool valve opens, high-pressure oil enters the injector and pushes down the intensifier piston
            and plunger. The intensifier piston is 7.1 times greater in area than the plunger so, injection pressure is
            7.1 times greater than injection control pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Plunger and Barrel</title>
        </para>
        <para>Fuel pressure builds at the base of the plunger in the barrel. When the intensifier piston pushes the
            plunger down, the plunger increases fuel pressure in the barrel 7.1 times greater than injection control
            pressure. The plunger has a hardened coating to resist scuffing.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Injector Needle</title>
        </para>
        <para>The injector needle opens inward when fuel pressure overcomes the Valve Opening Pressure (VOP) of 20 MPa
            (2,900 psi). Fuel is atomized at high-pressure through the nozzle tip.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Fuel Injector Operation</title>
        </para>
        <para>Injector operation has three stages:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Fill</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Injection</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>End of injection</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f3700001" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figK11/K11042A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="592px"
                     scalefitheight="432px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Fuel injector cross section</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Fill</title>
        </para>
        <para>During Fill, both coils are de-energized and the spool valve is closed. High-pressure oil from the
            high-pressure oil manifold is stopped at the spool valve.
        </para>
        <para>Low-pressure fuel fills the three ports and enters through the fuel inlet screens on its way to the
            chamber beneath the plunger. The needle control spring holds the needle onto its seat to prevent fuel from
            entering the combustion chamber.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Injection</title>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>A pulse-width controlled current energizes the OPEN coil. Magnetic force moves the spool valve
                    open. High-pressure oil flows past the spool valve and onto the top of the intensifier piston. Oil
                    pressure overcomes the force of the intensifier piston spring and the intensifier starts to move
                    down. An increase in fuel pressure under the plunger seats the fuel inlet check ball, and fuel
                    pressure starts to build on the needle.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The pulse-width controlled current to the OPEN coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains open.
                    High-pressure oil from high-pressure oil manifold continues to flow past the spool valve. The
                    intensifier piston and plunger continue to move and fuel pressure increases in the barrel. When fuel
                    pressure rises above Valve Opening Pressure (VOP), the needle lifts off its seat and injection
                    begins.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <title>End of Injection</title>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>When the ECM determines the correct injector on-time has been reached (the correct amount of fuel
                    has been delivered), the ECM sends a pulse-width controlled current to the CLOSE coil of the
                    injector. The current energizes the CLOSE coil and magnetic force closes the spool valve.
                    High-pressure oil is stopped against the spool valve.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The pulse-width controlled current to close the coil is shut off, but the spool valve remains
                    closed. Oil above the intensifier piston flows past the spool valve through the exhaust ports. The
                    intensifier piston and plunger return to their initial positions. Fuel pressure decreases until the
                    needle control spring forces the needle back onto its seat.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_S305010105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
