<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - INTRODUCTION - Engine Description
        - Glow Plug Controller System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Glow Plug Controller System</title>
        <figure id="f120in29" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg3/eg3137.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Glow Plug Controller System Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The purpose of the glow plug system is to warm up the engine cylinders to improve cold engine starting and
            to reduce exhaust emissions during the engine warm-up period.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM is programmed to turn on the "wait to start" light. The ECM also energizes the glow plugs via the
            glow plug relay each time the ignition switch is placed in the ON position before starting an engine.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM monitors battery voltage and uses information from the Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) and
            barometric (BARO) sensors to determine the amount of "wait to start" light time and glow plug activation
            time. The ECM controls the "wait to start" light ON time and the activation of the glow plugs separately.
        </para>
        <para>The glow plugs are activated for a longer period of time if the engine is cold or the barometric pressure
            is low (high altitude). Battery voltage is monitored to extend glow plug life. If the battery voltage is
            high, power to the glow plugs is modulated by turning the glow plug relay ON or OFF at programmed intervals.
        </para>
        <para>The engine is ready to start when the "wait to start" light is turned off by the ECM. To reduce exhaust
            emissions during engine warm up, the glow plugs may remain ON for up to 120 seconds while the engine is
            running.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_SECTION1.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
