<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Timing Gear Train and Front
        Cover - Engine Gear Train Timing - Measure Engine Gear Train Timing without Front Cover Removed or Engine Tear
        Down
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s210010802.2" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Measure Engine Gear Train Timing without Front Cover Removed or Engine Tear Down</title>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010802.2.1">
            <title>Feeler Gauge Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate engine to approximately Top Dead Center (TDC) compression on cylinder 1 (no
                    valves open). Set lash on intake valve 1 to nominal lash setting of 0.635 mm (0.025 in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place mark on damper pulley at radial distance of 82.5 mm (3.25 in) or straight line
                    distance of 81 mm (3.188 in) clockwise from timing notch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f210010804" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa03/A03003.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Measure engine gear train timing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Straight line</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Scribe mark</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Radial distance</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Timing notch</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place 0.25 mm (0.010 in)
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_231.xml" xrefid="t210010803">Feeler Gauge</hotlnk>
                    between valve lever and valve stem of intake valve 1. Slowly rotate engine forward (clockwise) until
                    intake valve starts to lift and feeler gauge becomes tight. Mark should line up with TDC arrow on
                    front cover or be within 3.5 crank degrees of TDC. A radial (or straight) line distance of 6.8 mm
                    (0.27 in) at damper pulley is equivalent to 3.5 degrees of TDC.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>One tooth "out of time" on gear train equals approximately 11 degrees of movement or 21.4 mm
                        (0.84 in) of radial distance of damper pulley.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If timing on valve 1 is within specifications, other valves, barring extreme camshaft
                    lobe wear or poor adjustment, will also be in time. If timing is found to be incorrect, engine's
                    front cover removal is required to inspect punch marks on gear train.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s210010802.2.2">
            <title>Dial Indicator Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para id="s210010802.2.2.1" count="1">Adjust intake valve 1 for piston set 1 at TDC compression stroke
                    to 0.64 mm (0.025 in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position magnetic base
                    <hotlnk document="eges2101_231.xml" xrefid="t210010803">Dial Indicator</hotlnk>
                    on valve cover fence of cylinder head rail with indicator tip on intake valve rotator 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Zero Dial Indicator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate engine approximately one full revolution either direction to a position of 360
                    degrees from starting point.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dial Indicator should read 0.28 to 0.84 mm (0.011 to 0.033 in) from starting position
                    for proper gear train timing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If Dial Indicator readings are outside specified range, engine's front cover must be
                    removed and punch mark and gear tooth position adjusted.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210010802.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_S210010803.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
