<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        VEHICLE FEATURES - Standard Features
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="OVERVIEW" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Standard Features</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Governor Control</title>
            <para>INTERNATIONAL DT 466 and DT 530 engines are electronically controlled for all operating ranges.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>American Trucking Association Datalink Provisions</title>
            <para>Vehicles are equipped with the American Trucking Association (ATA) datalink connector for
                communication between the ECM and the Electronic Service Tool (EST).
            </para>
            <para>The datalink provides communication capabilities for the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission of engine parameter data</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics and troubleshooting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Customer programming</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Production line programming of vehicle features</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Field programming</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Diagnostics</title>
            <para>The electronic service tool provides diagnostic information for the Master Diagnostics (MD)
                Software.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC's)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTC's for sensors, actuators, electronic components, and engine systems are detected and stored in the
                ECM. The ECM transmits DTC's to the EST to assist with diagnostic action. The ECM also provides DTC's
                emitted by the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Speedometer and Tachometer Provisions</title>
            <para>The engine control system calibrates vehicle speed to 157,157 pulses/mile. Dip switches no longer need
                to be changed when components affecting speed calibration are changed. However, the new speed
                calibration information must be programmed with an Electronic Service Tool.
            </para>
            <para>The tachometer signal is generated by the ECM by computing the CMP signal. The result of this
                calculation is transmitted to the instrument dash cluster via the J1939 Datalink and the EST via the ATA
                Datalink.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Over Temperature Protection System (Coolant Temperature Compensation)</title>
            <para>Coolant Temperature Compensation reduces fuel delivery if engine coolant temperature is above the
                cooling system specifications. Fueling is reduced proportionally to the design limit exceeded. Fuel
                reduction is calibrated to a maximum of 40% before standard engine warning or optional warning/shutdown
                is engaged. If warning or shutdown occurs, a Diagnostic Trouble Code is stored in the ECM memory.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Coolant Temperature Compensation may be omitted on emergency vehicles that require 100% power
                        on demand.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Event Logging System</title>
            <para>The event logging system records engine operation above maximum rpm (overspeed), high coolant
                temperature, low coolant level, or low oil pressure. This information and readings for the odometer /
                hourmeter are stored in the ECM memory and may be accessed using the EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Crank Inhibit</title>
            <para>Engine Crank Inhibit will not allow the starting motor to crank if the engine is running or the
                automatic transmission is in gear. Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) is an optional system for vehicles with
                manual transmissions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Accelerator Pedal</title>
            <para>The Electronic Accelerator Pedal eliminates the mechanical linkage used with conventional accelerator
                pedals. An accelerator position sensor, part of the accelerator pedal assembly, provides the ECM with an
                analog voltage signal representing the driver's demand for power.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750125" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1279.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Electronic Accelerator Pedal System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control</title>
            <para>Cruise Control regulates vehicle speed using automotive style, on/off, set/accel buttons. Speed
                control is disabled when the service brakes are applied, the clutch pedal is depressed, or the automatic
                transmission is placed in neutral. The accelerator pedal can be used to increase speed from the selected
                cruise speed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750126" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8866.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Cruise Control Buttons on the Steering Wheel</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cold Ambient Protection (CAP)</title>
            <para>The CAP system safeguards the engine from damage caused by prolonged periods of idle at no load during
                cold weather conditions. CAP also improves cab warm up.
            </para>
            <para>CAP maintains engine coolant temperature by increasing the engine rpm to a programmed value when the
                Ambient Air Temperature is below 32&#176;F (0&#176;C), the Engine Coolant Temperature is below 149&#176;F
                (65&#176;C), and the engine has been idling with no load for more than 5 minutes.
            </para>
            <para>CAP is standard on all trucks without an Idle Shutdown Timer, with a clutch switch (manual
                transmission), or a neutral safety switch (automatic transmission).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
