<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; DT 466E, DT 466, 530, 530E, and HT 530 Diesel Engines - Introduction - Cooling System -
        Thermostat Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="1">
        <title>Thermostat Operation</title>
        <para>An internal passageway located in the crankcase directs coolant from front to rear, evenly distributing
            coolant to the lower sections of the cylinder sleeves. The coolant flow is directed toward each cylinder
            sleeve on a tangent causing a swirling motion upward towards the cylinder head. This swirling action
            improves heat dissipation.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant leaves the area around the cylinder sleeves in the following two ways:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>The coolant is directed to the oil cooler via an exterior tube leading to the rear of the oil
                    cooler header. Coolant flows through passages in the oil cooler and exits at the water pump to be
                    remixed with incoming coolant from the radiator. Coolant is supplied to the rear of the air
                    compressor from the left side of the crankcase. After the coolant exits at the front of the air
                    compressor, it is returned to the crankcase on the left side.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Coolant exits from the crankcase, through two cored holes at the top of each side of the cylinder
                    sleeve bore, and is metered for even distribution by holes in the head gasket. Coolant then flows
                    through the cylinder head to the thermostat. The thermostat incorporates two outlets to direct
                    coolant either to the radiator when the engine is at operating temperature, or directly back to the
                    water pump when the engine has not yet reached operating temperature.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <figure id="f2100107" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6150.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="502px"/>
            <caption>Thermostat Operation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When the engine coolant temperature is below specified thermostat opening temperature, the coolant flows
            through the bypass passage to the water pump because the radiator outlet port is blocked. As the engine
            reaches operating temperature, the thermostat opens, directing coolant towards the radiator; this also
            gradually restricts the bypass opening.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2101.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
