<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Engine Systems - Engine
        Lubrication System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Engine Lubrication System</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Lubrication System Components and Oil Flow</title>
            <figure id="f2700132" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31020.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="562px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Lubrication system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Unfiltered oil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cooled unfiltered oil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Filtered oil</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Secondary filtration filter (optional)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Gerotor oil pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Reservoir for high-pressure oil pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pick-up tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Unfiltered oil gallery</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler / filter header assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure regulator relief valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Regulator relief valve drain to crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pan assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston cooling tube (6)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main filtered oil gallery</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Vertical gallery</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder head</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve cover</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Rocker arm assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Air compressor (optional)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Oil Flow Diagram</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f2700133" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Lubrication system</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Sump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Secondary filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil pressure regulator relief valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil reservoir for high-pressure pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">To high-pressure oil system</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Cam bearing</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main bearings</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston cooling tube (6)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Connecting rods</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Rocker arm shaft</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The gerotor oil pump, driven by the engine crankshaft, draws unfiltered oil from the oil pan through
                an oil pick-up tube into the inlet port of the front cover. Unfiltered oil (under pressure) flows
                through the outlet port in the front cover into the unfiltered oil gallery in the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>The unfiltered oil gallery has one exit port to the header of the oil cooler. The oil is then
                internally diverted to the oil cooler plate stack or by-passed into the oil cooler/filter module.
            </para>
            <para>An oil temperature control valve, in the oil cooler/filter header, senses inlet oil temperature.
                During engine start-up, when the oil is cold, the oil temperature control valve allows unfiltered oil to
                bypass the oil cooler plate stack. When the unfiltered oil reaches engine operating temperature, the oil
                temperature control valve routes unfiltered oil to the oil cooler. Oil flows through both the oil cooler
                core and bypass gallery when the valve is partially open.
            </para>
            <para>Unfiltered oil at full flow moves through plates in the oil cooler. Engine coolant flows through the
                plates to cool the surrounding oil.
            </para>
            <para>The cooled, unfiltered oil leaving the oil cooler stack mixes with the uncooled, unfiltered oil (that
                bypassed the oil cooler). The oil mixture flows through the oil filter (from element outside to element
                inside). The oil filter bypass valve in the header ensures full flow of oil to the engine should the
                filter element become plugged. Oil bypass occurs within the module when differential filter pressure
                reaches 345 kPa (50 psi).
            </para>
            <para>Cooled, filtered oil flows to and past the oil pressure regulator relief valve, in the oil cooler
                module. The oil pressure regulator valve maintains correct operating oil pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The pressure regulator valve opens at 379 kPa (55 psi) and dumps excess oil into the crankcase. The
                filtered oil continues to the main oil gallery for distribution throughout the engine.
            </para>
            <para>Connecting rod bearings are fed through drilled passages in the crankshaft from main journals to rod
                journals, that receive pressurized oil from the main bearings.
            </para>
            <para>Camshaft journals are fed through passages drilled vertically in the main bearing webs. Pressurized
                oil from the main gallery, through piston cooling tubes, lubricates and cools the pistons.
            </para>
            <para>Valve rocker arms are lubricated through an annulus on the outside of the rear camshaft bushing. The
                oil passes up and through the vertical gallery in the rear of the crankcase, through a passage in the
                cylinder head. Oil continues through rocker arm shaft pedestal and into the rocker arm shaft. Oil
                continues flowing through drillings in the rocker arm shaft to the rocker arms. The oil then drains to
                the oil pan sump through push rod holes.
            </para>
            <para>Filtered oil from the main gallery flows up through a passage in the front of the crankcase and front
                cover into the oil reservoir for the high-pressure oil pump.
            </para>
            <para>The turbocharger receives filtered oil through an external tube connected to the oil cooler header.
                Oil drains back to the oil pan sump through a tube connected to the crankcase.
            </para>
            <para>The air compressor (if equipped) receives filtered oil from the main oil gallery through an external
                tube connected to the left side of the crankcase. Oil drains to the front cover and back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>The front gear train is splash lubricated with oil draining from the high-pressure reservoir and the
                air compressor (if equipped).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
