<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Vehicle Retarder (VRE)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="VRE" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Vehicle Retarder (VRE)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Circuit Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503102" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8849.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Vehicle Retarder Function Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>On engines/vehicles equipped with an exhaust brake the VRE (Vehicle Retarder Circuit) circuits
                function is to control the relay that turn the brake on and off. This circuit has many applications and
                can be wired in many configurations.
                <emph type="bold">The applicable wiring diagram for the correct application must be used for
                    troubleshooting the correct circuit.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Whenever a vehicle retarder is installed, regardless of type or mode of operation, the operator is
                supplied with an in-cab switch that will allow the system to be turned ON or OFF. The switch signals the
                operator's request to the Electrical System Controller (ESC) and the ESC relays that request to the
                Power Train Data Link to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>An open or short to ground can be detected on the coil side of the engine brake relay during an "On
                Demand" Engine Standard Test by the technician.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503103" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8851.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Vehicle Retarder Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connector always check for damaged pins, corrosion, and loose terminals.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503036" frame="all">
                <title>Vehicle Retarder Circuit Diagnostic Checks</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="69.59*"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="46.59*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="279.82*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Exhaust Brake Solenoid Voltage/Resistance Checks - With Exhaust
                                        Brake Solenoid Unplugged</emph>(check with ignition key ON and exhaust brake
                                    activated)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Exhaust Brake Solenoid</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pin A of Ex-Brake Solenoid</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If no voltage is present, either relay is not ON or open in circuit to solenoid
                                    (test with in-line connector unplugged, check voltage from exhaust brake relay).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pin B of Ex-Brake Solenoid to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Solenoid will not operate unless grounded.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pin A to Pin B of Ex-Brake Solenoid</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5 to 30&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check resistance of exhaust brake solenoid. Resistance will vary with
                                    manufacturer, but solenoid coil should not indicate infinite resistance (open coil).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>Exhaust Brake Relay Voltage Checks - With Exhaust Brake Relay Unplugged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>(check with EFC solenoid and battery positive cable disconnected, with breakout
                                    box installed)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Exhaust Brake Relay</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage should be present with ignition key ON. If 0V, check fuse and power
                                    circuit
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage should be present with ignition key ON. If 0V check fuse and power
                                    circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No voltage expected</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>87 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No voltage expected</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Continued on Next Page</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operational Voltage Checks</emph>
                                    (check with breakout box installed and exhaust brake relay &#38; solenoid plugged
                                    in)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>47 to 23</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage value when exhaust brake is activated by ECM. ECM grounds relay to turn it
                                    on.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>47 to 23</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12V &#177; 1.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage value when exhaust brake is turned OFF - ECM grounds relay to turn it
                                    on.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>265 = Exhaust brake relay failed the output circuit test during a Key-ON
                                    Engine-OFF Standard Test.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vehicle Retarder</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This group of parameters customizes the retarder feature. The purpose for the Vehicle Retarder is to
                provide the proper logic to enable or disable a mechanical engine/transmission brake. Several types of
                engine brakes exist.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Exhaust Brakes</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission Retarders</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Anti-lock Braking Devices</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The purpose of these devices is to aid in the deceleration rate of the vehicle by providing additional
                vehicle or engine load. This can reduce brake wear for vehicles in situations that require frequent
                braking. Also provided is over-speed protection which will decrease the odds of engine damage due to
                excessive engine speed.
            </para>
            <para>The on-board electronics provides the proper control logic necessary to determine when the vehicle
                retarder should be enabled. Currently, there are five states of electronic operation; OFF, LATCHED,
                COAST, TRANSMISSION LATCHED and overspeed
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vehicle Retarder</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics the desired mode of operation for the vehicle
                retarder feature.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">OFF</emph>- Feature is disabled at all times.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Latched</emph>- The vehicle retarder will be enabled when the proper
                        engine/vehicle conditions are satisfied. When either cruise control or PTO speed control is on,
                        the brake pedal must be applied before vehicle retarder will be enabled. The vehicle retarder
                        will remain enabled until the accelerator pedal is depressed or low idle speed has been reached.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Coast</emph>
                        - The vehicle retarder will be enabled when the proper engine/vehicle conditions are satisfied.
                        When either the cruise control or PTO speed control is on, the brake pedal must be applied
                        before vehicle retarder will be enabled. The vehicle retarder will remain enabled only if the
                        brake pedal is continually depressed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Transmission Latched</emph>
                        - The vehicle retarder will be operated similarly to the LATCHED state, however the engine is
                        allowed to operate at a higher rpm range in this state because the transmission is the retarding
                        device.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Overspeed</emph>
                        - This protection is provided in all active vehicle retarder states. This is included so the
                        vehicle retarder will become enabled when rpm is too high.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM Diagnostics</emph>
            </para>
            <para>There are three components required for vehicle retarder operation:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The operator request for vehicle retarder operation. This is accomplished with an in-cab
                        switch that will allow the system to be turned ON or OFF. The switch signals the operator's
                        request to the Electrical System Controller (ESC) and the ESC relays that request over the Power
                        Train Data Link to the ECM. The operator's request for vehicle retarder operation can be
                        verified by viewing the condition of the vehicle retarder dash switch with an EST. If the ECM
                        receives the request from the ESC, the EST will show the Switch State as ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The programmable parameter "retarder mode" must be set for the desired operational mode. The
                        parameter enables the engine strategy which checks engine operational conditions to determine if
                        the vehicle retarder should be engaged. The parameter can be checked using the EST.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM PIN 47 controls the vehicle retarder relay. This is accomplished by grounding PIN 85
                        of the vehicle retarder relay. This can be checked with a breakout box installed on the chassis
                        side of the ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para id="f175fc265">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 265</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 62, FMI 11</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vehicle Retarder Relay OCC Diagnostic Trouble Code</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Output Circuit Test, performed during an ON Demand Engine Standard Test, will test the coil side
                of the vehicle retarder relay and circuit for an open or short condition. If an Out of Range condition
                exists, Diagnostic Trouble Code 265 will be set.
            </para>
            <figure id="f17503103.1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8850.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Electronic Engine Controls Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to S08285 - Electrical Circuit Diagrams - 4200/4300/4400</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_P17503001.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_110.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
