<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INJECTION CONTROL PRESSURE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="OVERVIEW" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Injection Control Pressure System Operation</title>
            <para>The Injection Control Pressure system provides the necessary energy to hydraulically actuate the HEUI
                injectors. Engine lube oil is the hydraulic fluid used for this purpose.
            </para>
            <para>Lube oil is drawn from the oil pan through the pickup tube by the engine oil lubrication pump. The
                lubrication pump is a gerotor type pump driven by the crankshaft. Filtered oil is fed through passages
                in the front cover to the oil reservoir which is an integral part of the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir makes available a constant supply of oil to a high pressure hydraulic pump mounted to
                the front cover. The high pressure pump is a gear driven swash plate type pump. High pressure oil is
                delivered by the high pressure pump to the high pressure oil supply manifold and into oil passages
                machined into the cylinder head.
            </para>
            <para>When the solenoid of an injector is energized high pressure lube oil is utilized to pressurize and
                atomize the fuel into the combustion chamber. After injection is complete the solenoid is deactivated
                and the oil within the injector is vented through the top portion of the injector and allowed to drain
                back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>Injection control pressure is, governed by the Electronic Control Module, (ECM) depending upon
                operating conditions and the driver's demand for power. The Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) is used
                by the ECM for this purpose. The IPR valve is mounted on the high pressure pump and achieves injection
                control pressure regulation by dumping excess oil into the front cover and back to the oil pan.
            </para>
            <para>The injection control pressure sensor (ICP) provides feedback pressure information to the ECM in the
                form of an analog voltage signal. Injection control pressure ranges from 500 to 3500 psi (3.4 to 25
                MPa), depending on the engine family.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750103" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/eg8529.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Injection Control Pressure System Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Internal Oil Reservoir (cast into front cover)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. High Pressure Oil Pump Assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Injection Pressure Regulator valve (IPR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. High Pressure Oil Supply Rail</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. High Pressure Oil Supply Hose</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. Injection Control Pressure Sensor (ICP)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
