<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - HARD START AND NO START DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - Engine
        Systems
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Engine Systems</title>
        <figure id="f2400513" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD31/D3156.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Purpose</emph>
        </para>
        <para>To check engine systems for hard or no start conditions</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Tools</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Inspection lamp</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                    safety instructions in the foreword of this manual. Follow all warnings, cautions, and notes.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Procedure</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect entire fuel system (including tank and lines) for leaks and damage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check entire engine for any oil leaks.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect entire cooling system for leaks.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check sensor, relay, and control module connections. All connections must be seated, in good
                condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The engine will not start with the IPR valve, CMP sensor, or CKP sensor disconnected.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect battery cable and fuse connections for corrosion. All connections must be seated, in
                good condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect engine wiring harness for correct routing and protection against rubbing or
                chaffing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check air induction system for leaks.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If leaks in the air induction system are suspected, continue with Step 8.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner housing for damage or distortion that could allow unfiltered air into
                the engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect for end seal movement inside the housing. End seal movement is indicated if the seal
                contact area is polished. A polished contact area indicates that unfiltered air has passed by the filter
                element and into the engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect air cleaner element for end cap dents, holes, damaged seals, and soot.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect air intake hoses and clamps for tightness and positioning over sealing beads.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the chassis mounted charge air cooler and piping.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Possible Causes</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Loose or leaking fuel supply lines could cause fuel system to lose prime.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Kinked or blocked fuel supply lines can restrict fuel flow.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Massive or excessive fuel and oil leaks</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Coolant leaks could indicate serious engine damage.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Damaged or incorrectly installed electronic connectors</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Blockage in the air induction system</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_75.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_77.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
