<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Hard Start and No Start
        Diagnostics - Test Procedures - 8. Engine Systems
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>8. Engine Systems</title>
        <figure id="f2700533" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH31/H31129.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Purpose</title>
        </para>
        <para>To inspect engine and control system for damage (leaks, open connections, or harness chaffing)</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Tools</title>
            <item>
                <para>Inspection lamp</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, read all
                    safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect fuel supply system (including tank and lines) for leaks and damage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check high-pressure oil line from high-pressure pump to supply manifold for major leaks.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check engine for oil leaks.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect cooling system for leaks.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check sensor, relay, and control module connections. All connections must be seated, in good
                condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The engine will not start if the following components are disconnected or damaged:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Injection Pressure Regulator (IPR) valve</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Camshaft Position (CMP) sensor</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Crankshaft Position (CKP) sensor</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Injector Driver Module (IDM)</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect battery cable and fuse connections for corrosion. All connections must be seated, in
                good condition, and free of damage or corrosion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect engine wiring harness for correct routing and protection against rubbing or
                chaffing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the following components of the air induction system for leaks:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect air filter housing for damage or distortion that could allow unfiltered air into the
                        engine.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect air filter housing for end seal movement. End seal movement is indicated if the seal
                        contact area is polished. A polished contact area indicates that unfiltered air has passed by
                        the filter element and into the engine.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect air filter element for end cap dents, holes, damaged seals, and soot.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect air intake hoses and clamps for tightness and positioning over sealing beads.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect the chassis mounted Charge Air Cooler (CAC) and piping.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Unfiltered air will cause accelerated engine wear.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Record identified problems on Diagnostic Form.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If problems were identified, repair as necessary and verify if a hard start and no start
                        condition still exists.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If no problems were identified, continue with the next diagnostic test.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <item>
                <para>Loose or leaking fuel supply lines could cause fuel system to lose prime.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Kinked or blocked fuel supply lines can restrict fuel flow.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Massive or excessive fuel or oil leaks</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Coolant leaks could indicate serious engine damage.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Damaged or incorrectly installed electronic connectors</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Blockage in the air induction system</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_86.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_88.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
