<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Cylinder Head and Valve Train -
        Clean, Inspect, Measure, and Test - Measure Rocker Shaft
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="measure" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Measure Rocker Shaft</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent engine damage, if replacing the rocker arm shaft, all rocker arms must be replaced.
                    Reusing rocker arms on a new shaft will not allow proper break-in, causing premature failure.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f3350013357" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH08/H08023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Rocker arm shaft measurement</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect rocker shaft for scoring, pitting, and wear. Replace rocker arm shaft and all of the
                rocker arms if required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>It is normal to see slight polishing at rocker arm contact areas.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure a non-contact area of the rocker arm shaft using an
                <hotlnk document="eges3351_341.xml" xrefid="t335001303" appearance="hottext">outside micrometer</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t335001303"/>. This dimension will be used as a baseline for shaft diameter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure each of the 12 rocker arm contact areas of the rocker arm shaft with a micrometer.
                If the difference between the baseline measurement and any of the contact area measurements is greater
                than 0.03 mm (0.001 in), replace the rocker shaft and all rocker arms.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean oil supply holes with a small wire or another suitable tool.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect cup plugs at each end of the rocker arm shaft. Do not disturb the cup plugs unless
                they are damaged. If replacement is required, pry out plugs and press in new plugs.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_313.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_315.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
