<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine Service, Model Year 1994 - 1998 - CRANKCASE, CRANKSHAFT, CONNECTING
        RODS AND PISTONS - Crankcase Reconditioning
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Crankcase Reconditioning</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Cleaning</title>
            <para>The best way to clean the crankcase during an engine overhaul is in a chemical bath or HOT TANK. This
                procedure removes all carbonized material and mineral deposits which collect in the cooling passages.
                However, when a HOT TANK is not available, use the following.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Thoroughly clean and inspect crankcase before and after reconditioning.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a scraper and a sanding block to clean all old gasket material from the machined
                    surfaces of the crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the cylinder bore with soap, water and a nylon brush.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the pipe plugs on front of crankcase. Thoroughly clean all of the oil passages
                    and bolt holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the main oil gallery plugs. Use a nylon brush to clean the main oil gallery.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1200761" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1855.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Valve Lifter and Main Oil Gallery Plug Locations</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve Lifter Oil Gallery Plugs</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main Oil Gallery Plug</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the valve lifter oil gallery plugs located in the rear of the crankcase and
                    discard them. Use a nylon brush to clean to clean the valve lifter oil galleries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Aviation Permatex No. 3 to the main oil gallery plug and install it into the
                    crankcase. Make sure the top of main oil gallery plug is below the surface level of the crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Aviation Permatex No. 3 to the new valve lifter oil gallery plugs and install them
                    into the crankcase.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_195.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201_197.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1201.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
