<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Engine Service Manual - Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) -
        Removal
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="s05.2">
        <title>Removal</title>
        <svcproc id="s05.2.1" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information"
                        section of this manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, shift the transmission to park or neutral, set the
                        parking brake, and block the wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, make sure the engine and turbocharger have cooled before
                        removing the turbocharger.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, remove the ground cable from the negative terminal of the
                        main battery before disconnecting or connecting electrical components. Always connect the ground
                        cable last.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not let engine fluids stay on your skin. Clean skin
                        and nails using hand cleaner and wash with soap and water. Wash or discard clothing and rags
                        contaminated with engine fluids.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <regulation>
                    <para>Engine fluids (oil, fuel, and coolant) may be a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose
                        of engine fluids according to applicable regulations. Never put engine fluids in the trash, on
                        the ground, in sewers or bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </regulation>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the following service sections for information on removal of components prior to this
                        section.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine Electrical</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculating (EGR) System</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_109.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451_111.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3451.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
