<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Power Cylinders - Installation -
        Installing Piston and Connecting Rod Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="svcproc005" graphiccount="7">
        <title>Installing Piston and Connecting Rod Assembly</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, keep the fractured mating surfaces of the connecting rod and cap clean and
                    free of lint and debris. Do not allow the mating surfaces to rest on any surface. Do not bump mating
                    surfaces or drop the connecting rod or cap. This could cause chipping and wear on the mating
                    surface, resulting in improper mating during installation and possible engine damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
            <note>
                <para>Turn the crankshaft so that the No. 1 and No. 6 connecting rod journals are at TDC. Install the
                    No. 1 and No. 6 piston and connecting rod assemblies first. Then repeat the procedure for the No. 2
                    and No. 5 assemblies. Finish with the No. 3 and No. 4 assemblies.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, make sure that the longer side of the connecting rod bolted joint is
                    oriented opposite the camshaft side of the engine.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the piston rings with clean engine oil. Stagger the piston ring gaps approximately
                120 degrees around the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f26508install15" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH04/H04018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Installing the piston ring compression tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the
                <hotlnk document="eges2651_175.xml" xrefid="t08007" appearance="hottext">piston ring compression tool
                </hotlnk>
                over the piston rings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the cylinder sleeve and connecting rod bearing shell with clean engine oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f26508install16" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figH04/H04019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Installing the piston and connecting rod assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the piston and connecting rod assembly without the rod cap into the cylinder sleeve.
                Use a wooden or plastic handle to carefully push the assembly into the cylinder sleeve. Do not scratch
                the cylinder wall.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully guide the piston and connecting rod assembly onto the crankshaft connecting rod
                journal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To avoid engine damage, always make sure the rod cap serial number is assembled to the same side
                    as the connecting rod serial number (they must match). If the rod cap is reversed when assembled to
                    the connecting rod or a rod cap is not installed on its original matching connecting rod, the
                    fractured mating surfaces will be ruined. This may cause the rod cap to come loose and cause severe
                    engine damage. The entire connecting rod assembly must then be replaced.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f26508install17" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figF04/F0403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Matching serial number locations</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The fractured mating surfaces of each rod and cap pair are precisely matched. Always keep each cap with
            its respective rod. If unsure, match the serial numbers on the sides of each rod and cap.
        </para>
        <figure id="f26508install18" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figF04/F0402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>An offset indicates incorrect rod cap assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The rod cap can only be correctly installed on the connecting rod if it is oriented in the correct
            direction. If the rod cap is reversed during assembly of the connecting rod, an obvious offset will be seen
            at the mating surfaces. If the connecting rod assembly is installed on the crankshaft in this manner, the
            connecting rod must be replaced. Also check the crankshaft journal fillets for damage. Such damage will
            require replacement of the crankshaft.
        </para>
        <figure id="f26508install19.5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figF04/F0401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Arrow for correct orientation</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Each rod cap has an arrow for correct orientation in the engine during installation. The arrow
                    must point toward the front of the engine.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the bearing shell in the connecting rod cap with clean engine oil.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f26508install18.5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh04/h04021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Installing the connecting rod cap</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the cap and two bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f26508install19" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figh04/h04022.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Torquing the connecting rod cap bolts</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque the connecting rod cap bolts to the
                <hotlnk document="eges2651_174.xml" xrefid="t08006" appearance="hottext">special torque value</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_170.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_172.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
