<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Electronic Control
        Systems Diagnostics - Circuit Diagnostics - ECI System (Engine Crank Inhibit)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>ECI System (Engine Crank Inhibit)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f27007047" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Function diagram for ECI system</caption>
            </figure>
            <para id="ECI">The function diagram for the ECI system consists of the following.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Starter</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Starter relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>World Transmission Electronically Controlled (WTEC)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Neutral Start Backup Switch (NSBU)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para id="s27007034">
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The Engine Crank Inhibit (ECI) is a function of the ECM to control the operation of the starter. The
                ECM prevents engagement of the starter when the engine is running. This prevents damage to the starter
                pinion and ring gear. The transmission neutral safety switch or clutch switch prevents engagement of the
                starter when the transmission is in gear or when the clutch pedal is not depressed.
            </para>
            <para>The engine starter relay controls battery voltage to the starter solenoid. The starter relay can also
                be controlled by an optional over crank thermocouple.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The ECM controls the starting system. The clutch switch or transmission neutral switch provide input
                to the ECM. Both switches prevent the starter from being engaged unless the transmission is in neutral
                or the clutch is depressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Start Relay</title>
            </para>
            <para>The engine starter relay controls voltage to the starter motor. Turning the ignition switch to start
                position supplies current to energize the relay at Pin 86. If the engine is not running and the
                driveline is not engaged, the ECM Pin X3-23 will enable the relay by suppling a ground circuit to Pin 85
                of the relay. When the relay is closed, current passes through the relay to the pins on the starter
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect circuit connectors for loose or damaged pins or wires. Wires and
                connections must be free of damage or corrosion. When connectors corrode, a white residue will be
                present and must be removed. Make sure the batteries are fully charged. To ensure accurate readings,
                check battery cables and grounds for clean and tight connections.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Clutch Switch</title>
            </para>
            <para>Manual transmissions use the clutch switch to supply a signal to the ECM indicating that the driveline
                is disengaged. A 12 V signal on the Driveline Disengagement Switch (DDS) circuit indicates that the
                clutch is disengaged. A 0 V signal indicates that the clutch is engaged.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Neutral Switch</title>
            </para>
            <para>Allison LCT transmissions use the neutral position switch to supply power to the starter relay and a
                signal to the ECM that the driveline is disengaged. Vehicles programmed for Allison AT/MT transmissions
                receive a 12 V signal on the DDS circuit indicating that the transmission is out of gear. A 0 V signal
                indicates that the transmission is in gear. When the transmission is in gear no power is available to
                the ECI relay.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>WTEC MD with Auto Neutral</title>
            </para>
            <para>Allison MD World Transmission Electronically Controlled (WTEC) transmissions (with optional Auto
                Neutral) have a crank inhibit system with an additional relay. The relay inhibits cranking when the
                transmission is in auto neutral. Pin 6 of the transmission ECU controls 12 V to Pin 86 of the starter
                relay. Pin X3-8 of the ECM receives 12 V from the WTEC Auto Neutral relay when the transmission is
                shifted to neutral or auto neutral. Without the additional relay, the DDS input (Pin X3-8) allows
                cranking in auto neutral.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM recognizes that the engine is not running and the driveline is not engaged, the ECM will
                ground Pin X3-23. This provides a current path for the ECI relay to close when the Start switch is
                engaged or the starter button is depressed.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM recognizes that the engine is running or the driveline is engaged, the ECM will open Pin
                X3-23. This prevents the ECI relay from closing and the starter motor from engaging.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            </para>
            <para>When the on demand Engine ON standard test is run, an open or short to ground can be detected on the
                coil side of the ECI relay.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>EST with MasterDiagnostics&#174; software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EZ-Tech&#174; interface cable</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Digital Multimeter (DMM)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Breakout Box</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-Banana Plug Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>500 Ohm Resistor Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Relay breakout harness</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECI Circuit Diagnostics</title>
            <figure id="f27007048" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh31/h31063.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>ECI circuit diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECI circuit requires the use of vehicle circuit diagrams. See truck Chassis Electrical Circuit
                Diagram Manual for circuit numbers, connector and fuse locations.
            </para>
            <table id="te27007038" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.05in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.12in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Relay Voltage Checks</emph>
                                    (Turn the ignition switch to ON. Check with ECI relay removed.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>86 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12 V &#177;1.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Check with relay disconnected and starter switch (key or button) engaged. If no
                                    voltage present, troubleshoot ignition crank circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>30 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12 V &#177; 1.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If no voltage is present, troubleshoot battery wiring.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>85 to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4 V to 5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>ECM will pull circuit up to 4 V to 5 V with switch ON and go to 0 V when the
                                    clutch is depressed or transmission is in neutral.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle - comply
                        with the following:
                    </para>
                    <para>When running the engine in the service bay, make sure the parking brake is set, the
                        transmission is in neutral, and the wheels are blocked.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>ECI Circuit Test - With the transmission out of gear and the clutch depressed with wheels safely
                blocked, insert a harness between socket Pin 86 and 87 of the starter relay. If the engine cranks when
                the start switch is engaged, check for failed ECI relay or problems with the ECM or ECM wiring harness.
            </para>
            <table id="te27007039" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.03in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.12in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="3.00*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ECI Chassis Circuit Checks</emph>
                                    (Check with key-on engine-off, ECI relay installed, and breakout box connected.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Comment</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>X3-8 to X3-7</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0 V or 12 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Manual Trans - 12 V with clutch pedal down, 0 V clutch pedal up.</para>
                                <para>Auto Trans - 12 V with trans in neutral, 0 V trans in gear.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="2">
                                <para>X3-23 to X3-7</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>12 V &#177; 1.5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If no voltage is present with ignition switch in start position or start button
                                    pressed, troubleshoot battery wiring.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>0 V to 0.6 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>At crank with clutch down or auto trans in neutral, if ECM Pin X3-8 is at 12 V and
                                    Pin X3-23 is not at 0 V to 0.6 V, check ECM programming. Cranking allowed. See truck
                                    Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>4 V to 5 V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>Pull up voltage from ECM with key-on engine-off or running: transmission in gear
                                    or clutch up.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_135.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_137.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
