<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - ENGINE ELECTRICAL - Cleaning and Inspection</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="s26510.4">
        <title>Cleaning and Inspection</title>
        <svcproc id="s26510.4.5" svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Main Engine Wiring Harness</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully inspect wiring harness for worn conduit, frayed insulation or heat damage on
                    wires. Repair or replace if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect sensor and valve connectors for cracked connector bodies, bent pins, chaffing,
                    and damaged or missing O-rings. Replace connectors if necessary. Replace O-rings if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect each connector for the following conditions and replace, if necessary:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Corroded connectors (green or gray) and white deposits on metal terminals.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Female connector sleeves spread open.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Terminals incorrectly latched in connector body or pushed back relative to other terminals
                            in same connector.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure that each connector has its ribbed seal in place. During disassembly, a ribbed
                            seal may pull off of its connector and remain in the mating socket of a sensor or actuator.
                            A connector assembled without the correct ribbed seal can be contaminated with moisture and
                            have corroded terminals, causing a poor electrical connection.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check engine wiring harness connectors, connector covers, seals, and cover shields for
                    cracks, cuts or worn areas. Replace if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_221.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_223.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
