<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - DIAGNOSTIC PROCEDURES FOR THE ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM - Using Master Diagnostics To Test 3 Wire
        Pressure and APS / IVS Sensors
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="PROCTYPE" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Using Master Diagnostics To Test 3 Wire Pressure and APS / IVS Sensors</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Displaying Sensor Voltages</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Sensor voltages can be displayed on Master Diagnostics (Version 2.31 and above) by opening the session
            file
            <emph type="bold">SENSOR VOLTAGE</emph>
            and starting the
            <emph type="bold">KEY-ON ENGINE-OFF CONTINUOUS MONITOR</emph>test. Voltages can be displayed with the engine
            running by using the
            <emph type="bold">KEY-ON ENGINE-RUNNING CONTINUOUS MONITOR</emph>
            test. The voltage displayed by Master Diagnostics represents the voltage read by the ECM on the internal
            circuitry connected to the sensor signal pin of the 60-pin ECM connector. The following signal voltages will
            be displayed: APS, BAP ECT, EOP, EOT, EPS, IAT, ICP, MAP, RPS, IVS PWR.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Signal Circuit, Open Circuit Check (3 wire)</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use Master Diagnostics to display the sensor signal voltage. Install the breakout tee in the harness
            connector. Read the displayed voltage with the sensor disconnected. The displayed voltage should match the
            expected voltage listed in the diagnostic section for that sensor. The open circuit signal will be near zero
            unless the circuit is shorted or incorrectly wired to V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>, B+, or other voltage sources, .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17503008.1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8832.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Testing Open Circuit Signal Voltage with ZTSE4347</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. Ground, (black)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. Signal, (green)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. Vref, (blue)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Reference Voltage, V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                Check (3 wire)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use a 0.5 k&#x2126; jumper wire to connect the V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            pin to the signal pin of the breakout tee. View the voltage on the EST. Reference voltage should measure
            greater than 4.9 volts with the sensor disconnected. If the voltage reading is lower than expected, verify
            reference voltage at other V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            sensors that share the same circuit (V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>D: EOP, MAP, CMP, ICP), (V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>B: APS/IVS, BAP), (V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>C: body builder accessories). If the other sensors on the shared circuit have V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            that meets the expectations, the harness wire from the harness splice point to the sensor connector is at
            fault. If the other sensors have also lost the reference voltage, disconnect the sensors one at a time while
            observing the voltage. If V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            returns after disconnecting a sensor, that sensor is shorting V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            to ground. If V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            is suspected of shorting out intermittently during engine operation, use a breakout tee on the ICP or MAP
            sensor. Jumping V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            to the signal will allow V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>
            to be displayed on Master Diagnostics while running the engine.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Operation of the engine may be degraded slightly because the sensor will set an active code and
                    fault management will take over its function. Refer to Measuring Reference Voltage with Master
                    Diagnostics, . Sensor voltage cannot be displayed while the vehicle is moving.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f17503008.2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8833.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Measuring Reference Voltage using Master Diagnostics with ZTSE4347</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. Ground, (black pin)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. Vref, (blue pin)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. Signal, (green pin)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>THE ECM WILL NOT DISPLAY A SENSOR SIGNAL VOLTAGE GREATER THAN 5 VOLTS. If V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    is shorted high (voltage greater than 5.5 volts) the signal voltage will also be biased higher than
                    its true reading. The MAP sensor is the most sensitive to this higher V
                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                    and will set an in-range Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC) before the ICP and EOP sensors.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Sensor Ground Check (3 wire)</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use a jumper wire to connect V
            <subscript>REF</subscript>, the signal , and the ground together through the breakout tee. View the voltage
            on the EST with the sensor disconnected. The displayed voltage should match the expected voltage listed in
            the diagnostic section for that sensor. The displayed voltage will be near 0 volts if the ground circuit has
            the correct resistance. Refer to Sensor Ground Check, .
        </para>
        <figure id="f17503008.3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figEg8/EG8834.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Sensor Ground Check with ZTSE4347</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. Ground, (black pin)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. Vref, (blue pin)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. Signal, (green pin)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_ELEC.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_74.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
