<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Flywheel and Flywheel Housing -
        Recondition
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Recondition</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="recondition" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Resurface Flywheel</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Flywheels used with manual transmissions may be resurfaced to correct minor wear and scoring
                        if flywheel is not cracked or damaged and meets minimum thickness
                        <hotlnk document="eges3351_364.xml" xrefid="t335001401">specification</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="t335001401"/>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not machine flywheel beyond minimum thickness
                        specified for flywheel resurfacing.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>Flywheel resurfacing information is provided for guidance only. International Truck and Engine
                        Corporation assumes no responsibility either for the results of any work performed in accordance
                        with this information or for the ability of service personnel to detect cracks.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f3350014433" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg2/EG2375.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Flywheel surface dimension (typical)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Flywheel thickness (dimension "A")</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Clutch disc mounting face</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Crankshaft flange mounting face</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, carefully examine flywheel for any cracks or heat checks
                        before and after resurfacing. Cracks in the flywheel can cause it to separate. If there are any
                        questions, do not reuse the flywheel.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check flywheel for cracks and damage. Replace flywheel if required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure flywheel thickness and compare to minimum required thickness
                    <hotlnk document="eges3351_364.xml" xrefid="t335001401">Specification</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t335001401"/>. Discard flywheel if below minimum thickness specification or if flywheel
                    will be below minimum thickness after resurfacing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Resurface flywheel. See flywheel resurfacing machine operators manual for instructions
                    on flywheel resurfacing procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check flywheel for cracks and damage after resurfacing. Replace flywheel if required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure flywheel thickness after resurfacing and compare to minimum required thickness
                    Specification. Discard flywheel if below minimum thickness specification.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_356.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_358.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
