<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diamond Logic&#8482; Engine Brake -
        Installation
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Installation</title>
        <svcproc graphiccount="8">
            <title>Brake Assembly</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                        certain that the parking brake is set, wheels are blocked, and transmission is in neutral before
                        cranking engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The seal and backup ring for the high-pressure oil manifold and brake assembly oil inlet
                        adapters may be the same color. The larger diameter ring must be installed first and then the
                        smaller seal can be installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Back off all valve lash adjustments. This must be done to eliminate the possibility of
                    additional forces on the brake assembly when torqing mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2651416" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh08/h08053.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>High-pressure oil manifold and brake assembly oil inlet adapter seal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Backup ring</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Seal</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat six new injector oil inlet seals with clean engine oil and install onto
                    high-pressure oil manifold and brake assembly oil inlet adapters.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2651417" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh08/h08052.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>High-pressure oil manifold and brake assembly O-ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat new oil inlet O-ring with clean engine oil and install onto cylinder head oil inlet
                    recess.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, have an
                        assistant help remove or install the engine brake assembly when working within the chassis due
                        to its heavy weight and limited accessibility.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f2651418" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh08/h08051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Installing the high-pressure oil manifold and brake assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift assembly up and place onto engine. Align high-pressure oil manifold oil inlet
                    adapters with injector inlets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2651419" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH08/H08090.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Engine brake bolt torque sequence</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and hand tighten all brake housing bolts (M8 x 90). Torque bolts to the
                    <hotlnk document="eges2651_285.xml" xrefid="t2651402" appearance="hottext">special torque value
                    </hotlnk>
                    in a circular pattern, beginning from the center.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Air trapped within the engine brake rail will be purged automatically during the cranking and
                        start-up phase.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f2651420" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh09/h09048.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Injector electrical connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect each valve cover gasket pass-through connector to its respective injector and
                    clip harness onto the brake housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2651421" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh09/h09034.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor electrical connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor electrical connector to valve cover
                    gasket pass-through connector (rear) and clip harness to brake housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2651422" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figh09/h09035.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Brake shutoff valve assembly electrical connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect brake shutoff valve electrical connector to valve cover gasket pass-through
                    connector and clip harness to brake housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor electrical connector to the valve cover
                    gasket pass-through connector.
                </para>
                <figure id="f2651423" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figh09/h09036.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                    <caption>Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor electrical connector</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) sensor electrical connector to the valve
                    cover gasket pass-through connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_281.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_S2651499.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
