<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diagnostic Software
        Operation - Diagnostic Tests - Key-On Engine-Running Tests
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="13">
        <title>Key-On Engine-Running Tests</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The KOER Standard test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is
                        required.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>During the KOER Standard test, the ECM commands the IPR through a step test to determine if the ICP
                system is performing as expected. The ECM monitors signal values from the ICP sensor and compares those
                values to the expected values. When the Standard test is done, the ECM returns the engine to normal
                operation and transmits DTCs set during the test.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before doing this test, confirm the following conditions:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Problems causing active DTCs were corrected, and active DTCs were cleared.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine coolant temperature must be at least 70 &#176;C (158 &#176;F).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Battery voltage must be higher than 10.5 volts.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>No signal from Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Transmission in park or neutral</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f27003022" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31180.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>KOER Standard session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine running, select D_KOER_Standard.ssn from the open session file window.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003023" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31148.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Standard test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOER Diagnostics menu, select Standard and select Run to start the test.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>The ECM increases engine idle to a predetermined value and commands the IPR valve to set ICP to rated
                speed pressure. If the performance of the ICP system is acceptable, the ECM will control the IPR valve
                and reduce the pressure in steps, while continuing to monitor the ICP system.
            </para>
            <para>When the test is done, the ECM restores normal engine operation, and the Diagnostic Trouble Code
                window will display DTCs, if there are problems.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Correct problem causing active DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003024" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Continuous Monitor Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Continuous Monitor test troubleshoots intermittent connections at sensors and actuators. The
                engine can be off or running.
            </para>
            <para>The EST monitors the following circuits:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Barometric Absolute Pressure (BAP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Battery Voltage (VBatt)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake Control Pressure (BCP) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGR Valve Position (EGRP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Level (ECL)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure (EOP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Temperature (EOT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake Air Temperature (IAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Control Pressure (ICP)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Air Temperature (MAT)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f27003025" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31240.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Continuous Monitor session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine running, select D_ContinuousMonitor.ssn from the open session file
                    window.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003026" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31233.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Continuous Monitor test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOER Diagnostics menu, select Continuous Monitor and select Run to start the
                    test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, be
                        careful to avoid rotating parts (belts and fan) and hot engine surfaces.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wiggle connectors and wires at all suspected problem locations. If circuit continuity is
                    interrupted, the EST will display DTCs related to the condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Correct problem causing active DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003027" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Management Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before doing this test, Performance Diagnostics tests 1 through 12 should be completed.
                        Problems with other systems (injectors, fuel supply, etc.) can affect Air Management test
                        results.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>The Air Management test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is
                        required. The Standard test must be done before doing the Air Management test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Air Management test checks the operation of the Air Management System and the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>EVRT&#174; electronically controlled turbocharger - International's version of a Variable
                        Geometry Turbocharger (VGT)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) valve</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>During the Air Management test, the ECM commands the VGT control actuator and EGR actuator through a
                step test sequence to determine if actuators and the Air Management System are performing as expected.
                The ECM monitors the feedback signal values from the Exhaust Back Pressure (EBP) sensor and compares
                those values to the expected values.
            </para>
            <para>If a fault is detected the test will end, engine operation will return to normal, and a DTC will be
                set.
            </para>
            <para>If there are no faults, the test will be completed and engine operation will return to normal.</para>
            <figure id="f27003028" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31238.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Air Management session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine running, select D_KOER_AirManagement.ssn from the open session file
                    window and select OPEN to open the session.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003029" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31234.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Air Management test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From KOER Diagnostics menu, select Air Management and Run to start the test.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Correct problem causing active DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear DTCs.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003030" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Air Management Test</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f27003031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Air Management diagnostic readout</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECM commands the EGR valve to close. The ECM then increases engine idle speed to 950 RPM and
                commands the VGT vanes to fully open. The ECM allows EBP to stabilize. The ECM monitors the EBP pressure
                and compares this pressure to the expected pressure; pressure is expected to drop. If EBP pressure does
                not match expected pressure, DTC 345 is set and the test is cancelled.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Although commanding the EGR to close, it may be stuck partially open, which would cause EBP
                        values to be lower than expected causing the test to fail during the VGT portion of this test.
                        If this is suspected, the operation of the EGR valve should be visually inspected using the
                        Output State tests.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>With the EGR still closed, the ECM commands the VGT vanes to fully close. The ECM allows EBP to
                stabilize. The ECM monitors the EBP pressure and compares this pressure to the expected pressure;
                pressure is expected to increase. If EBP pressure does not match expected pressure, DTC 345 is set and
                the test is cancelled.
            </para>
            <para>With the EGR still closed, the ECM commands the VGT vanes to fully open. The ECM allows EBP to
                stabilize. The ECM monitors EBP pressure and compares this pressure to the expected pressure; pressure
                is expected to drop. If EBP pressure does not match expected pressure, DTC 345 is set and the test is
                cancelled.
            </para>
            <para>If all pressures matched the expected pressures, no DTC is set and the test will continue for EGR.
            </para>
            <para>With the EGR still closed, the ECM increases engine RPM to 1200 rpm and commands the VGT vanes to
                fully close. The ECM allows EBP to stabilize. The ECM monitors the EBP pressure and compares this
                pressure to the expected pressure; pressure is expected to increase. If EBP pressure does not match
                expected pressure, DTC 346 is set and the test is cancelled.
            </para>
            <para>With the VGT vanes still closed, the ECM commands the EGR to open, and allows EBP to stabilize. The
                ECM monitors the EBP pressure and compares this pressure to the expected values; pressure is expected to
                drop. If EBP pressure does not match expected pressure, DTC 346 is set and the test is cancelled.
            </para>
            <para>With the VGT still closed, the ECM then commands the EGR to close, and allows EBP to stabilize. The
                ECM monitors the EBP pressure and compares this pressure to the expected pressure; pressure is expected
                to increase. If EBP pressure does not match expected pressure, DTC 346 is set and the engine will return
                to normal operation.
            </para>
            <para>If all pressures matched the expected pressures, no DTC is set and the engine is returned to normal
                operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VGT Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The VGT test can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is required. The
                        Standard test must be done before doing the VGT test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The VGT test is a manual test that allows the technician to set the VGT duty to low, medium, or high
                and inspect the exhaust system for leaks.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Monitor EBP and MAP as VGT duty cycles are changed.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f27003032" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31238.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>VGT session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine running, select D_KOER_AirManagement.ssn from the open session file
                    window and select OPEN to open the session.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f27003033" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figH31/H31232.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>VGT Low Duty cycle test</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard test is always selected and
                        run first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard test does not have to be run
                        again.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the KOER Diagnostics menu, select Low Duty Cycle from VGT, and select Run to start
                    test:
                </para>
                <para>Use the suggested toggle sequence below, to check turbocharger operation from one duty cycle to
                    the other.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Low to medium</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Medium to high</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>High to low</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Low to high</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <para>If the ECM does not receive a request from the EST, after about 40 seconds, the test will
                automatically end and the engine will return to normal operation.
            </para>
            <figure id="f27003034" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_56.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_58.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
