<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 365 Diesel Engine - 2004 Model Year - ENGINE SYSTEMS - Engine Systems - Cooling System</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Cooling System</title>
        <figure id="f2400132" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figD05/D0518.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Engine cooling system components</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Intake manifold</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">EGR cooler</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant outlet cap</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler cover</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Oil cooler (not serviced separately)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Cylinder head</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Front cover housing</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Water pump</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Thermostat assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Coolant deaeration fitting (to deaeration tank)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The cooling system keeps the engine within a designated temperature range.</para>
        <para>The centrifugal water pump (hub and impeller) is mounted in the pump housing of the front cover. The water
            pump has a built in reservoir to catch small amounts of coolant that may seep past the seal.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The water pump impeller may be damaged if dropped or hit by a hard object.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <title>Front cover housing flow</title>
        </para>
        <para>The water pump draws coolant from the radiator through inlet of the front cover housing. Coolant flows
            from the water pump through three passages in the front cover.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Two passages (left and right) direct coolant into the crankcase (front to rear) to cool the
                    cylinder walls and the cylinder heads.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The third passage directs coolant through a passage in the crankcase to the oil cooler cover.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If an oil cooler seal is damaged, weep holes in the oil filter base allow coolant to seep from the
                    cooler cover.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Coolant returns to the water pump through three passages in the front cover.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Two passages (left and right) from the crankcase direct coolant to the front cover.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A third passage directs coolant from the intake manifold to the front cover.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Return coolant is directed to the thermostat in the front cover.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>If the thermostat is open, coolant flows to the radiator.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the thermostat is closed, coolant returns to the water pump through a bypass passage in the
                    front cover, because the radiator outlet is blocked.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>As the engine reaches operating temperatures, the thermostat opens and directs coolant to the radiator.
            This also restricts the bypass opening.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Crankcase and cylinder head flow</title>
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows through passages in the front cover to the left and right sides of the crankcase. Coolant
            flows through the front of both sides of the crankcase, evenly distributing coolant around the cylinders,
            and exits the rear of the crankcase flowing up to the cylinder heads.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows from the rear of the cylinder heads to the front of the cylinder heads, exits down a passage
            in the crankcase, and returns to the front cover.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Oil cooler and EGR cooler flow</title>
        </para>
        <para>The front cover directs coolant to a passage in the crankcase. Coolant flows from the crankcase to the
            front of the oil cooler cover. The oil cooler and the oil filter base direct coolant to the front of the oil
            cooler.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows through the oil cooler from the front to rear and exits through the EGR cooler supply
            port.
        </para>
        <para>Coolant flows from the rear of the EGR cooler to the front returning to the front cover though a passage
            in the intake manifold.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The deaeration port is on top of the intake manifold.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For engines equipped with an air compressor the deaeration point is at the air compressor and
                    intake manifold.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Earlier engines have a single line from the air compressor to the deaeration tank. Later engines
                    have two lines. One from the intake and one from the air compressor that intersect one line to the
                    deaeration tank.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2952.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
