<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ENGINE SYMPTOMS DIAGNOSTICS - Test Procedures - ECM Reset/ IDM
        Reset (Intermittent Engine Stumble)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ECM Reset/ IDM Reset (Intermittent Engine Stumble)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Glow plug lamp cycles ON while engine running</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Glow plugs recycle while engine running</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Engine stumble and die</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Loss of accelerator pedal authority</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Miles driven are not logged if ECM reset occurs during current key cycle
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <title>Causes</title>
            </para>
            <para>An Electronic Control Module (ECM) reset occurs when the ECM momentarily reboots or is turned OFF and
                ON while the engine is operating.
            </para>
            <para>If a reset occurs, the engine will momentarily stumble and the ECM will go through a normal KEY ON
                cycle. This includes the following:
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Illuminate the WAIT TO START lamp</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Enable glow plugs</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Validate the accelerator pedal position</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the pedal is not at idle position when the reset occurs, a DTC is set and engine speed goes to low
                idle. The ECM will not allow accelerator pedal authority until the Accelerator Pedal Sensor (APS) is
                released.
            </para>
            <para>An Injector Drive Module (IDM) reset will occur if power is lost to the circuits for IDM Logic or IDM
                Main Power while the engine is operating. If power is lost, the engine will miss and recover or stall.
                The APS will not be affected by this fault.
            </para>
            <para>Momentary loss of power to the ECM or IDM may be caused by the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Defective fuses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent open at connectors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective battery power feed harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor ground connection</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective power relay</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shorted or open harness</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostics for Engine Stumble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EST, check for DTCs for both the engine and chassis modules.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If DTC 626 (unexpected reset fault) or 534 (IDM relay voltage low) are present as active
                            or inactive codes, continue with step 4.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If any other engine DTCs are active, perform appropriate diagnostics and repairs before
                            continuing with these procedures.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If any chassis DTCs are active when checking the Electronic System Controller (ESC),
                            perform appropriate diagnostics and repairs before continuing.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete Test 3 (Fuel Pressure) on the Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 or Section
                    6 of this manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete Test 4 (Fuel Inlet Restriction) on the Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 or
                    Section 6 of this manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">See Section 7 in this manual, the Chassis Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual and
                    Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide for the model and year of the vehicle when performing the
                    following steps.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check all ECM and IDM related fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check all Battery, VIGN and ground connections for the ECM and IDM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monitor ECM powers and grounds with breakout box under operator complaint conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monitor IDM powers and grounds with 12 Pin Breakout Harness under operator complaint
                    conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If root cause has not been identified in previous steps, continue diagnosis by
                    performing the remaining steps on the Performance Diagnostics form EGED-250 or Section 6 of this
                    manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_62.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_64.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
