<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT-365 Diesel Engine Diagnostics (2002) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEMS DIAGNOSTICS - Circuit Diagnostics -
        Engine Warning and Protection System (EWPS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Engine Warning and Protection System (EWPS)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f24007" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="d3342" filename="../figd33/D3342.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Function Diagram for the Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Function</title>
            </para>
            <para>The Engine Warning Protection System (EWPS) safeguards the engine from undesirable operating
                conditions to prevent engine damage and to prolong engine life. When a warning condition is detected,
                the on-board electronics will illuminate the red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <para>When a critical engine condition is detected, the on-board electronics will shut the engine down if
                the protection feature has been enabled. The critical engine condition will be recorded by a logging
                feature that records the event in engine hours and odometer readings. After the engine has shutdown, the
                engine may be restarted for a thirty second run time.
            </para>
            <para>There are four options of EWPS:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Standard</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>2-way warning</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-way warning</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-way protection</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EWPS Operational Diagnostics</title>
            <para>The EWPS includes the following features:</para>
            <deflist>
                <term>EWPS mode</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics the desired mode of operation for the engine
                    warning and protection feature.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>Standard warning (rpm, ECT)</term>
                <def>Engine overspeed and overheat are provided as the default operating mode. No engine shutdown is
                    available.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>2-way warning (rpm, ECT, EOP)</term>
                <def>Engine overspeed, overheat, and low oil pressure are monitored in the engine warning operating
                    mode. No engine shutdown is available.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>3-way warning (rpm, ECT, EOP, ECL)</term>
                <def>Engine overspeed, overheat, low oil pressure, and low coolant level are monitored in the engine
                    warning operating mode. No engine shutdown is available.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>3-way Protection (rpm, ECT, EOP, ECL)</term>
                <def>Engine overspeed, overheat, low oil pressure, and low coolant level are monitored in the engine
                    protection operating mode. Engine shutdown is available when a critical engine condition is
                    detected. Critical engine conditions include overheat, low oil pressure and low coolant level.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>ECT Warning Temperature</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when an engine overheat condition warrants the red ENGINE lamp to be
                    illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>ECT Critical Temperature</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when an engine overheat condition warrants an engine shutdown. The event
                    logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP RPM Boundary 1</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 1 is used for the loss of
                    engine oil pressure detection.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP RPM Boundary 2</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 2 is used for the loss of
                    engine oil pressure detection.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP RPM Boundary 3</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 3 is used for the loss of
                    engine oil pressure detection.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Warning Level 1</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure warrants the red ENGINE lamp to be
                    illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Warning Level 2</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants the red ENGINE lamp
                    to be illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Warning Level 3</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants the red ENGINE lamp
                    to be illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Critical Level 1</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown.
                    The event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer
                    readings.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Critical Level 2</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown.
                    The event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer
                    readings.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <deflist>
                <term>EOP Critical Level 3</term>
                <def>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown.
                    The event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer
                    readings.
                </def>
            </deflist>
            <para>
                <title>EWPS Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs)</title>
            </para>
            <para>DTCs are read using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by counting the flashes from the amber and
                red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc323">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 323</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine coolant below warning/critical level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 323 is set by the ECM when coolant is low. When the EWPS mode is 3-way protection and DTC
                        323 is active, the engine will shutdown. The ECM will log the engine hours and odometer reading
                        at the time of occurrence. After the shutdown, the engine can be restarted for thirty seconds.
                        When the coolant has returned to correct levels, DTC 323 will become inactive.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If coolant level is correct, see Electronic Diagnostics for ECL. An ECL signal shorted to
                        ground can cause DTC 323.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc321">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 321</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Above warning level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 321 is set by the ECM when the engine coolant temperature is above 109&#176;C (228&#176;F).
                        The ECM illuminates the red ENGINE lamp and sounds the audible alarm. When the temperature drops
                        below 109&#176;C (228&#176;F) the DTC will become inactive. See section 4 for diagnostics.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc322">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 322</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine coolant temperature above critical level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 322 is set by the ECM when the engine coolant temperature is above 112.5&#176;C (234.5&#176;F).
                        The ECM illuminates the red ENGINE lamp and sounds the audible alarm. When the temperature drops
                        below 112.5&#176;C (234.5&#176;F) the DTC will become inactive. See section 4 for diagnostics.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc325">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 325</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Power reduced, matched to cooling system performance</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 325 is set by the ECM when the cooling system temperature exceeds 107&#176;C (225&#176;C
                        ). At this temperature the ECM will reduce the fuel delivered to the engine. . When the
                        temperature drops below 107&#176;C (225&#176;C ) the DTC will become inactive and the engine
                        will return to normal operation.
                    </para>
                    <para>For each Celsius degree of temperature the fuel will be reduced 6%. This reduces the heat
                        produced by the engine and reduces the burden on the cooling system. The vehicle speed will also
                        be reduced and allow the operator to downshift and increase the efficiency of the cooling
                        system. As the temperature is reduced the compensation level is reduced until the temperature
                        drops below 107&#176;C (225&#176;C ) and normal operation is resumed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc316">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 316</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">CAP fault - unable to warm engine</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Note: DTC 316 only indicates the engine has not been able to reach operating
                        temperature. It does not indicate an electronic fault.
                    </emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 316 is set if the engine does not reach operating temperature. DTC 316 will only be set
                        with engines that have Cold Ambient Protection (CAP) strategy enabled. DTC 316 is set after the
                        engine has run for more than 120 minutes and has not exceeded the following specifications for
                        engine coolant temperature. DTC 316 can be cleared with the Electronic Service Tool.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Manual transmission 65&#176; C (149&#176; F)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Automatic transmission 60&#176; C (140&#176; F)</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 316 can be set due to any of the following conditions:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Extended idle time</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cold ambient temperatures (may require use of winter front)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Thermostat stuck in open position</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Incorrectly plumbed cooling system (thermostat bypassed)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Auxiliary heater cores cooling off engine (school bus application)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fan clutch locked on</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc313">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 313</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine oil pressure below warning level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 313 is set by the ECM when the oil pressure has dropped below the warning level. The
                        specification for the warning level is:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>34kPa (5.0 psi) @ 700 rpm</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>69 kPa (10.0 psi) @ 1400 rpm</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>138 kPa (20.0 psi) @ 2000 rpm</para>
                            <para>The ECM illuminates the red ENGINE lamp and sounds an audible alarm. See section 4 for
                                diagnostics.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 313 can be set due to a defective sensor sending an incorrect signal. To confirm this,
                        compare actual oil pressure to the reading on the data list of the EST. Low oil pressure due to
                        defective mechanical components will also set DTC 313.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc314">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 314</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine oil pressure below critical level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 314 is set by the ECM when the oil pressure has dropped below the critical level. The
                        specification for the critical level is:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>14kPa (2.0 psi) @ 700 rpm</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>34 kPa (5.0 psi) @ 1400 rpm</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>152 kPa (12.0 psi) @ 2000 rpm</para>
                            <para>The ECM flashes the red ENGINE lamp and sounds an audible alarm. See section 4 for
                                diagnostics.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 314 can be set due to a defective sensor sending an incorrect signal. To confirm this,
                        compare actual oil pressure to the reading on the data list of the EST. Low oil pressure due to
                        defective mechanical components will also set DTC 313.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <verbatim id="f240dtc315">
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">DTC 315</emph>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine speed above warning level</emph>
                </line>
            </verbatim>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 315 is set by the ECM when the engine rpm has exceeded 3350 rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>DTC 315 can be set due to any of the following conditions:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Excessive engine speed in an unintended downshift.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Steep acceleration downhill without correct brake application.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>External fuel source being ingested into air intake system.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When DTC 315 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated. The engine hours and miles of the
                        last two over speed occurrences will be recorded in the Engine Event Log.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_146.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240_148.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges240.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
