<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - GLOSSARY OF TECHNICAL TERMS -
        PROGRAMMABLE Parameters for MASTER DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PROGRAMMABLE Parameters for MASTER DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>The following programmable parameters are grouped according to control system features. Please refer to
            other engine service manuals for additional details.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">AUDIT (AUD) (ECM software)</emph>: This group of parameters allows the factory and engine
            engineering to trace the origin and the date of programming changes through the life of the engine
            electronics.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Calibration Download Date</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Calibration Tool ID</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Last Service Tool ID I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Last Service Tool ID 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Strategy Download Date</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">AUD: Strategy Tool ID</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">CRUISE CONTROL (CC):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the cruise control feature. The purpose of the cruise control feature is
            to provide electronic controlled vehicle speed regulation when the vehicle is under highway driving
            conditions. This feature also has the "bump up" and "bump down" functions. Where, the operator may "bump up"
            the vehicle speed in 1.0 mph increments when the Resume/Accel button is momentarily pressed. The operator
            may "bump down" the vehicle speed in 1.0 mph decrements when the Set/Coast button is momentarily pressed.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CC: Cruise Control High VS Limit</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CC: Cruise Control Low RPM Limit</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CC: Cruise Control Low VS Limit</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CC: Cruise Control Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CC: Cruise Control VS Ramp Rate</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">COLD AMBIENT PROTECTION MODE:</emph>This parameter customizes the cold ambient protection
            feature. Cold ambient protection (CAP) allows the engine to idle at an elevated RPM when the coolant
            temperature falls below a certain point and the ambient temperature is cold. This allows the engine to warm
            up to normal operating temperature.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">COOLANT SURGE TANK TYPE:</emph>This parameter describes the type of coolant tank installed
            in the vehicle.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">COOLANT TEMPERATURE COMPENSATION:</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the coolant temperature compensation features. The purpose of Coolant
            Temperature Compensation is to reduce the amount of fuel delivered to the engine when the engine is running
            near its maximum torque fuel delivery and coolant temperature is above a programmed value. This fuel
            reduction has two effects: First, the heat generated by the engine is reduced thereby reducing the burden on
            the engine cooling system. Second, the vehicle speed will decrease. In order to maintain the vehicle speed
            the operator is encouraged to downshift, which will result in increased efficiency of the engine cooling
            system.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CTC: Begin Derate Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CTC: Coolant Temp Compensation Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CTC: Derate Factor</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">CTC: Modify Derate Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE CRANK INHIBIT (ECI):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the crank inhibit feature. The purpose of ECI is to prevent the operator
            from cranking the engine while the engine is running or the driveline is engaged. A programmable time (1-5
            seconds) allows the on-board electronics to inhibit cranking for a short duration until engine speed reaches
            idle speed.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">ECI: Engine Crank Inhibit Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">ECI: Engine Crank Inhibit Run Mode Time</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE FAN CONTROL (EFC):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the engine fan control feature. The purpose of EFC is to provide the
            proper logic to determine when the fan should be turned on or off by energizing/de-energizing the fan
            control relay. The purpose of the engine fan is to allow more air flow for heat exchange between the
            radiator and the ambient air when needed.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Air Conditioner</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Engine Fan Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Fan Off Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Fan On Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE FAN CONTROL (EFC) FOR RADIATOR SHUTTER:</emph>
            The purpose of Radiator Shutter Enable is to provide the proper logic to open or close the radiator shutters
            (energize or de-energize a solenoid). The purpose of this device is to keep the engine warm during cold
            weather operation. This will enable faster warm up of the passenger cab thereby enabling faster defrost of
            the windshield. Fuel economy will also be improved when the radiator shutters are closed.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Radiator Shutter Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Shutter Close Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFC: Shutter Open Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE FAMILY RATING CODE:</emph>
            This group of parameters allows the on-board electronics to precisely control the fueling requirements based
            on the particular engine configuration. The on-board electronics has what is known as the Multiple Engine
            Rating Map. This allows a single on-board electronic controller to provide different engine configurations.
            Optimal control is provided for vehicles with various engine configurations and ratings: engine model, rated
            engine speed, rated engine power, and transmission type.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFRC: Engine Family Extension</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EFRC: Engine Family Rating Code</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">EVENT LOGGER (EL):</emph>
            This group of parameters indicates the electronic automatic engine event logging feature. The purpose of
            this feature is to record the accumulated engine hours and odometer readings when certain excessive engine
            operating conditions have occurred.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Coolant Hour I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Coolant Hour 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Coolant Odometer I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Coolant Odometer 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Oil Pressure Hour I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Oil Pressure Hour 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Oil Pressure Odometer I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Low Oil Pressure Odometer 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Overheat Hour I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Overheat Hour 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Overheat Odometer I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: Overheat Odometer 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: RPM Overspeed Hour I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: RPM Overspeed Hour 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: RPM Overspeed Odometer I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EL: RPM Overspeed Odometer 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ECM MANUFACTURING DATA:</emph>
            This group of parameters provides the manufacturing data feature. The date and the serial number of the
            on-board electronics are indicated, along with the level of hardware and software.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: S/W Strategy Checksum</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: ECM H/W Version</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: ECM Manufacturing Date</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: ECM S/W Calibration Version</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: ECM S/W Strategy Version</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: ECM Serial Number</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: PP List Checksum</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: PP List Level</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMD: S/W Calibration Checksum</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE SERIAL NUMBER (ESN):</emph>
            This parameter is the factory programmed engine serial number.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE WARNING AND PROTECTION SYSTEM (EWPS):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the engine warning and protection feature. The Engine Warning and
            Protection System safeguards the engine from undesirable operating conditions in order to prevent engine
            damage and to prolong engine life. When a warning condition is detected, the on-board electronics will light
            up the OIL / WATER lamp and activate the warning buzzer. When a critical condition is detected, the on-board
            electronics will shut down the engine if the engine warning and protection system has the protection feature
            enabled. After an engine shut down, the operator may restart the engine for a thirty second run time if
            desired. The event-logging feature will also record when an excessive (i.e., critical) engine event has
            occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings. Currently there are four states of electronic
            operation: STANDARD, 3-WAY WARNING, 3-WAY PROTECTION, and 2- WAY WARNING.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: ECT Critical Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: ECT Warning Temperature</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Critical Level I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Critical Level 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Critical Level 3</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP RPM Boundary I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP RPM Boundary 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP RPM Boundary 3</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Warning Level I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Warning Level 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EWPS: EOP Warning Level 3</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ELECTRONIC PRESSURE GOVERNOR (EPG):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the Electronic Pressure Governor feature. The purpose of the Electronic
            Pressure Governor is to provide closed loop control over an external pressure input. This feature is
            targeted for fluid delivery pumps, especially fire truck applications. The EPG feature also provides a loss
            of pressure detection. This is achieved by monitoring the hydraulic pressure, the engine speed, and the
            status of the EPG select switch. When a loss of pressure is detected the EPG feature is disabled and a
            corresponding DTC is set.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Driveline Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Hydraulic Pressure Governor Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Integral Gain Adjust</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Mode Indicator</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Proportional Gain Adjust</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EPG: Cavitation Operation Time</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ENGINE IDLE SHUTDOWN CONTROL (IST):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the prolonged engine idle automatic shutdown feature. The purpose of
            this feature is to shut the engine down after a programmable idle time has been exceeded. This allows the
            reduction of fuel usage, engine wear, and emissions. Thirty (30.0) seconds before an automatic engine
            shutdown, the operator will be warned via the red Oil/Water Lamp. This lamp will begin flashing until the
            engine is shutdown. The operator may override the electronics at any time. After an engine shutdown occurs,
            the Oil/Water Lamp will stop flashing and a diagnostic code will be recorded. The diagnostic code is
            recorded to assist in diagnosing possible service complaints of the engine shutting down. Currently there
            are four states of electronic operation: OFF, PTO AVAILABLE, NO ENGINE LOAD, and TAMPER PROOF.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IST: Idle Shutdown Time</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IST: Idle Shutdown Timer Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IST: Max IAT for Idle Shutdown</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IST: Min IAT for Idle Shutdown</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">IVPWR: Expected Vbat -</emph>Expected operating battery voltage on the vehicle.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">POWER TAKE OFF SPEED CONTROL (PTO):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the power take off speed control feature. Power Take Off (PTO) Speed
            Control provides a method for the operator to set and maintain a regulated engine speed, without using the
            accelerator pedal, for the purpose of operating auxiliary equipment. The power take off feature has in-cab
            and remote operator interfaces. Depending on configuration, the operator may turn on and activate PTO speed
            control while in the comfort of the cab or at the convenience of a remote interface. If both in-cab and
            remote operations are enabled, the on-board electronics senses that interface is active depending on
            operator actions. No active mobile PTO operation is possible when the PTO speed control is turned on using
            the remote interface. This feature also has the "bump up" and "bump down" functions. Where, the operator may
            "bump up" the RPM in 25 RPM increments when the Resume/Accel button is momentarily pressed or "bump down"
            when the set/coast button is momentarily pressed.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: In-Cab Control</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: In-Cab Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Max RPM</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Max VS</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Power Take Off Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Preset RPM I (Set)</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Preset RPM 2 (Resume)</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: Remote Pedal</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">PTO: RPM Ramp Rate</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TWO SPEED AXLE:</emph>
            This group of parameters is used by the ECM to determine vehicle speed calculations.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Two speed axle</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Pulses Per Mile I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Pulses Per Mile 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Rear Axle Ratio I</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Rear Axle Ratio 2</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Tire Revolutions</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Transmission Gear Teeth</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Transmission Top Gear Ratio</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">ROAD SPEED LIMITING (RSL):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the road speed-limiting feature. Road Speed Limiting is used by the ECM
            for maximum road speed governing. If the vehicle's maximum road speed exceeds the programmed maximum vehicle
            speed limit, the ECM will reduce or cut-off fueling. This feature is primarily for improving fuel economy.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">RSL: Maximum Vehicle Speed</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">RSL: Road Speed Limiting Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">RSL: RPM Limit with VSS Fault</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SHIFT SCHEDULE:</emph>
            This parameter determines how and when the ECM will request the electronic transmission controller for
            up-shifts and downshifts.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SERVICE INTERVAL (SI):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the Service Interval feature. Service Interval allows the truck owner to
            customize when a truck requires servicing, such as changing the oil. When the programmed distance, fuel
            used, or engine hour has been reached the Change Oil Lamp will be lit to indicate its time for maintenance
            and service.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Change Oil Lamp On Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Change Oil Lamp On Time</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Distance Interval</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Fuel Interval</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Hour Interval</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Service Interval Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Service Interval Reset</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Service Soon Percent</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Starting Fuel Reading</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Starting Hour Reading</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SI: Starting Odometer Reading</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TRACTION CONTROL (TC):</emph>
            This parameter determines how and when the ECM will activate its electronic traction control.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">TC: Traction Control Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TORQUE LEVEL TAILORING (TLT):</emph>
            This group of parameters customizes the torque level-tailoring feature. The torque level-tailoring feature
            allows the on-board electronics to control the engine based on possible driving situations. A typical
            application for this feature is a vehicle with on-highway and off-highway torque curves.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">TLT: Lower N/VS Ratio</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">TLT: Torque Level Tailoring Mode</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">TLT: Upper N/VS Ratio</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TOTAL MILES:</emph>
            This group of parameters indicates the vehicle accumulator data. The purpose of the Accumulators feature is
            to record the total engine hours, the total fuel used, and the total vehicle miles. This system requirement
            is intended to track engine operation for scheduled preventive maintenance and as an aid to warranty
            administration.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Total Engine On Time</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Total Fuel Used</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TOTAL TATTLETALE:</emph>
            This is an internal ECM programming tracking mechanism.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">VEHICLE RETARDER MODE:</emph>
            This parameter indicates the vehicle retarder type and its mode of operation.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">VEHICLE SPEED SIGNAL SELECTION:</emph>
            This parameter customizes the vehicle speed signal feature.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">VEHICLE IDENTIFICATION NUMBER (VIN):</emph>
            This parameter is the factory programmed vehicle identification number.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_199.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
