<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="S1750208" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEg8/Eg8882.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Camshaft Position Sensor Functions</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The CMP (Camshaft Position) sensor is a Hall Effect type sensor that generates a digital frequency as
                windows on the timing disk pass through its magnetic field. Engine speed is determined by counting 24
                windows on the timing sensor disk each camshaft revolution. The position of cylinder 1 is determined by
                distinguishing a narrow vane on the camshaft timing sensor disk.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Mode Selection -</emph>
                Allows the ECM to discern when the engine is in the off, crank or run mode.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Control Pressure -</emph>
                Engine speed is one of the controlling variables in the calculation of desired injection control
                pressure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Quantity Control/Torque Limiting -</emph>
                Engine torque and fuel is controlled and is dependent on engine speed. Fuel quantity is determined by
                engine speed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection / Management</title>
            <para>An inactive CMP signal during cranking is detectable by the ECM. An inactive CMP signal will cause a
                no start condition. Electrical noise can also be detected by the ECM, if the level is sufficient to
                effect engine operation a corresponding Diagnostic Trouble Code will be set.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The engine will not operate without a functioning CMP</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f17503032" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/eg1221.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Camshaft Position Sensor Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After removing connectors always check for damaged pins, corrosion, loose terminals.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="te17503006" frame="all">
                <title>Camshaft Position Sensor and Circuit Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="43.40*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="43.41*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="309.20*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to3"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Connector Voltage Checks</emph>(check with sensor connector
                                    disconnected, ignition key ON, all accessories off)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ground circuit, no voltage expected.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    not present, check open/short to ground Pin #40 to B, see V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    circuit (a defective EOP, ICP or MAP sensor can short V
                                    <subscript>REF</subscript>
                                    to ground).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If &#60; than 4.5V check for poor connection, if 0V check for open/short to ground
                                    circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Connector Checks to Chassis Ground</emph>(check with sensor
                                    connector (406) disconnected, positive battery cable disconnected and ignition key
                                    OFF)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance to chassis ground, check with key off, > than 5&#x2126; the harness is
                                    open.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>B to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance &#60; 1k&#x2126; indicates a short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>C to gnd</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>>1k&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance &#60; 1k&#x2126; indicates a short to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Harness Resistance Checks</emph>(check with breakout box installed
                                    on engine harness only with ignition key Off)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>53 to A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance from harness connector to 60 pin connector - Signal ground (CMP) has
                                    dedicated ground circuit, > 5&#x2126; indicates an open circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40 to B</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance from harness connector to 60 pin connector - V
                                    <subscript>REF.</subscript>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>51 to C</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;5&#x2126;</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Resistance from harness connector to 60 pin connector - CMP signal.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                                <para>Test Points (+) #51 to (-) #53</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operational Voltage Checks</emph>(check with breakout tee
                                    installed in line with the ECM and ignition key ON)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Voltage</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Position</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5V &#177; 0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vane</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>With the breakout tee or breakout box installed, the CMP sensor &#38; ECM
                                    connected, bar engine by hand.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.2V to 2V</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Window</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>The CMP signal voltage should change voltage state as timing wheel on cam is
                                    rotated.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Continued on Next Page</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>612 = ECM / target disk mismatch detected (wrong ECM Programming Installed).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>315 = Engine rpm exceeded 3000 rpm.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>143 = Incorrect number of sync to transition counts detected, possible
                                    intermittent CMP sensor/circuit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>144 = Electrical noise detected, check wire routing and grounds.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                                <para>145 = Inactive CMP signal detected during engine cranking when ICP pressure was
                                    sufficient for starting.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Function</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The International engine control system includes a Camshaft Position Sensor (CMP). This sensor
                provides the Electronic Control Module (ECM) with a signal that indicates camshaft position and engine
                speed.
            </para>
            <para>The CMP sensor signal is used by the ECM to synchronize piston position to injector firing sequence.
                The injector firing order sequence begins when the ECM detects the narrow vane on the timing disk
                indicating the position of number 1 cylinder. Engine position for each cylinder is then continuously
                calculated as each vane on the timing disk passes by the CMP sensor. This information is processed by
                the ECM and used for injection timing and fuel delivery control. The ECM can then initiate the beginning
                of firing.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Camshaft Position Sensor is a Hall Effect type sensor that generates a digital frequency as
                windows on the timing disk pass through the magnetic field. The frequency of the windows passing by the
                sensor as well as the width of selected windows allows the ECM to detect engine speed and position. When
                the narrow vane passes the CMP sensor, the signal on time is less than when the other vanes pass the
                sensor. This produces a signal that the ECM uses to indicate engine position.
            </para>
            <para>Engine speed is detected by the ECM by counting the frequency of the 24 signal pulses for each
                camshaft revolution.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECM Diagnostics</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Once the ECM has recognized the narrow vane (wide window) it will synchronize the engine firing order
                to the timing of the CMP signal. Every 2 crankshaft revolutions it will verify that synchronization. If
                the ECM receives too many or too few pulses for the number of engine revolutions, it will set a
                Diagnostic Trouble Code.
            </para>
            <para>The engine will not operate without a functioning CMP signal. However, the ECM will attempt to
                determine the cause of an invalid signal and identify it with a Diagnostic Trouble Code. CMP codes that
                are set will become inactive codes if the key is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the
                Diagnostic Trouble Code flashes from the amber and red ENGINE lamps, see .
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc143">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 143</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 21, FMI 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Incorrect Number of CMP Signal Transitions per Cam Revolution</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 143 indicates the ECM has received CMP signals with the wrong number of transitions. This
                indicates that the ECM has counted the voltage transitions and found less than the specified number of
                pulses from the sensor. When this problem is continuous, the engine will stop running and the ECM will
                log an active code. If the key is shut off, the code will become an inactive code. This code will not
                turn the amber ENGINE lamp on.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for code 143: Intermittent CMP signal caused by a intermittent circuit, defective
                Camshaft Position Sensor or incorrect CMP sensor to timing disk clearance.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc144">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 144</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 21, FMI 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CMP Signal Noise Detected</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Code 144 indicates that the ECM has detected voltage spikes or transitions other than the CMP signal.
                If this problem is continuous, the engine could stop running and the ECM will log an active code. If the
                key is shut off, the code will become inactive. This code will not turn the amber ENGINE lamp on.
            </para>
            <para>Code 144 may be due to: Poor ground connections for CMP or other electronic components. Wire harness
                shielding missing or incorrectly installed on the engine harness. Outside components that could induce
                voltage signals.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc145">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 145</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 21, FMI 12</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CMP Signal Inactive while ICP has Increased</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 145 indicates that the ECM does not detect a CMP signal. This code would be
                set if the engine was rotating and the ECM detected a rise in ICP pressure, but did not detect a CMP
                signal. To set this code the engine must be rotated long enough for the ICP pressure to increase. When
                this code is set, the engine will not operate.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes for Diagnostic Trouble Code 145: V
                <subscript>REF</subscript>
                shorted to B+, defective CMP sensor, faulty sensor circuitry or improper air gap between sensor and
                camshaft timing disk.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc612">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 612</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, SID 21, FMI 7</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Incorrect ECM Installed for CMP Timing Disk</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When code 612 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated and the odometer displays the message
                WARN ENG.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 612 indicates that the ECM has monitored the CMP signal and the signal is
                incorrect for the programming in the ECM. This means that the ECM does not recognize the signal
                generated from the timing disk and CMP sensor.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes: ECM has been accidently replaced with an incorrect ECM for the particular engine
                application. For example, the timing disk for the I-6 and the V-8 (T 444E) are dissimilar, with each
                generating a distinctive signal. The ECM from the V-8 (T 444E) engine will not run an I-6 engine and
                vice-versa. Incorrect signal due to a defective CMP sensor or incorrect air gap between the CMP sensor
                and the timing disk.
            </para>
            <para id="f175fc315">
                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Code 315</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ATA Code, PID 190, FMI 0</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Speed Above Warning Level</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When code 315 is active the amber ENGINE lamp is illuminated and the odometer displays the message
                WARN ENG.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Code 315 indicates that the ECM has detected an engine speed above 3000 rpm. The
                most likely cause of the excessive engine speed is an unintended down shift, steep acceleration down a
                hill without correct brake application or an external fuel source being ingested into the air intake
                system. The engine hours and miles on the last two overspeed occurrences will be recorded in the Engine
                Event Log.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_81.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_83.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
