<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; DT, 9 and 10 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Fuel Supply
        System - Fuel Supply System Flow
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>Fuel Supply System Flow</title>
        <figure id="f2700131" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk35/K35127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
            <caption>Fuel flow</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The low-pressure fuel pump draws fuel through the fuel lines from the fuel tank. Fuel enters the fuel
            filter header assembly and passes through the 150 micron strainer.
        </para>
        <para>An optional 250 watt electric heating element is available to warm incoming fuel to prevent waxing and
            improve cold weather performance. The heater is located in the base of the fuel strainer.
        </para>
        <para>Fuel flows from the strainer through the low-pressure fuel pump to the fuel filter for further
            conditioning.
        </para>
        <para>Fuel flows through the filter element and the standpipe. The filter element removes debris from the fuel.
            The standpipe prevents fuel from draining from the fuel rail during service.
        </para>
        <para>If water is in the fuel, the fuel filter element repels the water. The water is collected at the bottom of
            the main filter element cavity in the fuel filter assembly.
        </para>
        <para>When the maximum amount of water is collected in the element cavity, the WIF sensor sends a signal to the
            Engine Control Module (ECM). The ECM will turn on the amber FUEL FILTER lamp located on the instrument
            panel.
        </para>
        <figure id="f370001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figk35/K35173.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Fuel filter header assembly</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter cap</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter element</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Standpipe</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Filter assembly housing</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel outlet with check valve</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Water drain valve assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Water In Fuel (WIF) sensor</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">250 Watt fuel heater assembly (optional)</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Diagnostic coupling assembly</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel inlet</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel primer</callout1>
                <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel strainer element</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>A water drain valve is located on the fuel filter assembly and can be opened to drain contaminants
            (usually water) from the assembly.
        </para>
        <para>A fuel pressure regulator valve is built into the fuel filter header assembly. The regulator valve is
            calibrated to open at 455 kPa &#177; 34 kPa (66 psi &#177; 5 psi) to regulate and relieve excessive fuel
            pressure. Excess fuel is sent through a fuel return line back to the fuel tank. Return fuel is not filtered.
        </para>
        <para>Fuel continuously flows from the top of the filter element cavity, through a 0.2 mm air bleed orifice
            (filter center tube feature), and into the return fuel line. This aids in removing trapped air from the
            element cavity as a result of servicing.
        </para>
        <para>When the fuel filter is removed, an automatic drain-to-tank valve is opened. Fuel present in the filter
            housing then drains out and back to the tank to provide improved cleanliness during servicing.
        </para>
        <para>The Engine Fuel Pressure (EFP) sensor detects low fuel pressure caused by a fuel restriction or dirty fuel
            filter. The EFP sensor sends a signal to the ECM when pressure is below programmed values for various engine
            conditions and the ECM will turn on the amber FUEL FILTER lamp located on the instrument panel.
        </para>
        <para>Filtered fuel flows from the fuel filter header assembly into the fuel rail. The fuel rail is an integral
            part of the intake manifold. The fuel flows into six cylinder head passages to each fuel injector.
        </para>
        <para>When the fuel injectors are activated, fuel flows from the fuel passages through the injector inlet ports
            and inside the fuel injectors.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3351.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
