<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Performance Diagnostics - Test Procedures - 11. Air Management</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010603.11" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="5">
        <title>11. Air Management</title>
        <figure id="f305010650" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/j31106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para id="tp305010611">
            <title>Purpose</title>To check the operation of the Air Management System and the Exhaust Gas Recirculation
            (EGR) valve
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Tools</title>
            <item>
                <para>EST with MasterDiagnostics&#174; software</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EZ-Tech&#174; interface cable</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, comply with the
                    following:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Before running engine for diagnostic or service procedures, shift transmission to park or
                            neutral, set parking brake, and block wheels.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or death, use proper ventilation when operating an engine in a closed
                    area, in order to remove deadly exhaust fumes. Inhalation of exhaust fumes may be fatal.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f305010651" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/j31177.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>KOER Air Management session</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select D_KOER_AirManagement_V6.ssn in the Open Session File window, select Open to monitor
                engine operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When using the EST to do KOEO or KOER diagnostic tests, Standard Test is always selected and run
                    first. If the ignition switch is not cycled, the Standard Test does not have to be run again.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f305010652" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/j31051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Air Management test</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from menu bar.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">From the KOER Diagnostics menu, select Air Management and select Run to start the test.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM will start the Air Management test and direct the engine to accelerate to a predetermined rpm.
                The ECM will monitor the effects of the EGR valve movement using MAF.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If a problem is detected the ECM will cancel the test, set a DTC, and restore normal engine
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If engine load is above the engine load specification the test won't run.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Record DTCs on Diagnostic Form. See "
                <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050112.xml" xrefid="e3050112">Appendix B: Diagnostic Trouble Codes</hotlnk>
                " for a definition of the DTCs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Correct problems causing active DTCs. Before replacing the EGR valve, check all other
                possible causes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clear DTCs.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f305010653" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Close session</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f305010654" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figj31/j31272.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px" box="no"/>
            <caption>Air Management diagnostic readout for engine rpm, EGR position, and MAF</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The ECM commands the EGR valve to close and increases the engine idle speed to 900 rpm. The ECM allows the
            Manifold Air Flow (MAF) to stabilize. The ECM reads and matches the MAF pressure to the expected values;
            pressure is expected to increase to greater than 3.8 lb/min to pass. If the MAF does not meet the expected
            pressure, DTC 346 is set and the test is cancelled.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM commands the EGR to open, and allows MAF to stabilize. The ECM reads MAF pressure and matches it
            to the expected pressure; pressure is expected to decrease to less than 2.97 lb/min to pass. If the MAF
            pressure does not match the expected pressure, DTC 346 is set and the test is cancelled.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM commands the EGR valve to close, and allows MAF to stabilize. The ECM reads MAF pressure and
            matches it to the expected pressure; pressure is expected to increase to greater than 3.8 lb/min to pass. If
            the MAF pressure does not match the expected pressure, DTC 346 is set and the test is cancelled.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM returns the EGR valve and engine idle speed to normal operation. If all flows matched or exceeded
            the expected flows, no DTC is set and the engine is returned to normal operation.
        </para>
        <table id="t305010615" type="simple" frame="topbot">
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <tgroup cols="1">
                <colspec colname="col1"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exhaust leaks</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Intake leaks</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Biased MAF sensor</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Failed turbocharger</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Failed EGR control valve and drive module</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Plugged or restricted Catalytic converter - if equipped</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Plugged or restricted Catalyzed Diesel Particulate Filter (CDPF) - if equipped</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_107.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_109.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
