<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; T 444E Diesel Engine - Model Years Late 1997 to 2003 - Introduction - Engine Description
        - Lubrication System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Lubrication System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f120in15" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1829.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Lubrication System Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft Gear</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft Thrust Plate</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Camshaft</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">High-pressure Pump Oil Reservoir</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Piston Cooling Jets (8)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Hydraulic Valve Lifter Oil Gallery</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Pedestal</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Turbocharger Assembly (Typical)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Hydraulic Valve Lifter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Push Rod</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Valve Lever Assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Intake/Exhaust Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main Oil Gallery</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Main Crankshaft Bearings</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Filter Bypass Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Filter</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Pressure Regulating Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Cooler Header</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Pick-Up Tube</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Pump</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Connecting Rod Bearings</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Check Valve</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The lubrication system is pressure regulated, cooled, and full flow filtered. In addition to providing
                engine lubrication, pressurized lube oil is used to control fuel delivery to the HEUI fuel injectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Flow</title>
            <para>Lube oil is drawn from the oil sump, through the pick up screen and tube, and into the oil pump. The
                oil pump is of the gerotor type with the inner rotor portion driven directly by the crankshaft. The pump
                housing, containing the inner and outer gerotor gears, is bolted onto the front cover. The pump inlet
                and outlet passages are ports in the front cover. Upon leaving the oil pump, unfiltered lube oil enters
                the front oil cooler header through a passage in the front cover.
            </para>
            <para>At initial engine start up, a small portion of the oil is passed directly from the pump to the high
                pressure pump oil reservoir on top of the front cover. Oil flows from the oil cooler header around the
                oil cooler tubes into the oil filter assembly. The oil enters the oil filter through the outside of the
                filter element and flows through the filtering medium to the center. The filtered oil now passes through
                the oil gallery in the crankcase. The oil pressure regulator controls lube oil pressure via a spring
                loaded plunger which relays oil back to the sump once operating pressure is reached. The rear oil cooler
                header supports the oil filter, which also contains a bypass valve that allows oil to pass directly to
                the main oil gallery if the filter becomes excessively restricted.
            </para>
            <para>The five crankshaft main bearings are oil fed through drilled passages in the crankcase directly from
                the main oil gallery. Connecting rod bearings receive pressurized oil from the main bearings through
                drilled passages within the crankshaft. The camshaft journals receive pressurized oil through passages
                drilled vertically through the main bearing webs.
            </para>
            <para>Two tappet galleries, which are fed from the main oil gallery through the holes of main bearing bolt
                number 1, intersect each tappet bore to provide pressurized lube oil to the valve lifters and piston
                cooling jets. The valve lever assemblies and push rods are lubricated by oil passing from the lifter
                ball socket upward through the hollow push rods to valve lever arms. Oil drains back to the sump through
                holes located at each end of the cylinder head.
            </para>
            <para>The oil reservoir, which is used to maintain a ready supply of oil to the high pressure pump, is
                filled via two passages. At initial start up, oil is directed from the oil pump discharge port through a
                passage in the front cover and crankcase, which also contains a cold startup bypass check valve. To
                ensure sufficient oil pressure to operate the injectors for quick starts, this reservoir oil supply
                quickly replenishes oil to the high pressure pump during cold cranking. The primary reservoir oil supply
                is continuously fed from the left bank tappet gallery through the front cover, and discharges oil near
                the top of the reservoir.
            </para>
            <para>Pressurized lube oil reaches the turbocharger bearings from the main oil gallery (left bank) through a
                passage in the turbocharger pedestal (mounting pad). Oil drains from the turbocharger through another
                adjacent passage in the pedestal directly back to the sump. This oil supply and drain eliminate the need
                for external lube lines to the turbocharger.
            </para>
            <para>Hydraulic oil pressure that is used to actuate the exhaust back pressure (EBP) warm-up control is
                received from the turbocharger lube supply port. This port is located in the turbocharger support
                pedestal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges205.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
