<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Diesel Engine Diagnostic Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Diagnostic Software
        Operation - Diagnostic Trouble Code Detection - Continuous Monitor
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Continuous Monitor</title>
        <para id="s27007029">Continuous Monitor is a series of continuous diagnostic tests done by the Electronic
            Control Module (ECM) to detect failure modes (Out of Range, In Range, and System Faults). During Continuous
            Monitor the ignition switch is on.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Out of Range High</emph>
                    (Voltage over normal operating range)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Out of Range Low</emph>
                    (Voltage under normal operating range)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">In Range</emph>
                    (In normal operating range but not correct for conditions)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">System Malfunction</emph>
                    (System is not operating according to conditions)
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If an input signal is out of range (over or under normal operating range), the ECM logs a fault and sets a
            Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC). The ECM monitors the operation of systems for in range conditions to
            determine if systems are working in a normal operational range; If the ECM detects that a system falls
            outside a predetermined range, it will log a fault and set a DTC.
        </para>
        <para>Each DTC has a three digit number to identify the source of a malfunction measured or monitored
            electronically. A fault is a malfunction measured or monitored electronically.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM continuously monitors the Injection Control Pressure (ICP) system and the Air Management System
            (AMS). If the ECM detects that a system falls outside a predetermined range, the ECM logs a fault and sets a
            DTC.
        </para>
        <para>During normal engine operation, the ECM automatically performs several tests to detect faults. When a
            fault is detected, the ECM often runs a fault management strategy to allow continued, though sometimes
            degraded, vehicle operation.
        </para>
        <para>With the engine running, engine events are permanently recorded in the ECM; engine events can be retrieved
            with the Electronic Service Tool (EST).
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Events</title>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Standard Engine Events</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Standard engine events include excessive coolant temperature and engine rpm (over-speed).</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Optional Engine Events</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Optional engine events are monitored and recorded, if the engine is equipped with the optional Engine
            Warning Protection System (EWPS). Optional engine events recorded by the ECM include low coolant level and
            low oil pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Engine Event Hours/Odometer</title>
        </para>
        <para>The ECM records engine events in two ways, hours and odometer readings.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <title>Examples</title>
            <item>
                <para>Overheat Hour 1</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Overheat Hour 2</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Overheat Odometer 1</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Overheat Odometer 2</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The ECM stores the two most recent events. Two events could happen in the same hour, and two events could
            happen in the same mile.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_50.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270_52.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
