<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Engine Symptoms Diagnostics - Test Procedures - Water In Fuel (WIF)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010402.11" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Water In Fuel (WIF)</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010402.11.1">
            <table id="t305010409" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>Cause</title>
                <tgroup cols="1" align="left">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Water in fuel supply system</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ice in fuel lines</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Short circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Damaged connection</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Corrosion on connector, sensor, or cover plate assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed WIF sensor</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>Clean drain pan, flat with a wide opening</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010402.11.2">
            <title>Drain Water from HFCM</title>
            <step1>
                <para id="s305010402.11.2.1" count="1">Determine if the WIF lamp is on. If the lamp is on, the fuel is
                    probably contaminated with water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, comply with the
                        following:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information" section of this manual.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Dispose of fuel according to local regulations in a correct container clearly marked
                                DIESEL FUEL.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>DO NOT smoke.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Keep away from open flames and sparks.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, comply with the following:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not mix gasoline, gasohol, or alcohol with diesel fuel. This practice creates a
                                fire hazard and is potentially explosive.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not allow engine fluids to stay on your skin. Clean skin and nails with soap and
                                water, or a good hand cleaner. Wash or properly dispose of clothing or rags containing
                                engine fluids. Engine fluids contain elements that may be unhealthy for skin and could
                                cause cancer.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Engine fluids, oil, fuel, and coolant, are a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose of
                        engine fluids according to local regulations. Never put engine fluids in the trash, on the
                        ground, in sewers or other bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a clean flat drain pan under the HFCM drain plug</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe down the frame around and under the drain plug or the HFCM and drain plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010421" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31352.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>HFCM drain plug</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Area to be wiped down before draining</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Drain plug</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010422" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31322.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>HFCM drain plug</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010423" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31353.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Drain plug remove and hanging from stem</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the drain plug from the threads and hang it from the stem. Drain HFCM
                    to the clean flat drain pan.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Flow out of the drain should be as steady a stream as possible. When running down the side
                            of the frame with the plug fully removed, or just running down the plug while it is hanging,
                            use your best judgement if it is a steady flow. An unsteady flow could indicate fuel system
                            problems.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the O-ring on the drain plug. The drain plug will have to be removed to replace
                    the O-ring. Install and hand tighten the drain plug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the fuel in the drain pan for contamination. Dispose of the contents in the drain
                    pan properly in accordance with local requirements.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Excessive water or contaminants may indicate that the tank and fuel system need to be
                            flushed and cleaned.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Some sediment and water may be present if the fuel filter has not been replaced for a
                            prolonged period of time, or if the sediment and water have not been drained recently.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The fuel should be clear, not cloudy. Cloudy fuel indicates that the fuel is not a
                            suitable grade for cold temperatures.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The fuel should not be dyed red or blue, these colors indicate off-highway fuel.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The fuel should not indicate evidence of waxing or gelling. Waxing or gelling in some
                            fuels in cold weather could clog fuel filters and the fuel pump and cause restrictions in
                            the fuel or low fuel pressure.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition switch to ON, determine if the WIF lamp is off.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is off, the procedure is complete, do not continue.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is still on, continue with step 8.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Redo steps 4, 5, and 6. Turn the ignition switch to ON to start the HFCM fuel pump,
                    determine if the WIF lamp is off.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is off, the procedure is complete, do not continue.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is still on, continue with step 9.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the WIF indicator stays on after the water has been drained, the WIF sensor, the WIF sensor
                        connector, or the cover plate assembly may be corroded, the condition should be corrected and
                        retested.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the WIF sensor connector, do "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_163.xml" xrefid="s305010706.34.1.1">WIF (Water In Fuel) Sensor</hotlnk>
                    " in "
                    <hotlnk document="eges3052_E3050107.xml" xrefid="e3050107">Electronic Control Systems Diagnostics
                    </hotlnk>
                    " section of this manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the HFCM to service the WIF sensor or check for corrosion on the cover plate
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the HFCM, and redo steps 4, 5, and 6. Turn the ignition switch to ON to start
                    the HFCM fuel pump, determine if the WIF lamp is off.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is off, the procedure is complete, do not continue.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the WIF lamp is still on, replace the HFCM.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_73.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_75.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
