<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ENGINE CONTROL SYSTEM OVERVIEW -
        HEUI INJECTOR OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>HEUI INJECTOR OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Standard Injector Operation</title>
            <figure id="f1750108" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg1/EG1268.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="no"/>
                <caption>HEUI Injector Stages of Operation</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The injection operation is divided into three stages or cycles:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Fill Stage</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Injection Stage</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">End of Injection</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fill Stage</emph>
            </para>
            <para>During the fill stage, the solenoid is deactivated and the poppet valve is closed preventing the flow
                of high pressure oil to the intensifier piston. At this point the intensifier piston is up allowing the
                fuel to enter and fill the injector nozzle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Injection Stage</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Once the ECM commands injection, the solenoid is energized and the injection stage is initiated. This
                action rapidly lifts the poppet valve from its seat, allowing high pressure oil to enter the injector.
                The intensifier piston transmits the pressure from the high pressure oil to the fuel and multiplies it 6
                to 7 times creating fuel injection pressures of up to 21,000 psi.
            </para>
            <para>As the fuel pressure increases, check valves prevent the fuel from flowing back to the supply
                manifold. Once the pressure is high enough to lift the needle valve fuel is forced into the combustion
                chamber.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">End of Injection</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Once injection is completed, the ECM deactivates the solenoid, the poppet valve and the intensifier
                piston return to the closed position and the injector returns to the fill stage .
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
