<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM
        DIAGNOSTICS - CIRCUIT FUNCTION AND DIAGNOSTICS - Engine Warning and Protection System (EWPS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Engine Warning and Protection System (EWPS)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Functions</title>
            <figure id="f17503074" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg7/eg7317a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Engine Warning and Protection System Functions</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The red ENGINE lamp is turned on when conditions are present that will cause impending damage to the
                engine. The level of protection is dependent on which Engine Warning And Protection Systems (EWPS) are
                turned on in the ECM. See Extended Description.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM does not monitor the EWPS system for faults. Requests by the ECM to turn on the red ENGINE
                lamp on the dash are sent over the Power Train Data Link. There are no Diagnostic Trouble Codes for this
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engine Warning and Protection System</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This group of parameters customizes the engine warning and protection feature. The engine warning and
                protection system safeguards the engine from undesirable operating conditions in order to prevent engine
                damage and to prolong engine life. When a warning condition is detected, the on-board electronics will
                illuminate the red ENGINE lamp.
            </para>
            <para>When a critical condition is detected, the on-board electronics will shut down the engine if the
                engine warning and protection system has its protection features enabled. After an engine shutdown, the
                operator may restart the engine for a thirty second run time if desired.
            </para>
            <para>The event logging feature will also record when an excessive (i.e., critical) engine event has
                occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings. There are four states of Engine Warning and
                Protection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Four States of Engine Operation</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Standard</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>2-Way Warning</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-Way Warning</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-Way Protection</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EWPS Mode</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates to the on-board electronics the desired mode of operation for the engine
                warning and protection feature.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Standard Warning (rpm, ECT)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Engine overspeed and engine overheat are provided as the default operating mode. No engine shutdown is
                available.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">2-Way Warning (rpm, ECT, EOP)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Engine overspeed, engine overheat and low engine oil pressure are monitored in the engine warning
                operating mode. No engine shutdown is available.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">3-way Warning (rpm, ECT, EOP, ECL)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Engine overspeed, engine overheat, low engine oil pressure, and engine coolant are monitored in the
                engine warning operating mode. No engine shutdown is available.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">3-Way Protection (rpm, ECT, EOP, ECL)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Engine overspeed, engine overheat, low engine oil pressure, and engine coolant are monitored in the
                engine protection operating mode. Engine shutdown is available if an critical engine condition is
                detected. Critical engine conditions include overheat, low oil pressure and low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECT Warning Temperature</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when an engine overheat condition warrants the OIL/WATER lamp to be
                illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECT Critical Temperature</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when an engine overheat condition warrants an engine shutdown. The event
                logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP RPM Boundry 1</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 1 is used for the loss of engine
                oil pressure detection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP RPM Boundry 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 2 is used for the loss of engine
                oil pressure detection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP RPM Boundry 3</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates the rpm range that engine oil pressure level 3 is used for the loss of engine
                oil pressure detection.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Warning Level 1</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure warrants the OIL/WATER lamp to be
                illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Warning Level 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants the OIL/WATER lamp to
                be illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Warning Level 3</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants the OIL/WATER lamp to
                be illuminated and the warning buzzer to be activated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Critical Level 1</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown. The
                event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Critical Level 2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown. The
                event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">EOP Critical Level 3</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This parameter indicates when a loss of engine oil pressure condition warrants an engine shutdown. The
                event logging feature will log when this event has occurred in both engine hours and odometer readings.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>ECM Diagnostics</title>
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic Trouble Codes can be retrieved using the Electronic Service Tool (EST) or by reading the
                Diagnostic Trouble Code flashes from the amber and red ENGINE lamps, see .
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line>THIS PAGE INTENTIONALLY LEFT BLANK</line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
                <line></line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_101.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_103.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
