<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS - Introduction
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Forms</title>
            <para>Engine diagnostic forms provide customer satisfaction and assist technicians in troubleshooting DT 466
                and International&#174; 530 diesel engines. Diagnostic test procedures help technicians find problems
                systematically and quickly to avoid unnecessary repairs.
            </para>
            <para>Two forms are used for engine diagnostics:
                <emph type="bold">Mechanical Diagnostic Form EGED-180-2 and Electronic Control System Diagnostic Form
                    EGED-185-2.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Mechanical Diagnostic Form EGED-180-2</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f175201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG8/EG8755C.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Mechanical Diagnostic Form EGED-180-2 (front side)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Form EGED-180-2 helps the technician diagnose and correct engine starting problems and engine
                performance.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The front left side of the form (Hard Start / No Start Diagnostics) has fourteen procedures
                        for correcting engine starting problems.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The front right side of the form (Performance Diagnostics) has seventeen procedures for
                        correcting engine performance.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do all procedures in sequence. For correct operation, some components depend on the function
                        of other components. Doing a test out of sequence could cause incorrect results.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>All procedures on form EGED-180-2 are explained in detail in this section of the manual.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The rear side of the form has reference figures to show check points, test points, and
                        equipment hookup described in diagnostic procedures on the front side of the form.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f175202" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG9/EG9003B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Mechanical Diagnostic Form EGED-180-2 (Rear side)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Electronic Control System Diagnostic Form EGED-185-2</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Form EGED-185-2 includes a complete listing of Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTCs), signal values, an
                engine schematic, and a vehicle schematic. Form EGED-185-2 is shown and described in Section 3.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Information</title>
            <figure id="f175203" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG9/EG9095.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Heading for Vehicle Information</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before starting the diagnostic tests, fill out the heading for vehicle information on the
                        front side of form EGED-180-2.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Date, Miles, and Hours are for warranty claims.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Serial Number (ESN) and Vehicle Identification Number (VIN) are for ordering parts and
                        referencing service information. The engine serial number is on a machined pad behind the fuel
                        filter on left side of engine block. The Vehicle Identification Number is on the door jamb on
                        the driver's side.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Horsepower / Emissions Information and Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC) helps determine
                        if the engine is the correct horsepower for the application and if the ECM is calibrated to the
                        correct horsepower and emissions level. Information for engine horsepower and emissions is on
                        the emission label on the intake manifold/valve cover.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC) is found with the Electronic Service Tool (EST).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Technician and Unit numbers are for reference only.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Diagnostic forms EGED-180-2 and EGED-185-2 are available in 50 sheet pads from:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation</line>
                <line>Printing, Procurement and Distribution</line>
                <line>61 Clark Road North</line>
                <line>Battle Creek, MI 49015</line>
                <line>269-968-4856</line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_36.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_38.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
