<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 530 Engine Diagnostic Manual for 4000 Series Trucks (2001) - DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS - DIGITAL
        MULTIMETER USE - Ohm's Law Review
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Ohm's Law Review</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Ohm's law describes the relationship of current, voltage, and resistance in an electrical circuit.
                Ohm's law also provides the basic formula for simple calculations .
            </para>
            <para>Basic formula for Ohm's law</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>I = Current (amperes)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>E = Voltage (volts)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>R = Resistance (ohms)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>I = E / R</para>
                    <para>This formula states that current flow (I) = voltage (E) applied to a circuit divided by total
                        resistance (R) in the circuit. This shows that an increase in voltage or a decrease in
                        resistance increases the current flow.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>R = E / l</para>
                    <para>This formula states that resistance (R) = voltage (E) applied to a circuit divided by current
                        flow (I) in the circuit. Resistance can be calculated for a specific current flow when a
                        specific voltage is applied, e.g. 12V.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>E = IR</para>
                    <para>(I multiplied by R)</para>
                    <para>IR gives the voltage drop (resistance) across a particular load device that is part of a
                        series of load devices.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Memorize the formula in the circle. Cover the letter with your finger for the desired formula. For
                example, if you cover the I, the formula is I = E / R.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750531" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg8/EG8530.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Ohm's Law</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If any two of the values are known for a given circuit, the missing one can be found by substituting
                the values in amperes, volts, or ohms.
            </para>
            <para>In a typical circuit, battery voltage is applied to a bulb through a 10-amp fuse and a switch .
                Closing the switch turns on the bulb.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1750532" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6124.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Simple Electrical Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To find the current flow use formula:</para>
            <para>I = E / R</para>
            <para>Fill in the numbers for the formula.</para>
            <para>I = 12V / 2 ohms
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
                I = 12 divided by 2 = 6 amperes of current flow.
            </para>
            <para>The bulb in this circuit operates at 6 amps and is rated at 6 amps. With 12 volts applied, the bulb
                will glow at the rated output level (candlepower rating). However,
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>if the voltage applied is low (low battery), then the value of "E" is lower and current flow
                        will be less and the bulb will glow less brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>if the connections are loose, or the switch corroded, the circuit resistance will be greater
                        (value of R will be larger) and the current flow will be reduced and the bulb will glow less
                        brightly.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Voltage drops are important for the following reasons:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>High voltage drops indicate excessive resistance. For example, if a blower motor runs too
                        slowly or a light glows too dimly, the circuit will have excessive resistance. Voltage drop
                        readings can isolate problems in parts of a circuit (corroded or loose terminals for example).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Too low of a voltage drop indicates low resistance. For example, if a blower motor ran too
                        fast, the problem could be isolated to a low resistance in a resistor pack by taking voltage
                        drop readings.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maximum allowable voltage drop under load is critical, especially if there is more than one
                        high resistance problem in a circuit. It is important because all voltage drops in a circuit are
                        cumulative. Corroded terminals, loose connections, damaged wires or other similar conditions
                        create undesirable voltage drops that decrease the voltage available across the key circuit
                        components. Remember our earlier discussion, the increased resistance from the undesirable
                        conditions will also decrease the current flow in the circuit and all the affected components
                        will operate at less than peak efficiency. A small drop across wires (conductors), connectors,
                        switches, etc. is normal. This is because all conductors have some resistance, but the total
                        should be less than 10 percent of the total voltage drop in the circuit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Using the Voltmeter</title>
            <para>In electrical diagnosis, the voltmeter is used to answer:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Is voltage present?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage reading?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>What is the voltage drop across a load device?</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When using a voltmeter to determine if voltage is present to power a device, connect the positive
                meter lead to input connection of the device (positive side) and connect the negative meter lead to a
                good vehicle ground . This shows how much of the source voltage is available to the device. Note that
                the meter is connected in parallel to the device.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1750533" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6125.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Checking Power to a Load Device</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Voltage to a device can also be measured by disconnecting the harness connector and using the
                appropriate tool from the Terminal Test Adapter Kit (ZTSE 4435).
            </para>
            <para>To check the voltage drop across a load device , connect the positive lead of the voltmeter to the
                positive side of the device and the negative meter lead to the negative side of the device.
            </para>
            <figure id="ef1750534" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg9/EG9001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Checking Power to a Connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="ef1750535" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Checking Voltage Loss</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>With the device operating, this will measure the voltage drop across the device. With only one device,
                all of the voltage should be dropped at the device . In any circuit, the voltage applied will equal the
                voltage dropped in the circuit. If this circuit only dropped 9V across the load, it indicates the wires
                and connections dropped 3V and suggests excessive circuit resistance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_154.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215_156.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges215.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
