<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>VT 275 Engine Diagnostics Manual - Performance Diagnostics - Test Procedures - 9. Injector Disable</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s305010603.9" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="8">
        <title>9. Injector Disable</title>
        <svcprocinfo id="s305010603.9.1">
            <figure id="f305010638" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31104.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
            <para id="tp305010609">
                <title>Purpose</title>
            </para>
            <para>To determine the cause of rough engine idle</para>
            <para>The Injector Disable tests can only be done with the EST; MasterDiagnostics&#174; software is
                required.
            </para>
            <para>The Injector Disable tests allows the technician to shut off injectors to determine if a specific
                cylinder is contributing to engine performance. Injectors can be shut off one at a time.
            </para>
            <para>Firing order: 1-2-5-6-3-4</para>
            <para>When all cylinders are active, the contribution of each cylinder is 17% of its overall effect to
                maintain governed speed. The technician should monitor fuel rate and engine load.
            </para>
            <para>This test is used in conjunction with "
                <hotlnk document="eges3052_107.xml" xrefid="tp305010610">Test 10. Relative Compression</hotlnk>
                " to distinguish between an injector problem or a mechanical problem.
            </para>
            <para>Before doing the Automatic Test make sure Tests 1 through 8 were completed and the following
                conditions are maintained:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Make sure accessories are turned off (for example: fan and air conditioning). If these items
                        were to cycle during this test it could corrupt the test results.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maintain engine idle.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Keep EOT within a 2 &#176;C (5 &#176;F)range from the beginning to the end of the test. EOT
                        affects injection timing; too much of a change in EOT temperature could corrupt the test
                        results.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The Automatic Test is the preferred test, do the Manual Test - Engine Cold only if investigating a
                cold misfire.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>Tools</title>
                <item>
                    <para>EST with MasterDiagnostics&#174; software</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EZ-Tech&#174; interface cable</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010603.9.2">
            <title>Automatic Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If any injectors are removed and reinstalled or replaced, test drive vehicle for 32 km (20 mi)
                        before checking for misfire or rough idle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The automatic test is best done when comparing cylinder to cylinder test data.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do "
                        <hotlnk document="eges3052_104.xml" xrefid="tp305010607">Test 7. KOER Standard</hotlnk>
                        " before doing this test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, use proper ventilation when operating an engine in a closed
                        area, in order to remove deadly exhaust fumes. Inhalation of exhaust fumes may be fatal.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, before running
                        engine for diagnostic or service procedures, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking
                        brake, and block wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010639" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31178.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>KOER injector disable session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While engine is running, select D_KOER_IDT_V6.ssn in the Open Session File window,
                    select Open to monitor engine operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010640" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31251.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Injector Disable Diagnostics</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select V6 Injector Disable Tests from drop down menu.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The EOT indicator will change from red to green when engine temperature reaches 70 &#176;C
                            (158 &#176;F) or higher.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>If the EOT indicator is red, erroneous comparisons are likely from cylinder to
                                    cylinder.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>When the EOT indicator is green and the engine temperature is 70 &#176;C (158
                                    &#176;F) or higher, fuel rate and timing are more stable, making comparisons from
                                    cylinder to cylinder more accurate. Overall engine operation is more stable.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Auto Run.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If any injectors are removed and reinstalled or replaced, test drive vehicle for 32 km (20
                            mi) before checking for misfire or rough idle.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                    <note>
                        <para>While running the engine, listen for sound variations from cylinder to cylinder.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010641" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31247.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>V6 Injector Disable Test Results (Auto Run - Text View)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f305010642" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31248.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>V6 Injector Disable Test Results (Auto Run - Graph View)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>During Auto Run, injectors are shutoff one at a time (1 through 6 in numerical sequence). Base line
                data and results for each cylinder is displayed in the window (Text View) for V6 Injector Disable Test
                Results. Test data for each injector can also be viewed by selecting the (Graph View). When finished the
                engine will return to normal operation.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record data from window (Text View) on Diagnostic Form.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If deviation values for average fuel rate and average engine load are less than the cut
                            off values for fuel rate and engine load, the injector is suspect for weak cylinder
                            contribution.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If only one deviation value is less than a cut off value, do not suspect that cylinder.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a suspect cylinder(s) is identified, do "
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_107.xml" xrefid="tp305010610">Test 10. Relative Compression
                            </hotlnk>
                            " to distinguish between an injector or mechanical problem.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If Test 10 shows that cylinders are mechanically sound, but Test 9 shows that one or more
                            cylinders are bad, continue with step 6.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, do not allow engine fluids to stay on your skin. Clean skin
                        and nails with soap and water, or a good hand cleaner. Wash or dispose of clothing or rags
                        containing engine fluids. Engine fluids contain elements that may be unhealthy for skin and
                        could cause cancer.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>Engine fluids, oil, fuel, and coolant, are a threat to the environment. Recycle or dispose of
                        engine fluids according to local regulations. Never dispose of engine fluids in the trash, by
                        pouring on the ground, in sewers, or in bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve covers following procedure in Engine Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace faulty injector(s) and replace valve covers following procedures in the Engine
                    Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test drive vehicle for 32 km (20 mi) to purge air from the ICP system fuel supply
                    system, and check for rough idle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If rough idle continues, do this test again.</para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t305010613" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                <title>Possible Causes</title>
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed connection from wiring harness to injector solenoid</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Open or shorted wiring harness to injector solenoid</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed solenoid on fuel injector</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed IDM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Failed ECM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Scuffed or damaged injector</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="s305010603.9.3">
            <title>Manual Test - Engine Cold</title>
            <para>The Manual Test is only done when diagnosing each cylinder for cold misfire, considering EOT
                changes.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The EOT indicator will change from red to green when engine temperature reaches 70 &#176;C
                        (158 &#176;F) or higher.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>If the EOT indicator is red, erroneous comparisons are likely from cylinder to
                                cylinder.
                            </para>
                            <para>However, when diagnosing a cold misfire, a technician can listen to tone changes from
                                cylinder-to-cylinder.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>When the EOT indicator is green and the engine temperature is 70 &#176;C (158 &#176;F)
                                or higher, fuel rate and timing are more stable, making comparisons from cylinder to
                                cylinder more accurate. Overall engine operation is more stable.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Shut off one injector at a time and listen for changes in exhaust tone.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If any injectors are removed and reinstalled or replaced, test drive vehicle for 32 km (20 mi)
                        before checking for misfire or rough idle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, use proper ventilation when operating an engine in a closed
                        area, in order to remove deadly exhaust fumes. Inhalation of exhaust fumes may be fatal.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, death, including damage to the engine or vehicle, when running
                        engine for diagnostic or service procedures, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking
                        brake, and block wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010643" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31178.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>KOER injector disable session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While engine is running, select D_ KOER_IDT_V6.ssn. in the Open Session File window,
                    select Open to monitor engine operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f305010644" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31251.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Injector Disable Tests</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select V6 Injector Disable Tests from drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select cylinder number and select Run. (Injector selected will be disabled and engine
                    noise should change.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Normal Operation. Injector will be enabled and engine noise should return to
                    normal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 4 and 5 for the remaining cylinders.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Listen for sound variations from cylinder to cylinder.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>If any injectors are removed and reinstalled or replaced, test drive vehicle for 32 km (20 mi)
                        before checking for misfire or rough idle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f305010645" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figj31/j31087.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Close session</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When finished with this test, select Session from menu bar, then Close.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_105.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052_107.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges3052.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
