<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT 466 / DT 570 / HT 570 Service Manual - 2004 Emissions with EGR - Crankcase, Crankshaft, and Camshaft -
        Cleaning and Inspection
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Cleaning and Inspection</title>
        <svcproc graphiccount="1">
            <title>Cleaning the Crankcase</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, the oil cooler must be replaced if there was a bearing failure. Debris
                        from a bearing failure cannot be removed from the oil cooler.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The best way to clean the crankcase during engine overhaul is in a chemical bath or hot tank.
                        This removes all carbonaceous material and mineral deposits that collect in the cooling
                        passages. If the hot tank is not available, use the following cleaning procedure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all old gasket material from the surfaces of the crankcase, if any.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f2650915" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg5/EG5364.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Removing crankcase plugs</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the main oil gallery cup plug, located at the rear of the crankcase by using a
                    hammer and chisel. Knockout main oil gallery cup plug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the plugs removed from the crankcase, clean the crankcase as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a
                        <hotlnk document="eges2651_205.xml" xrefid="t2650904" appearance="hottext">nylon brush</hotlnk>
                        with soap and water to clean oil galleries.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean cross drillings using a
                        <hotlnk document="eges2651_205.xml" xrefid="t2650904" appearance="hottext">nylon brush</hotlnk>
                        with soap and water.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use filtered
                        <hotlnk xrefid="safety10" appearance="hottext">compressed air</hotlnk>
                        to blow out oil galleries and cross drillings.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean all threaded holes with an
                        <hotlnk document="eges2651_205.xml" xrefid="t2650904" appearance="hottext">appropriately sized
                            tap
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new main oil gallery cup plug as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Clean the mating surfaces of the plug and crankcase.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply Loctite&#174; 262 to the outside edge of the cup plug.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use an arbor to drive the cup plug in. The arbor must be approximately 6 mm (&#188;
                        in) smaller in diameter than the plug that is being installed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Recess the cup plug 3.2 mm (&#x215B;).</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new plugs in the rear of the crankcase.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the piston cooling tubes for damage and blockage as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect both ends of the tube. Verify that the flanged end next to the bearing
                        saddle is intact and the orifice end protruding from the crankcase is not broken. Replace any
                        tubes that are damaged.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Hold tube under running water in a sink. Water should stream out of tube end. If
                        not, blockage will have to be physically removed by
                        <hotlnk xrefid="safety10" appearance="hottext">compressed air</hotlnk>
                        or piston oil tube must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_185.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651_187.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges2651.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
