<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 5 Engine Service Manual - Engine Systems - Electronic Control System -
        Electronic Control System Operation and Function
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s3050107.1" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electronic Control System Operation and Function</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Electronic Control Module (ECM) monitors sensor input signals and controls engine performance with
                actuators and relays to ensure maximum performance while adhering to emissions standards. The ECM also
                has an internal barometric air pressure sensor which measures atmospheric pressure to compensate for
                changes in elevation.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM has four primary functions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Provides Reference Voltage (VREF)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Conditions input signals</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Processes and stores control strategies</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Controls actuators</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reference Voltage (VREF)</title>
            <para>The ECM supplies a 5 volt VREF signal to input sensors in the electronic control system. By comparing
                the 5 volt VREF signal sent to the sensors with their respective returned signals, the ECM determines
                pressures, positions, and other variables.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM supplies two independent circuits for VREF:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>VREF A supplies 5 volts to engine sensors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VREF B supplies 5 volts to vehicle sensors</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Signal Conditioner</title>
            <para>A signal conditioner in the ECM converts analog signals to digital signals, squares up sine wave
                signals, or amplifies low intensity signals.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Microprocessor</title>
            <para>The ECM microprocessor stores operating instructions (control strategies) and value tables
                (calibration parameters). The ECM compares stored instructions and values with conditioned input values
                to determine the correct operating strategy for all engine operations.
            </para>
            <para>Continuous calculations in the ECM occur at two different levels or speeds: Foreground and
                Background.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Foreground calculations are faster than background calculations and are critical for engine
                        operation. Engine speed control is an example.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Background calculations are variables that change at slower rates. Engine temperature is an
                        example.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Diagnostic strategies are also programmed into the ECM. Some strategies monitor inputs continuously
                and command the necessary outputs for correct performance of the engine. If inputs or conditions are not
                within expected values, the microprocessor sets a Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM microprocessor includes Read Only Memory (ROM) and Random Access Memory (RAM).</para>
            <para>ROM stores permanent information for calibration tables and operating strategies. Permanently stored
                information cannot be changed or lost by turning the ignition switch OFF or when ECM power is
                interrupted. ROM includes the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle configuration, modes of operation, and options</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Family Rating Code (EFRC)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine warning and protection modes</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>RAM stores temporary information for current engine conditions. Temporary information in RAM is lost
                when the ignition switch is turned to OFF or when ECM power is interrupted. RAM information includes the
                following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine rpm</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator pedal position</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_S3050107.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390_37.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges390.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
