<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DT-466E and 530E Diesel Engine Diagnostics Model Years 1999-2000 - MECHANICAL DIAGNOSTICS - PERFORMANCE
        DIAGNOSTICS - Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Fuel Pressure Test (Full Load)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f175726" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figEG9/EG9085.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Purpose</title>
            <para>To determine if the fuel system is supplying the engine with the proper fuel quantity and pressure at
                full load conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Read all safety instructions in this manual before doing this procedure.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the fuel filter has a water-in-fuel probe, ask the vehicle operator if the water-in-fuel
                        lamp is illuminated during vehicle operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f175280" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6812.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Air bleeder valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If pressure gauge is not connected to fuel system in Test 2, remove air bleed valve on
                    fuel filter header.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install 1/8 in (3 mm) pipe fitting in place of the bleed valve .</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f175281" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figeg6/EG6817.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Gauge bar (PS94-831-3)</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a line from the fitting to the 0-160 psi gauge of the Gauge Bar.</para>
                <specpara></specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and run at low idle to check for fuel leaks in-line to pressure gauge.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Bleed air from the fuel line to insure an accurate reading.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive vehicle on road until engine reaches operating temperature. Find an open section
                    of road and select a suitable gear. Depress the accelerator pedal (full depression) to the floor and
                    accelerate to rated speed and 100% load.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Drive the vehicle uphill or fully loaded to reach the correct engine loading at rated
                            engine speed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure fuel pressure and record on Mechanical Diagnostics form EGED-180-2. If pressure
                    is not within specifications, replace fuel filter, clean fuel strainer, and recheck fuel pressure.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Several crank cycles may be required to purge the air from the fuel system after replacing
                            the fuel filter.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>If fuel pressure remains low after replacing the filter, do Transfer Pump Restriction Test (Test
                    3).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Possible Causes</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A clogged fuel filter or fuel strainer could cause high restriction and low fuel pressure.
                        Replace fuel filter, clean strainer, and retest.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Debris in the fuel regulator valve will cause low fuel pressure.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A kinked or severely bent fuel supply line, or blockage at the pickup tube.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A loose fuel line on the suction side of the fuel system. .</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The fuel pump could have internal damage; for example, a seized plunger or leaking check
                        valves.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A restriction between the transfer pump inlet and fuel tank.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Restriction between the fuel line inlet fitting, strainer, and transfer pump.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tools Required</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Gauge Bar (PS94-831-3) and an appropriate line with 1/8 in NPT fitting</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_64.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751_66.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="eges1751.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
