<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PROPELLER SHAFT - VIBRATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>VIBRATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>Vibration is the result of a force rapidly moving an object in opposite directions. There are two
                different kinds of vibration that affect propeller shaft operation, either transverse or torsional.
                Transverse vibration is a bending movement caused by improper balance. Torsional vibration is a twisting
                motion most commonly caused by engine power pulses and/or improper universal joint working angles.
            </para>
            <para>Vibration originating in the universal joint and propeller shaft assembly is usually present only at
                certain speeds and cycle as the shaft speed is raised and lowered. This intermittent characteristic
                differs from the generally constant noise from other sources of vibration.
            </para>
            <para>The most common causes of propeller shaft vibration are:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Universal joint flange or yoke misalignment.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Out-of-balance propeller shaft assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Propeller shaft out of phase.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Excessive flange runout or distorted yokes.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose flange or yoke nut.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Excessive propeller shaft rotational speed.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>To correct driveline vibration, the propeller shaft must be checked in such a manner that both balance
                and alignment are considered. Never change the driveline balance or alignment until a thorough check of
                the most common causes has been completed.
            </para>
            <para>Driveline vibration can be checked by road testing vehicle, spinning the driveline with vehicle up on
                floor stands, or by pulling the rear axle shafts and spinning the driveline.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury, be certain that vehicle is positively supported when checking for
                        vibration.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
