<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PROPELLER SHAFT - VIBRATION - TYPES OF VIBRATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TYPES OF VIBRATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Vibration that is felt during vehicle operation will generally fall in one or more categories. Not all
                vibrations are caused by the propeller shaft assembly.
            </para>
            <para>First you must determine the source of the problem. To assist in finding the source, you must
                interview the operator to determine what, where and when the vibration is encountered.
            </para>
            <para>Next, road test the vehicle with and without typical loads while recording engine RPM and road speed
                of disturbance in all transmission and rear axle ranges. If the problem is prevalent when pulling a
                trailer, it will be necessary to road test with a different trailer and load to assist in defining the
                cause of the disturbance.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes of chassis vibration other than propeller shafts are:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine and Accessories</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Steering Looseness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch, Transmission and Axles</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tires and Wheels</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cab and Cab Mounting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Driveline Brake Drum</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trailer Disturbance</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Load Retention or Distribution</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose or Worn Suspension Parts.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate section of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for correction of vibration
                from these areas.
            </para>
            <para>After the aforementioned items have been inspected and it is determined that the vibration is in the
                propeller shaft, visually inspect for the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Universal Joint Phasing</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn Universal Joint</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Damage to Propeller Shaft</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn Center Bearing Insulator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Missing Balance Weights</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose Slip Joint</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Heat Discolored Yoke</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Foreign Material on Shaft.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRANSVERSE VIBRATION</title>
            <para>Transverse vibration is the result of a bending movement caused by improper balance (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600133">Figure 33</hotlnk>). Transverse vibration or out-of-balance will have the
                following characteristics:
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600133" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600133" filename="../figg06/g0600133.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Transverse Vibration</caption>
            </figure>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>You may hear the vibration, but for the most part you will feel it.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Force from the imbalance increases with speed. It usually can be felt best at a certain road
                        speed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>This kind of vibration is not affected by load on the vehicle. It occurs bob-tail as well as
                        with a trailer.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TORSIONAL VIBRATION</title>
            <para>A universal joint has a maximum angle at which it will transmit power smoothly.</para>
            <para>Torsional vibration is a twisting motion most commonly caused by unequal universal joint working
                angles (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600134">Figure 34</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600134" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600134" filename="../figg06/g0600134.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="192px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Torsional Vibration</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When two shafts connected together by a universal joint are operated at an angle, the driven shaft
                speed will change in relation to the driving shaft speed. Twice during rotation, the driven shaft speed
                will increase and decrease compared to the driving shaft speed. This speed fluctuation creates torsional
                excitation (winding up and unwinding) of the propeller shaft.
            </para>
            <para>With equal working angles, the rear of the shaft will slow down by the same amount that the front
                speeds up. This results in a propeller shaft that turns at a constant speed without twisting.
            </para>
            <para>Torsional vibration is harder to identify during road testing, but it has certain characteristics:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Torsional vibration produces a very noticeable sound.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torsional vibrations can exist at one or more speeds and usually is more severe at low
                        speeds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque and load changes will affect the vibration. Normally the vibration will be affected
                        directly by a change in throttle position. Load, as in with or without a trailer, also affects
                        this kind of vibration.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
