<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PROPELLER SHAFT - ASSEMBLE - FULL ROUND YOKE UNIVERSAL JOINT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>FULL ROUND YOKE UNIVERSAL JOINT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before assembly, remove the four bearing caps and inspect the journal ends for check valve.
                If one journal has a check valve, they all should have a check valve.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the cross so that the lube zerk is in line with the zerk on the slip yoke and
                pointed inboard (towards) the propeller shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a cross journal through a cross hole far enough to allow the opposite journal to be
                tilted and positioned in the other cross hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the cross through the cross hole so it extends beyond the outer machined face of a yoke
                lug.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the outer diameter of the bearing caps with anti-seize compound and position
                bearing cap over journal (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600123">Figure 23</hotlnk>). The cap must be square and aligned with the cross hole in
                the yoke so the cap will not bind. If the bearing cap should bind in the hole, tap the cap with a ball
                peen hammer directly in center of bearing plate.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600123" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600123" filename="../figg06/g0600123.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Position Bearing Cap Over Journal</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>NEVER tap outer edges of the bearing plate. When bearing cap is aligned, it can be pressed
                        into place by hand. If bearing cap cannot be pushed in place, it is binding or yoke hole was not
                        properly cleaned.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the bearing cap is seated, line up the cap holes with the holes in the yoke. Assemble
                the lockstrap (if equipped) and bolts to the yoke lug (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600124">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600124" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600124" filename="../figg06/g0600124.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Assemble Lockstrap and Bolts to Yoke Lug</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the cross to the other cross hole so that the journal is beyond the machined surface of
                the yoke lug. Position the other bearing cap over the bearing surface and slide it into the cross hole
                in the yoke (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600125">Figure 25</hotlnk>). Seat the bearing plate on the lug mating surface and
                assemble lockstrap (if equipped) and bolts. Tighten bolts. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s06001_32.xml" xrefid="torquechart">Torque Chart
                    <xref refid="torquechart"/>
                </hotlnk>
                for torque specifications. If equipped, bend lockstrap tab over to lock the bolts.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600125" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600125" filename="../figg06/g0600125.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Position Bearing Cap Over Bearing Surface</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
