<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PROPELLER SHAFT - DISASSEMBLE - OUTSIDE/INSIDE SNAP RING YOKE UNIVERSAL JOINT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OUTSIDE/INSIDE SNAP RING YOKE UNIVERSAL JOINT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove each snap ring by pinching the end together with a pair of pliers (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600114">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600114" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600114" filename="../figg06/g0600114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Remove Snap Rings</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If a ring does not readily snap out of the groove in the yoke, tap the end of the bearing cap
                        lightly to relieve the pressure against the ring.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set the yoke in the arbor press with a piece of tube stock beneath it. Position the yoke
                with the lube fitting pointing up to prevent interference during disassembly. Place a solid plug on the
                upper bearing assembly and press it through to release the lower bearing assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600115">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600115" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600115" filename="../figg06/g0600115.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Press Plug Through Upper Bearing Assembly to Release Lower Bearing Assembly
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the opposite bearing assembly, turn the yoke over and straighten the cross in the
                open cross hole. Then carefully press on the end of the cross so the remaining bearing assembly moves
                straight out of the bearing cross hole. If the cross or bearing assembly is cocked, the bearing assembly
                will score the walls of the cross hole and ruin the yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the cross by sliding it through the side of the yoke, and tilting it outward while
                removing it from the yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
