<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PROPELLER SHAFT - VIBRATION - BALANCING THE PROPELLER SHAFT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>BALANCING THE PROPELLER SHAFT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>There are two methods of balancing the propeller shaft:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Rephasing the propeller shaft by rotating it 180&#176; in relation to its current position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Adding a small weight to the propeller shaft.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rephasing the Propeller Shaft</title>
            <para>Before any balance weights are added to the propeller shafts, disconnect the rear propeller shaft at
                the center bearing and rotate the shaft 180&#176; in relation to the companion flange (vehicles without
                center bearing, rotate the shaft at the transmission). Reconnect the shaft, then road test the vehicle
                or spin the driveline and check for vibration.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adding Weight to Propeller Shaft</title>
            <para>Use an adjustable hose clamp and a small metal weight (approximately 1/2 ounce). Clamp the weight to
                the rear shaft near the center bearing and cut off the excess material of the band as close to the clamp
                as possible (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0600137">Figure 37</hotlnk>). Road test the vehicle or spin the driveline; then, by
                moving the weight to various locations on the shaft, find the point of least vibration. Increase or
                decrease the weight at this point to obtain as perfect a balance as possible. Mark the location of the
                weight on the shaft and remove the hose clamp and weight. Weigh the weight and add 3/8 of an ounce for
                the clamp screw and nut. Select a piece of steel of this total weight and tack weld to the propeller
                shaft at the locating mark. Hold the weld material to a minimum.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0600137" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0600137" filename="../figg06/G0600137.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Clamp Weight to Rear Shaft Near Center Bearing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CUT OFF EXCESS MATERIAL OF BAND AS CLOSE TO CLAMP AS POSSIBLE.</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. POSITION WEIGHT UNDER HOSE CLAMP BELOW CLAMP SCREW.</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PLACE HOSE CLAMP AND WEIGHT AS CLOSE TO STUD END OF SHAFT AS POSSIBLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>For vehicles with a single propeller shaft, use an adjustable hose clamp and a small weight
                (approximately 1/2 ounce). Clamp the weight to the front end of the shaft and cut off the excess
                material of the band as close to the clamp as possible. Road test the vehicle or spin the driveline;
                then, by moving the weight to various locations on the shaft, find the point of least vibration.
                Increase or decrease the weight at this point to obtain as perfect a balance as possible. Mark the
                location of the weight on the shaft and remove the hose clamp and weight. Weigh the weight and add 3/8
                of an ounce for the clamp screw and nut. Select a piece of steel of this total weight and tack weld to
                the propeller shaft at the locating mark. Hold the weld material to a minimum.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When using hose clamps to attach loose weights to a propeller shaft (when checking for
                        vibration), make sure that the weights are clamped securely to the shaft to avoid the hazard of
                        weights flying off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s06001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
