<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR, REMOVE AND REPLACE - MXT - COMPONENT AND RADIATOR REMOVal</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>COMPONENT AND RADIATOR REMOVal</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Prior to removal of cooling system components, the cooling system should be drained. Place a tray
                below radiator Drain Plug Petcock (Figure 2) and drain coolant (approximately 8.5 gallons). Save coolant
                for refilling system after replacing all components.
            </para>
            <para>1.&#9;Begin by opening the Hood and locating the two Hood Tension Rods along the top of the Hood
                Mounting Bracket. (See example in Figure 3.)
            </para>
            <para>2.&#9;Remove the Tension Rods by removing the pin from each bracket (Figure 4) located on both the
                Left and Right Chassis Frame.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1201903" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201903.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Example of Hood Tension Rods</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1201904" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201904.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Example of Tension Rod Bracket and Pin</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>3.&#9;Locate the Hood Stabilizer Wires at the Top Front Radiator Frame (Figure 5). Disconnect the
                stabilizer wires and remove the Hood per instructions in the Hood, Grille, Bumpers and Fender Extensions
                Service Manual, S09013.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Fender extensions and front bumper do NOT need to be removed. However, the hood must be
                        removed once the stabilizer wires are disconnected, or the hood will fall forward with no
                        support.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>4.&#9;Disconnect the wiring to the two horns mounted on the front crossmember (Figure 6).</para>
            <para>5.&#9;Disconnect wire harness at the "snap" connection attached to driver side front crossmember
                (Figure 6). Disconnect wire harness attached to passenger side front crossmember if applicable.
            </para>
            <para>6.&#9;Disconnect the 2 radiator stabilizer rod bolts at the front crossmember side and at the radiator
                side.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1201905" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Hood Stabilizers Connected to the Radiator Frame</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1201906" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. View of Driver Side Front Crossmember with Horn, Wire Harness and Connecting "Snap",
                    and Hood and Grille Assembly Bracket. NOTE: Hood is in "Open" position in this photo (not removed
                    yet)
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <para>7.&#9;Locate and remove the front crossmember by loosening and removing the 4 bolts holding it to the
                chassis frame. The front crossmember with its four mounting bolts is shown in Figure 7. (Notice the hood
                stabilizer wires and hood and grille assembly are removed, as are the horns and wire harness from Figure
                6.)
            </para>
            <figure id="f1201907" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Front Crossmember</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
