<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR/COOLING SYSTEM SERVICE MANUAL - PROSTAR&#8482; - COOLING PACKAGE COMPONENTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>COOLING PACKAGE COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent vehicle damage, personal injury, or possible death, park the vehicle on a flat
                        level surface. Make sure the engine ignition is in the off position, and the transmission is in
                        neutral or in the park position if the vehicle is equipped with an automatic transmission. Set
                        the parking brake, chock the wheels, and disconnect the batteries at the negative terminal
                        before doing any service procedures on the engine or vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent vehicle damage and/or personal injury, use care when removing or installing cooling
                        system components with the hood in the open position. With the hood assembly in the open
                        position, the available space to maneuver components such as the charge air cooler, air
                        conditioning condenser, external transmission cooler (if applicable) and radiator frame and core
                        assembly is limited, making handling of the components difficult.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Before performing any work on the coolant package components, be sure to perform these basic
                        procedures:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="arabic">
                        <item>
                            <para>Park the chassis on a flat level surface.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Place transmission in neutral (or park if automatic transmission).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Set the parking brake.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Turn off ignition.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Install wheel chocks.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Disconnect the battery.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12021_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12021_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12021.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
