<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR SHUTTERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s12005" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5084" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>RADIATOR SHUTTERS</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3900</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>12UJA</ucode>
                <ucode>12UJB</ucode>
                <ucode>12801</ucode>
                <ucode>12802</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The function of radiator shutters is to keep the operating temperature of the engine in the
                        OPTIMUM TEMPERATURE RANGE, a consistent, predetermined heat range. The upper temperature limit
                        of the range is the maximum safe operating temperature of the engine, and the low temperature
                        limit is five or six degrees less.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Several benefits are provided by the vehicle operating within this optimum range: reduced
                        condensation inside the engine, decreased formation of sludge and corrosion, improved fuel
                        economy, elimination of cracked engine blocks, and extended engine life. Shutters are especially
                        effective in cold climates, and for applications with intermittent operation such as delivery
                        vans and busses.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The shutter assembly is composed of a galvanized steel box frame, extruded aluminum shutter
                        vanes, molded nylon vane cranks and a control cylinder. The frame supports the ends of the
                        vanes. A connecting rod links the vanes together so that they can open and close simultaneously
                        when the control cylinder actuates. To prevent ram air leakage when the shutters are closed, the
                        vanes have integral weather-tight seals on their leading edges (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200501">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1200501" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200501" filename="../figg12/G1200501.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Shutter Assembly Section</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. RADIATOR CORE</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. CONTROL CYLINDER</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. CONNECTING ROD</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. SHUTTER VANE</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. SEAL</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. SHUTTER FRAME</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The shutters operate in a fail-safe manner; that is, the vanes open automatically when the
                        vehicle is shut down. The control cylinder responds to air or hydraulic pressure from the
                        shutter control valve, and actuates to hold the spring-loaded vanes closed. When pressure is
                        relieved, the vanes open.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The shutters work with either an ON/OFF fan clutch or a viscous fan drive. Shutters may be
                        mounted either behind or in front of the radiator (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200502">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1200502" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200502" filename="../figg12/G1200502.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Shutter Installation</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. RADIATOR/CHARGE AIR COOLER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. SHUTTER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. SHUTTER VANE</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. FAN SHROUD</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. RADIATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12005_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
