<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Green Diesel Retrofit - Operation - Diagnostic Trouble Code Index</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Diagnostic Trouble Code Index</title>
        <para>Troubleshooting can generally be completed without connecting to a computer. If any faults are active, the
            lights will illuminate and may flash out a fault code, i.e. Fault 1 both lights will flash one time, Fault 2
            both lights will flash two times, Yellow (over pressure) event will illuminate the yellow light, Red (over
            pressure or over temperature) event will illuminate the red light, etc. The following is a simplified
            troubleshooting guide. For more in depth troubleshooting, contact FES or your distributor.
        </para>
        <table id="t1201603">
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.60*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.40*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Action</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault 1 (Switch 1 Failed)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Disconnect pressure switch. View the Status page of UCM interface software. Jumper
                                between light blue line (Terminal A) and red line (Terminal B). If Switch 1 (N.O.) is
                                closed, replace the pressure switch. If Switch 1 (N.O.) is open, replace the UCM
                                harness.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault 2 (Switch 1 Shorted)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check Status page of UCM Interface Software. If Switch 1 (N.O.) is closed, disconnect
                                the pressure switch. If after disconnecting the sensor Switch 1 on the Status page shows
                                open, replace the pressure switch. If it is still closed, replace the UCM harness.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault 4 (Switch 2 Failed Open)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Disconnect the pressure switch. Jumper between dark blue line (Terminal C) and red
                                line (Terminal B). Check Status page of UCM Interface Software. If Switch 2 (N.C.) is
                                closed, replace the pressure sensor. If it is open, replace the harness.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault 5 (Thermistor Failed)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify that the exhaust temperature was not below 100C for more than an hour
                                continuously (by downloading the drive cycle table) and that the thermistor is
                                connected. If both of these are true, replace the thermistor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fault 6 (Thermistor Shorted)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace thermistor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Solid Yellow Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clean filter.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Solid Red Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify that the temperature did not exceed 700 C. If the temperature did not exceed
                                the set point, clean the filter.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>No lights upon engine start-up.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify that the lights are functioning by using the Yellow On and Red On buttons on
                                the Status page of the Communications Software to activate the lights and replace if
                                they do not illuminate. If the lights are functioning, verify that the Battery Counts
                                increase by 4% after the engine is started. If the battery counts do not increase,
                                contact the distributor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
