<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Side Mount Cooling Package - RE Bus - REMOVE AND INSTALL PROCEDURES - HYDRAULIC OIL COOLER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="Remove and Install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>HYDRAULIC OIL COOLER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Oil Cooler - Removal</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Prior to draining any coolant from the system, close two heater shut-off valves. The heater
                        shut-off valves can be accessed through the left-side rear compartment service door.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unlatch and open the rear compartment service door.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the radiator drain valve prior to removal of the hydraulic oil cooler. Place tray
                    under the radiator to collect coolant from radiator. Open drain valve and drain coolant (
                    <hotlnk document="s12023_7.xml" xrefid="f1202301">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202315" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/g1202315.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Hydraulic Oil Cooler</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC OIL COOLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CLIPPING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BOLT AND WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. DRAIN PLUG</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two bolts, washers, and nuts from the hydraulic oil cooler and clipping
                    brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position hydraulic hoses out of the way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a suitable container under the hydraulic oil cooler to catch the hydraulic oil
                    from the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain the hydraulic fluid by removing the drain plug from the bottom of the hydraulic
                    oil cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202316" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/g1202316.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Hydraulic Oil Cooler Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOSE CLAMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COOLANT HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BOLT, WASHER, AND NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HYDRAULIC OIL COOLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. MOUNT BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HYDRAULIC HOSES</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. HYDRAULIC TRANSMISSION HOSES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Tag and mark hoses before removal to ensure proper installation.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cap and plug all hoses upon removal to stop leakage and prevent contamination.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </note>
                <important>
                    <para>If the transmission is equipped with a retarder the hydraulic oil cooler will have one small
                        coolant bypass hose on the right-side and two coolant hoses connected to the left-side. If the
                        transmission has no retarder than only two coolant hoses will be connected to the left-side of
                        the hydraulic oil cooler.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen clamps on three coolant hoses, two on the right side of the hydraulic oil cooler
                    and one on the left side of the hydraulic oil cooler. Remove three coolant hoses from the hydraulic
                    oil cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect two hydraulic hoses from the hydraulic oil cooler.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect two hydraulic transmission hoses from the hydraulic oil cooler.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack and strap should be used to remove the hydraulic oil cooler. The hydraulic oil cooler
                        weighs 110 lbs. (50 kg). Failure to comply could result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a suitable jack under the hydraulic oil cooler and secure the jack with a strap
                    around the hydraulic oil cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two bolts, washers, and nuts from top of the hydraulic oil cooler. Remove the
                    hydraulic oil cooler from the mount bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If replacement is needed, transfer all fittings to the new hydraulic oil cooler.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Oil Cooler - Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the hydraulic oil cooler on a suitable jack and secure the jack with a strap
                    around the hydraulic oil cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the hydraulic oil cooler on the mount bracket and install top two bolts, washers,
                    and nuts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202316">Figure 20, Items 3, 4, and 5</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 30 to 38 lbf-ft
                    (41 to 52 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Some hydraulic hoses and fittings in the hydraulic system are equipped with O-rings to seal
                        the hydraulic hoses. Inspect all O-rings prior to installation and replace as needed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>Be sure to remove all caps and plugs that were installed during the removal procedures before
                        installing hydraulic hoses.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect two hydraulic transmission hoses to the hydraulic oil cooler (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202316">Figure 20, Items 4 and 7</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect two hydraulic hoses to the hydraulic oil cooler (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202316">Figure 20, Items 4 and 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If the transmission is equipped with a retarder the hydraulic oil cooler will have one small
                        coolant bypass hose on the right-side and two coolant hoses connected to the left-side. If the
                        transmission has no retarder than only two coolant hoses will be connected to the left-side of
                        the hydraulic oil cooler.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install three coolant hoses on the hydraulic oil cooler and secure clamps (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202316">Figure 20, Items 1, 2, and 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two bolts, washers, and nuts on the hydraulic oil cooler and clipping brackets (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202315">Figure 19</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 30 to 38 lbf-ft (41 to 52 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the drain plug in the hydraulic oil cooler (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202315">Figure 19, Items 1 and 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the hydraulic system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system to proper level and leak test the cooling system. Special Tool
                    number
                    <emph type="bold">550500INT</emph>
                    is recommended to fill and leak test the cooling system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>After filling the cooling system, open two heater shut-off valves and recheck the coolant
                        level. The heater shut-off valves can be accessed through the left-side rear compartment service
                        door.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close and latch the rear compartment service door.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
