<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Intake Air Distribution/Filtering and Charge Air Cooler - Intake Air Distribution and
        Filtering - Diagnosis and Testing
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Diagnosis and Testing</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symptom Chart</title>
            <table id="t0312006" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Symptom Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.07*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Possible Sources</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Action</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Excessive black smoke under load/low power</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>High restriction caused by foreign material blocking air inlet screen.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>High restriction caused by the air inlet iced over.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>High restriction caused by foreign material blocking the air intake drain
                                            tube.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Leaks at air intake joints due to loose clamps or disconnected ducts.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Restriction in the air cleaner element.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Pressurized air leaking from loose connections or cracks in the
                                            charge-air-cooler, ducts or intake components.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Leaks or restrictions in the exhaust system will cause the turbine and
                                            impeller to operate at a lower speed and reduce the amount of air being
                                            forced into the cylinders.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>A restriction in the pressure side of the intake air system will change
                                            the air-to-fuel ratio.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>A malfunctioning or misadjusted turbocharger wastegate can result in low
                                            boost pressures.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Failure of the turbocharger internal components. A bearing failure can
                                            produce friction, reducing the speed of the rotor assembly. Bearing failure
                                            can cause the compressor and impeller blades to rub the housing, reducing
                                            the rotor assembly speed.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REMOVE foreign material.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the air intake pipe. If frozen, carefully thaw out.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REMOVE foreign material.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT air intake joints. REATTACH ducts and TIGHTEN clamps to
                                            specification.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL a new air cleaner element.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the entire intake air system for leaks. CARRY OUT the
                                            charge-air-cooler leak test. REFER to Leak Test - Charge-Air-Cooler under
                                            Charge Air Cooler Repairs within this section. REPAIR the intake air system.
                                            TEST the system for normal operation.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REPAIR the exhaust system. REFER to Exhaust System in S07002. TEST the
                                            system for normal operation.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK for restricted or leaking charge-air-cooler. CARRY OUT the
                                            charge-air-cooler leak test. REFER to Leak Test - Charge-Air-Cooler under
                                            Charge Air Cooler Repairs within this section. REPAIR the intake air system.
                                            TEST the system for normal operation.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the turbocharger wastegate function and adjustment. INSTALL a new
                                            turbocharger as necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service Manual.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CARRY OUT the bearing clearance check. INSTALL a new turbocharger as
                                            necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service Manual.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>High oil consumption</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>A restricted or damaged oil return passage will cause the turbocharger
                                            housing to become pressurized, causing engine oil to migrate past the
                                            turbocharger seals.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>If there is an excessive amount of engine oil in the turbocharger housing
                                            and no other causes are found for the excessive oil consumption.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Excessive crankcase pressure will not allow the oil to drain from the
                                            turbocharger. This will load the bearing housing and allow the engine oil to
                                            leak past the compressor seals and into the engine.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CLEAN or REPAIR as necessary. RESTORE the vehicle. TEST the system for
                                            normal operation.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL a new turbocharger as necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service
                                            Manual.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to EGES-305, Engine Diagnostics Manual for causes of the excessive
                                            blow-by.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Boost pressure high/low</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Turbocharger wastegate failure or misadjustment can result in excessively
                                            high or low boost pressures. Low boost pressures can cause excessive smoke
                                            and low power. High boost pressures can cause major engine damage.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Pressurized air leaking from loose connections or cracks in the charge air
                                            cooler, ducts or intake manifold runners.
                                        </para>
                                        <para>A restriction in the pressure side of the intake air system will change
                                            the air-to-fuel ratio.
                                        </para>
                                        <para>Leaks or restrictions in the exhaust system will cause the turbine and
                                            impeller to operate at a lower speed and reduce the amount of air being
                                            forced into the cylinders.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the turbocharger wastegate function and adjustment. INSTALL a new
                                            turbocharger as necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service Manual.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REFER to Excessive black smoke under load/low power within this symptom
                                            chart.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Noise/Vibration</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A. Leaks in the intake air system.</para>
                                <para>B. Rattles due to loose air cleaner support brackets.</para>
                                <para>C. Foreign material in the intake air system.</para>
                                <para>D. Leaks in the exhaust system.</para>
                                <para>E. Foreign material in the exhaust system.</para>
                                <para>F. Foreign material in the turbocharger.</para>
                                <para>G. Minor nicks or dents in the compressor or turbine wheel.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A. REPAIR or INSTALL new intake air system components as necessary. TIGHTEN the
                                    clamps to specification. TEST the system for normal operation.
                                </para>
                                <para>B. REPAIR or INSTALL new brackets as necessary. TIGHTEN fasteners to
                                    specification.
                                </para>
                                <para>C. CHECK the intake air system for foreign material. CLEAN, REPAIR or INSTALL new
                                    intake air system components as necessary. TEST the system for normal operation.
                                </para>
                                <para>D. REPAIR or INSTALL new exhaust system components as necessary. REFER to Exhaust
                                    System in S07002. TEST the system for normal operation.
                                </para>
                                <para>E. CHECK the exhaust system for foreign material. CLEAN, REPAIR or INSTALL new
                                    exhaust system components as necessary. REFER to Exhaust System in S07002. TEST the
                                    system for normal operation.
                                </para>
                                <para>F. CHECK the turbocharger for signs of damage due to rotor assembly damage.
                                    INSTALL a new turbocharger as necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service Manual.
                                </para>
                                <para>G. INSTALL a new turbocharger as necessary. REFER to EGES-300, Engine Service
                                    Manual.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>If the problem cannot be diagnosed using the preceding symptom chart, refer to EGES-305, Engine
                Diagnostics Manual for additional information.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12014_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12014_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
