<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - VISCOUS FAN DRIVES - MAINTENANCE CHECK</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1200201" svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MAINTENANCE CHECK</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Improper use or application, or modification of a viscous fan drive or the fan that it carries can
                    result in property damage or personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>DO NOT operate a vehicle with a drive or fan blades that are malfunctioning or are externally
                    damaged. Continued operation could result in property damage or personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>DO NOT attempt to restrict fan blade rotation during engine operation. Damage to the fan drive,
                    property damage or personal injury could result.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>Before performing tests on the fan drive with the engine running, insure that the wheels are
                    properly chocked and the parking brake is engaged, wear eye protection, prevent loose clothing from
                    contact with the rotating fan blades, stay clear of hot surfaces and insure that any test leads are
                    protected from rotating components. Failure to follow these warnings could result in property
                    damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>At 25,000 miles, perform the following:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the torque of fan blade fasteners.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the torque of fan drive-to-pulley, hub and bracket assembly fasteners.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the torque of pulley, hub and bracket assembly-to-engine fasteners.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the fan drive, fan blade assembly, shroud, radiator and the immediately adjacent areas
                for evidence of interference between rotating and non-rotating parts. If damage is present, isolate and
                repair or replace defective parts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the fan through at least 360 degrees. It should turn smoothly, but with some
                resistance. Replace fan drive if the fan binds, jerks, or spins freely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The following step is used to detect looseness in the fan or fan drive mounting; when performing
                    the step, do not force the blade tip (cause the blade to deflect) because this will distort the
                    resulting measurement.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Grasp one fan blade tip, and move it back and forth from the radiator. At 10 inches (254 mm)
                radius from the center, the blade tip should not move more than 1/16 inch (1.6 mm). If the blade moves
                more than specified and the excess cannot be attributed to pulley/water pump bearing wear, blade
                deflection, or loose fasteners (fan to fan drive or fan drive to hub/pulley), replace the fan drive.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
