<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM - CLEAN AND INSPECT - CLEANING THE
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLEANING THE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>If coolant is not conditioned with corrosion inhibitor, rust and scale will eventually clog up
                passages in the radiator and water jackets. In some places, the local water composition causes insoluble
                salt formations that aggravate radiator clogging.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the coolant shut-off cocks to heaters and other accessories to allow complete
                    circulation during cleaning, flushing and draining.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the engine until the temperature is up to operating range of 160 to 180&#176;F (71
                    to 82&#176;C). If necessary, cover the radiator to increase the operating temperature. Stop the
                    engine and remove the pressure cap.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the pressure cap from the deaeration tank.
                            ALWAYS INSULATE the cap by wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth. To prevent possible injury
                            from scalding water or steam, DO NOT pull the pressure cap off immediately when it has been
                            loosened to the first "notch." Pause momentarily to allow time for excess pressure to
                            release through the overflow tube.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the drain cocks on the radiator and crankcase to drain the coolant from the system.
                    Disconnect the radiator outlet hose to drain sediment that is too large to pass through the drain
                    cock.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be certain the engine has cooled completely, then install the radiator outlet hose, and
                    close the drain cocks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pour cleaning solution into the radiator, then fill the system with water. Use a clean
                    drain pan to catch any overflow. Avoid getting cleaning solution on vehicle paint; wipe up spills
                    promptly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the pressure cap, then run the engine at moderate speed until the radiator
                    reaches 180&#176;F (82&#176;C), or above.
                </para>
                <para>If necessary, cover the radiator to increase the operating temperature, but DO NOT allow the
                    cleaning solution to boil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the engine until the circulating solution has effectively cleaned the cooling system
                    - AT LEAST TWO HOURS. Check the radiator and replenish the solution level as necessary to maintain
                    circulation.
                </para>
                <para>DO NOT allow the radiator level to get low enough to interfere with circulation in the cooling
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>DO NOT allow the cleaning solution to boil. Stop the engine as necessary to prevent boiling.</para>
            <para>DO NOT drive the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the cleaning process is done, stop the engine. Observe the operating temperature;
                    when it has come down and remained stable for several minutes, drain the cooling system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>IF THE CLOGGED RADIATOR CORE IS CLEARED, fill the cooling system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s12003r_8.xml" xrefid="hl1200305">FILLING THE COOLING SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl1200305"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>IF THE CLOGGED CORE IS RELIEVED, but not yet fully corrected, allow the engine to cool completely,
                pressure-flush the system, then repeat this cleaning procedure. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s12003r_22.xml" xrefid="hl120031a">PRESSURE FLUSHING THE SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl120031a"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>IF THE CLOGGED CORE IS NOT RELIEVED, the radiator core will have to be replaced.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspect Engine Water Jacket</title>
            <para>CORE PLUGS: Replace core plugs that show signs of leaking or rusting through. Refer to GROUP 12-
                ENGINE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for core plug replacement.
            </para>
            <para>DRAIN PLUGS: The drain plugs located in the water jacket should receive seasonal care and be kept free
                of rust and scale.
            </para>
            <para>GASKETS: Gaskets must be in good condition to prevent both internal and external leaks. External leaks
                around gaskets may indicate there are also internal leaks in the engine. Tighten the head bolts properly
                with a torque wrench to prevent leaks around the head gasket.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use chemical mixtures to stop radiator leaks except in an emergency. Never use such
                        solutions in place of performing necessary radiator repair.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
