<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Side Mount Cooling Package - RE Bus - REMOVE AND INSTALL PROCEDURES - HYDRAULIC PUMP</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="Remove and Install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>HYDRAULIC PUMP</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Pump - Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unlatch and open the rear compartment service doors, left-side door, and rear door.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202306" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1202306.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Drive Belt</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC PUMP PULLEY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVE BELT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BELT TENSIONER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TENSIONER RELEASE HOLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert ratchet in belt tensioner release hole, relieve tension from drive belt, and
                    remove drive belt from hydraulic pump pulley.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202307" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1202307.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Hydraulic Pump Pulley</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BOLTS AND WASHERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HYDRAULIC PUMP PULLEY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HYDRAULIC PUMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove six bolts and washers from the hydraulic pump pulley.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hydraulic pump pulley from the hydraulic pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202308" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1202308.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Hydraulic Pump</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. UPPER HYDRAULIC HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BOLTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. MOUNT BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TEMPERATURE SENSOR LOCATION</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. LOWER HYDRAULIC HOSE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Cap and plug all hoses upon removal to stop leakage and prevent contamination.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a suitable container under the lower hydraulic hose to catch the hydraulic oil
                    from the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove P-clips and wire ties as needed from the lower hydraulic hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the lower hydraulic hose from the hydraulic pump and position lower hydraulic
                    hose into the container for draining.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the upper hydraulic hose from the hydraulic pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The hydraulic pump weighs 77 lbs. (35 kg) and care should be taken when removing the hydraulic
                        pump. The temperature sensor and wiring located under the hydraulic pump can be broken if the
                        hydraulic pump is allowed to drop down.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <important>
                    <para>To aid in removal of the hydraulic pump, remove two bolts from the pulley end mount holes,
                        install two 8 mm studs into those holes, and remove the remaining two bolts.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support the hydraulic pump and remove four bolts from the mount bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully lift the hydraulic pump up and clear of the engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1202309" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/G1202309.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Hydraulic Pump Disassembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FITTINGS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HYDRAULIC PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NUT AND WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. MOUNT BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HUB MOUNT NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HUB</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. MOUNT BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. NUT AND LOCK WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CABLE STRAP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the hydraulic pump is being replaced, follow these instructions to disassemble the
                    hydraulic pump:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="alphalc">
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the hub mount nut from the hydraulic pump.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Using an appropriate puller, remove the hub from the hydraulic pump.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Note the location of two fittings and remove two fittings from hydraulic pump.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove nut, lock washer, and cable strap from mount bracket and hydraulic pump.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove two mount bolts, washers, and nuts from mount bracket and hydraulic pump.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove hydraulic pump from mount brackets.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Pump - Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the hydraulic pump is being replaced, follow these instructions to assemble the
                    hydraulic pump:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="alphalc">
                    <item>
                        <para>Install the hydraulic pump on the mount brackets (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1202309">Figure 13, Items 2 and 7</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install two mount bolts, washers, and nuts on the mount bracket and hydraulic pump (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1202309">Figure 13</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 70 to 85 lbf-ft (95 to 115 N&#8226;m).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install the cable strap on the mount bracket and hydraulic pump. Secure the cable strap
                            with the lock washer and nut (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1202309">Figure 13</hotlnk>). Torque nut to 21 to 27 lbf-ft (28 to 37 N&#8226;m).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install two fittings on hydraulic pump as noted during removal procedure (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1202309">Figure 13, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install the hub on the hydraulic pump and secure with hub mount nut (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1202309">Figure 13, Items 2, 5, and 6</hotlnk>). Torque nut to 220 to 240
                            lbf-ft (298 to 325 N&#8226;m).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The hydraulic pump weighs 77 lbs. (35 kg) and care should be taken when installing the
                        hydraulic pump. The temperature sensor and wiring located under the hydraulic pump can be broken
                        if the hydraulic pump is allowed to drop down.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully align the hydraulic pump and mount brackets on the two studs that were
                    installed during the removal procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two bolts on the mount bracket, remove two studs, and install two remaining
                    bolts on the mount bracket (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202308">Figure 12, Items 1, 3, and 4</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 17 to 21 lbf-ft
                    (23 to 28 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Some hydraulic hoses and fittings in the hydraulic system are equipped with O-rings to seal
                        the hydraulic hoses. Inspect all O-rings prior to installation and replace as needed.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>Be sure to remove all caps and plugs that were installed during the removal procedures before
                        installing hydraulic hoses.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the upper hydraulic hose on the hydraulic pump (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202308">Figure 12, Items 1 and 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the lower hydraulic hose on the hydraulic pump (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202308">Figure 12, Items 1 and 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install P-clips and wire ties on the lower hydraulic hose as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the hydraulic pump pulley on the hydraulic pump and secure with six bolts and
                    washers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202307">Figure 11</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 13 to 16 lbf-ft (18 to 21 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert ratchet in belt tensioner release hole, relieve tension, and install drive belt
                    on hydraulic pump pulley (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1202306">Figure 10</hotlnk>). Ensure that the belt is properly mounted on all other
                    pulleys.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the hydraulic system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close and latch the rear compartment service doors, left-side door, and rear door.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
