<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FAN DRIVE CLUTCH: HORTON ON/OFF - FAN CLUTCH "SYSTEM SENTRY"&#8482; - "SYSTEM SENTRY" RELEASE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1200403" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>"SYSTEM SENTRY" RELEASE</title>
        <para>The "System Sentry" feature improves the long-term durability of the on/off fan clutch. If low air
            pressure occurs for any reason in the system, the piston friction disc will begin to slip. The friction of
            this slippage will create heat which will cause the "System Sentry" to react, releasing the clutch to
            prevent damage. The "System Sentry" is fitted to the piston friction disc in a 1/8 inch, left-hand thread
            pipe plug (
            <hotlnk document="s12004r_7.xml" xrefid="f1200404">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
            <emph type="bold">DO NOT ATTEMPT TO REPLACE THE "SYSTEM SENTRY" WITH A NORMAL PIPE PLUG</emph>.
            <emph type="bold">THIS WILL CAUSE THE CLUTCH TO BE OUT OF BALANCE, CREATING FURTHER ADVERSE CONDITIONS.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>The "System Sentry" must be replaced after it has released the clutch.</para>
        <para>A "System Sentry" clutch release is detectable when the engine is shut down because the sound of releasing
            air will be heard for a short time after the engine is turned off (see ,
            <hotlnk document="s12004r_HL1200404.xml" xrefid="hl1200404">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>, section marked "System
            Sentry," ). The rush of air at the front of the piston friction disc is the primary indicator that the
            "System Sentry" has released the clutch.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid possible personal injury, do not check for this air rush or any air leak unless the
                    ignition switch is in the OFF position and the engine is stopped.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>When the "System Sentry" has released the clutch and shut down the system, the entire clutch application
            system must be checked for air leaks, including clutch seals and air cartridge (refer to
            <hotlnk document="s12004r_HL1200404.xml" xrefid="hl1200404">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>). Also the electrical
            control switches and solenoid valve need to be tested for proper function. Any fan obstructions must be
            removed, and the hub must turn freely when not engaged.
            <emph type="bold">THE CAUSE OF CLUTCH SLIPPAGE MUST BE DETERMINED AND REPAIRED BEFORE THE CLUTCH IS PUT BACK
                INTO OPERATION.
            </emph>
            <emph type="bold">DO NOT REPLACE THE "SYSTEM SENTRY" WITHOUT DETERMINING THE CAUSE OF ITS RELEASE.</emph>As
            with the old fan clutch, "come home" bolts can be used to lock the clutch temporarily until repairs can be
            made.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12004r_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12004r_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12004r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
