<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Green Diesel Retrofit - Installation Procedure - Electrical Installation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electrical Installation</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The UCM is a fully encapsulated module integrated into a wiring harness. Each connector is labeled for
                its intended use. The warning light connector, derate (TLD) connector, and J1708 datalink connector are
                Packard Weather Pack connectors. The pressure switch connector is a Packard Metri-Pack connector. The
                thermistor connector is a Framatome connector.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All wiring should be run in such a way that it is not in contact with heat sources such as the
                        engine, exhaust manifold, or radiator.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Connection</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Connect all components with supplied connectors.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Excess wire should be secured to the vehicle with tie wrap or other fastening devices.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If components are not connected before the system is powered, faults will occur.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power Connection</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Locate an unswitched 12 or 24 volt power supply. (All systems should be connected to 12 volts
                        unless otherwise specified in the UCM kit.)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect the supplied fused power harness to the previously located power supply (the red wire
                        is run to the positive side of the power supply and black is run to ground).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trim any excess wire from the power harness.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Splice the UCM power wire and the power harness together.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The joint must then be heat sealed to ensure environmental protection. The warranty may be
                        void if this is not completed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TLD (Derate) Connection</title>
            <para>Various methods are used to connect the derate option to the engine. Contact your distributor/dealer
                or FES for complete instructions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Once all connections are made, reconnect the power to the vehicle. The warning lights should
                        flash one time if the base model is connected or two times if the temperature enabled model is
                        connected. If any lights flash after the original one or two, reset the unit by running a magnet
                        around the main harness label area. The lights should flash once or twice again and then all
                        lights should remain off. If the alarm persists, ensure that all connections are properly made
                        and reset the unit again. Contact the distributor/dealer if the problem persists.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
