<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Cooling System - Cooling System - General Procedures</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>General Procedures</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cooling System Draining, Filling and Bleeding</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Draining</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never remove the pressure relief cap while the engine is operating or when the cooling system
                        is hot. Failure to follow these instructions can result in damage to the cooling system or
                        engine or result in personal injury. To avoid having scalding hot coolant or steam blow out of
                        the degas bottle when removing the pressure relief cap, wait until the engine has cooled, then
                        wrap a thick cloth around the pressure relief cap and turn it slowly. Step back while the
                        pressure is released from the cooling system. When certain all the pressure has been released,
                        (still with a cloth) turn and remove the pressure relief cap. Failure to follow these
                        instructions can result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The coolant must be recovered in a suitable, clean container for reuse. If the coolant is
                        contaminated, it must be recycled or disposed of correctly and the system filled with new
                        coolant.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Always fill the cooling system with the same type of coolant that was drained from the system.
                        Do not mix coolant types.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Less than 80% of coolant capacity can be recovered with the engine in the vehicle. Dirty,
                        rusty or contaminated coolant requires replacement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Place a suitable container below the radiator draincock. If equipped disconnect the coolant
                        return hose at the fluid cooler.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the pressure relief cap from the coolant reservoir.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Open the radiator draincock. Remove the cylinder drain plug, if equipped, to drain the coolant
                        from the cylinder block.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Filling and Bleeding</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Engine coolant provides freeze protection, boil protection, cooling efficiency and corrosion
                        protection to the engine and cooling components. In order to obtain these protections, the
                        engine coolant must be maintained at the correct concentration and fluid level in the coolant
                        reservoir.
                    </para>
                    <para>When adding engine coolant, use a 50/50 mixture of engine coolant and distilled water.</para>
                    <para>To maintain the integrity of the coolant and the cooling system:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Add the same type of coolant that was drained from the system. Do not mix coolant
                                types.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not add alcohol, methanol, brine or any engine coolants mixed with alcohol or
                                methanol antifreeze. These can cause engine damage from overheating or freezing.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the engine cooling system via the coolant reservoir until coolant level is between
                    the coolant fill level marks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the engine until it reaches operating temperature at 2,000 rpm for 5 minutes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off the engine and allow the cooling system to cool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add the correct engine coolant mixture to the coolant reservoir until the coolant level
                    is between the "COOLANT FILL LEVEL" marks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the air discharge remains cool and the engine coolant temperature gauge does not move, the
                        engine coolant level is low in the engine and must be filled. Stop the engine, allow to cool and
                        fill the cooling system as described.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and allow to idle until normal operating temperature is reached. Hot
                    air should discharge from the A/C vents with the climate control setting to full heat. The engine
                    coolant temperature gauge should maintain a stabilized reading in the middle of the NORMAL range and
                    the upper radiator hose should feel hot to the touch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat Steps 3-5 until the level is OK.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Coolant System Flushing</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not unscrew the coolant pressure relief cap while the engine is operating or hot. The
                        cooling system is under pressure; steam and hot liquid can come out forcefully when the cap is
                        loosened slightly. Failure to follow these instructions may result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once pressure is released, remove the pressure relief cap.</para>
                <para>Drain the cooling system. For additional information, refer to Cooling System Draining, Filling
                    and Bleeding in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the coolant thermostat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the coolant hose connection without the coolant thermostat.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the cooling system flusher manufacturer's operating instructions for specific vehicle
                        hook-up.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use an appropriate cooling system flusher to flush the engine and radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the coolant thermostat. For additional information, refer to Thermostat in this
                    section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Backflush the heater core if necessary. For additional information, refer to Heater Core
                    Backflushing in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Always fill the cooling system with the same type of coolant that was drained from the system.
                        Do not mix coolant types.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the cooling system. For additional information, refer to Cooling System Draining,
                    Filling and Bleeding in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater Core Backflushing</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never remove the pressure relief cap while the engine is operating or when the cooling system
                        is hot. Failure to follow these instructions can result in damage to the cooling system or
                        engine or personal injury. To avoid having scalding hot coolant or steam blow out of the degas
                        bottle when removing the pressure relief cap, wait until the engine has cooled, then wrap a
                        thick cloth around the pressure relief cap and turn it slowly. Step back while the pressure is
                        released from the cooling system. When you are sure all the pressure has been released, (still
                        with a cloth) turn and remove the pressure relief cap.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once pressure is released, remove the pressure relief cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clamp off the heater hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the cooling system flusher manufacturer's operating instructions for specific vehicle
                        hook-up.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use an appropriate cooling system flusher to backflush the heater core.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamps from the heater hoses.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12015_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12015_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
