<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM - MAINTENANCE - SYSTEMS WITH LIQUID
        COOLANT CONDITIONERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SYSTEMS WITH LIQUID COOLANT CONDITIONERS</title>
        <para>To replenish coolant conditioner on vehicles not equipped with a coolant filter, add Fleetrite
            conditioner. Refer to the OPERATOR'S MANUAL for proper intervals.
        </para>
        <para>When the coolant and/or supplemental coolant conditioners are overconcentrated, excess silicate "drops
            out" of the coolant to form silica-gel (hydro-gel) on heat transfer surfaces such as oil coolers, radiators
            and heater cores. The gel restricts coolant flow and causes overheating.
        </para>
        <para>The gel feels slick or putty-like when rubbed between the fingers. Its color depends on the color of the
            antifreeze/supplemental coolant additive. It can be blue to blue-green, or red to clear. When coolant
            evaporates, the gel becomes a white powdery substance. The only way known to remove silica-gel is to agitate
            the heat transfer component surfaces in a caustic solution.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>DO NOT flush an engine with caustic solution. To do so will damage O-rings, gaskets, seals and
                    "soft" metals such as aluminum and solder.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Antifreeze formulas made for automobile cooling systems have high silicate content to increase
                    aluminum corrosion protection. Using automobile antifreeze can cause coolant overconcentration
                    because they are not compatible with coolant additives commonly used for heavy-duty diesel cooling
                    systems.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>Overconcentration of coolant and/or supplemental coolant additives can cause water pump leakage. The
            powdery or granulated substance can coat water pump seal contact surfaces, allowing coolant to seep and be
            expelled at the water pump weep opening. This can be mistaken for a failed water pump seal.
        </para>
        <para>Overconcentration problems can often be resolved by diluting the coolant with water, or by draining and
            flushing the cooling system, then adding new coolant. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s12003r_17.xml" xrefid="hl1200306">CLEAN AND INSPECT
                <xref refid="hl1200306"/>
            </hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <para>Use the following guidelines to avoid silica-gel formation.</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Maintain antifreeze concentration level in the coolant at about 50% unless more freeze protection
                    is required.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use proper supplemental coolant additive levels; do not overconcentrate coolant conditioners.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With any supplemental coolant additive, use an antifreeze with 0.1 percent, or lower, of silicate
                    in the additive package.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Do not mix hard water with coolant. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s12003r_26.xml" xrefid="hl1200301">COOLANT
                        <xref refid="hl1200301"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Completely drain, flush and refill with water and conditioner, or Fleetrite antifreeze and coolant
                    once a year. This includes all vehicles, regardless of annual mileage.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the cooling system has become rusty or dirty, carefully clean the system with Fleetrite cooling
                    system cleaner and neutralizer. Follow recommendations on the container. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s12003r_17.xml" xrefid="hl1200306">CLEAN AND INSPECT
                        <xref refid="hl1200306"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
