<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR, REMOVE AND REPLACE - MXT - COMPONENT AND RADIATOR REMOVal - RADIATOR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
        <title>RADIATOR</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Prior to removing the radiator, the assembly should be secured with lifting belts to prevent
                    possible injury from radiator when loosening mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>These lifting belts will be used to help guide and lift the radiator assembly from the vehicle.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the two radiator stabilizer rods (Figure 2), and remove stay rods from the bumper
                structure assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the radiator mounting bracket and mounting bushing on each side frame of the radiator
                shell, directly below and behind the CAC connecting pipe (Figure 20, Driver's side view).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The CAC connecting hose and clamp will have already been removed as shown in Figure 21.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1201920" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg12/g1201920.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 20. Radiator Mounting Bracket and Bushing (Driver's Side Shown)</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen and remove mounting bolts (Figure 21) from mounting bracket and bushing. Follow same
                procedure on passenger side.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1201921" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg12/g1201921.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 21. Radiator Mounting Bracket and Bushing Removal Top View (Driver's Side Shown)</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a hoist (Figure 22) and the lifting belts and sling already attached to the radiator
                assembly, lift the radiator from the chassis frame rail - by coming forward toward the front bumper to
                clear the fan, and then up, to clear the front bumper.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1201922" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg12/g1201922.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Sling Attached to Hoist to Lift Radiator from Chassis Rail</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
