<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR, REMOVE AND REPLACE - MXT - RADIATOR and Component INSTALLation - SURGE TANK</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SURGE TANK</title>
        <para>Check the condition of surge tank for leaks or damage before installing.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate surge tank on radiator surge tank mounting bracket and install upper mounting bolts
                (Figure 29).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1201929" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201929.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                     scalefitheight="328px"/>
            <caption>Figure 29. Surge Tank Showing Top of Mounting Bracket with All Hoses Attached</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align side-mounting holes in surge tank with holes in surge tank mounting bracket and
                install bolts (Figure 30).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten all four bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-attach the bottom hose to the engine thermostat housing using a worm-style clamp (if
                previously removed).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-attach the upper radiator surge hose to the radiator using a compression clamp.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-attach the overflow surge hose to the overflow tank using a compression clamp.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-attach the upper engine fitting surge hose (if it was removed) using a worm-style
                clamp.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close the petcock in lower radiator.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace coolant after all other installations have been completed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the front crossmember assembly between the frame rails at the front of the chassis.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the four mounting bolts and tighten.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>When all installations, surge tank and related components, including charge air cooler pipes and clamps
            and front crossmember are installed, start engine and check for leaks. If leaks appear, recheck connecting
            tubes and all clamps for proper installation.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1201930" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg12/G1201930.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 30. Properly Installed Surge Tank (Located on Driver Side)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
