<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FAN DRIVE CLUTCH: KYSOR 1090 (8000 SERIES) - TROUBLESHOOTING - FAN CLUTCH DOES NOT OPERATE PROPERLY (CONTROL
        SYSTEM CHECKS OK)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FAN CLUTCH DOES NOT OPERATE PROPERLY (CONTROL SYSTEM CHECKS OK)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Will Not Engage</title>
            <para>Disconnect the tube from the cylinder of the clutch. The clutch housing should move forward and engage
                the fan. It will be very difficult, if not impossible to rotate the fan blade by hand. If not, overhaul
                the clutch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Will Not Disengage</title>
            <para>Disconnect the tube from the cylinder of the clutch (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1200106">Figure 6</hotlnk>) and pressurize the cylinder with an external clean air
                source (90-120 psi).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1200106" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1200106" filename="../figg12/g1200106.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Disconnect Air Source</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The clutch housing should move rearward, and the fan should move easily by hand. If clutch does not
                move easily, sometimes tapping it lightly will free it. If it is still difficult to turn, overhaul
                clutch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Engages But Is Suspected of Slipping</title>
            <para>Disconnect the clutch tube from the fan clutch solenoid. Using a Photo Tachometer, measure fan blade
                speed and fan pulley speed with the engine running at rated speed. If there is a difference between the
                fan speed and pulley speed, the clutch should be overhauled.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Engages and Disengages Slowly</title>
            <para>Disconnect the clutch tube from the cylinder of the clutch and pressurize the cylinder with an
                external clean air source (90-120 psi).
            </para>
            <para>The clutch housing should move rearward freely and quickly. Disconnect the external air source and the
                clutch should move forward freely and quickly.
            </para>
            <para>If the clutch engages and disengages slowly with the external air source (90-120 psi), overhaul the
                clutch.
            </para>
            <para>If the clutch engages quickly and freely with the external source but not on the vehicle's air system,
                install an in-line air pressure gauge on input line to the fan clutch. If opening and closing the
                solenoid does not indicate a quick rise to 90-120 psi and a quick loss of pressure, check for a pinched
                hose, then replace the solenoid valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rapid Wear of Fan Clutch and/or Fan Belts</title>
            <para>Check the engine RPM under load at full throttle in first gear. Compare against the engine
                specifications on the engine data plate. If the engine RPM exceeds engine specifications, the engine has
                been altered (turned up).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Altering the fuel system setting overloads the entire cooling system, including the fan
                        clutch.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12001j_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12001j_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12001j.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
