<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Green Diesel Retrofit - Installation Procedure</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Installation Procedure</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The UCM installation should be first physically mounted and second electrically connected. Care must
                be taken during installation. Flex on the main UCM over molded section will create faults and can damage
                the unit.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following UCM installation conditions must be met or the warranty may be voided.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The UCM must be mounted in a space where the ambient temperature is below 85&#176;C under
                        normal vehicle operation. The UCM must be located away from direct sources of heat such as the
                        engine, exhaust manifolds, or the radiator.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The UCM should be mounted in a location where it is not directly exposed to the elements or
                        electrical discharge.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The UCM must be connected to a 12 or 24 volt DC power supply.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The UCM must be connected to an unswitched and fused power supply.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The UCM must not be subjected to voltage supply or power surges greater than 30 volts DC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The pressure switch must be mounted in a position higher than the DPF inlet. This will reduce clogging
                of the pressure switch from water that collects in the tubing between the DPF and the pressure switch.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The power must be turned off in the vehicle or the batteries disconnected before installing
                        the UCM.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
