<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM - OPERATION - CONTINUOUS DEAERATION
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CONTINUOUS DEAERATION SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>When the cooling system is filled through the pressure cap fill tube, coolant enters the main cooling
                system through the make-up line, from the deaeration (surge) tank to the suction side of the water pump.
                Coolant then fills the radiator core and engine from the bottom upward, forcing air out the vent tubes.
                The vent tubes connect from the radiator core and the engine side of the thermostat housing to ports
                located above the coolant level in the tank.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine is running, there is a continuous small flow of coolant through the engine vent hose.
                Once the thermostat opens, there is also a small flow through the radiator vent hose. Any air in the
                coolant will separate when it reaches the reservoir and will eventually exit through the pressure cap.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Cap Removal</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the coolant should get extremely low and the engine gets very hot, let the engine cool for
                        approximately 15 minutes before adding coolant. Then add coolant with the engine running. Adding
                        cold coolant to a hot engine can crack the cylinder head or crankcase.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the pressure cap from the deaeration tank.
                        ALWAYS INSULATE the cap by wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent possible injury from scalding water or steam, DO NOT pull the pressure cap off
                        immediately when it has been loosened to the first "notch." Pause momentarily to allow time for
                        excess pressure to release through the overflow tube.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the pressure cap down, then slowly turn it counter-clockwise to loosen it to the
                    first "notch" position. PAUSE to observe the WARNING.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue to push down and turn the pressure cap counter-clockwise, then remove it. Keep
                    your face away from cap opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
