<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR-TO-AIR CHARGE AIR COOLER - AIR LEAK TEST - LEAK TEST
        (AIR PRESSURE APPLICATION)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LEAK TEST (AIR PRESSURE APPLICATION)</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect a filtered air supply to the quick disconnect fitting (Item 9) on the
                gauge-regulator assembly (Item 6).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open the air valve (Item 10) slightly, and increase the air pressure SLOWLY until the gauge
                (Item 11) reads 30 psi (205 kPa). Close the valve and monitor the gauge with a stop watch for 15
                seconds. Note any decrease in air pressure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent possible injury from the adapters blowing off during testing, increase air pressure
                        SLOWLY.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>After testing, relieve the pressure SLOWLY through the bleed valve before removing the test
                        equipment from the charge air cooler.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat the test at least three times to verify the results.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">THE CHARGE AIR COOLER PASSES if the pressure drop is 5 psi (34 kPa) or less in 15
                    seconds.
                </para>
                <para>If the charge air cooler passes, the test is complete. Bleed air from the system by depressing the
                    bleed-off valve (Item 12) on the bleed-off coupler (Item 8). Remove the air hose, gauge-regulator
                    assembly and both couplers. Connect the charge air hoses to the turbocharger exhaust piping and the
                    engine air intake piping. Tighten the hose clamps to the value in the
                    <hotlnk document="s12006_18.xml" xrefid="hl1200606">TORQUE CHART
                        <xref refid="hl1200606"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">THE CHARGE AIR COOLER FAILS if the pressure drop is more than 5 psi (34 kPa) in 15
                    seconds.
                </para>
                <para>Check for air leaks by using a pump spray bottle to apply a soapy solution to the hoses and the
                    charge air cooler hose connections and test equipment. No bubbles should appear.
                </para>
                <para>If the charge air cooler fails or any hoses fail, REPLACE the defective part. Assemble the charge
                    air cooler and hoses; tighten the hose clamps to the value found in the
                    <hotlnk document="s12006_18.xml" xrefid="hl1200606">TORQUE CHART
                        <xref refid="hl1200606"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Repeat the
                    <hotlnk document="s12006_13.xml" xrefid="hl1200605">AIR LEAK TEST
                        <xref refid="hl1200605"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12006_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12006_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
