<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RADIATOR SHUTTERS - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Automatic radiator shutters control ram air flow to the radiator by closing and opening rapidly in
                response to fluctuations in the coolant temperature. This effectively keeps the engine within the
                OPTIMUM TEMPERATURE RANGE.
            </para>
            <para>With the vehicle shut down, the shutter vanes are always open. When a cold engine is started, the
                shutter vanes close to block ram air flow so the engine will heat up rapidly. When the coolant has
                heated to the high temperature limit, the sensor on the shutter control (solenoid) valve closes (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1200503">Figure 3</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1200504">Figure 4</hotlnk>). This cuts off the (air or hydraulic) pressure to the
                shutter control cylinder, and the shutter vanes open.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1200503" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1200503" filename="../figg12/G1200503.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Typical Air Shutter Controls</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AIR CYLINDER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1200504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1200504" filename="../figg12/G1200504.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Typical Hydraulic Shutter Controls</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC CONTROL CYLINDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CONTROL ROD ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HYDRAULIC CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>With the vanes open, ram air flows through the radiator and around the engine, lowering the coolant
                temperature. The shutter vanes close when the low temperature limit is reached. The cycle repeats as
                frequently as necessary to keep the engine within the correct temperature range.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If more air flow (cooling effect) is needed than open shutter vanes provide, the fan clutch or
                        viscous fan drive engages. When the low temperature limit is reached, the fan operation stops
                        before the vanes close. This cycle also repeats as needed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12005_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12005_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
