<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - VISCOUS FAN DRIVES - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>The fan drive operates on the viscous fluid shear principle. The drive is attached to the engine jackshaft
            or water pump. The input and output ends are coupled by silicone fluid, which must be driven at a certain
            speed before it will turn the fan blades.
        </para>
        <para>Fan speed is controlled by the amount of coupling between the input and output shafts. When the fan drive
            is disengaged, fluid is evacuated from the drive chamber into a storage reservoir. This condition provides
            minimum coupling and minimum or reduced fan speed. When the fan drive is engaged, a valve is opened allowing
            fluid into the drive chamber. This condition provides maximum coupling and maximum fan speed. Valve opening
            and closing is controlled by the bi-metal disk on bi-metal drives. On solenoid-activated drives a solenoid
            on the front of the fan drive unit controls valve opening and closing.
        </para>
        <para>With the viscous fan drive engaged, as the input r.p.m. increases, the difference between input speed and
            output speed ("slip") becomes greater until a predetermined peak speed is reached. At peak speed, fluid
            shear prevents the fan from turning faster regardless of further increases in input speed.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
