<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s12003r" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5071R" revno="R" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL</title>
                    <para>The purpose of the cooling system is to circulate the coolant, maintain efficient operating
                        temperature and protect system components. About one-third of the energy produced when diesel
                        fuel burns is converted into power by the engine. The remaining energy must be disposed of by
                        the exhaust and cooling systems, or the engine components will be damaged by excessive heat and
                        contamination. The cooling system's main components are:
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>COOLANT</title>
                    <para>The required coolant is a mixture of antifreeze and coolant conditioner (inhibitor or
                        additive) with water. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s12003r_26.xml" xrefid="hl1200301">COOLANT
                            <xref refid="hl1200301"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        , for recommended antifreeze and conditioner properties and concentration levels.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>RADIATOR</title>
                    <para>The radiator is the main component for cooling system heat dissipation. It is constructed of
                        tubes to circulate the coolant, and fins to disperse excess heat. International uses two basic
                        radiator configurations: Vertical Down Flow (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200301">Figure 1</hotlnk>) and Horizontal Cross Flow (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200302">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s12003r_3.xml" xrefid="hl1200302">RADIATOR
                            <xref refid="hl1200302"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1200301" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200301" filename="../figg12/g1200301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Vertical Flow Radiator</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. ENGINE</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. UPPER TANK</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. RADIATOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. LOWER TANK</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f1200302" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200302" filename="../figg12/g1200302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Horizontal Flow Radiator</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. LEFT TANK WITH INLET</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. RADIATOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. RIGHT TANK WITH OUTLET</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. ENGINE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WATER PUMP</title>
                    <para>The purpose of the water pump is to circulate coolant through the water jackets of the engine
                        block and cylinder head(s), where the coolant accumulates engine heat.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>THERMOSTAT</title>
                    <para>The flow of coolant is controlled by the thermostat, which restricts coolant (water) flow
                        through the radiator during engine warm-up, and prevents overheating that can cause coolant loss
                        and engine damage.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ENGINE FAN</title>
                    <para>The fan pulls air around the radiator tubes to transfer heat from the coolant and decrease
                        coolant temperature. International uses two types of engine cooling fan drives, viscous and
                        on/off.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Viscous Fan drive</title>
                        <para>The viscous fan drive is standard equipment on International medium-duty vehicles. It
                            works by sensing air temperatures behind the radiator. A bi-metal spring in the fan drive
                            assembly responds to the temperature, engaging the clutch when it is sufficiently hot, and
                            disengaging the clutch when the temperature has lowered.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>On/Off Fan Drive</title>
                        <para>The on/off fan drive is standard on International heavy-duty vehicles. It works by means
                            of a temperature switch that senses coolant temperatures to regulate an air solenoid. The
                            solenoid directs compressed air and engages the fan clutch friction drive when the coolant
                            is hot. When the coolant temperature has lowered, a spring disengages the clutch.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>CONTINUOUS DEAERATION SYSTEM</title>
                    <para>The continuous deaeration (air removal) system is made up of a remote-mounted deaeration
                        (surge) tank, or reservoir, with external vent hoses from the radiator and engine, and a make-up
                        line to the water pump (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200303">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1200303" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200303" filename="../figg12/g1200303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. Continuous Deaeration System</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. DEAERATION (SURGE) TANK</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. ENGINE VENT HOSE</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. RADIATOR VENT HOSE</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. RADIATOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. WATER PUMP</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. ENGINE</callout1>
                            <callout1>7. MAKE-UP LINE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The main function of the continuous deaeration system is to continuously keep the cooling
                        system free of trapped air. The deaeration tank removes air from the engine when it is cold and
                        when the thermostat is closed. When the engine reaches operating temperature and the thermostat
                        opens, air is also removed from the radiator.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>PRESSURE CAP</title>
                    <para>The pressure cap is constructed with a spring-loaded valve that seats below the overflow pipe
                        in the filler neck to prevent escape of air or coolant while the cap is in the lock-down
                        position. When pressure rises to a predetermined point, the cap valve opens; when the pressure
                        drops below this point, the cap valve closes (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1200304">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1200304" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1200304" filename="../figg12/g1200304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4. Pressure Cap</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. FILLER NECK</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. VACUUM INLET ROUTE</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. PRESSURE RELEASE ROUTE</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. OVERFLOW TUBE</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. COOLANT RESERVOIR</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. VENT TUBE</callout1>
                            <callout1>7. COOLANT LEVEL</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>TRANSMISSION OIL COOLER</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Automatic Transmission</title>
                        <para>On vehicles with automatic transmissions, transmission oil is cooled by circulating it
                            through a water-to-oil cooler (heat exchanger) that is located in the bottom radiator tank,
                            or between the radiator and water pump.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Manual Transmission</title>
                        <para>Some International vehicles with manual transmissions use an air-to-oil cooling unit that
                            may be located in front of the radiator, or inside the fan shroud.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
