<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ENGINE COOLING SYSTEM - MAINTENANCE - SYSTEMS WITH COOLANT
        FILTERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SYSTEMS WITH COOLANT FILTERS</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>The coolant filter on a new vehicle is equipped with a normal service element. The factory fill
                    coolant contains a pre-charge of supplemental coolant additives. In combination with the service
                    element, this provides full protection for the new engine.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Too frequent replacement of the filter element can cause silica-gel to form in the cooling system.
                    This shows as slick gel, or when dry, as white, powdery residue on heat transfer surfaces.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Use a normal service filter element to replace the element after the first 12,000 miles (19,000 km). Make
            subsequent replacements at 10,000 to 12,000 miles (16,000 to 19,000 km) intervals, or as recommended in
            GROUP 12-ENGINE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual to maintain the required concentration. Change coolant
            filters if the engine coolant is changed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use coolant filters only with ethylene glycol antifreezes that do not contain anti-leak
                    ("stop-leak") additives. The coolant filter element removes anti-leak additives, which can then
                    restrict coolant flow from the filter. Do not use methanol or methoxy propanol (DowTherm 209) -based
                    antifreeze, because it is not compatible with the treated service element.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When changing from older-style borate and chromate water filters, thoroughly drain, then
                    chemically flush the cooling system with inhibited hydrochloric acid or inhibited oxalic acid. Then
                    neutralize the cooling system before using the new-style filters.
                </para>
                <para>Failure to do this prior to using new-style filters can cause plugged radiator and heater cores,
                    and solder deterioration, because the new-style water filters can loosen cooling system scale.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s12003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
