<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 00907 - Allison Transmission Upshifting Complaints in International 1652, 3400, 3800, and 4700 Models
        with T 444E Engine Codes 12NNA, 12NNB, 12NNC, 12NND, 12NNE, 12NNH, 12NNJ, and 12NNK Built Between August 1, 2000
        and August 7, 2000
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc00907">
        <afcnum>00907</afcnum>
        <afcdate>November, 2000</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Allison Transmission Upshifting Complaints in International 1652, 3400, 3800, and 4700 Models with T
            444E Engine Codes 12NNA, 12NNB, 12NNC, 12NND, 12NNE, 12NNH, 12NNJ, and 12NNK Built Between August 1, 2000
            and August 7, 2000
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1652
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/07/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/07/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/07/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/01/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/07/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The vehicles described above may exhibit poor transmission upshifting. To correct this issue, the
                    engine ECM must be re-programmed.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When performing the service procedure in this AFC letter, you must click on the box marked
                        "Check if replacing module on the vehicle" to insure that the latest information is available
                        for your vehicle.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>To perform this procedure, the EZ-Tech service tool must be used. The ECM cannot be
                        re-programmed without the EZ-Tech service tool. To acquire this tool, contact Mr. Joe Hamilton
                        at International Truck and Engine Corporation phone number 630-691-5428.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Record the
                        <emph type="bold">Customer Parameters</emph>
                        before programming the ECM. The
                        <emph type="bold">Customer Parameters</emph>
                        may change after the ECM is re-programmed and may need to be changed back to the settings the
                        vehicle had when it arrived in the shop.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Re-program the ECM using the EZ-Tech service tool and NETS 2.0 software. Follow the instructions
                attached to this letter.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Starting the NETS/AFC Software</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the Vehicle Diagnostics folder on desktop and select Navistar NETS (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0090701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0090701" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Open Vehicle Diagnostics Folder</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The following window appears when the Navistar Nets icon is selected (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0090702">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Notice that two different services are available with
                    NETS, each one of the options can be selected by clicking on the appropriate button.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For AFC 00-907 you MUST use the Navistar NETS side to process the information.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0090702" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. This Window Appears When Navistar NETS Icon is Selected</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If only NETS is required, click on "Navistar NETS". Notice that when NETS is selected a
                    Navistar NETS window appears (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0090703">Figure 3</hotlnk>). If an AFC window appears instead you are not in the
                    window for normal programming, you must then go back to the main screen and select the "Navistar
                    NETS" button. Make sure you are doing the process that you want. If you do service using NETS, any
                    AFC changes will automatically be applied during this process; so you do not have to do an extra
                    process.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0090703" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090703.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Navistar NETS Window</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Navistar NETS includes 4 steps:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">GET:</emph>
                        Retrieves the data from the truck. This stage takes place at the truck with no need to have a
                        phone line available.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">SEND:</emph>
                        During this step the data retrieved from the truck is sent via modem to Navistar. In order to
                        perform this operation you must be connected to your phone or DCN II line so data can be
                        transmitted. There is no need to be connected to the truck during this process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">RECEIVE:</emph>
                        Once the files containing the truck and engine data have been transmitted to Navistar the system
                        will update the information for the latest calibration. During the RECEIVE step, these files
                        containing the new information are electronically transmitted back to the EZ-Tech.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">PROGRAM:</emph>
                        The last step takes place back at the truck where the files containing the new engine or truck
                        data are transmitted back to the engine ECM. Same as the GET process this stage takes place at
                        the truck with no need to have a phone line available.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="18">
            <title>Reprogramming an ECM Using NETS</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>On vehicles equipped with Allison electronic transmissions, and ABS brakes,
                            <emph type="bold">all of the ECUs MUST BE DISCONNECTED</emph>
                            prior to beginning any reprogramming operation using NETS or Navistar AFC. Please refer to
                            the "Table of Contents" for details on how to disconnect the transmission.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>For the reprogramming operation to be successful the instructions provided on the screen
                            and this manual must be strictly followed at all times. Always verify that all connections
                            are solid and make sure that the key is in the right position according to the instructions.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Make sure that the right COM port is selected when performing the GET and the
                        PROGRAM steps. Refer to CONNECTING THE EZ TECH TO THE VEHICLE in the Table of Contents
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Step 1 GET</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the "Get Data" button to start the GET process, the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090704">following window</hotlnk>
                        will appear:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090704" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090704.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Start the GET Process</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter the eight-digit VIN number.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the box marked (Check if replacing module on the vehicle)</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Enter the correct Mileage, Hours, and Fuel used.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the OK button.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click
                        <emph type="bold">Get Data</emph>
                        and the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090705">following window</hotlnk>
                        appears:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090705" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090705.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Get Data Window</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090706">ignition key is in the ON position</hotlnk>
                        and click OK:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090706" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090706.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Turn Key Off and Then Back On</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the key off and then back on. Even if the ignition key was ON prior to this
                        step, IT MUST BE TURNED OFF AND BACK ON. Once you have done this click OK.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090707">next window appears</hotlnk>; it reads data from the ECM module.
                        Please Wait.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090707" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090707.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Get Parameters Window</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the message "Engine controller is not responding" appears on the screen, make sure
                            cable is in correct COM port, that the power is ON, and all electronic auxiliary equipment
                            is disconnected. After verifying this try again.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090708">following screen</hotlnk>
                        is then obtained: Click OK to complete the GET process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090708" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090708.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Data Transfer Success Screen</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the close button.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Step 2 SEND</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">In order to perform this step you MUST have the following:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>A dedicated Phone line or DCN II network connection</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The modem card must be installed to the EZ-Tech. If the modem card is not installed
                                the computer must be shut off before the card can be installed.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The Modem adapter must be connected to the modem card and the phone line. There is no
                                need to be connected to the truck to perform the SEND process.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Also make sure that you have a user ID (DYYxxxx) and a valid password so you can
                                access the Navistar DCN II.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the "Send Data" button to start the SEND process, the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090709">following window</hotlnk>
                        will appear:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090709" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090709.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Send Data Screen</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the desired chassis or Select All. Then click "Send Data". You can also select
                        multiple VINs by holding the "Ctrl" key while clicking on the desired ones. Once you click on
                        the "SEND DATA" button the EZ-Tech will initiate the connection with Navistar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select modem (phone) or Direct DCN II network connection. If using phone, make sure
                        that your cable and lines are connected to modem. Type your login user id for DCN II NET'S
                        (Navistar System 21 Support Group Supplied) and hit the ENTER key.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once connected the EZ-tech will start sending the selected file(s) to Navistar. The
                        EZ-Tech will send one file per VIN selected and will display a message indicating the number of
                        files that were successfully sent (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090710">Figure 10</hotlnk>). Please verify that the number of files
                        successfully sent matches the amount of VINs previously selected. Click OK and then close the
                        "Send data" window to continue with the process. LEAVE THE EZ-TECH CONNECTED TO NAVISTAR if you
                        are replacing an Engine Module.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090710" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090710.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. File Sent Successfully Screen</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">For this process the system will automatically process the parameters and in about
                        5 to 10 minutes you can do the Receive Process
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Step 3 RECEIVE</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the "Receive" button at the main NETS window to start the RECEIVE process,
                        the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090711">following window</hotlnk>
                        will appear:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090711" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090711.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Start the RECEIVE Process</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the desired chassis or Select All. Then click "Receive". You can also select
                        multiple VINs by holding the "Ctrl" key while clicking on the desired ones. Once you click on
                        the "RECEIVE" button the EZ-Tech will initiate the transmission of files back to the EZ-Tech.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>You can only select the VINs that you last SENT to Navistar. Only these will be Received.
                            If you request to receive a chassis that was not Sent originally, the EZ-Tech will display a
                            message saying that the data for this chassis was not found.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The transmission of the files will start as soon as the RECEIVE button is
                        selected.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If you are still connected to the network the program will not request you to connect
                            again, however if the connection is not present, you will be requested to repeat the
                            connection steps described on the SEND instructions.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The screen will display the number of successfully received files. Two files will be
                        received for each received VIN. Due to different file sizes, some files might take longer than
                        others to transmit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click the OK and select the Close button on the Receive window to complete the
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Step 4 PROGRAM</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Back at the vehicle, use the cigarette lighter power adapter or your 120 volt power
                        supply for power during programming, connect the EZ-Tech to the ATA connector and assure the
                        appropriate COM port is selected.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the ignition Key ON.
                        <emph type="bold">Remember to carefully follow the Key ON / Key OFF directions since this is
                            very critical for a successful programming.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the "Program" button at the main NETS window to start the Programming
                        process, the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090712">following window</hotlnk>
                        will appear:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090712" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090712.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Start the PROGRAM Process</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the desired VIN from the list and click on the PROGRAM button. A
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090713">message will be displayed</hotlnk>
                        asking you to confirm the VIN.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090713" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090713.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Confirm VIN Screen</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Please verify that the VIN to be programmed matches the vehicle and click the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090714">"YES" button</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090714" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090714.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Program Engine Screen</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Read the instructions and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090715">click Next</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090715" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090715.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Program Engine Instructions</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Make sure that the ignition key is turned ON</emph>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090716">click Next</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090716" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090716.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. More Program Engine Instructions</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">REMEMBER:</emph>
                    on vehicles equipped with Allison electronic transmissions, and ABS brakes,
                    <emph type="bold">all of the ECUs MUST BE DISCONNECTED</emph>
                    prior to beginning any reprogramming operation using NETS or Navistar AFC. Please refer to the
                    "Table of Contents" for details on how to disconnect the transmission.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>For the reprogramming operation to be successful the instructions provided on the screen
                            and this manual must be strictly followed at all times. Always verify that all connections
                            are solid and make sure that the key is in the right position according to the instructions.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Verify that the EZ-Tech is connected to the truck through the appropriate COM
                            port and the ignition key is in the ON position
                        </emph>
                        and click Next. This action will initiate the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090717">first stage on the programming</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090717" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090717.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. First Stage on the Programming</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT WALK AWAY FROM VEHICLE DURING NEXT STEP</emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">During this stage of programming the EZ-Tech will program all the parameters and
                        calibrations into the ECM. This process will take approximately 10 minutes.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After completing the step one of programming you will get a
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090718">message</hotlnk>
                        indicating that the ignition key must be turned OFF and then back ON.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IT IS VERY IMPORTANT FOR THE INTEGRITY OF THE PROCESS THAT THE KEY IS TURNED OFF
                        AND THEN BACK ON. NOT PERFORMING THIS STEP WILL INDUCE A PROGRAMMING FAILURE TO THE MODULE.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <figure id="f0090718" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090718.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18. Turn Key Off and Back On</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Turn the ignition key OFF (leave OFF for 3 seconds) and then back ON</emph>
                        before you click on the Next button.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090719" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090719.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19. Second Stage of Programming</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once you click on the Next button, the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090719">second stage</hotlnk>
                        of programming will take place. This stage is much faster than the first one, it only lasts a
                        few seconds. After this second step is completed you will get a message stating "
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090720">Engine Programming Completed Successfully</hotlnk>"
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090720" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090720.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Engine Programming Completed Successfully</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click OK once you get this message. This will prompt a second message stating,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0090721">Engine programming was successful</hotlnk>. At this point you must
                        turn the key OFF so the program can be stored on the module.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IT IS VERY CRITICAL THAT YOU TURN KEY OFF AT THIS TIME. NOT PERFORMING THIS STEP
                        WILL INDUCE A PROGRAMMING FAILURE TO THE MODULE.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After turning the key OFF you can click on the Finish button and then click Close on
                        the program window.
                        <emph type="bold">Programming is complete. Nice Job !</emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0090721" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0090721.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21. Engine Programming Was Successful</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t0090701">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.01in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-00907-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Re-program ECM (International Single Box Controller)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.7 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-00907.
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-00907 activity must
                be submitted by November 30, 2001 or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after
                November 30, 2001.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="300"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
