<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 01911R - Re-Programming the Cab Electrical System Controller (ESC) to Prevent the Air Conditioning
        Compressor from Latching Out Under Certain Conditions on 4300 and 4400 Models Built Before July 19, 2001
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc01911">
        <afcnum>01911R</afcnum>
        <afcdate>October, 2001</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subject>Re-Programming the Cab Electrical System Controller (ESC) to Prevent the Air Conditioning Compressor
            from Latching Out Under Certain Conditions on 4300 and 4400 Models Built Before July 19, 2001
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/19/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/19/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>0016WKA</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../afcs/AFC01911.pdf" bookname="AFC">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the AFC
                        letter
                    </exhotlnk>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">SPECIAL NOTES: THIS AFC CAMPAIGN HAS BEEN REPLACED!</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>AFC 01911 has been canceled and replaced by Safety Recall 01514 because the software used
                            to reprogram for 01514 includes the fix for 01911.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Safety Recall 01514 is a reprogramming campaign for the ESC and includes ALL the vehicles
                            that are in campaign 01911.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Campaigns 01514 and AFC 01911 will be completed with software versions 13 or higher for
                            Infineon based ESC's or version 105 or higher for Hitachi based ESC's.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Destroy all copies of the CD's provided for 01911 because they are outdated.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>VIN records for customers that did not have the ESC reprogrammed for 01911 were unmarked
                            for 01911 and AFC 01911 was replaced by Safety Recall 01514.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicles reprogrammed in 01911 prior to version 13/ 105 must be reprogrammed under Safety
                            Recall 01514.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>All original copies of letter G-01911 at your DEALERSHIP
                            <emph type="bold">MUST HAVE THE FOLLOWING NOTE WRITTEN ON THE FIRST PAGE:</emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: WARRANTY CLAIMS WILL NOT BE APPROVED FOR 01911 AFTER OCTOBER 10,
                                2001. THIS AFC HAS BEEN REPLACED BY SAFETY RECALL 01514.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>This letter will also replace letter G-01911 on ISIS.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refer to G-01514 to reprogram all vehicles originally in AFC 01911.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>G-01514 instructs dealers to reprogram all involved vehicles due to the possibility of a
                            software fusing condition that can cause headlight failure, see G-01514.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>The program installed in the Electrical System Controller (ESC) prior to July 19, 2001 may cause
                    the air conditioning compressor to latch out under certain conditions. Diagnostic Fault Code
                    613-14-1-11 will be present when this condition occurs. This problem will be fixed when the ESC is
                    reprogrammed for Safety Recall 01514.
                </para>
                <para>AFC 01911 involved all 4300 and 4400 models built before July 19, 2001. The new Safety Recall
                    01514 includes the same models and all of 01911 population, but expands the build date range to
                    include vehicles built from 10/24/00 through 9/19/01.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </afc>
</isis>
