<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 02902 - New Design Surge Tank Cap for 7300, 7400 and 7500 Models Built Between May 28, 2001 and March
        19, 2002 with Dual De-Aeration Tanks in the Engine Cooling System
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc02902">
        <afcnum>02902</afcnum>
        <afcdate>June, 2002</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>New Design Surge Tank Cap for 7300, 7400 and 7500 Models Built Between May 28, 2001 and March 19, 2002
            with Dual De-Aeration Tanks in the Engine Cooling System
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/28/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/19/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/28/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/19/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>05/28/2001</startdate>
                        <enddate>03/19/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../afcs/AFC02902.pdf" bookname="AFC">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the AFC
                        letter
                    </exhotlnk>
                </para>
                <para>The engine cooling system in 7300, 7400, 7500 Models has a de-aeration system comprised of a surge
                    tank and an overflow tank. The surge tank cap used on these Models, built between May 28, 2001 and
                    March 19, 2002, will allow coolant to flow from the surge tank to the overflow tank but not return
                    to the surge tank as the system cools, leading to the possibility of low coolant levels and/or
                    engine overheating condition.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>New design surge tank cap, Part Number 130704C1, will be shipped directly to customers with 7300,
                7400, 7500 Models built between May 28, 2001 and March 19, 2002. Dealers with inventory vehicles will
                receive surge tank caps for their vehicles. Dealers that receive surge tank caps for vehicles that have
                already been sold are to forward the caps to the new owners.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent property damage and/or personal injury, park the vehicle on a level surface, set
                        the parking brake, chock the wheels, turn the engine off and place the ignition in the off
                        position.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify the surge tank cap is the old design. If the cap matches Figure 1, it is the new
                    design and should not be replaced. If the cap does not match Figure 1, it must be replaced. Proceed
                    to Step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f029021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g029021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. New Design Surge Tank Cap</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the surge tank cap. Always insulate the cap by
                        wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth, to prevent possible injury from scalding coolant or
                        steam. Do not pull the cap off immediately when it has been loosened to the first notch. Pause
                        momentarily to allow time for excess pressure to release through the overflow tube.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the surge tank cap, discard and replace with the new cap.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>
                <title>LABOR INFORMATION</title>
            </para>
            <para>To minimize inconvenience to the customers and dealers the surge tank caps will be sent directly to
                the owners; therefore, no labor operation has been set-up and no warranty claims need to be filed.
            </para>
        </laborinfo>
    </afc>
</isis>
