<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 03903 - Allison Transmission Upshifting Complaints in International 4300 and 4400 Models with DT 466
        Engines Built in Escobedo Between July 25, 2002 and November 22, 2002
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc03903">
        <afcnum>03903</afcnum>
        <afcdate>April, 2003</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subject>Allison Transmission Upshifting Complaints in International 4300 and 4400 Models with DT 466 Engines
            Built in Escobedo Between July 25, 2002 and November 22, 2002
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/25/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/22/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/25/2002</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/22/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../afcs/AFC03903.pdf" bookname="AFC">Print ready (PDF file) copy of the AFC
                        letter
                    </exhotlnk>
                </para>
                <para>The vehicles described above may exhibit poor transmission upshifting. To correct this issue, the
                    engine ECM must be re-programmed.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When performing the service procedure in this AFC letter, you must click on the box marked
                        "Check if replacing module on the vehicle" to insure that the latest information is available
                        for your vehicle.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>To perform this procedure, the EZ-Tech service tool must be used. The ECM cannot be
                        re-programmed without the EZ-Tech service tool. To acquire this tool, contact Mr. Eric Brown at
                        International Truck and Engine Corporation phone number 260-461-1894.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Record the
                        <emph type="bold">Customer Parameters</emph>
                        before programming the ECM. The
                        <emph type="bold">Customer Parameters</emph>
                        may change after the ECM is re-programmed and may need to be changed back to the settings the
                        vehicle had when it arrived in the shop.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Re-program the ECM using the EZ-Tech service tool and NETS 3.1 software. Follow the instructions
                attached to this letter.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>NETS 3.3 software can also be used.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Starting the NETS Software</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the EZ Tech is started, you should see the screen below. With Engine Diagnostics
                    selected, choose the
                    <emph type="bold">International NETS</emph>
                    button. If you don't see the International Main Screen, click on the
                    <emph type="bold">International Diagnostics</emph>
                    shortcut as shown below.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0390301" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0390302" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The following window appears. Click
                    <emph type="bold">OK</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0390303" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The main NETS screen will appear.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0390304" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Just like the previous versions of NETS, the Navistar NETS 3.1 includes 4 steps:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">GET:</emph>
                        Retrieves the data from the truck, saves it to the EZ Tech and passes it to Tech Service. This
                        stage takes place at the truck with no need to have a phone line available.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">SEND:</emph>
                        During this step the data retrieved from the truck is sent via modem/network to International.
                        In order to perform this operation you must be connected to your phone or DCN II line so data
                        can be transmitted. There is no need to be connected to the truck during this process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">RECEIVE:</emph>
                        Once the files containing the truck and engine data have been transmitted to International and
                        processed, the system will update the information for the latest changes in parameters. During
                        the RECEIVE step, these files containing the new information are electronically transmitted back
                        to the EZ-Tech.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">PROGRAM:</emph>
                        The last step takes place back at the truck where the files containing the new engine or truck
                        data are transmitted back to the engine ECM. Same as the GET process this stage takes place at
                        the truck with no need to have a phone line available.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="program">
            <title>Programming (or Reprogramming) an ECM or VPM</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>On vehicles equipped with Allison MD electronic transmissions and ABS Brakes,
                            <emph type="boldundersc">the ECU's MUST BE DISCONNECTED</emph>
                            prior to beginning the GET process or any programming/reprogramming operation using NETS.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>For programming and reprogramming operation to be successful the instructions provided on
                            the screen and this manual must be strictly followed at all times. Always verify that all
                            connections are solid and make sure that the key is in the right position according to the
                            instructions.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>GET Operation</title>
                <para>The first step in using Navistar NETS is to get data from the truck. When the cables are properly
                    connected to the truck, the user can click on Get Data. This will bring up a screen where the user
                    can enter the 8-digit chassis number of the truck. This number must be used in order to properly
                    identify the vehicle to Tech Service. It is important that the user enter the proper chassis number.
                    The chassis number is the last 8 positions of the truck's VIN number.
                </para>
                <para>When the user clicks Get Data, data will be taken from the truck and put into the laptop. This
                    process should take less than one minute. This procedure must be completed successfully for any
                    further steps to work. This step must be completed even if there is a brand new blank module in the
                    truck. This is because the database will need to know the module serial number for future servicing.
                    If the module, for some reason, has a different Chassis number than the truck, enter in the truck's
                    chassis number. The program will then prompt you saying that the chassis number entered does not
                    match the one on the module. Verify correct chassis is entered, and click OK. When the module gets
                    reprogrammed, it will then report the correct chassis number in the future.
                </para>
                <para>It is possible that some errors could occur during the get process. Most of these problems can be
                    solved by checking a few important things:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Prior to selecting Get Data, is the truck key on?</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Is the truck-computer interface cable securely attached to both the truck and to the
                            computer?
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Is the interface cable attached to the communications port on the back of the computer?
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Is the correct cable being used?</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Are the ABS and transmission unplugged?</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the ignition key is
                        <emph type="bold">ON</emph>.
                    </para>
                    <para>Click on the
                        <emph type="bold">Get Data</emph>
                        button to start the GET process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390305" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The window below will appear.</para>
                    <para>Enter the last 8 digits of the VIN number.</para>
                    <para>Check VPM/ECM for all vehicles except those equipped with the VT-365. Check ECM2/IDM2 for
                        VT-365 equipped vehicles.
                    </para>
                    <para>Click
                        <emph type="bold">Get Data</emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When replacing a module on vehicle, it is mandatory to enter mileage. If the checkbox for
                            replacing module is checked, a place to enter mileage will appear (along with gallons and
                            hours).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0390306" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Read the note and click
                        <emph type="bold">Yes</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390307" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the ignition key off and back on and then click
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390308" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390308.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Navistar NETS then reads data from the ECM module.</para>
                    <para>Please Wait...</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the message "Engine controller is not responding" appears on the screen, the power is
                            ON and all electronic auxiliary equipment is disconnected. After verifying this try again.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0390309" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390309.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once the data has been retrieved from the ECM the following message will appear:
                        Verify the VIN number and click
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                        to complete the GET process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390310" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390310.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>SEND Operation</title>
                <para>In this step, data is transferred from the local computer (EZ-Tech), to the computers at Tech
                    Service. If you are installing a new module, Tech Service does not need to do anything with the
                    files. The files will automatically be processed and sent back within 15 minutes. If you are making
                    changes, you should FAX (260-461-1820) the program request form found on ISIS (a copy of the form is
                    included at the end of this manual) with the requested programming changes. Send this form after
                    sending the data.
                </para>
                <para>From the send screen, you can send information, one chassis number at a time. However, you can do
                    as many chassis numbers as you want in one session. NETS is a network application, it needs to be
                    connected to the International network in order to communicate properly with Tech Service either
                    directly (DCN-II), or through a modem/network connection. After you have connected to the network,
                    you can choose the Chassis number to send. This file will then be sent to the Tech Service
                    computers. This transmission can take anywhere from a couple of seconds (if on DCN-II) to several
                    minutes (if using a modem/network). Once the file is successfully sent, Tech Service can begin
                    processing the data.
                </para>
                <para>If any errors occur during the transmission, try again. Occasionally phone lines can have trouble,
                    so it may take more than one try to send the file. There is no harm in sending the same data more
                    than once if Tech Service has not started service programming. If Tech Service has started
                    processing, resending the file will clear out any work they have done up to this point. Check with
                    Tech Service before resending data. If a file is sent more than once, only the most recently sent
                    file will be used by Tech Service.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">To perform the SEND operation:</emph>
                </para>
                <para>In order to perform this step you MUST have the following:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>A dedicated Phone line or DCN II network connection.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The modem/network card must be installed to the EZ-Tech. If the modem/network card is not
                            installed the computer must be shut off before the card can be installed. You will not lose
                            data from the GET operation.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The Modem/network adapter must be connected to the modem/network card and the phone line.
                            There is no need to be connected to the truck to perform the SEND process.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If using a phone connection, make sure that you have an user ID (DYYXXXX) and a valid
                            password so you can access the International DCN II.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the
                        <emph type="bold">Send Data</emph>
                        button to start the SEND process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390311" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The window below will appear:</para>
                    <para>Click the desired chassis or Select All. Then click
                        <emph type="bold">Send</emph>. You can also select multiple VINs by holding the "Ctrl" key while
                        clicking on the desired ones. Once you click on the Send Data button the EZ-Tech will initiate
                        the connection with International.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390312" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0390313" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The following window asks you to select modem/network (phone) or Direct DCN II
                        network connection. If using phone, make sure that your cable and lines are connected to
                        modem/network. Click desired setting and then click Connect.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If connecting using a phone line, clicking on the connect button the program will initiate
                            a Password Entry screen as shown. Enter User ID and Password. Otherwise the process is the
                            same as using DCN II.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0390314" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390314.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0390315" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390315.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Wait while SEND is in progress.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390316" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390316.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Once connected the EZ-tech will start sending the selected file(s) to International.
                        The EZ-Tech will send one file per VIN selected and will display a message indicating the number
                        of files that were successfully sent. Please verify that the number of files successfully sent
                        matches the amount of VINs previously selected. Click
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                        and then close the "Send data" window to continue with the process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390317" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390317.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="192px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>RECEIVE Operation</title>
                <para>If checked as a new module, you can receive the file back in approximately 15 minutes. If not,
                    after Tech Service receives your FAX with the parameters you wish to change, they will make the
                    corrections and call you and let you know there is data ready to be received. As with the send
                    portion of NETS, this receive portion will only work properly if connected to the International
                    network. Once connected to the network, select a chassis number and click Receive Data. The receive
                    process will take varying amounts of time, depending on the network connection.
                </para>
                <para>After you have completed the SEND process the EZ-Tech can remain connected to International. If
                    you are replacing a module the program will take approximately 15 minutes. Navistar NETS 3.1 allows
                    you to initiate the RECEIVE process without having to talk to Tech Service.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the
                        <emph type="bold">Receive</emph>
                        button at the main NETS 3.1 window to start the RECEIVE process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390318" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The window below will appear:</para>
                    <para>Click the desired chassis or Select All. Then click
                        <emph type="bold">Receive</emph>. You can also select multiple VINs by holding the "Ctrl" key
                        while clicking on the desired ones. Once you click on the RECEIVE button the EZ-Tech will
                        initiate the transmission of files back to the EZ-Tech.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390319" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390319.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Wait while Receive is in progress. The following screens will appear.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390320" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390320.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="112px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0390321" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390321.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="112px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21.</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>You can only select the VINs that you last Sent to International. Only these will be
                            Received. If you request to receive a chassis that was not Sent originally, the EZ-Tech will
                            display a message saying that the data for this chassis was not ready.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The transmission of the files will start as soon as the RECEIVE button is selected. The following
                    screens will be observed then.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If you are still connected to the network the program will not request you to connect
                            again, however if the connection is not present, you will be requested to repeat the
                            connection steps described on the SEND instructions.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0390322" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390321.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="112px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0390323" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390323.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="112px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The screen will display the number of successfully received files. 2 files will be
                        received for each received VIN (ECM, 1 file for VPM) if done automatically. If not, there will
                        be one file for the parameter change. Due to different file sizes, some files might take longer
                        that others to transmit. Once the files have been received successfully, the following screen
                        appears:
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390324" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390324.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Click
                    <emph type="bold">YES</emph>
                    to go to PROGRAM or
                    <emph type="bold">NO</emph>
                    to return to the Main Screen
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>PROGRAM Operation</title>
                <para>When the received data file(s) have been loaded onto the laptop, the user can then go and program
                    the truck. The program part of Navistar Nets consists of several steps. First, the user must press
                    program and then select which chassis number is on the truck to be programmed. Since it is important
                    that the proper data is sent to the proper truck, the user will be asked to confirm that the proper
                    chassis number is selected. Next, the program will walk the user through the steps of programming
                    the truck. Sometimes there will be a one-step programming process (parameters only), while other
                    times there will be a two-step programming process (includes strategy/calibration). This process can
                    take a long time. If strategies/calibration needs to be done, the programming process can take as
                    long as 8 minutes.
                </para>
                <para>It is very important that this process is not interrupted!! If this process is stopped in the
                    middle for any reason, (cable came loose, truck was keyed off, computer was turned off) it may be
                    necessary to start the entire programming process again, starting with getting data from the truck.
                    You can try to do programming again, and it may work if the programming process has not gotten far
                    enough at the point of failure. If the message "The TP password does not match" or "proprietary
                    password" comes up, then it will be necessary to completely restart the programming process from the
                    'Get' step.
                </para>
                <para>After programming is completed, it is necessary to key the truck off. The data will not be saved
                    properly to the module if the key is left on. If another Get is done before the key is turned off,
                    the programmed data will not be stored on the module. Once programming is successfully completed,
                    NETS will automatically delete all of the NETS data files for the truck that was just programmed.
                    These files are not needed anymore. To reprogram the same module again, new data would have to be
                    taken from the truck and sent to Tech Service.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Perform the PROGRAM operation</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Back at the vehicle, connect the EZ-Tech to the ATA connector.</para>
                <para>Turn the ignition Key ON.
                    <emph type="bold">Remember to carefully follow the Key ON / Key OFF directions since this is very
                        critical for a successful programming. DO NOT LEAVE THE TRUCK DURING PROGRAMMING.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click on the
                        <emph type="bold">Program</emph>
                        button at the main NETS 3.1 window to start the Programming process.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390325" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">This window will appear:</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390326" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390326.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Select the desired VIN from the list and click on the
                    <emph type="bold">PROGRAM</emph>
                    button.
                </para>
                <para>Key the truck ON. Read the note. Click
                    <emph type="bold">Yes</emph>
                    to start Programming the vehicle.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0390327" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390327.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">REMEMBER:</emph>
                    on vehicles equipped with Allison MD electronic transmissions or has ABS Brakes, the ECU's MUST BE
                    DISCONNECTED prior to begin any reprogramming operation using Navistar NETS 3.1. Please refer to
                    Appendix A for details on how to disconnect the transmission.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT:</emph>
                    For the reprogramming operation to be successful the instructions provided on the screen and this
                    manual must be strictly followed at all times. Always verify that all connections are solid and make
                    sure that the key is in the right position according to the instructions.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the key OFF and back ON and click
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390328" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Read the note and click
                        <emph type="bold">Next</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390329" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390329.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 29.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Read the instructions and click Next.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390330" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390330.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 30.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Follow the instructions and click
                        <emph type="bold">Next</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390331" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390331.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 31.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Programming will begin.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Do NOT Walk Away From Vehicle</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>During this stage of programming the EZ-Tech will program all the parameters and calibrations
                        into the ECM. This process will take approximately 10 minutes.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390332" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390332.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 32.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn Key
                        <emph type="bold">off</emph>
                        for 3 seconds and then back on.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390333" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390333.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 33.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Click
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390334" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390334.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 34.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Key vehicle off to store data in the module. Click
                        <emph type="bold">Finish</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0390335" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0390335.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 35.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t0390301">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.01in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-03903-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Re-program ECM (International Single Box Controller)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.7 Hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-03903.
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-03903 activity must
                be submitted by April 30, 2004 or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after April 30,
                2004.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
