<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC G-04911 - 7400 models with DT 570 Engine, Code 12NPW, and Allison Transmission Built Between April 6,
        2004 and August 13, 2004 May Experience Poor Shift Quality
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc04911">
        <afcnum>G-04911</afcnum>
        <afcdate>December, 2004</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subject>7400 models with DT 570 Engine, Code 12NPW, and Allison Transmission Built Between April 6, 2004 and
            August 13, 2004 May Experience Poor Shift Quality
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/06/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>08/13/2004</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>7400 Models built between April 6, 2004 and August 13, 2004 with Allison transmissions may
                    experience up shift difficulties (hung shift) that results from a mismatch between the engine
                    governed speed (2200 rpm) and the transmission governed speed (2400 rpm) calibration.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <para>A campaign letter will be sent to owners on record advising them to contact their International Dealer
                for an appointment to have the Allison transmission re-calibrated.
            </para>
            <para>International dealers that are certified, by Allison, to perform this service will re-calibrate the
                transmission. The re-calibration information is available from Allison and will require the vehicle VIN.
            </para>
            <para>International dealers that are not certified by Allison will contact the nearest Allison dealer and
                set an appointment for the customer to bring the vehicle in to the Allison dealer for re-calibration.
                The International dealer will pay the Allison labor charge, which may vary by dealer.
            </para>
            <para>In either case the International dealer will process campaign expense in the usual manner.</para>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t039071">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.01in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-04911-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Re-Calibrate Allison Transmission by International Dealer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.0 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>A40-04911-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Re-Calibrate Allison Transmission by Allison Dealer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0.3 hr.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Dealers will only be responsible for paying labor costs, not to exceed 1.0 hour at the shop's standard
                labor rate, when the re-calibration is performed by an Allison dealer. This charge should be included in
                the warranty claim under Outside Charges.
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-04911.
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-04911 activity must
                be submitted by December 31, 2005 or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after
                December 31, 2005.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
