<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC G-05910 - Replacement of 100 Gallon Between the Rails (BTR) Fuel Tanks on CE, FE and RE Buses Built
        Between March 16, 2005 and July 20, 2005
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc05910">
        <afcnum>G-05910</afcnum>
        <afcdate>November, 2005</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>FUEL TANKS</subjectfile>
        <subject>Replacement of 100 Gallon Between the Rails (BTR) Fuel Tanks on CE, FE and RE Buses Built Between March
            16, 2005 and July 20, 2005
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Beach Mfg</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE 200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/16/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CE 300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/16/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>FE 300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/16/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE 200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/16/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE 300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/16/2005</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/20/2005</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Certain CE, FE, and RE bus models built between March 16, 2005 and July 20, 2005 have between the
                    rails 100 gallon fuel tanks that do not meet material specification and rust internally, causing
                    fuel filters to plug, resulting in low engine power.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0591001">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.50*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3584274C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Tank, 100 Gal. BTR</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3586922C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Tank, 100 Gal. BTR</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>3596530C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Tank, 100 Gal. BTR</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When ordering the replacement fuel tank, order the same number listed on the line set
                        ticket.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface,
                        set the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Diesel fuel is flammable, keep away from ignition sources. Failure to heed this warning may
                        result in property damage, personal injury, and/or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the primary fuel filter/strainer (rock catcher) for signs of rust in the fuel
                    system.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If evidence of rust is present, the fuel must be drained and discarded following good shop
                            practices and replace the fuel filters.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If
                            <emph type="bold">no</emph>
                            evidence of rust is found, drain the fuel into a suitable clean container for reuse at the
                            completion of this Service Procedure.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f059101" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g059101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Fuel Tank and Cage Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. MOUNTING NUT (24)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MOUNTING BOLT PAIR (12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FILLER NECK TUBE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. VENT HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RUBBER FILLER HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FUEL RETURN LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. FUEL SUPPLY LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. CENTER VENT LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SENDING UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. ELECTRICAL CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. TANK HOLDING STRAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. CROSS BAR (CLOSED END)</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. HOLDING STRAP BOLT (6)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. HOLDING STRAP MOUNTING NUT (6)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a transmission jack or other suitable lifting device under the center of the
                    tank cage assembly, and raise the jack until it just makes contact with the bottom of the cage
                    (Figure 2). The jack should be located at the center of the tank cage assembly to prevent the
                    assembly from tipping while being lowered.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f059102" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/G059102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Jack in Contact with Fuel Tank Cage</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Working on one side of the fuel tank , remove a mounting nut from each of the three (3)
                    tank holding straps (Figure 1, Item 11).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the mounting nut at the other end of each holding strap (3), but do not remove.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the rubber filler hose from the filler neck tube by removing the two hose
                    clamps and sliding the hose off of the filler tube (Figure 1). It may be necessary to cut tie-straps
                    to move the fuel hose. Note the original location of all tie-straps to allow correct replacement
                    during installation. If the hose cannot be fully separated from the filler tube, verify that the
                    hose clamps are loose so that the hose will disconnect as the tank is lowered.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the tank cage to the jack 'table' using a safety chain or ratchet safety strap.
                    NOTE: Do not position the chain or strap over the tank. Secure only the cage. The tank must be free
                    to remove.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The mounting bolts are arranged in vertical pairs. Each pair of bolts is welded to a strap to
                        simplify installation (Figure 1, Item 2 and Figure 3).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f059103" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/G059103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Mounting Bolt Pair</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leaving one mounting nut installed at each corner of the cage, remove the other 20 nuts
                    securing the fuel tank cage to the vehicle frame (Figure 1, Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, do not work under the tank and cage assembly while it is
                        supported by the jack.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four remaining mounting nuts, then raise the jack slightly to allow removal
                    of all remaining mounting bolts. The tank and cage is now free from the vehicle frame, but is still
                    connected by fuel lines and the wire harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, while the tank cage is being lowered, watch for signs of binding and
                        tipping. If necessary, use a pry bar to prevent the cage from binding.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly and carefully lower the jack only enough to provide access to the top of the fuel
                    tank (approx. 8 to 12 inches).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>While it may be possible to access the top of the fuel tank through an access hole in the
                        floor of the vehicle, in most cases, it is easier to access this area from under the vehicle
                        once the tank and cage assembly have been partially lowered.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, finish disconnecting the rubber filler hose from the filler neck tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the top of the tank in the area of the sending unit and hose connections.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When disconnecting lines in the following step, note the placement of any tie-straps that must
                        be removed or relocated. All tie-straps must be replaced in their original location during
                        installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the top of the fuel tank (refer to Figure 1):</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connector from the sending unit.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the 'filler' vent hose by removing the hose clamp.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the supply and return fuel lines by disconnecting the Voss fittings (note
                        the fitting that each line is connected to).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the fuel filler hose from the tank by removing the hose clamp.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly lower the jack to its lowest position. Note the orientation of the tank and the
                    cage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Some cages are 'closed' with a cross bar at one end (Figure 1, Item 12). Note which end of the
                        cage faces the front of the vehicle, and whether the filler port is located at the front or the
                        rear of the fuel tank. This information will be needed when installing the replacement tank.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that there is clearance to move the tank and cage assembly (and jack) from under
                    the vehicle. If necessary, raise the vehicle to provide the necessary clearance.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the tank and cage assembly from under the vehicle, to a suitable working
                    location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a jack was used to raise the vehicle, it can be lowered at this time.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the tank still contains a small amount of fuel, drain it now.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the loose ends of the three tank holding straps to allow movement of the tank.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Removal of the tank from the cage in the following Step will require two people.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the fuel tank from the open end of the cage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer the following components from this tank to the replacement tank (Figure 1):
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fuel sending unit, tighten 5 screws using a criss / cross pattern to 20 to 25 Lbf-in
                        ( 2.3 to 2.8 Nm)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Vent hose fitting (front) for vent hose at filler neck</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Vent hose and fitting (center) for vent hose near sending unit (note location of
                        vent hose)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fuel supply hose fitting</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fuel return hose fitting</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dispose of the fuel tank using good shop practices.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Placing the fuel tank into the tank cage requires two people.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>While sliding the fuel tank into the cage, position the tank holding straps to prevent them
                        from interfering with the tank.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the replacement tank into the cage so that the fuel filler inlet is oriented
                    correctly. The tank should be approximately 1 inch from the cross bar at the closed end of the cage.
                    The other end of the tank should be even with the cage rails.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the three fuel tank holding straps (Figure 1). Tighten the mounting strap nuts
                    on one side of the cage (call this side A) to 20 to 25 Lbf-ft (27 to 34 Nm) and the strap nuts on
                    the opposite side (call this side B) to 45 to 50 Lbf-ft. (61 to 68 Nm) then return to side A and
                    retighten the nuts to 45 to 50 Lbf-ft ( 61 to 68 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To gain the clearance needed to perform the following step, it may be necessary to raise the
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the tank and cage assembly in its approximate mounting location under the
                    vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a jack was used to raise the vehicle, lower the vehicle and remove the jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the transmission jack, raise the tank and cage assembly approximately 8 to 12
                    inches below its final mounting location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following Step return all hoses and wires to their original routing and secure with
                        tie-straps, as necessary.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On top of the fuel tank (Figure 1):</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the supply and return fuel lines by connecting, and locking, the Voss
                        fittings. (Insure that the lines are connected to the correct fitting, as noted during
                        'Removal'.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the harness to the sending unit electrical connector.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the vent hose to the tank fitting and install the hose clamp.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the fuel filler hose to the tank, but leave the hose clamp loose to allow
                        final alignment in a later step.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the two hose clamps onto the top of the rubber filler hose (Figure 1); then, align
                    and connect the rubber filler hose to the filler neck tube. Do not tighten the hose clamps at this
                    time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the rubber filler hose at the top of the tank to relieve strain or binding; then,
                    tighten the hose clamp.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully raise the tank and cage assembly until at least one mounting bolt can be
                    installed at each corner of the assembly (Figure 1). Leave the mounting nuts loose enough to allow
                    alignment of the remaining mounting holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following Step it may be necessary to use pry bars and/or adjust the jack to align the
                        remaining cage mounting holes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosely install the remaining mounting bolts and nuts. Once nuts have been installed on
                    all mounting bolts, tighten all 24 mounting nuts to 340 to 370 Lbf-ft (461 to 502 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the safety strap and the transmission jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the fuel filler tube is fully inserted into the rubber filler hose, and is
                    positioned correctly at the filler door. Tighten the two hose clamps securing the hose to the tube
                    (Figure 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the fuel tank with the fuel that was removed If
                    <emph type="bold">no</emph>
                    evidence of rust was found in Step 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prime the fuel system following the procedure in the engine manual and start the
                    engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for fuel leaks at the new fuel tank.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t0591002">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.01in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.57in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-05910-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Remove and Replace Fuel Tank</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.6 Hrs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-05910.
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44. To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all
                claims for G-05910 activity must be submitted by November 30, 2006 or within the normal warranty period
                for the vehicle, if after November 30, 2006.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
