<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC G-07903 - Potential for Hendrickson AirTek Front Suspension Spring Contact with the End of a Huck Bolt
        at the Front Suspension Rear Bracket on International 9000 Model Trucks
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc07903">
        <afcnum>G-07903</afcnum>
        <afcdate>August, 2007</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subject>Potential for Hendrickson AirTek Front Suspension Spring Contact with the End of a Huck Bolt at the
            Front Suspension Rear Bracket on International 9000 Model Trucks
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>AirTek</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/29/2006</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/10/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/29/2006</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/10/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/29/2006</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/10/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>03AZE</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This AFC applies to all 9000 trucks that are equipped with feature code 03AZE.</para>
                <para>All of the above mentioned truck models need to be inspected for potential spring contact with the
                    end of a Huck bolt at the front suspension rear bracket. This contact could result in a front
                    suspension spring fracture.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0790301" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.70*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.66*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.63*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Huck Replacement</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>414078C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Bolt, Hex Flg Hd 5/8-18 UNF x 2.0" Grade 8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>414089C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Nut, Hex Lock Flg 5/8-18 UNF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8000892R91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spring replacement kit - for single spring replacement</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1 or 2 as required by service procedure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>service procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place hood in raised position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove left and right fender extensions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect left and right suspension springs for any contact made with the end of huck bolt
                    (Figure 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0790301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790301x.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="408px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If any contact is visible on a spring, that particular spring requires replacement.
                    Continue to Step 5 for repair of any side of the vehicle where the spring does NOT exhibit contact.
                    Go to the Spring Replacement Procedure below for springs that show evidence of contact.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove huck bolt (Figure 1) and replace it with bolt number 414078C1 (5/8" x 2" Grade 8)
                    or equivalent. Bolt must be installed from the bottom (head facing down). Install nut part number
                    414089C1 (5/8" Grade 8) or equivalent and torque to 220 lbf-ft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the fender extensions if no spring replacement is required and close hood.
                    Procedure is complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If one or both springs require replacement, continue to Spring Replacement Procedure
                    below.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SPRING REPLACEMENT PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, deflate and disconnect the air system prior to raising the
                        front of the vehicle. Prior to and during deflation and inflation of the front air suspension
                        system, ensure that all personnel and equipment are clear from under the vehicle and around the
                        service area.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, park truck on solid level surface. Place vehicle in neutral
                        and set parking brake.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">See Air Spring Warnings above prior to deflating or inflating the suspension system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Deflate the air springs by detaching the upper rubber grommet of the height control
                    valve linkage from the upper stud and exhaust the suspension system air by lowering the height
                    control valve linkage arm.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Completely drain all of the air tanks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the air lines from the air spring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a floor jack with a 4" lifting plate below the axle and raise the truck.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the tires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install frame stands behind the front spring rear mounts to support the vehicle. It may
                    be necessary to remove peripheral components for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the jack allowing the axle to hang, but do not remove the jack from the axle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen both spring eye bolts, but DO NOT remove the bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both rear spring eye bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>SERVICE HINT : To ease in the removal of the spring eye bolts it may be necessary to raise or lower
                the axle slightly.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both lower shock absorber mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the lower air spring mounting fasteners from the top pad and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen (DO NOT REMOVE ) the clamp group nylon locknuts for the leaf spring that is NOT
                    being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not use a cutting torch to remove clamp group bolts or attaching fasteners. The use of such
                        heat on suspension components can adversely affect the strength of the parts. A component
                        damaged in this manner can result in the loss of vehicle control and possible personal injury or
                        property damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 3/4" clamp group fasteners, top pad, and the bottom axle wrap and liner from
                    the leaf spring that is going to be removed (Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0790302" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="484px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the jack, allowing the suspension to pivot down out of the rear hanger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the front spring eye bolts from the leaf spring being serviced and discard.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the leaf spring assembly. Approximate weight of the spring is 60 pounds.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be aware of the amount and the orientation of caster wedges (if equipped) on the top axle
                        wrap, they may slide during leaf spring removal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">HUCK BOLT REPLACEMENT:</emph>Remove huck bolt (Figure 1) and replace it with bolt part
                number 414078c1 or equivalent. Bolt must be installed from the bottom (head facing down). Install nut
                part number 414089c1 or equivalent, and torque to 298 Nm (220 lbf-ft).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Spring Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the leaf spring assembly over the axle and into the front spring hanger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the 3/4" front spring eye bolt and fastener, but DO NOT tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure to re-install any caster wedges (if equipped) that may have been displaced during
                    leaf spring disassembly, in the same orientation as removed prior to disassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engage the leaf spring to the axle with the leaf spring locating stud into the aligning
                    hole of the top axle wrap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the top pad on top of the leaf spring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new bottom axle wrap liner in the bottom axle wrap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bottom axle wrap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new clamp group bolts (Grade 8), washers, and the new nylon locknuts (Grade
                    c). The nylock locknuts must be replaced when the clamp group is removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the clamp group fasteners to 136 Nm (100 lbf-ft).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the axle and guide the spring assembly into the rear spring hanger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the 3/4" rear spring eye bolt in the rear hanger. The bolt must be installed
                    from the inboard side to the outboard side (see Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the lower shock mounting bolts from the outboard side to the inboard side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the floor jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Only the weight of the axle should be on the spring at the time of the front and rear spring
                        eye fasteners are tightened to torque.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the lower shock mounting bolts to 352 Nm (260 lbf-ft) torque.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the front and rear spring eye 3/4" locknuts to 407 Nm (300 lbf-ft) torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the air spring into the top pad with new nuts. Torque nuts to 41 Nm (30 lbf-ft).
                    Make sure the air spring piston seats into the top pad correctly (see Figure 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0790303" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                         scalefitheight="408px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the tires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">See air spring warnings and instructions in the important safety notice section of this
                    publication prior to deflating or inflating the suspension system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air lines to the air spring and air up the system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the height control valve linkage and inflate the suspension to normal operating
                    pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the vehicle and remove the frame supports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the floor jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the clamp group is properly aligned and the hex bolts are seated in the top
                    pad, and the bottom axle wrap is centered on the top axle wrap (see Figure 4).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0790304" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the clamp group locknuts evenly in 70 Nm (50 lbf-ft) increments to 386-414 Nm
                    (285-305 lbf-ft) torque in the proper pattern to achieve uniform bolt tension (see Figure 5).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0790305" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify proper ride height. See attachment for Alignment and Adjustment section of this
                    publication.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t0790301" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.69in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.38in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.34in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-07903-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspect and replace huck bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.0 hr</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>A40-07903-2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Add on for one spring</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>1.3 hrs</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>A40-07903-3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Add on for both springs</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>2.4 hrs</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-07903
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-07903 activity must
                be submitted by August 31, 2008 or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after August
                31, 2008.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/AFCLAIM.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
