<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 07901 - Air Lines May be Crossed at Pressure Protection Valve on Certain FE School and FE Commercial Bus
        Models
    </stitle>
    <afc id="afc07901">
        <afcnum>07901</afcnum>
        <afcdate>February, 2007</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>Brakes</subjectfile>
        <subject>Air Lines May be Crossed at Pressure Protection Valve on Certain FE School and FE Commercial Bus
            Models
        </subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>FE 300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/11/2004</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/28/2006</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>14TBS</ucode>
                <ucode>14TBT</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Air lines may be crossed coming from the SR-1 inversion and air bag leveling valve to the Pressure
                    Protection Valve at the air tank on certain FE School and Commercial bus models.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>No parts are required. The lines that are being swapped have sufficient length to reverse
                orientation.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>service procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking
                            brake, and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent personal injury or death, completely drain all air tanks and air lines before
                            disconnecting air lines or components.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>This service procedure is split into two (2) sections: 1) an inspection and 2) a plumbing change
                    section. Perform the inspection on the vehicle first to determine if a plumbing change is required.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The air tanks and air lines can be viewed by looking under the front of the bus. If
                        the air line color is not visible because of dirt or paint, you will have to perform the
                        inspection by sliding under the bus and wiping the dirt off or scraping the paint from the air
                        lines.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0790101" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="192px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the air line plumbing is CORRECT as shown in Figure 2, No plumbing change is
                        required and the recall is complete. You will need to fill out and apply the enclosed recall
                        decal S00109.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the black and orange lines are not plumbed as indicated in Figure 1, they should
                        appear as in Figure 2, which is the correct orientation. The SR-1 inversion valve should be
                        plumbed from the primary air tank, with redundant plumbing from the secondary air tank. The air
                        suspension leveling valve is also plumbed from the primary tank via a pressure protection valve.
                        See correct orientation in Figure 2.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Determine if the black and orange lines are plumbed as indicated in Figure 1, these
                        are INCORRECT. In this INCORRECT state, the SR-1 inversion valve is plumbed through the pressure
                        protection valve (PPV), and the air suspension valve is plumbed directly from the primary tank.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0790102" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../afcfigures/g0790102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Plumbing Change Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">REFER to Figure 2 for correct orientations while making repairs.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Completely bleed both air tanks to 0 psi (0 KPa).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the 5/8" black tube from the pressure protection valve (PPV).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the 5/8" orange tube from the primary air tank.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect the orange air line to the pressure protection valve, making sure there
                        are no kinks.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Re-connect the black air line to the primary air tank.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the vehicle to pressurize the system and check for leaks at the intermediate
                        connection on the cross-member and the tank connections. repair as required.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Test Brake System: Drain the primary air tank. Ensure that the secondary air tank
                        retains pressure. Apply the service brake and ensure that the brakes actuate. Reinstate primary
                        air tank pressure to normal.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="t0790102" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Labor Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.69in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.38in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.32in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Operation No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>A40-07901-01</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Inspection and Repair</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.4</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>A40-07901-02</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspection Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0.3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>
                <title>ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty.
                <hotlnk xrefid="afclaim">Claims</hotlnk>
                are to be submitted in the normal manner, making reference to Authorized Field Change Number G-07901
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to Items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-07901 must be
                submitted by February 28, 2008 or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after February
                28, 2008.
            </para>
            <figure id="afclaim" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
            </figure>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
