<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AFC 98901 - Bendix AD-9 Air Dryer Upgrade</stitle>
    <afc id="AFC98901">
        <afcnum>98901</afcnum>
        <afcdate>March, 1998</afcdate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subject>Bendix AD-9 Air Dryer Upgrade</subject>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Holset</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>General</title>
                    <para>This AFC applies to all models with Holset (Cummins) type EOVEQ compressor built between
                        October 1, 1996 and December 31, 1997.
                    </para>
                    <para>The Bendix AD-9 air dryer could malfunction if the purge valve becomes blocked. An upgraded
                        purge valve assembly is available which eliminates the possibility of valve blockage.
                    </para>
                    <para>The new assembly is designed to improve performance and extend the service life of the AD-9
                        air dryer purge valve assembly mechanism. It includes the following improvements:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>A heavier purge piston return spring to ensure positive return of the piston and
                                better sealing of the purge valve.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>A modified piston and seal combination for improved sealing at higher temperatures.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Identification</title>
                    <para>All AD-9 air dryers manufactured or remanufactured after December 31, 1997, incorporate the
                        new purge valve assembly. Air dryers with the new purge valve assembly can be identified in one
                        of two ways.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>AD-9 air dryers manufactured or remanufactured with date codes between K0196T or F
                                (October 1, 1996) and M3197T or F (December 31, 1997) should be upgraded to the new
                                purge valve assembly (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f9890101">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="f9890101" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9890101" filename="../afcfigures/g9890101.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The first letter of the date code is the month, A=January, B=February, etc. The first
                                pair of digits is the day while the second pair of digits is the year. The last letter
                                indicates the plant location.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>The date code will be L0197F or later.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Visually inspect for the presence of a white paint marking or green disk on the purge
                                valve assembly (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f9890102">Figure 2</hotlnk>). If either is found no repair is necessary.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <figure id="f9890102" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9890102" filename="../afcfigures/g9890102.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9890101" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.76in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.74in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>New Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Old Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Purge Valve Assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>BX800405</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>BX109569</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure does not require removal of the Bendix AD-9 air dryer.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9890103">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9890103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g9890103" filename="../afcfigures/g9890103.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and prevent movement by setting the parking brakes
                    and blocking the vehicle.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Whenever any component is serviced or removed from the air system, be sure to set the
                            parking brake and/or block the vehicle to prevent it from moving while the service is being
                            performed.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air reservoirs to 0 PSI.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Drain off all air from the air system before removing brake system components. Failure to
                            do so could result in personal injury and/or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the exterior of the air dryer end cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the three self tapping screws that secure the purge valve assembly to the end
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the purge valve assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the bores in the dryer end cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the dryer end cover bores and the outside surface of the purge valve assembly
                    with the grease provided. Make certain the O-rings have been coated with lubricant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new purge valve assembly in the end cover while making certain the purge
                    valve is fully seated against the end cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the three self tapping screws which retain the purge valve assembly. Tighten the
                    screws to 85 to 125 in-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all reservoir drain cocks. Start the engine to build up system air pressure and
                    note that the AD-9 air dryer purges air with an audible escape of air. Exercise the service brake
                    pedal to reduce the system air pressure to governor cut-in. Verify that the air system regains full
                    air pressure and the air dryer purges air audibly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap solution around the purge valve in the air dryer end cover and surrounding
                    area of the purge valve. Leakage should not exceed a 1 inch bubble in 1 second. If leakage exceeds
                    specification, remove and re-install the purge valve assembly. If leakage continues, replace the air
                    dryer assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <laborinfo>
            <para>Operation number must appear on all claims.</para>
            <table id="labortab" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.56in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.85in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.08in"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Operation No.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Time</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>A40-98901-1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Replace air dryer purge valve assembly</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>0.5 hour</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </laborinfo>
        <claims>
            <para>Expense is to be charged to Warranty. Claims are to be submitted in the normal manner, making
                reference to
                <hotlnk xrefid="afcclaim">Authorized Field Change</hotlnk>
                Number G-98901.
            </para>
            <figure id="afcclaim" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="afclaim" filename="../afcfigures/afclaim.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
            </figure>
            <para>It is important that the coding be completed properly to assist in processing the warranty claim.
                Complete instructions will be found in the Warranty Manual, Section 7-1. Special attention should be
                given to items 39 through 44.
            </para>
            <para>To assure this important improvement is made in a timely manner, all claims for G-98901 activity must
                be submitted by March 31, 1999, or within the normal warranty period for the vehicle, if after March 31,
                1999.
            </para>
        </claims>
    </afc>
</isis>
