<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - CYLINDER HEAD OR REPLACE GASKET; REMOVE &#38; RE-INSTALL</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="a12-3100" wtscode="A12-3100" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>CYLINDER HEAD OR REPLACE GASKET; REMOVE &#38; RE-INSTALL</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4300</model>
        <model>4400</model>
        <model>7000</model>
        <model>8500</model>
        <modelyr>2001</modelyr>
        <engine>530E, DT 466E</engine>
        <tran>ANY</tran>
        <config>Vehicle equipped with air conditioning. It is not necessary to open the air conditioning system.
        </config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks and open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground and remove front bumper
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine splash shield.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air cleaner housing with turbo inlet tube attached, include disconnect IAT
                    sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring from alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine position / timing sensor (CAM), include wire support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine coolant temperature sensor (ECT).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring support clamp at alternator for access to heater hoses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect water heater hose, include support clamps. Secure hoses out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring and engine harness from valve cover, include support
                    clamps. Secure out of way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect surge tank hose from tank and thermostat housing. Include support clamp.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect coolant level sensor and freon compressor clutch wire if applicable. Secure
                    harness out of way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine wiring and connectors to include MAP, ICP and injector wiring at valve
                    cover and secure harness out of way.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Remove engine harness from plastic clip on left front side of valve cover.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect high pressure oil line from oil/fuel manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel line from fuel filter and oil/fuel manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air compressor inlet hose from compressor if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cowl tray assembly, include remove wiper arms and radio antenna.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove windshield wiper linkage assembly with motor attached, include disconnect wiring
                    at motor and washer hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect radiator hose at thermostat housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine housing cover, include remove or reposition seat, shifter lever, cup
                    holder and floor mat as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil drain hose from turbocharger and block. Remove supply hose from turbocharger
                    and oil cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect exhaust pipe assembly (turbo outlet) from turbocharger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove turbocharger assembly from exhaust manifold. Cap open ports on turbocharger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankcase ventilation pipe from valve cover and block.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain radiator coolant from block (plug on oil cooler) and re-install plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air conditioning compressor assembly if applicable, reposition out of way and
                    secure. Include disconnect support clamps and belt.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>With 7000 model, remove with bracket attached. All others, remove from water manifold
                            housing.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve/intake cover, include disconnect under valve cover injector harness from
                    valve cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve cover gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fuel line from rear of cylinder head.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Squeeze white clip to release connector.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain oil/fuel supply manifold of oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove injector wiring harness, include wire harness channel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove electronic injectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove rocker arm shaft assembly and push rods.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Loosen valve lever adjusting screws to prevent damage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cylinder head bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect hood stop cables and support hood with stand (step performed to increase
                    access for lifting device).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device and remove cylinder head from vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leak test valves.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all parts and mating surfaces.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cylinder head gasket, include install dowl guides if removed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cylinder head to vehicle using lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rocker arm shaft assembly and push rods, include apply oil to bolts.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not tighten bolts at this time.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cylinder head bolts, include apply oil to bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque rocker arm shaft assembly and head bolts to spec., include set rocker arm end
                    play.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace injector o-rings (set).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install electronic injectors and torque to spec.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Torque shoulder bolts prior to installing injectors.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install injector wiring harness, include install wire harness channel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust valves.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel line to rear of cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil/fuel supply manifold plug, include replace o-ring and torque plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve/intake cover and gasket, include connect under valve cover harness
                    connector to valve cover. Torque bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air conditioning compressor assembly to mount bracket if applicable, include
                    connect support clamps and belt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankcase ventilation pipe to valve cover and block.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install turbocharger assembly to exhaust manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect exhaust pipe assembly to turbocharger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil supply hose to turbocharger and oil cooler. Install oil drain hose to
                    turbocharger and block.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect radiator hose to thermostat housing using heat gun to shrink clamp.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel line to fuel filter and oil/fuel manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect high pressure oil line to oil/fuel manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine wiring and connectors to include MAP, ICP and injector wiring at valve
                    cover.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Install wire harness to plastic clip at valve cover.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring to alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring and engine harness to valve cover, include support clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect surge tank hose to tank and thermostat housing, include support clamp at air
                    conditioning compressor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine coolant temperature sensor (ECT).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine position / timing sensor (CAM), include wire support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect water heater hose, include support clamps.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring support clamp at alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect coolant level sensor, and freon compressor clutch wire if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air cooler hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air cleaner housing with turbo inlet tube attached, include connect IAT
                    sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install windshield wiper linkage assembly with motor attached, include connect wiring
                    and washer hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cowl tray assembly, include install wiper arms and radio antenna.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air compressor inlet hose to compressor if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wire harness ties to hoses and wiring harnesses as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill coolant system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace engine oil and oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed fuel system, start engine and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Top off fluids as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine housing cover, include install seat, shift lever, cup holder and floor
                    mat as required
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine cover and close hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks and check/test operation while road testing vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
