<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE FRONT COVER AND/OR GASKET; R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="A12-3190" wtscode="A12-3190" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE FRONT COVER AND/OR GASKET; R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4300</model>
        <model>4400</model>
        <model>7000</model>
        <model>8500</model>
        <modelyr>2000</modelyr>
        <engine>530E, DT466E</engine>
        <tran>MANUAL</tran>
        <config>This guideline is for R &#38; R of front section only. It is not necessary to open the Air Conditioning
            or Power Steering system if equipped. It is not necessary to remove the oil pan when servicing the front
            section only.
        </config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper assembly</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open hood</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground wire</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood assembly, includes disconnect hood wiring harness, hood stop cables and
                    pivot bolts
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove right engine splash shield</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler hoses, include cap open ports</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect water heater hose from mount bracket at radiator and secure out of way for
                    access
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disonnect condenser assembly from radiatior assembly and secure out of way. Includes
                    disconnect pressure transducer, removing P-clips securing lines and remove right recirculation seal
                    if applicable
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fan hub air hose if applicable</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect surge tank hoses and coolant level sensor connector</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect ground strap from lower left side of radiator</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect lower radiator Hose from thermostat housing</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect lower right radiator hose from front cover</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect lower radiator stay rods</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove stone shield lower screws</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper frame cross member with grill attached</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower frame cross member section, include remove tow hooks</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device, remove radiator assembly mounting bolts and remove assembly
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan blade, drive, pulley and hub components, includes belt and tensioner</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine position / timing sensor (CAM), includes disconnect wiring</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove alternator mounting bracket with alternator attached, includes disconnect wiring
                    and remove support bracket
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankshaft damper using puller</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pump assembly, include remove drift key</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove water pump drive pulley and water pump assembly</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine bracket to cross member bolts</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position bottle jack to raise block and remove engine bracket</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Position jack to allow rotation of crankshaft</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air compressor bolts if applicable</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Loosen rear tail support bracket</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cover assembly bolts and front section of front cover</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align timing gears and mark camshaft gear in relation to upper idler gear</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check timing gears back lash and camshaft end play</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean parts and block mating surfaces</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cover assembly front section</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine bracket to front of engine</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower complete engine using bottle jack</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine bracket bolts to cross member</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air compressor if appliciable and torque to spec.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Tighten tailshaft support bracket at block first and then at rear of compressor</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Heat crankshaft damper using heating iron</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install water pump assembly and drive pulley, includes torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace front seal and install oil pump assembly, include install drift key. Torque
                    bolts to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankshaft damper, includes replace wear ring and torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan hub, pulley, drive and blade components, includes belt and tensioner. Torque
                    to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan hub line fitting if applicable</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator hose clamp (shrink type) on lower right hose before installing
                    radiator
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator assembly using lifting device, install mounting bolts and remove
                    lifting device
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Position lower right hose onto front cover while installing</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect lower radiator stay rods</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect ground cable (strap) at radiator</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect radiator hose to thermostat housing and shrink clamp using heat gun</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and shrink lower right radiator hose clamp at front cover</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ConnectsSurge tank hoses and low coolant level sensor connector, include install plactic
                    ties
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fan hub air hose if applicable</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect condenser to radiator assembly, includes connect pressure transducer connector,
                    securing lines and installing right recirculation seal if applicable
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lower and upper frame cross members, include install tow hooks</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator stone guard grill screws to lower frame cross member</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air cooler hoses</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator mounting bracket with alternator attached, includes connect wiring
                    and install support bracket
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine position / timing sensor (CAM), include replace o-ring and connect
                    wiring
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install belt tensioner, torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect heater hose to mount bracket at radiator</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood assembly, includes connect stop cables, harness connectors and install
                    pivot bolts
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground wire</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper assembly</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check/test engine operation and for leaks</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Top off fluids as needed</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and remove wheel chocks</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
