<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - VALVE COVER(S) AND/OR GASKET; R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="a12-3060" wtscode="A12-3060" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>VALVE COVER(S) AND/OR GASKET; R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4300</model>
        <model>4400</model>
        <modelyr>2001</modelyr>
        <engine>530E, DT 466E</engine>
        <tran>ANY</tran>
        <config></config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks and open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine housing cover if required. Include remove or reposition seat, shifter
                    lever, cup holder, trim and floor mat as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler outlet hose at valve cover and cooler. Cap open ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect surge tank hose (overflow), include disconnect coolant level sensor connector
                    and disconnect wire from hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air conditioning compressor assembly if applicable and secure out of way.
                    Include disconnect compressor belt, hose support clamps and compressor clutch wire connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine control wiring harness from valve cover and secure out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring at alternator and from valve cover including support
                    clamps. Secure out of way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove alternator wiring support bracket from valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect injector wiring harness at valve cover and disconnect under valve cover
                    harness connector from valve cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove heater hose clamp for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect manifold pressure sensor (map) wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankcase ventilation pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve/intake cover bolts and valve cover from vehicle, include mark studs for
                    ease of installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean mating surfaces.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve/intake cover to vehicle, include connect under valve cover wiring
                    connector to valve cover. Torque bolts to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankcase ventilation pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect manifold pressure sensor (map) wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect injector wiring harness at valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator wiring support bracket to valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring harness to valve cover, support clamps and at alternator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install heater hose clamp.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electronic engine control wire harness to valve cover. Include tape plastic clip
                    to harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air conditioning compressor assembly if applicable. Include connect compressor
                    belt, hose support clamps and compressor clutch wire.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect surge tank hose (overflow), include connect coolant level sensor connector at
                    tank and strap harness to hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect charge air cooler outlet hose at cooler and valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and check for leaks. Top off fluids as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine housing cover if required. Include install seat, shifter lever, cup
                    holder, trim and floor mat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
