<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - FUEL INJECTOR(S) (ELECTRONIC ENGINES); R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="a12-3135" wtscode="A12-3135" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>FUEL INJECTOR(S) (ELECTRONIC ENGINES); R &#38; R AND/OR REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4300</model>
        <model>4400</model>
        <model>7000</model>
        <model>8500</model>
        <modelyr>2001</modelyr>
        <engine>DT 466E, 530E</engine>
        <tran>ANY</tran>
        <config>It is not necessary to open the air conditioning system if equipped.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks and open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine housing cover, include remove or reposition seat, shifter lever, cup
                    holder, trim and floor mat as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler outlet hose at valve cover and cooler. Cap open ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect surge tank hose (overflow), include disconnect coolant level sensor connector
                    at tank and wire from hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air conditioning compressor assembly if applicable and secure out of way. Include
                    disconnect harness connector from clutch, compressor belt and support clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine wiring and connectors to include MAP, ICP and injector wiring at valve
                    cover and secure out of way.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Remove engine harness from plastic clip on left front of valve cover.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring at alternator and valve cover, including support clamps and
                    secure out of way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove alternator wiring support bracket from valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect injector wiring harness at valve cover connection. Disconnect under valve
                    cover harness connector from valve cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove heater hose clamp from support bracket at valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect manifold pressure sensor (map) wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankcase ventilation pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve/intake cover bolts and valve cover from vehicle, include mark studs for
                    installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain oil/fuel supply manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove injector wiring harness, include wire harness channel from injectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove electronic injector assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace injector o-rings (set) (one set for one injector).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all parts and mating surfaces.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install electronic injector assembly, include torque bolts to spec.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Torque injector shoulder bolt prior to installing injector.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install injector wiring harness, include install harness channel to injectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil/fuel supply manifold plug, include replace o-ring and torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve/intake cover to vehicle, include connect under valve cover wiring
                    connector to valve cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve/intake cover bolts. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankcase ventilation pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect manifold pressure sensor (MAP) wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect injector wiring harness connector at valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator wiring support bracket to valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring to alternator and harness to valve cover and support clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install heater hose clamp to support bracket at valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electronic engine controls wire harness to valve cover. Include tape plastic
                    clip to harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air conditioning compressor assembly if applicable. Include connect support
                    clamps, wire harness to clutch and compressor belt. Install plastic ties as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect surge tank hose (overflow), include connect coolant level sensor connector and
                    strap harness to hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect charge air cooler outlet hose at cooler and at valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable, include ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed diesel engine fuel, start engine, check for leaks and top off fluids.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine housing cover, include install seat, shifter lever, cup holder, trim and
                    floor mat as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check/test operation while road testing vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
