<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE ASSEMBLY (COMPLETE); REMOVE AND REINSTALL</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="a12-2040" wtscode="A12-2040" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE ASSEMBLY (COMPLETE); REMOVE AND REINSTALL</wtsdescrip>
        <model>3800</model>
        <model>4700</model>
        <model>4900</model>
        <modelyr>1999</modelyr>
        <engine>DT 466E</engine>
        <tran>Automatic</tran>
        <config></config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open hood assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable, include disconnect ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect hood wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood prop rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect hood stop cable and hood tilt assist springs using two people.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood hinge pins, then remove hood using two people.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air cleaner housing with tube attached, include disconnect IAT sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler hoses, include pipe from turbo to lower port of charge air
                    cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect power steering reservoir, include lower left radiator support strut and hood
                    hinge bracket.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>DO NOT OPEN SYSTEM</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect radiator hoses and surge tank hoses as needed to remove radiator assembly,
                    include p-clip retaining lower hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both upper rods and right side lower radiator stay rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect lifting device to radiator assembly. Tilt assembly forward.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan clutch assembly using special tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil cooler lines from radiator, include cap ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove radiator assembly, include remove lower radiator nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove alternator mounting bracket with belt tensioner and a/c compressor attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine wiring harness support clamps as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect starter wiring. Reposition main harness out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect manifold pressure sensor (MAP) and remove air intake y-pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Siphon high pressure oil pump reservoir of oil, include remove/install EOT sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect high pressure oil pump line from left head for access to power steering
                    pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove power steering pump and secure out of way, includes p-clip from left head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect water heater hose and surge tank hose from engine. Secure out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect exhaust outlet pipe at turbocharger. Secure out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect engine block heater wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise front axle, support with wood blocks under tires.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Wood blocks are used to increase access for large crane.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove drive shaft from behind main transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil cooler lines from engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil cooler lines from front cross member.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Mark left/right side as needed</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil cooler lines from bell housing, include starter cables.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower and upper flywheel inspection plates from bell housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove torque converter bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission wiring harness as needed to remove transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain automatic transmission fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect automatic transmission filter housing from mount bracket with lines attached,
                    secure to trans.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect parking brake lever cable from transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect gear select cable from transmission, include p-clip retaining select cable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect oil dipstick tube from engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil dipstick tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining transmission to engine EXCEPT 2.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure transmission jack to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove automatic transmission assembly, include remove remaining bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect chassis wiring harness support clamp at rear of left cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery to ground cable from rear of engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine mount insulator bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove rear engine mount through bolts, reposition exhaust assembly as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fuel line clamps and support bracket, include supply and return lines at
                    filter housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete engine assembly.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install complete engine assembly. Install through bolt, but do not tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lifting device from engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten rear engine mount engine bracket through bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten front engine mount insulator bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel line clamps and support bracket, include supply and return lines at filter
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable to rear of engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect chassis wiring harness support clamp at rear of left head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install automatic transmission assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts retaining transmission to engine. Remove jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil dipstick tube to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect oil dipstick tube to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect gear select cable assembly to transmission, includes p-clip retaining select
                    cable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect automatic transmission filter housing to mount bracket with lines attached,
                    secure to transmission.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect parking brake lever cable to transmission if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install torque converter bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lower and upper flywheel inspection plates to bell housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to bell housing, include starter cables.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to front cross member.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install drive shaft. Torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine block heater wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect exhaust outlet pipe at turbocharger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect water heater hose and surge tank hose to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering pump, include p-clip and replace gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect high pressure oil pump line to left head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect starter wiring, include p-clip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect manifold pressure sensor (MAP) and install air intake y-pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator mounting bracket with belt tensioner and a/c compressor attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect alternator wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect engine wiring harness support clamps as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator assembly, include install lower radiator nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan clutch assembly using special tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect lifting device from radiator assembly. Connect right side stay rod.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not tighten stay rod at this time</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering reservoir, include lower left radiator support strut and hood
                    hinge bracket.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Leave lower reservoir mount bolt loose at this time. It also retains the charge air
                            pipe.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten radiator stay rod on the right side, include tighten lower mount nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install upper radiator stay rods. Tighten all stay rods.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect radiator hoses and surge tank hoses, include p-clip retaining lower hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to radiator, include p-clip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower front axle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air cooler hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air cleaner housing with tube attached, include connect IAT sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill automatic transmission fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace engine oil, includes replace oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery to ground cable, include connect ECM ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install complete hood Assembly and hood hinge pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect hood stop cable spring and cable using two people.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Tilt spring to outside, stop cables to the inside.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood prop rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect hood wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
