<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - BRAKE SHOES AND/OR SPRINGS, REPLACE - REAR BRAKES (INBOARD DRUMS)</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w0490003" wtscode="A04-151" group="04">
        <wtsdescrip>BRAKE SHOES AND/OR SPRINGS, REPLACE - REAR BRAKES (INBOARD DRUMS)</wtsdescrip>
        <model>9000</model>
        <model>8000</model>
        <model>4000</model>
        <model>2000</model>
        <modelyr>1996</modelyr>
        <engine>Cummins M11</engine>
        <tran>International 9-Speed</tran>
        <config>Inboard mounted brake drum / Q-brake.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise vehicle and support axle being serviced with stands.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Back off brakes on wheel being serviced.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>On rear wheels with spring brake air chambers, cage spring brake air chamber and then back
                            off brake being serviced.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove nuts retaining axle shaft. Remove axle shaft and gasket. Catch fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lock nut, washer, adjusting nut, and outer bearing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using wheel dolly, remove wheel and hub as an assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using suitable pry tool, lift brake shoe and remove both rollers and retaining clips.
                    Note position of clip.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Use caution to prevent personal injury.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using suitable tool, remove brake shoe return spring (spring closest to brake cam).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate upper shoe off spider assembly. Remove upper and lower shoes with brake shoe
                    retaining springs attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove brake shoe retaining springs from brake shoes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove anchor pins. Clean and lubricate anchor pins and bushings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace wheel seal and axle shaft gasket.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install anchor pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install brake return spring pin into new brake shoes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install brake shoe retaining springs to upper and lower shoes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place upper brake shoe onto spider assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate lower brake shoe and install brake shoe return spring using suitable tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rollers and retaining clip. Note position of clip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust brake s-cam so that the rollers are in the s-cam hollow lowest point.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel / hub assembly using wheel dolly. Fill hub cavity with proper fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install outer bearing and adjusting nut. Remove wheel dolly. Adjust bearing preload.
                    Install adjusting nut lock washer. Install lock nut. Torque to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install axle shaft gasket and axle shaft. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust brakes on axle being serviced.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>On rear wheels with spring brake air chamber, uncage spring brake. Release brakes using
                            vehicle air pressure, then adjust brakes.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise vehicle, remove stands and lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check rear differential fluid level on axle being serviced. Top off as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
