<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - FUEL INJECTOR LEFT BANK REAR INJECTOR, REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1210044" wtscode="A12-1137" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>FUEL INJECTOR LEFT BANK REAR INJECTOR, REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>1000</model>
        <modelyr>1996</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <tran>International 6+1</tran>
        <config>RPS Model</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open hood, disconnect support shocks, and raise hood support for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete engine cover housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove floor panel section by accelerator pedal area for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both charge air pipes and air intake pipe for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wire harness and hose support clamps at frame area left side. Secure hose for
                    access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wire harness at valve cover and reposition for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hose clamp at valve cover breather tube and remove breather tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wire connection at valve cover gasket connection.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts/nuts and retaining valve cover. Remove cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel and oil plugs from cylinder head to relieve pressure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wire connector at injector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove injector oil spill spout. Remove injector hold down clamp bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove injector seals.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install injector seals and lubricate with clean engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install shoulder bolt and torque bolt. Install injector with hold down and torque hold
                    down bolt. Install oil spill spout and secure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel and oil plugs on cylinder head and torque plugs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts/nuts/retaining valve cover. Torque bolts/nuts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wire connection at valve cover gasket connection.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install breather tube and secure with hose clamp.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wire harness and hose support clamps at frame area left side and secure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install both charge air pipes and air intake pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install floor panel section by accelerator pedal area.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install complete engine cover housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect hood and support shocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check engine oil, start engine, and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test vehicle to bleed air from oil supplied to injector.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
