<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - OIL PAN AND/OR GASKET (3600, V-8), REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1236020" wtscode="A12-1222" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>OIL PAN AND/OR GASKET (3600, V-8), REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>3600</model>
        <modelyr>1995</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <tran>Automatic</tran>
        <config></config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise front of vehicle and support.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect hood support cables -- support hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air filter, and pipe assembly and mounting bracket for better access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect entrance door (right side) remote control rod at door.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inside bus, remove engine compartment cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil at pan and coolant from radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine oil filter and water (coolant) filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove water (coolant) filter header and related piping for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air piping at left side of radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove power steering hose clamp at frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen engine front mount bolts at block (do not remove bolts at this time).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine fan blade from fan drive (let blade rest on shaft).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower radiator "U" pipe for access for later moving engine crossmember forward.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts and nuts securing engine crossmember brackets to frame rails (4 on each
                    side).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove nut from bolt securing engine front mount to crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil dipstick tube, which is secured at exhaust manifold and rear of engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove brackets routing automatic transmission cooler lines, wire harness loom with
                    brackets, and ground cable from engine crossmember and block for access to oil pan.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is not necessary to disconnect transmission cooler lines from cooler.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position overhead lifting device; route chain hook through opening at the alternator-A/C
                    mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise engine slightly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine front mount bolts from block and position mount forward approximately
                    (1.5) inches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide engine mount crossmember forward, as far as possible to allow access for oil pan
                    removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan from engine block using special tool, hammer and pry bars to cut sealant
                    material and loosen pan from mating surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan from under chassis.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Depending on front axle/spring application, it may be necessary to increase the distance
                            between the frame rails and the axle in order to remove and re-install the pan. To
                            accomplish this, position a hydraulic floor jack and block of wood under the radiator
                            crossmember, and raise the chassis approximately 3 to 4 inches.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean oil pan and engine block mating surfaces.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Straighten oil pan lip.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is important that the pan lip be as straight and smooth as possible. Inspect the lip
                            for cracks or gouges.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before applying sealant, position the oil pan under the chassis to establish proper
                    routing of the pan to block mating surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Apply a slightly heavier than normal bead of sealant in the valleys on the ends of the
                            pan.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position oil pan to engine block mating surface, taking care not to rub off any sealant
                    from the lip of the pan.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pan bolts and torque bolts in proper sequence.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If applicable, lower and remove hydraulic floor jack from under radiator crossmember.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position engine crossmember, install fasteners and secure crossmember to frame rails.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position engine front mount to block. Install bolts securing engine mount to block and
                    torque to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower and remove engine lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install nut securing front engine mount to crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and secure brackets routing transmission cooler lines, wire harness loom with
                    brackets, and ground cable to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install water (coolant) pump header and associated piping.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine water (coolant) filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lower radiator "U" pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering hose clamp at frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan blade to fan clutch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air piping.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine oil dipstick tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine coolant system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inside bus, install rear engine compartment cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install entrance door (right side) remote control rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood support cables.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine, run to normal operating temperature, and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
