<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - SERVICE ENGINE, REPLACE WITH SERVICE ENGINE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1239031" wtscode="A12-2030" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>SERVICE ENGINE, REPLACE WITH SERVICE ENGINE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>3900</model>
        <model>3000FE</model>
        <modelyr>1994</modelyr>
        <engine>DT 466</engine>
        <tran>Automatic</tran>
        <config></config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove grille and front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil and coolant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air line and wire to shutter solenoid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect spring at radiator retractable fill spout. Remove spout pivot arm retaining
                    bolts at support bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect coolant hose from radiator and fill spout.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all hose connections from upper radiator section; include wire harness
                    connections / clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove radiator support struts at engine mount brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect lower radiator hose at radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission cooler lines at radiator. Cap ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen lower radiator support bolts. Pull radiator assembly forward for access. Remove
                    heater hose support bracket at radiator frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to radiator assembly. Remove lower radiator bolt. Remove radiator
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan / clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove radiator support strut bracket from engine. Remove upper radiator, by-pass and
                    heater hoses from front of engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring. Remove alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove exhaust manifold with turbo attache;, include disconnect air filter connection.
                    Remove oil line and crankcase breather tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect accelerator linkage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air compressor main line and air filter hose at air compressor. Disconnect
                    all wire harness clamps and wire connections necessary to remove engine, to include disconnect oil
                    line and hoses at governor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect power steering hoses at pump. Catch fluid and secure hoses out of way for
                    access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove skid plate from front crossmember, include hose support clamps at crossmember.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fuel lines at filter, also at transmission support brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect coolant and heater hoses at water pump outlet. Secure out of way for
                    access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect drive shaft safety bracket, also remove drive shaft. Disconnect transmission
                    shift linkage at transmission. Remove bell housing bolts retaining support brackets, include
                    disconnect ground wires attached to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine mount bolt and disconnect air line support bracket at left rear
                    engine mount.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining front crossmember except (2).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer right side engine lift bracket to rear section of engine right side, for better
                    engine balance, while lifting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use fork lift. Support engine. Remove rear engine mount from left side of engine. Remove
                    remaining bolts retaining front crossmember. Remove crossmember. Remove engine with transmission.
                    This operation will take 2 people.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Be sure that the fork does not slide past the lifting chain when pulling the engine out of
                            vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer all necessary engine parts and transmission to new engine.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new engine with transferred parts and transmission onto fork lift.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place engine in vehicle (2 people).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rear engine mount and front crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower engine in position. Secure engine mounts front and rear. Remove fork lift and
                    chain.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer engine lifting bracket to front original position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air line to support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect drive shaft, safety support bracket and support bracket attached to transmission
                    bell housing. Connect transmission linkage and engine grounds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect coolant and heater hoses to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel lines and support brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install skid plate and hose support clamps to front crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect power steering hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all wire harness connections, and oil lines / hoses to air compressor and
                    governor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect accelerator linkage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install exhaust manifold with turbo. Connect air filter assembly, oil line and crankcase
                    breather tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator and wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator support strut bracket to engine. Connect all coolant hoses to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan / clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator assembly; include secure / remove lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all hoses to radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission cooler lines to radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator support struts at engine mount bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install all wire harness connections and retaining clamps.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install coolant fill spout.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect shutter hose and wire to shutter solenoid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil, coolant system, power steering and transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine, check for leaks and operation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed power steering per manual instructions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install grille and bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test vehicle. Check for leaks. Refill fluids as needed.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
