<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - REPLACE ENGINE WITH SERVICE ENGINE (V-8)</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1247007" wtscode="A12-2070" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>REPLACE ENGINE WITH SERVICE ENGINE (V-8)</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4700</model>
        <model>3800</model>
        <modelyr>1995</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <tran>International 6+1</tran>
        <config>This vehicle is equipped with air conditioning.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect batteries.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood -- includes: disconnect wiring harness, support cables, and pivot pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air pipes and air filter/pipe assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate A/C system, if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the following hoses and lines: A/C condenser lines at condenser, all cooling
                    system hoses at radiator, and power steering hoses at pump and reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove radiator/charge air cooler assembly -- includes: removal of clamps, support
                    brackets, upper and lower radiator support struts, and connection of overhead lifting device to lift
                    radiator assembly from chassis.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan/clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan/clutch pulley bolts; remove serpentine belt and fan pulley.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wires from alternator; remove alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining A/C compressor mounting bracket to engine; secure A/C compressor
                    and bracket to air filter mounting bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fuel line hoses at filter; disconnect upper/lower radiator hoses and heater
                    hoses from engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all wiring necessary to remove engine from chassis -- includes: wiring to
                    transmission, all support clamps and brackets, and time to mark wiring for re-installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect vacuum hose, high oil pressure line and exhaust pipe at turbo.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close fuel valve, disconnect fuel line at fuel tank and cap ends, and remove fuel
                    crossover support brace at fuel tanks for access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission shift stick cover boot.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission shift tower from top of transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect prop shaft at front carrier bearing and transmission; support and secure prop
                    shaft to one side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect emergency brake cable and clutch linkage arm from transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all transmission bolts except for two (2); remove clutch inspection cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and install transmission jack to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two remaining transmission bolts; remove transmission from rear of engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air intake y-pipe at air intake plenum.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front and rear engine mount bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install overhead lifting device and remove engine from chassis (two people).</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the new engine positioned near the engine being replaced, transfer the following:
                    clutch, fittings, alternator, chassis wiring harness, air compressor, optional sensors (the sensors
                    required for engine operation are provided with the service engine), and starter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install overhead lifting device and position new engine into chassis (two people).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install motor mount bolts and secure engine to mounts; torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and install transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect prop shaft and torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air intake y-pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect emergency brake cable and clutch linkage arm to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install transmission shift tower to top of transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install transmission shift stick cover boot.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel line at fuel tank and open valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect vacuum hose, high oil pressure line and exhaust pipe at turbo.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all wiring necessary to install engine to chassis -- includes: wiring to
                    transmission, all support clamps and brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect fuel line hoses at filter, as well as upper and lower radiator hoses and heater
                    hoses to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install A/C compressor and bracket to engine, if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator and connect wires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan drive pulley and serpentine drive belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan/clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator/charge air cooler assembly. -- includes: installation of clamps,
                    support brackets, upper and lower radiator support struts, and connection of overhead lifting device
                    to lift radiator assembly from chassis.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the following hoses and lines: A/C condenser lines at condenser, all cooling
                    system hoses at radiator, and power steering hoses at pump and reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air pipes and air filter/pipe assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge A/C system, if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed power steering system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect batteries.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test drive.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
