<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - OIL PAN AND/OR GASKET (V-8), REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1247008" wtscode="A12-1221" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>OIL PAN AND/OR GASKET (V-8), REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4700</model>
        <model>3800</model>
        <modelyr>1997</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain radiator and remove coolant filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Step 4 applies to vehicles with engines built after 10/3/94.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove coolant surge tank hose mount bracket at radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil dipstick tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air pipe from radiator frame (left side).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan blade from clutch, and slide on shaft toward front of engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Under chassis, remove front engine mount to crossmember nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove (4) bolts and nuts from the left and right side frame rails (2 at top of frame
                    rail flange and 2 at bottom of frame rail flange), securing front engine mount crossmember brackets.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If vehicle is equipped with air brakes, the air compressor and bracket must be removed for
                            access to one of the left side crossmember bracket bolts.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install overhead lifting device to lift eye at front top of engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine mount bolts from block and position the mount forward approx. 1.5
                    inches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using hammer, drive engine mount crossmember forward approximately 1 inch for oil pan
                    access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan, using special tool to cut sealant material, along with pry bars to break
                    pan loose from mating surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pan from under chassis.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Depending on front axle/spring application, it may be necessary to increase the distance
                            between the frame rails and the axle in order to remove the pan. Position a hydraulic floor
                            jack and block of wood under the radiator crossmember and raise the chassis approximately 3
                            to 4 inches.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean oil pan and engine block mating surfaces, using special cleaner.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is very important that all of the original sealant is removed and that the pan, block,
                            and rear plate mating surfaces are clean and dry before resealing.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Straighten oil pan lip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before applying sealant, position the oil pan under the chassis to establish proper
                    routing of the pan to block mating surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant to lip of oil pan. Apply a slightly heavier than normal bead of sealant in
                    the valleys on the ends of the pan.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position oil pan to engine block mating surface, taking care not to rub off any of the
                    sealant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pan bolts and torque bolts in sequence to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position engine crossmember bracket fasteners and secure crossmember to frame rails.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position front engine mount and secure to engine block and torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine mount to crossmember nut, and torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan blade to clutch, and torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air pipe to radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil dipstick tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install coolant surge tank hose mount bracket at radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install coolant filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill coolant system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine, run to normal operating temperature, and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
