<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE FRONT COVER - BOTH SECTIONS (I-6E), REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1249035" wtscode="A12-1193" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE FRONT COVER - BOTH SECTIONS (I-6E), REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4900</model>
        <model>3800</model>
        <modelyr>1997</modelyr>
        <engine>DT 466E</engine>
        <tran>Spicer 7 Speed</tran>
        <config>Vehicle is equipped with air conditioning and air brakes.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise vehicle and support vehicle with wood blocks under front tires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood assembly (2 people).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate A/C system (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove power steering reservoir from radiator frame. Lay aside and secure.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not open system.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all coolant hoses necessary to remove radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect A/C lines at A/C dryer and A/C compressor (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper and side radiator assembly support struts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan/clutch assembly. Use proper tools.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Left hand threads.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to radiator assembly. Remove lower radiator bolt. Remove radiator
                    assembly as one unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all drive belts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan drive belt tensioner.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan drive pulley and fan drive housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankshaft damper. Use puller.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pump assembly, include crankshaft drift key.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove water pump pulley and pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove camshaft position sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove coolant filter for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect alternator wiring. Remove alternator mount bracket with alternator
                    attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil. Remove oil pan.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pick up tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen bolts retaining air compressor rear support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining air compressor to front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining front engine mount to crossmember. Use bottle jack, raise/lower
                    engine and remove front engine mount bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining front cover. Remove front cover front section.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Stop here if repair is only to the front section of the front cover.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align timing marks on all gears.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring at computer. Remove computer and computer mount bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring at IPR sensor. Disconnect oil and fuel lines from high pressure oil
                    pump. Remove high pressure oil pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both idler gears.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove camshaft timing disc from cam gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark camshaft gear in relation to rear cover. Move cam gear slightly in order to remove
                    bolt behind cam gear hole opening. Remove bolt
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This will allow the cam gear puller to take good hold of cam gear for removal. Remove cam
                            gear.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower radiator hose from cover. Disconnect heater hoses from front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining rear section of front cover. Remove rear section.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use marker crayon, heat cam gear for installation per manual.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all gasket and mating surface area before installation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new gasket to rear cover. Install rear cover. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With camshaft gear heated to 350&#176;, install cam gear. After cam gear cools off,
                    reposition to original location as marked before removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install camshaft timing disc. Torque screws to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install both idler gears. Torque bolts to spec. per manual. Note timing marks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install high pressure oil pump with new gasket. Torque bolts to spec. Connect oil lines,
                    fuel lines and IPR wiring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check all timing marks to be sure they are in proper alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new gasket to front cover front section. Install front cover. Torque bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine mount. Torque bolts to spec. Remove bottle jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts retaining air compressor to front cover. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten/torque bolts at air compressor rear support bracket.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Torque bolts after front cover bolts have been torqued.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pick up tube and gasket. Install oil pan and gasket. Torque all bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator support bracket with alternator attached. Torque bolts to spec.
                    Connect alternator wiring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install camshaft position sensor with new O-ring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install heater hoses and lower radiator hose to rear section of front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new coolant filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pump assembly with new gaskets; include crank drift key. Torque bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install water pump with new gasket. Install pulley. Torque all bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankshaft damper. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Heat damper with heating tool per manual before installation.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan drive housing and pulley. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install computer support bracket and computer include wiring. Torque all bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan drive belt tensioner. Torque bolt to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install all belts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator in position. Leave lifting device attached.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan/clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install radiator upper/side support struts and lower radiator support bolt. Remove
                    lifting device.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all coolant hoses to radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering reservoir to radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install A/C lines to A/C dryer and A/C compressor (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil to proper level.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood assembly (2 people).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge A/C system (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine. Check operation and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
