<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE, REPLACE WITH SERVICE ENGINE (V8-AUTO)</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1247028" wtscode="A12-2060" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE, REPLACE WITH SERVICE ENGINE (V8-AUTO)</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4700</model>
        <model>3800</model>
        <modelyr>1998</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <tran>Automatic</tran>
        <config>Vehicle has hydraulic brakes and NAVPAC computer. Radiator assembly includes: radiator, charge air
            cooler and shroud.
        </config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air filter assembly with pipe; include disconnect IAT sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring harness at computer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove computer from support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all hoses, fuel lines, wire harness and glow plug relay connected to computer
                    support bracket. Remove computer support bracket.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: The computer may be removed with the computer support bracket as a unit.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood; include disconnect wire harness and cable / spring. Remove hood hinge
                    pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate A/C system (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler pipes / hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove left side hood hinge bracket and radiator support strut bracket from radiator
                    frame. Remove power steering reservoir from side of radiator frame. Secure reservoir out of way for
                    access.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: do not open power steering system.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all coolant hoses necessary to remove radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both A/C lines at air conditioning compressor; include A/C line at A/C dryer
                    and A/C low pressure line at expansion valve (if applicable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper radiator support strut rods and right side lower radiator support strut
                    rod.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to radiator assembly. Tilt radiator assembly forward for access
                    to engine fan.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fan / clutch assembly from engine using special tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil cooler lines at radiator. Cap ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower radiator support nut. Remove radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring from alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining bracket supporting A/C compressor, alternator and belt tensioner.
                    Remove bracket with components attached as an assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all support clamps retaining main wire harness at top of engine area.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring at starter. Reposition main harness and secure out of way for
                    access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect map sensor. Remove air intake y - pipe. Cap open ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Siphon oil from high pressure oil pump reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect high pressure oil pump line at left cylinder head for access to power
                    steering pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove power steering pump, include disconnect hoses from support brackets. Reposition
                    pump and secure.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Do not open system.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect fuel line support brackets, include disconnect fuel lines at fuel filter
                    assembly. Reposition lines out of way and secure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all heater hoses and surge tank hose from engine. Secure out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect exhaust pipe at turbocharger. Secure out of way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission oil fill / dipstick from engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect chassis wire harness support clamp at rear of left cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise vehicle, support vehicle with wood block under tires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect block heater wiring at block heater.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all transmission oil cooler support brackets at engine. Secure out of way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front section of drive shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission oil cooler line support brackets at transmission bell housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove flywheel inspection plate. Remove bolts retaining torque converter to flywheel
                    flex plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove rear engine support mount through bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all bolts
                    <emph type="bold">except</emph>
                    3 retaining transmission to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and secure transmission jack to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove remaining 3 bolts retaining transmission to engine. Move transmission rearward
                    from engine to gain needed clearance. Leave transmission on jack.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine mount nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install over head lifting device to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Partially remove engine and remove ground strap from left rear of engine. Remove engine
                    from vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place engine on floor stands.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Have replacement engine on stands, ready to transfer parts.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer starter and ground strap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer thermostat / housing. Use new gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer all fittings, include block heater unit.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Clean threads and apply sealant to threads.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission adapter housing first, in order to transfer flywheel / flex plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer flywheel and flywheel flex plate. Torque bolts to spec. Install transmission
                    adapter housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer guide dowel pin from crankshaft (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove water filter and transfer front engine mount. Torque bolts to spec. Replace water
                    and oil filter.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Both engines will need to be raised / lowered</emph>. Fill new oil filter
                    with oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Transfer rear engine mounts. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil from old engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill new engine with oil to proper level.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to replacement engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Partially install engine in position. Install engine ground strap. Complete the
                    installation of the engine to the engine mounts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine mount bolts / nuts. Torque to spec. Remove lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install transmission to engine. Secure transmission to engine. Remove transmission
                    jack.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts retaining torque converter to flywheel flex plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install flywheel inspection plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to support brackets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install drive shaft. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect block heater wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect chassis wire harness to left rear side of cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil fill tube / dipstick tube to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect exhaust pipe to turbocharger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all heater hoses and surge tank hose to engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all fuel lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering pump with new gasket. Secure power steering hoses to support
                    brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect high pressure oil pump line to left cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air intake y-pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to starter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to map sensor. Connect main wire harness to engine support clamps.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wood blocks. Lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bracket supporting A/C compressor, alternator and belt tensioner. Torque bolts
                    to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place radiator assembly in position using lifting device. Install lower radiator support
                    nut. Do
                    <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                    tighten at this time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan / clutch assembly using special tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install upper and lower right side radiator support struts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lifting device from radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten lower radiator nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission oil cooler lines to radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all A/C lines (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all coolant lines to radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install power steering reservoir to radiator frame. Install left side hood hinge
                    bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install charge air cooler pipes / hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install computer support bracket base mounts to valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install computer support bracket. Connect glow plug relay, hoses, fuel lines and wire
                    harness to computer support bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install computer. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to computer. Torque to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air filter assembly with pipe. Connect wiring to IAT sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge A/C system (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood; include hood hinge pins, cables and wire harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine. Check engine operation. Check for fluid leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks. Road test vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
