<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE, REPLACE WITH NEW SKELETON (SHORT BLOCK)</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1240040" wtscode="A12-2120" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE, REPLACE WITH NEW SKELETON (SHORT BLOCK)</wtsdescrip>
        <model>4000</model>
        <model>3800</model>
        <model>3600</model>
        <model>3000RE</model>
        <model>1000</model>
        <modelyr>1996</modelyr>
        <engine>T 444E</engine>
        <tran>International 6+1</tran>
        <config>Vehicle has no A/C or air brakes.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine from vehicle and support engine with stands. Leave lifting device
                    attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove starter, clutch, flywheel and flywheel housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise engine to comfortable height and remove oil level gauge, oil level tube (oil
                    dipstick and dipstick tube), oil pan and oil pick-up tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support engine back on stands and remove lifting device.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air inlet y-pipe (crossover pipe).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove turbo to manifold exhaust tubes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove turbo and pedestal assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both exhaust manifolds.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove electronic engine wiring harness, include glow plug relay.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel filter assembly and fuel lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel transfer (tandem) pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Siphon oil from high pressure oil pump reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure oil pump reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure oil pump lines from pump and cylinder heads.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure oil pump gear access cover plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check high pressure oil pump gear backlash. Remove bolt retaining high pressure oil pump
                    gear to pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure oil pump. Remove gear.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Replace gear if backlash was not in spec.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both valve covers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wiring harness from valve cover gaskets, glow plugs and injectors. Remove valve
                    cover gaskets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all glow plugs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all oil director spouts and injectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all rocker arms and push rods.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Mark each location to allow for correct installation.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both cylinder heads.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil filter and discard. Remove oil cooler assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front engine mount bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove camshaft position sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankshaft damper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil pump housing and oil pump assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove water pump pulley and water pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fittings and sensor as needed for transfer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove new short block from crate and install block to engine stand. Secure damaged
                    block to shipping crate.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Replace all gaskets and seals. The valve cover gasket may be re-used if it
                        is not damaged.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all parts and mating surfaces as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cover. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install water pump. Torque bolts to spec. Install water pump pulley. Torque bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front crankshaft seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pump and lubricate outer gerotor gear with clean engine oil.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Observe stamping on oil pump gears for correct installation.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pump housing. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new front crankshaft seal using special tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace wear ring on damper using special tool. Install damper. Apply RTV to damper
                    washer and torque bolt to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check camshaft sensor clearance and shim if necessary. Install camshaft position
                    sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine mount bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil cooler assembly. Install new oil filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace both intake cover gaskets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new cylinder head gaskets. Install cylinder heads. Tighten bolts in proper
                    sequence and to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install push rods with copper color ball end up. Install rocker arms and torque bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all injector seals. Install injectors and oil director spouts. Torque bolts to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply " never seez " compound to glow plug threads. Install glow plugs. Torque to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve cover gaskets. Install wiring harness to glow plugs, injectors and valve
                    cover gaskets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install valve covers. Tighten bolts in proper sequence and to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert high pressure oil pump drive gear into opening on top of front cover. Install
                    high pressure oil pump and torque bolts to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts retaining high pressure oil pump drive gear to pump. Torque bolt to
                    spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply RTV to high pressure oil pump gear access cover plate. Install cover plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install gasket to top of front cover. Install high pressure oil pump reservoir. Torque
                    bolts to spec.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install high pressure oil pump lines to pump and cylinder heads.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel transfer (tandem) pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuel filter housing and fuel lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install glow plug relay and electronic engine wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install turbo pedestal and turbo. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air inlet y-pipe (crossover pipe).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pick-up tube and oil pan. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install flywheel housing. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install flywheel. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install clutch. Tighten bolts in proper sequence and to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to engine. Remove engine from engine stand. Reposition engine on
                    floor, support with stands. Leave lifting device connected to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install complete turbo and manifold exhaust system. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Apply " never seez " compound to exhaust flange bolts prior to assembly.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil dipstick tube and stick.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fittings and sensors as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install starter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine is ready to install into vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
