<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - ENGINE FRONT COVER - BOTH SECTIONS (I-6), REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1281003" wtscode="A12-1191" group="12">
        <wtsdescrip>ENGINE FRONT COVER - BOTH SECTIONS (I-6), REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>8100</model>
        <modelyr>1996</modelyr>
        <engine>530</engine>
        <tran>International 9 Speed</tran>
        <config>Vehicle is equipped with air conditioning.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels. Open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hood; include disconnect wiring (2 people).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete air filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate air conditioning system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air conditioning lines at condenser. Cap ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all coolant hoses to radiator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lifting device to radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect radiator support struts at frame mount.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen lower radiator support bolts. Tilt radiator assembly forward for access to engine
                    fan. Using proper tools, remove fan/clutch assembly.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Left hand threads.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower radiator support bolts. Remove radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove serpentine belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining fan pulley. Remove pulley. Remove bolts retaining fan mount.
                    Remove fan mount.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect line/hoses at air conditioning compressor. Cap ends. Remove bolts retaining
                    air conditioning compressor mount bracket. Remove compressor with bracket attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining belt tensioner. Remove tensioner.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring at alternator. Remove wiring support clamps.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining alternator support bracket. Remove bracket with alternator
                    attached.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining water pump pulley. Remove pulley. Remove bolts retaining water
                    pump. Remove pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining injection pump gear cover plate. Remove plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bring engine to number 1 firing order timing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining crankshaft damper. Use puller and remove damper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove crankshaft key way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining oil pump assembly. Remove oil pump assembly and gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and install front crankshaft seal and wear ring. Use special tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain engine oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining oil pan. Remove oil pan.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining oil pick up tube. Remove tube and gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both bolts retaining front engine mounts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use bottle jack and suitable block of wood to support the engine. Raise/lower engine as
                    needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining front engine mount bracket to block. Remove mount.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen bolts retaining air compressor rear support bracket at engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining air compressor to front cover.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not remove air compressor.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining front section of front cover. Remove front section of front
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>These are the steps for the front cover front section only. Continue for rear section of
                            front cover.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check to insure timing marks are in alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper and lower idler gear retaining bolts. Remove gears.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining injection pump gear. Remove gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>At this point, mark the position of camshaft gear to the rear section of the front cover.
                            This is done for reference only. The camshaft gear will need to be rotated slightly in order
                            for the jaws of the puller to fit into the opening of camshaft gear to remove it.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use special puller to remove camshaft gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove banjo fitting from outlet of fuel transfer pump for access.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen bolts retaining injection pump support bracket at engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove nuts retaining injection pump to front cover.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not remove injection pump.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove coolant filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect coolant hoses from rear section of front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining rear section front cover. Remove cover and gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove oil high pressure relief valve and seal from rear section of front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all necessary parts and mating surfaces.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Place camshaft gear in oven and heat to 350 degrees. Use temperature indicator stick. A
                            liquid smear will show at the specified temperature rating.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new gaskets on fuel injection pump, air compressor and rear section of front
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rear section of front cover. Torque all bolts.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Torque nuts retaining injection pump to rear section of front cover first, then torque
                            bolts retaining injection pump support bracket at engine.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install banjo fitting to fuel transfer pump.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil relief valve and seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect coolant hoses to rear section of front cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new coolant filter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With camshaft gear heated to 350 degrees, install gear to camshaft.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Use gloves intended for handling hot parts.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After gear has cooled, move gear to original position mark on rear section of front
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install upper and lower idler gears. Be sure gears are in proper time with outer gears.
                    Torque bolts.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A new upper idler bolt must be used.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install injection pump gear. Torque bolts. Recheck timing marks on all gears.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front section of front cover with new gasket. Torque bolts
                    <emph type="bold">except</emph>
                    alternator mount bracket bolts and air compressor bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque air compressor bolts first, then torque air compressor support bracket bolts at
                    engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front engine mount bracket to block. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower engine onto crossmember. Remove jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install engine mount bolts. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install water pump and pulley. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install injection pump gear cover plate. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pump pick up tube and gasket. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pump assembly. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crankshaft key way.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use special heating tool to heat damper.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Heat damper and install. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install alternator support bracket with alternator attached. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to alternator and secure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install belt tensioner. Torque bolt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air conditioning compressor mount with compressor attached. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan mount. Torque bolts. Install fan drive pulley. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install serpentine belts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil pan and gasket. Torque bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using lifting device, install radiator assembly in position. Do not tighten bolts at
                    this time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fan/clutch assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten radiator support struts and lower radiator support bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lifting device from radiator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all coolant hoses to radiator and engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all air conditioning lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install both charge air pipes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill cooling system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill engine oil to proper level.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge air conditioning system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hood; include connect wiring (2 people).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
