<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - TRANSMISSION (AIR RIDE DAY CAB, CAT. ENGINE), REMOVE/RE-INSTALL</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1394006" wtscode="F13-102" group="13">
        <wtsdescrip>TRANSMISSION (AIR RIDE DAY CAB, CAT. ENGINE), REMOVE/RE-INSTALL</wtsdescrip>
        <model>9400</model>
        <modelyr>1997</modelyr>
        <engine>Caterpillar 3406E</engine>
        <tran>Fuller 18 Speed</tran>
        <config>Air ride cab/dual vertical exhaust/air ride assembly includes: upper and lower mounting brackets, air
            bags, shock absorbers, leveling valve and air line.
        </config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels. Open hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise vehicle, support axle with stands.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open air tank drain valves, drain air pressure, and close valves.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using small bottle jack at rear frame rail of cab, support cab with jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air supply line from leveling valve. Disconnect air line from valve to air
                    bags, allow air to escape from air bags, and connect air line back to valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside of the cab, disconnect both safety belts from center trim panel at rear of
                    cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove screws retaining center trim panel. Remove bottom screws retaining trim to rear
                    glass window. Remove center trim panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull back bottom trim in center of cab for access to bolts retaining upper mounting
                    bracket of air ride assembly. Remove both bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove frame cat walk.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front drive shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining lower mounting bracket of air ride assembly to crossmember.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise cab using bottle jack to gain clearance to remove air ride assembly. Remove air
                    ride assembly.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Be sure hood is open to prevent damage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support cab with wood on one side of frame rail and jack on other frame rail.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air lines necessary to remove air tanks. Remove air tanks with frames.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air lines and wiring from air dryer. Remove air dryer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wiring/hose harness from crossmember located behind transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts retaining crossmember to side gussets located behind transmission. Remove
                    crossmember from right side frame rail first.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It may be necessary to use a hydraulic device to slightly spread frame rails for clearance
                            to remove crossmember. Do not remove gussets.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grind 1/8 inch off each end of crossmember to ease installation of crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove flex tube at both muffler inlet exhaust pipes. (y-pipe).</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Cut flex tube if necessary.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove exhaust clamps retaining y-pipe (rear of cab area).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect flex tube at exhaust pipe (turbo outlet pipe).</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Cut flex if necessary.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove y-pipe from vehicle.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>To remove y-pipe it may be necessary to remove jack. (Cab must be supported with wood
                            block on other side.) Position y-pipe rearward of previous jack position. Support cab with
                            jack. Remove wood block supporting cab. Remove y-pipe. Support cab with wood block and jack.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Working from rear of transmission, disconnect all air lines necessary to remove
                    transmission, include slave valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all electrical necessary to remove transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shift tower and lay off to the side.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect clutch linkage from clutch arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove clutch inspection cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain transmission fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect transmission cooler lines from transmission. Cap ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission temperature sensor from transmission. Temporarily install pipe plug
                    in sensor port.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all bolts
                    <emph type="bold">except</emph>
                    2 retaining transmission to engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and secure transmission jack to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove remaining 2 bolts retaining transmission. Remove transmission.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install transmission to engine. Install all bolts retaining transmission to engine,
                    include fuel hose/line support bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove transmission jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove pipe plug and install transmission temperature sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect transmission cooler lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install clutch inspection cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install shift tower.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect clutch linkage to clutch arm.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Adjust clutch after air ride assembly is installed and cab is at proper height.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all electrical to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all air lines to transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install crossmember. Torque bolts/nuts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wiring/hose harness to crossmember.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install exhaust y-pipe and all flex tubes. Install exhaust clamps retaining y-pipe.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position air ride assembly in place.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside cab, install bolts retaining upper mounting bracket of air ride assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install center trim panel, include screws retaining trim for rear glass window.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect both safety belts to rear of cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install bolts retaining lower mounting bracket of air ride assembly to crossmember.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air supply line to air ride leveling valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bottle jack/wood.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install drive shaft. Torque bolts to spec.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air dryer. Connect air lines and wiring to air dryer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air tank assembly. Connect air lines to air tanks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install frame cat walk.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build air pressure and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
