<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Procedural Guideline - CLUTCH ASSEMBLY, REPLACE</stitle>
    <wtsproc id="w1394003" wtscode="A13-100-3" group="11">
        <wtsdescrip>CLUTCH ASSEMBLY, REPLACE</wtsdescrip>
        <model>9400</model>
        <modelyr>1996</modelyr>
        <engine>Cummins N14</engine>
        <tran>International 9 Speed</tran>
        <config>Transmission removed (pull-type clutch); clutch caddie used.</config>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to clutch removal, install a clutch disc aligning tool to the driven disc and
                    release bearing assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two 5/8-inch wooden blocks between the clutch release bearing housing and the
                    clutch flywheel ring.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The wooden spacers relieve the heavy internal spring load in the clutch assembly.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install clutch caddie to clutch disc aligning tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the clutch retaining bolts in a criss-cross pattern.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This is done to prevent cocking and binding within the clutch.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When all bolts have been removed, slide the clutch assembly back and off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect clutch flywheel and clutch flywheel housing for runout.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSTALL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new pilot bearing in the flywheel. If the old bearing is to be re-used, it
                    must be cleaned and checked thoroughly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the front-driving disc assembly in the flywheel with the side stamped "flywheel"
                    facing the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the intermediate plate in the flywheel, locating the drive slots on the drive
                    pins.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If equipped with flat flywheel, use guide bolts.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install three anti-rattle springs equally spaced between drive pins. Install with the
                    curved side of the hole toward the flywheel face.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear heavy gloves when installing anti-rattle springs. They have sharp edges.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the clutch disc aligning tool through the hub of the rear driven disc with the
                    side stamped "pressure plate" facing the transmission. Insert the aligning tool through the hub of
                    the front driven disc and into the pilot bearing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the pressure plate assembly on the flywheel with the lock strap (wear
                    compensator assembly) aligned with the opening in the bell housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install clutch retaining bolts progressively in a criss-cross pattern to pull the clutch
                    ring into its proper position in the pilot bearing.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>See CTS-5000 for the proper sequence pattern of the clutch retaining bolts.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Torque clutch retaining bolts to specifications.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">As the clutch retaining bolts are tightened, the wood blocks should fall free. If they
                    do not fall free, be sure to remove them.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the aligning tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After entire job is performed, remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </wtsproc>
</isis>
