<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION, SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - LUBRICATION -
        WHEEL END LUBRICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>WHEEL END LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>In cases where wheel equipment is being installed, either new or after maintenance activity,
                        the lube cavities are empty. Bearings and seals must be manually supplied with adequate
                        lubricant or they will be severely damaged before the normal motion of the vehicle can supply
                        lube to the hub ends of the housing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1401273">Figure 73</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1401273" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401273" filename="../figg14/g1401273.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 73. Wheel Hub Lube Cavity</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To avoid the risk of premature damage to wheel bearings and seals, they must be "prelubed" any time
                the wheel equipment is being installed. There are two methods of doing this. The correct method will
                depend on the type of wheel equipment being used.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lubrication When Hubs Have No Filler Holes (Preferred Method*)</title>
            <para>(Follow procedure in numerical sequence.)</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill axle with lube through axle housing cover filler hole.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up left side of axle. Maintain this position for one minute to allow lube to flow
                    into wheel ends at right side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up right side of axle. Maintain this position for one minute to allow lube to flow
                    into wheel ends at left side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle level again, add lube through axle housing cover filler hole. The axle
                    should require two additional pints of lube to bring level up to bottom of filler hole.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>*The above procedure is the preferred method since it optimizes the lube supply to the wheel end
                components and axle sump.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternate Method of Wheel End Lubrication</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the wheel hub seal has been installed, charge the hub cavity with as much axle
                    lubricant as possible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prelube the bearings with clean axle lubricant at installation.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the hub has no cavity to accept a precharge of axle lube, the bearings can be prepacked
                            with a good quality grease instead of axle lube. However, excess grease should be removed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Exercise caution when mounting a precharged hub and drum assembly to prevent spilling
                            lubricant on the brake linings.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Hubs Equipped with Lube Filler Holes</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Pour a pint of standard axle lubricant into the hub through the cavity filler hole provided.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
