<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES: SPICER S100-S, S105-S, S135-S, S150-S - ASSEMBLE
        - DIFFERENTIAL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DIFFERENTIAL</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401726">Figure 26</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1401726" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401726" filename="../figg14/G1401726.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption>Figure 26. Differential Exploded View</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If ring gear was removed from differential case, re-install at this time. Bolt ring gear to
                differential case in three places, 120 degrees apart, before compressing rivet; this will eliminate ring
                gear runout. Use hydraulic or mechanical press and suitable riveting fixture (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401727">Figure 27</hotlnk>). Pressure requirement per rivet is 45 to 50 U.S. tons (41
                to 45 metric tons).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401727" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401727" filename="../figg14/G1401727.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Use Hydraulic or Mechanical Press and Suitable Riveting Fixture</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press bearing cones onto differential case halves. Place bearing cups on cones during
                remainder of assembly to prevent damage to bearings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a small amount of gear lubricant to all mating surfaces. This will aid in assembly by
                keeping parts together and providing initial lubrication.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place thrust washer and side gear in differential case flange half.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble pinion mates and thrust washers onto cross shaft. Place assembly in flange half
                differential case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place remaining side gear and thrust washer in position on differential pinions.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble case halves, making sure match marks are lined up.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install differential case bolts. Tighten evenly to 100 to 120 ft-lbs. (135 to 163 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
