<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - SYSTEM OPERATION - Auto Lift in Reverse
        Feature (Self-Steering Systems Only)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Auto Lift in Reverse Feature (Self-Steering Systems Only)</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; be aware of the Auto-Lift in Reverse
                    feature on trucks with self-steering lift axles. On trucks with self-steering lift axles, any axle
                    that is in the DOWN position when reverse is selected, will automatically raise to its UP position;
                    <emph type="boldundersc">AND</emph>
                    that axle
                    <emph type="bold">will automatically return to the down position</emph>
                    when the transmission is shifted out of reverse.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>The self-steer lift axles are not designed to be in the down position while the truck is backing.
            Therefore, on vehicles with self-steer axles, when the transmission is shifted into reverse, all lowered
            axles will automatically be raised to the up position, and the indicators on all of the lift axle switches
            will turn off. Shifting the transmission out of reverse will return power to the system, turning on the
            indicator on the AXLE ENABLE switch. If an axle UP/DOWN switch is in the DOWN position its indicator will
            also turn on and that axle will automatically be lowered to its down position.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
