<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES: SPICER S100-S, S105-S, S135-S, S150-S - REMOVE -
        CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Steam clean axle assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove drain plug and drain lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect drive shafts at rear U-joint.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If end yoke and/or seal is to be replaced, loosen yoke nut at this time.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove axle shaft flange nuts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold a large brass drift or a brass hammer against center of the axle shaft flange. Strike
                the drift with sharp blows from a large hammer or sledge until the axle shaft separates from the hub.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not strike the flange directly with a steel hammer or sledge. This may crack and splinter
                        material, possibly causing serious or fatal injury. Do not pry or chisel axle flange away from
                        hub; damage to sealing surfaces could occur.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove axle shafts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the differential carrier assembly on a roller jack. Secure as necessary to prevent
                it from falling off the jack when removed from the housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the carrier-to-housing mounting bolts. Remove all bolts except top two. These two
                bolts will prevent the carrier assembly from falling.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Separate differential carrier from the housing using removal slots (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401705">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Be certain carrier is balanced properly on jack, and
                remove top two carrier mounting bolts. Remove differential carrier assembly from the axle housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401705" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401705" filename="../figg14/G1401705.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Separate Differential Carrier From Housing Using Removal Slots</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount carrier assembly in a suitable rebuild stand. (Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14017v_27.xml" xrefid="hl1401701">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.)
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
