<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION, SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - WHEEL
        DIFFERENTIAL LOCK - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401252">Figure 52</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1401252" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401252" filename="../figg14/G1401252.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 52. Wheel Differential Lock Operation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Differential Lock Engaged.</emph>
            Air pressure applied to the shift cylinder moves the piston, push rod, shift fork and sliding curvic clutch
            as an assembly. The sliding curvic clutch engages the fixed curvic clutch.
        </para>
        <para>The sliding clutch is splined to the axle shaft (double-splined shaft). The fixed clutch is splined to the
            differential case hub. Engaging the two clutches locks the wheel differential, thus preventing wheel
            differential action.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Differential Lock Disengaged.</emph>
            When air pressure at the shift cylinder is released, a compression spring (mounted on the push rod) moves
            the push rod, shift fork and sliding clutch as an assembly. The sliding clutch moves out of engagement with
            the fixed clutch. The wheel differential is unlocked and operates normally.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Differential Lock Engagement Indicator</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Differential lock engagement is detected by a switch (electric) mounted on the differential carrier. An
            actuator, mounted on the shift fork push rod, operates the switch.
        </para>
        <para>When the shift fork moves to engage the differential lock, the switch actuator moves away from the switch,
            allows the switch to close and send an electrical signal to turn on a cab-mounted indicator light (or an
            audible signal).
        </para>
        <para>When the shift fork moves to disengage the differential lock, the compression spring also moves the
            actuator to contact the switch. The switch is opened and turns off the cab-mounted indicator light (or the
            audible signal).
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
