<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>2 SPEED AND DOUBLE REDUCTION SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - ADJUST/INSTALL - ADJUST RING GEAR TOOTH CONTACT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="7">
        <title>ADJUST RING GEAR TOOTH CONTACT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>After differential bearing preload and gear backlash adjustment is complete, check gear tooth contact
                pattern and adjust if necessary (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401645">Figure 45</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401645" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401645" filename="../figg14/g1401645.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 45. Ring Gear Tooth Contact Adjustment</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (New Gearing)</title>
            <para>Paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and roll the gear to obtain a contact pattern as shown in
                the figures. The length of the pattern in an unloaded condition is approximately one half to two thirds
                of the ring gear tooth in most models and ratios (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401646">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401646" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401646" filename="../figg14/g1401646.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Correct Pattern (New Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (Used Gearing)</title>
            <para>Used gearing may not display the square, even contact pattern found in new gear sets. The gear may
                have a "pocket" at the heel end of the contact pattern (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401647">Figure 47</hotlnk>). The more use a gear has had, the more the pocket becomes
                the dominant characteristic of the pattern.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401647" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401647" filename="../figg14/g1401647.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Typical Pattern (Used Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Adjust used gear sets to display the same contact pattern observed before disassembly. A correct
                pattern is up slightly off the toe and centers evenly along the face width between the top land and
                root. Otherwise, the length and shape of the pattern are highly variable and are considered acceptable
                as long as there is some pattern on toe end of the tooth.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Tooth contact patterns are a function of the relative positions of the ring gear and pinion.
                        An improper pattern will require relocation of either or both. Always adjust pinion position
                        first, then ring gear position. Recheck backlash when done.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Pinion Position</title>
            <para>If the contact pattern shows incorrect tooth depth contact, change drive pinion position by altering
                the shim pack under the cage and cup assembly. Used gears should achieve proper contact with the same
                shims removed from the axle at disassembly.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is too close to the root of the gear tooth, add pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401648">Figure 48</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401648" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401648" filename="../figg14/g1401648.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Pinion Position (Incorrect Pattern)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If the pattern is too close to the top land of the gear tooth, remove pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401649">Figure 49</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401649" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401649" filename="../figg14/g1401649.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. Pinion Position (Incorrect Pattern)</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Check ring gear backlash after each shim change and adjust if necessary to maintain correct
                        backlash (refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s14016_21.xml" xrefid="hl1401612">Backlash Specifications</hotlnk>). Always
                        recheck tooth contact pattern after making shim pack changes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Backlash</title>
            <para>If the contact pattern shows incorrect face width contact, change backlash and recheck the contact
                pattern.
            </para>
            <para>With the pattern concentrated at the toe (too far down the tooth) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401650">Figure 50</hotlnk>), ADD BACKLASH by loosening the bearing adjuster on the
                teeth side of ring gear several notches. Loosen the opposite adjuster one notch.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401650" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401650" filename="../figg14/g1401650.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Backlash Adjustment (Incorrect Pattern)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Tighten adjuster on teeth side of ring gear until it contacts the bearing cup. Continue tightening the
                same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is concentrated at the heel (too far up the tooth) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401651">Figure 51</hotlnk>), REMOVE BACKLASH by loosening the bearing adjuster on the
                teeth side of ring gear several notches. Tighten the opposite adjuster one notch.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401651" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401651" filename="../figg14/g1401651.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. Backlash Adjustment (Incorrect Pattern)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Tighten adjuster on teeth side of ring gear until it contacts the bearing cup. Continue tightening the
                same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
            <para>When preload, backlash, and tooth contact are correct, align differential bearing adjusters and locks,
                then tighten differential bearing cap bolts. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14016_HL1401602.xml" xrefid="hl1401602">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
