<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - CONTROLS - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl14019076" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This section describes the operation of the electrical control system used in the lift axle system.
                The
                <emph type="underscr">operation</emph>
                of the pneumatic controls is described in the sections covering each axle type;
                <hotlnk document="s14019_15.xml" xrefid="hl14019050">FIXED AXLE ASSEMBLIES</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl14019050"/>, or
                <hotlnk document="s14019_24.xml" xrefid="hl14019060">SELF-STEERING AXLE ASSEMBLIES</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl14019060"/>.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1401907a">
            <title>ENABLING THE LIFT AXLE SYSTEM</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; set all UP/DOWN switches to the
                        UP position before enabling the system (pressing the AXLE ENABLE switch). If any axle UP/DOWN
                        switch is in the DOWN position when the ignition is switched off, the axle controlled by that
                        switch will automatically raise to its up position. Enabling the lift axle system with an axle
                        UP/DOWN switch in the DOWN position will cause that axle to be immediately lowered. The position
                        of the UP/DOWN switches should be checked carefully because the DOWN indicators on the switches
                        are always unlit (in either switch position) until the system is enabled.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Vehicles with self-steering lift axles cannot be enabled while the transmission is in
                        reverse.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is good practice to place all axle UP/DOWN switches to the UP position before enabling the
                        system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the lift axle system is not enabled, no voltage is applied to the electrically controlled air
                solenoid. When the solenoid is not energized, the pressurized supply air is routed through the solenoid
                to the lift bags, keeping the lift axles in the UP position. To allow connector identification, the
                following description of lift axle 1 assumes that this system has a single pusher axle that is located
                immediately ahead of the rear drive axles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019a">FIGURE 41</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019a"/>
                for a fixed lift axle and
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019b">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019b"/>
                for a self-steering lift axle.
            </para>
            <para>Turning on the vehicle ignition provides +12 Vdc to one side of the AXLE ENABLE momentary switch.
                Pressing the AXLE ENABLE switch will apply power to the AXLE ENABLE relay at connector 1021, terminal 5.
                The relay is wired to 'latch up', routing the +12 Vdc from connector 1019, terminal B through connector
                1021, terminal 1 and the relay contacts to terminal 4 of connector 1021. Once energized, this relay will
                stay in this state (latched up) until the +12 Vdc is removed from connector 1021, terminal 1 (ignition
                must be turned off). In this condition pressing or releasing the AXLE ENABLE switch will have no effect
                on the system.
            </para>
            <para>On fixed axle trucks, the voltage from connector 1021, terminal 4 is routed to the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN
                switch at connector 1022, terminal 2B. This switch controls the position of lift axle 1. To indicate
                that the system is enabled the +12 Vdc is also routed to connector 1020, terminal 8 where it lights the
                indicator in the AXLE ENABLE switch.
            </para>
            <para>On trucks with self-steer axles, the voltage from connector 1021, terminal 4 is routed to the reverse
                lift relay at connector 1916, terminal 1. If the vehicle transmission is NOT in reverse, the voltage
                passes through the 'normally closed' relay contacts to 1916, terminal 3. The voltage from connector
                1916, terminal 3 is routed to the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switch at connector 1022, terminal 2B. This switch
                controls the position of lift axle 1. To indicate that the system is enabled the +12 Vdc is also routed
                to connector 1020, terminal 8 where it lights the indicator in the AXLE ENABLE switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LOWERING THE LIFT AXLE</title>
            <para>To lower a lift axle, an electrical signal must energize the air solenoid. The solenoid will switch
                the pressurized air from the lift bags to the load bags. To allow connector identification, the
                following description of lift axle 1 assumes that this system has a single pusher axle that is located
                immediately ahead of the rear drive axles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019b">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019b"/>.
            </para>
            <para>With the lift axle system enabled (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl1401907a">ENABLING THE LIFT AXLE SYSTEM</hotlnk>), +12 Vdc is applied to the AXLE 1
                UP/DOWN switch at terminal 2B of connector 1022. While in the UP position, the switch contacts are open
                and no voltage is applied to the solenoid. When the solenoid is not energized, the supply air is routed
                through the solenoid and the lift bag QRVs to the lift bags, keeping the axle in the UP position.
            </para>
            <para>When the switch is set to the DOWN position, the +12 Vdc is routed through the switch contacts,
                connector 1022, terminal 1 and connectors 1027, 9761 and 9762 to the solenoid. With the other side of
                the solenoid connected to ground through connectors 9762 and 9700, the solenoid will become energized.
                In this condition, the solenoid and the lift bag QRVs vent the air in the lift bags to the atmosphere
                and route the pressurized air to the load bags, through the pressure regulator and the load bag QRV.
                With the switch in the DOWN position, +12 Vdc is also applied to terminal 8 of connector 1022, causing
                the indicator in the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switch to light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RAISING THE LIFT AXLE</title>
            <para>To raise a lift axle, the +12Vdc electrical control signal must be removed from the solenoid. The
                de-energized solenoid will vent the air in the load bags to the atmosphere and route the pressurized air
                from the tank to the lift bags, raising the axle to the UP position. To allow connector identification,
                the following description of lift axle 1 assumes that this system has a single pusher axle that is
                located immediately ahead of the rear drive axles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019b">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019b"/>.
            </para>
            <para>While the UP/DOWN switch is set in the DOWN position, +12 Vdc is routed through the switch contacts
                (and connectors 1027, 9761 and 9762) to energize the air solenoid. When the switch is set to the UP
                position, the voltage at connector 1022, terminal 2B is blocked by the open switch contacts. With no
                voltage applied to the solenoid, the solenoid becomes de-energized. The de-energized solenoid will stop
                applying pressurized air to the load bag QRV. The QRV and solenoid will vent the air in the load bags to
                the atmosphere. The solenoid will now route the pressurized air from the tank to the lift bags through
                the lift bag QRVs, raising the axle to the UP position. With the switch in the UP position, +12 Vdc is
                also removed from terminal 8 of connector 1022, turning off the indicator in the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1401907b">
            <title>DISABLING THE LIFT AXLE SYSTEM</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; set all UP/DOWN switches to the
                        UP position before enabling the system (pressing the AXLE ENABLE switch). If any axle UP/DOWN
                        switch is in the DOWN position when the ignition is switched off, the axle controlled by that
                        switch will automatically raise to its up position. Enabling the lift axle system with an axle
                        UP/DOWN switch in the DOWN position will cause that axle to be immediately lowered. The position
                        of the UP/DOWN switches should be checked carefully because the DOWN indicators on the switches
                        are always unlit (in either switch position) until the system is enabled.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is good practice to place all axle UP/DOWN switches to the UP position before disabling the
                        system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the lift axle system is disabled, no voltage is being passed through the AXLE ENABLE switch or
                the axle enable relay. Voltage is not present at the AXLE UP/DOWN switches or the reverse lift relay
                (self-steering axle systems only). This also means that no voltage is applied to the air solenoid. The
                de-energized solenoid routes the pressurized air from the tank to the lift bags, raising the lift axles
                or keeping the lift axles in the UP position. The air in the load bags is vented to the atmosphere. Once
                the ignition has been turned off, the lift axle system can be enabled only by switching the ignition on
                and then pressing the AXLE ENABLE switch. To allow connector identification, the following description
                of lift axle 1 assumes that this system has a single pusher axle that is located immediately ahead of
                the rear drive axles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019a">FIGURE 41</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019a"/>
                for a fixed lift axle and
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019b">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019b"/>
                for a self-steering lift axle.
            </para>
            <para>The lift axle system is disabled by switching the vehicle ignition off. This removes the switched +12
                Vdc from connector 1019, terminal B and connector 1021, terminals 1, 4 and 5. This condition
                de-energizes (unlatches) the axle enable relay, opening the contacts between terminals 4 and 1 of
                connector 1021.
            </para>
            <para>On fixed axle systems the open relay contacts remove power from terminal 8 of connector 1020 and from
                the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switch at connector 1022, terminal 2B. With no voltage at connector 1020, terminal 8
                the indicator in the AXLE ENABLE switch will turn off. With no voltage at connector 1022, terminal 2B
                the indicator in the AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switch will turn off regardless of the switch position.
            </para>
            <para>On self-steering axle systems the open contacts of the axle enable relay removes +12 Vdc from the
                reverse lift relay at connector 1916, terminal 1. With the reverse lift relay contacts closed, the
                voltage is also removed from connector 1916, terminal 3; connector 1020, terminal 8; and connector 1022,
                terminal 2B. This action turns off the indicators in the AXLE ENABLE and AXLE 1 UP/DOWN switches as
                described in the previous paragraph.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AUTO LIFT IN REVERSE FEATURE (SELF-STEERING AXLE SYSTEMS ONLY)</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; be aware of the Auto-Lift in
                        Reverse feature on trucks with self-steering lift axles. On trucks with self-steering lift
                        axles, any axle that is in the DOWN position when reverse is selected, will automatically raise
                        to its UP position;
                        <emph type="boldundersc">AND</emph>
                        that axle
                        <emph type="bold">will automatically return to the down position</emph>
                        when the transmission is shifted out of reverse.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>On vehicles with self-steering lift axles, all lowered axles will automatically be raised to the UP
                position when the transmission is shifted into reverse. Also, the indicators on the AXLE ENABLE and all
                AXLE UP/DOWN switches will be turned off. It is important to note that this is NOT the same as disabling
                the system. In this condition the lift axles will return to their previous positions when the
                transmission is shifted out of reverse. It does NOT require cycling the ignition switch off or pressing
                the AXLE ENABLE switch. The following description assumes that the lift axle system is enabled and lift
                axle 1 is in the DOWN position. To allow connector identification, the following description of lift
                axle 1 assumes that this system has a single pusher axle that is located immediately ahead of the rear
                drive axles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml" xrefid="f14019b">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019b"/>.
            </para>
            <para>When reverse is selected +12 Vdc is applied to the reverse lift relay through connectors 9700; 9761;
                1917, terminal A; and connector 1916, terminal 5. The voltage energizes the relay, opening the contacts
                between terminals 1 and 3 of connector 1916. The open relay contacts remove power from terminal 8 of
                connector 1020, and from the AXLE UP/DOWN switch at connector 1022, terminal 2B. With no voltage at
                connector 1020, terminal 8 the indicator in the AXLE ENABLE switch will turn off. With the AXLE 1
                UP/DOWN switch contacts closed, the lack of voltage at connector 1022, terminals 2B and 8 will turn off
                the AXLE 1 DOWN indicator even though the switch is in the DOWN position. This action also removes power
                from the lift axle 1 solenoid through connectors 1027, 9761, and 9762. Any axles that were in the
                lowered position when reverse was selected, will be raised to the UP position.
            </para>
            <para>Unlike the 'disabled system' condition described earlier (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl1401907b">DISABLING THE LIFT AXLE SYSTEM</hotlnk>), the axle enable relay remains
                energized, providing +12 Vdc to the reverse lift relay at connector 1916, terminal 1. This allows the
                lift axle system to be returned to its previous operating condition by removing +12 Vdc from terminal 5
                of the reverse lift relay (shifting out of reverse). Shifting the transmission out of reverse removes
                the +12 Vdc from connector 1916, terminal 5; de-energizing the reverse lift relay, and closing the
                contacts between terminals 1 and 3 of connector 1916. This action will immediately enable the system by
                routing voltage to the AXLE UP/DOWN switches and the AXLE ENABLE indicator. If an axle UP/DOWN switch is
                in the DOWN position, that axle will automatically be lowered to its DOWN position and its indicator
                will light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_39.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
