<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS - WHEEL BEARING ADJUSTMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1400104">
        <title>WHEEL BEARING ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Satisfactory wheel seal operation as well as long bearing life depends on correct wheel bearing
                installation, cleanliness, lubrication and adjustment. The following will help you perform these
                required services for wheels and hubs.
            </para>
            <para>Wheels or hubs, bearing cups, nuts, locks, washers, shafts and spindles are to be clean from any
                foreign matter. Bearings must be pre-lubed before installation. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the proper lube specifications.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If new bearing(s) are being installed, the new bearings must be seated to insure maximum
                        service reliability. After the bearing and hub are assembled on the spindle, install the bearing
                        adjustment nut. Tighten the adjustment nut to 200 ft-lbs. (271 N&#8226;m) while rotating the hub
                        to seat the bearing. Back off the adjusting nut 1/2 turn and follow the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400105">BEARING END PLAY CHECK PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                        below.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc id="hl1400105" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="1">
            <title>BEARING END PLAY CHECK PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>This procedure is done with vehicle on floor stands.</para>
            <para>The bearing must be fully installed before checking end play (jam nut jammed). Use a dial indicator to
                measure hub end play (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400111">Figure 11</hotlnk>) with respect to the axle tube (spindle) with
                <emph type="bold">axle shaft not installed</emph>. It is recommended that the wheel assembly not be
                installed also.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400111" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400111" filename="../figg14/G1400111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Measuring End Play with Dial Indicator</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Mount the dial indicator to the drum or hub as illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400111">Figure 11</hotlnk>or to the bottom of the wheel (remove axle shaft if
                installed). Grasp drum, hub or tire at 3 o'clock and 9 o'clock position. First push, then pull evenly on
                the drum hub or tire to measure the amount of end play. Note total indicator reading.
            </para>
            <para>The bearing adjustment procedures are intended to result in .001 to .005 inch (.0254 to .127 mm) end
                play with no preload (measured after the jam nut is tightened).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
