<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - ASSEMBLE -
        CHECKING AND ADJUSTING THE END PLAY OF THE OUTPUT BEARING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CHECKING AND ADJUSTING THE END PLAY OF THE OUTPUT BEARING</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Specification:</emph>
            0.001-0.004 inch (0.025-0.102 mm) bearing end play.
        </para>
        <para>The end play of the output bearing is controlled by the size of the snap ring that holds the bearings in
            the output cage. The snap rings are available in increments of 0.003 inch (0.076 mm). Install the snap ring
            which results in an end play of 0.001 to 0.004 inch (0.025 to 0.102 mm).
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the output shaft and the bearing cage assembly in a vise with soft metal covers on the
                jaws of the vise.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a suitable tool to install the yoke or flange on the output shaft. DO NOT USE THE NUT TO
                DRAW THE YOKE ONTO THE SHAFT. DO NOT INSTALL THE OIL SEAL AT THIS TIME.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nut that fastens the yoke or flange to the output shaft. Put a holding tool on
                the yoke or flange and tighten the nut to 450 to 600 ft-lbs. (610 to 815 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the yoke or flange toward the cage and rotate the shaft in each direction to make sure
                that the bearings are correctly installed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a dial indicator so that the base of the indicator is on the mounting flange of the
                cage. The pointer of the indicator must touch the yoke or flange end of the output shaft. Adjust the
                dial indicator to the zero (0) setting (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011b6">Figure 116</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011b6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011b6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 116. Install Dial Indicator</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put pry bars under the yoke or flange and push the yoke or flange away from the cage. Record
                the reading on the dial indicator. The reading must be 0.001 to 0.004 inch (0.025 to 0.102 mm). The
                reading is the measurement of the end play on the output bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the end play reading is not within the 0.001 to 0.004 inch (0.025 to 0.102 mm)
                specification, remove and replace the snap ring that fastens the bearings in the cage. Install a thinner
                snap ring to increase end play. Install a thicker snap ring to decrease end play (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011b7">Figure 117</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011b7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011b7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 117. Output Bearing End Play</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. SNAP RING</callout1>
                <callout1>2. TO INCREASE END PLAY, INSTALL A THINNER SNAP RING. TO DECREASE END PLAY, INSTALL A THICKER
                    SNAP RING.
                </callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the nut that fastens the yoke or flange to the through shaft. Use a suitable puller
                tool to remove the yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
