<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - INSTALL -
        Checking the Tooth Contact Patterns of the Gear Set
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="11">
        <title>Checking the Tooth Contact Patterns of the Gear Set</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General Information</title>
            <para>In the following procedures, movement of the contact pattern along the length of the tooth is
                indicated as toward the "heel" or "toe" of the ring gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d5">Figure 135</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011d5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 135. Heel and Toe of Ring Gear</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Always check the tooth contact patterns on the drive side of the gear teeth (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d6">Figure 136</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011d6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 136. Check Tooth Contact Patterns on Drive Side</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tooth Contact Patterns</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the backlash of a new gear set to 0.012 inch (0.30 mm). Adjust the backlash of an
                    old gear set to the setting that was measured before the carrier was disassembled.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a marking compound to approximately 12 gear teeth of the ring gear. Rotate the
                    ring gear so that the 12 gear teeth are next to the drive pinion (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d7">Figure 137</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f14011d7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 137. Apply Marking Compound</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the ring gear forward and backward so that the 12 gear teeth go past the drive
                    pinion six times to get the contact pattern. Repeat, if needed, to get a more clear pattern.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Look at the contact patterns on the ring gear teeth. Compare the patterns to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d8">Figure 138</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d9">Figure 139</hotlnk>, and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e0">Figure 140</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <para>The location of a good hand-rolled contact pattern for a new gear set is toward the toe of the
                    gear tooth and in the center, between the top and the bottom of the tooth.
                </para>
                <para>When the carrier is being operated under load, the pattern will extend approxi- mately the full
                    length of the tooth. The top of the pattern will be near the top of the gear tooth (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e1">Figure 141</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>The location of a good hand-rolled pattern for a used gear set must match the wear pattern in the
                    ring gear. The contact pattern will be smaller in area than the wear pattern.
                </para>
                <para>If the contact pattern requires adjust- ment, continue by following Step 5 to move the contact
                    patterns to a deeper or shallower position on the gear teeth. If contact patterns are in the center
                    of the gear teeth, continue by following Step 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f14011d8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 138. Good Hand-Rolled Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011d9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 139. High Pattern</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011e0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 140. Low Pattern</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011e1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 141. Good Pattern in Operation</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Change the thickness of the shim pack between the pinion inner bearing cup and the
                    differential carrier to move the contact patterns between the top and the bottom of the gear teeth.
                    Use the following procedure:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A high-contact pattern indicates that the drive pinion was not installed deep enough into
                            the carrier. A deep- contact pattern indicates that the drive pinion was installed too far
                            in the carrier.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the drive pinion, the inner bearing cup and the shims from the carrier.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To correct a high-contact pattern, increase the thickness of the shim pack. When you
                        increase the thickness of the shim pack, the drive pinion will move toward the ring gear (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e2">Figure 142</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <para>To correct a deep-contact pattern, decrease the thickness of the shim pack. When you decrease
                        the thickness of the shim, the drive pinion will move away from the ring gear (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e3">Figure 143</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f14011e2" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 resolution="150"/>
                        <caption>Figure 142. Increase Shim Pack</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f14011e3" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 resolution="150"/>
                        <caption>Figure 143. Decrease Shim Pack</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the inner bearing cup, the shims and the drive pinion into the carrier.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat Steps 2-5 until the contact patterns are in the center between the top and
                        bottom of the gear teeth.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the backlash of the ring gear within the specification range to move the contact
                    patterns to the correct location along the length of the gear teeth.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Decrease backlash to move the contact patterns toward the toe of the ring gear teeth
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e4">Figure 144</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Increase backlash to move the contact patterns toward the heel of the ring gear
                        teeth (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14011e5">Figure 145</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat Steps 2-4 and 6 until the contact patterns are at the correct location along
                        the length of the gear teeth.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f14011e4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 144. Decrease Backlash to Move Contact Patterns Toward Toe</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011e5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011e5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 145. Increase Backlash to Move Contact Patterns Toward Heel</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After all the adjustments are finally completed, install the lock pin on the bearing cap
                    so that the pin is between the lugs of the adjusting ring.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_45.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_47.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
