<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION, SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - ADJUST - RING
        GEAR TOOTH CONTACT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="15">
        <title>RING GEAR TOOTH CONTACT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Axle Models 15040-23085</title>
            <para>After differential bearing preload and gear backlash adjustment is complete, check gear tooth contact
                pattern and adjust if necessary (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401236">Figure 36</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401236" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401236" filename="../figg14/g1401236.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Ring Gear Tooth Nomenclature</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (New Gearing)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401237">Figure 37</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401237" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401237" filename="../figg14/g1401237.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (New Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and roll gear to obtain a contact pattern as shown in the
                drawings. The length of pattern in an unloaded condition is approximately one half to two thirds of the
                ring gear tooth in most models and ratios.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (Used Gearing)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401238">Figure 38</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401238" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401238" filename="../figg14/g1401238.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (Used Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Used gearing may not display the square, even contact pattern found in new gear sets. The gear may
                have a "pocket" at heel end of contact pattern. The more use a gear has had, the more the pocket becomes
                the dominant characteristic of the pattern.
            </para>
            <para>Adjust used gear sets to display the same contact pattern observed before disassembly. A correct
                pattern is up slightly off the toe and centers evenly along the face width between the top land and
                root. Otherwise, the length and shape of the pattern are highly variable and are considered acceptable
                as long as there is some pattern on toe end of the tooth.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Tooth contact patterns are a function of the relative positions of ring gear and pinion. An
                        improper pattern will require relocation of either or both. Always adjust pinion position first,
                        then ring gear position. Recheck backlash when done.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before adjusting ring gear position in the following procedures, loosen thrust screw locknut
                        and back off thrust screw (if so equipped). This procedure is necessary to provide adequate
                        clearance and allow ring gear movement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Pinion Position</title>
            <para>If the contact pattern shows incorrect tooth depth contact, change drive pinion position by altering
                the shim pack under the cage and cup assembly. Used gears should achieve proper contact with the same
                shims removed from the axle at disassembly.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is too close to the root of the gear tooth, add pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401239">Figure 39</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401239" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401239" filename="../figg14/g1401239.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Pattern Too Close to Tooth Root</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If pattern is too close to the top land of gear tooth, remove pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401240">Figure 40</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401240" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401240" filename="../figg14/g1401240.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Pattern Too Close to Tooth Top Land</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Check ring gear backlash after each shim change and adjust if necessary to maintain correct
                        backlash. Always recheck tooth contact pattern after making shim pack changes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Backlash</title>
            <para>If contact pattern shows incorrect face width contact, change backlash and recheck contact pattern.
            </para>
            <para>With pattern concentrated at the toe (too far down tooth) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401241">Figure 41</hotlnk>), ADD BACKLASH by loosening the bearing adjuster on the
                teeth side of ring gear several notches. Loosen the opposite adjuster one notch.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401241" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401241" filename="../figg14/g1401241.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Pattern Too Close to Toe End of Tooth</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Return to adjuster on teeth side of ring gear and tighten adjuster until it contacts the bearing cup.
                Continue tightening the same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is concentrated at the heel (too far up the tooth) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401242">Figure 42</hotlnk>), REMOVE BACKLASH by loosening the bearing adjuster on the
                teeth side of ring gear several notches. Tighten the opposite adjuster one notch.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401242" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401242" filename="../figg14/g1401242.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Pattern Too Far Along Tooth Toward Tooth Heel End</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Return to adjuster on teeth side of ring gear and tighten adjuster until it contacts the bearing cup.
                Continue tightening the same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Axle Models 23105, 26105, 30105</title>
            <para>After differential bearing preload and gear backlash adjustment is complete, check gear tooth contact
                pattern and adjust if necessary.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (New Gearing)</title>
            <para>Paint the ring gear teeth with marking compound and roll the gear to obtain a contact pattern. The
                correct pattern is well centered on the ring gear tooth with lengthwise contact up off the toe. The
                length of the pattern in an unloaded condition is approximately one half to two thirds of the ring gear
                tooth in most models and ratios (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401243">Figure 43</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401243" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401243" filename="../figg14/g1401243.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (New Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (Used Gearing)</title>
            <para>Used gearing may not display the square, even contact pattern found in new gear sets. The gear will
                normally have a "pocket" at end of contact pattern. The more use a gear has had, the more the pocket
                becomes the dominant characteristic of the pattern (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401244">Figure 44</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401244" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401244" filename="../figg14/g1401244.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 44. Correct Tooth Contact Pattern (Used Gearing)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Adjust used gear sets to display the same contact pattern observed before disassembly. A correct
                pattern is up slightly off the toe and centers evenly along the face width between the top land and
                root. Otherwise, the length and shape of the pattern are highly variable and are considered acceptable
                as long as they do not run off the tooth at any point.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Tooth contact patterns are a function of the relative positions of the ring gear and pinion.
                        An improper pattern will require relocation of either or both. Always adjust pinion position
                        first, if necessary, then ring gear position. Recheck backlash when done.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before adjusting ring gear position in the following procedures, loosen thrust screw locknut
                        and back off thrust screw. This procedure is necessary to provide adequate clearance and allow
                        ring gear movement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Pinion Position</title>
            <para>If the contact pattern shows incorrect tooth depth contact, change drive pinion position by altering
                the shim pack under the cage and cup assembly. Used gears should achieve proper contact with the same
                shims removed from the axle at disassembly.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is too close to the root of the gear tooth, add pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401245">Figure 45</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401245" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401245" filename="../figg14/g1401245.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 45. Pattern Too Close or Off Tooth Root</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If pattern is too close to the top land of gear tooth, remove pinion shims (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401246">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401246" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401246" filename="../figg14/g1401246.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Pattern Tool Close to Tooth Top Land</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Check ring gear backlash after each shim change and adjust if necessary to maintain correct
                        backlash. Always recheck tooth contact pattern after making shim pack changes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Backlash</title>
            <para>If the contact pattern shows incorrect face width contact, change backlash and recheck the contact
                pattern.
            </para>
            <para>With the pattern concentrated at the toe (too far down the tooth), ADD BACKLASH by loosening the
                bearing adjuster on the teeth side of ring gear several notches. Loosen the opposite adjuster one notch
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401247">Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401247" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401247" filename="../figg14/g1401247.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Pattern Too Close to Edge of Tooth Toe</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Return to adjuster on teeth side of ring gear and tighten adjuster until it contacts the bearing cup.
                Continue tightening the same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
            <para>If the pattern is concentrated at the heel (too far up the tooth), REMOVE BACKLASH by loosening the
                bearing adjuster on the teeth side of ring gear several notches. Tighten the opposite adjuster one notch
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401248">Figure 48</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401248" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401248" filename="../figg14/g1401248.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Pattern Too Far Along Tooth Toward Tooth Heel</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Return to adjuster on teeth side of ring gear and tighten adjuster until it contacts the bearing cup.
                Continue tightening the same adjuster 2 or 3 notches. Recheck backlash.
            </para>
            <para>When preload, backlash and tooth contact are correct, align differential bearing adjusters with cotter
                pin holes (or locks), then tighten differential bearing cap bolts. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14012_32.xml" xrefid="hl1401203">TORQUE CHART
                    <xref refid="hl1401203"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . Install cotter pins (or locks). On 23105-30105 axles, lockwire differential bearing cap bolts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjust Ring Gear Thrust Screw</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thread thrust screw into the carrier until firm contact with the backface of the ring
                    gear is made.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the thrust screw 1/4 turn to obtain the correct adjustment of 0.020 inch (0.50
                    mm) clearance between gear face and screw. Tighten jam nut. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s14012_32.xml" xrefid="hl1401203">TORQUE CHART
                        <xref refid="hl1401203"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
                <para>Hold thrust screw stationary with a wrench while tightening nut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401249">Figure 49</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401249" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401249" filename="../figg14/g1401249.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 49. Thrust Screw Adjustment</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recheck to assure minimum clearance during full rotation of ring gear.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Drive Axle with Wheel Differential Lock. After carrier is assembled and adjusted (without
                            Differential Lock), install Differential Lock.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Differential Carrier Assembly</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before installing carrier assembly, inspect and thoroughly clean interior of axle housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use silicone rubber gasket compound on axle housing mating surface as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1401250">Figure 50</hotlnk>. For the correct gasket material, refer to GROUP 10
                        - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. Gasket compound will set in 20 minutes.
                        Install carrier before compound sets or reapply.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1401250" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401250" filename="../figg14/g1401250.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Use Silicone Rubber Gasket Compound on Axle Housing Mating Surface</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install differential carrier assembly in axle housing. Install bolts and lockwashers.
                    Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s14012_32.xml" xrefid="hl1401203">TORQUE CHART
                        <xref refid="hl1401203"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Fasteners using self-locking thread "patches" may be reused if not damaged, but should be
                            secured by a few drops of Loctite #277 on threaded surface of differential carrier. Reused
                            fasteners should be wiped clean of excess oil, but do not require special cleaning.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Drive Axle with Differential Lock. When installing axle shafts, make sure the
                            double-splined axle shaft is installed in the shift unit side of the differential carrier.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install axle shaft, silicone gasket compound, and stud nuts. Connect driveline.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill axle with correct lube. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master
                    Service Manual.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When axle has been disassembled or housing, gears, axle shafts or wheel equipment
                            replaced, check axle assembly for proper differential action before operating vehicle.
                            Wheels must rotate freely and independently.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
