<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS - BEARING CUP (RACE)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1400101">
        <title>BEARING CUP (RACE)</title>
        <svcproc id="hl1400102" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REMOVE (CAST IRON HUB ASSEMBLY)</title>
            <para>Removal is done with hub assembly removed from vehicle (with or without wheel(s) removed from hub
                assembly), and inner bearing and seal removed from hub assembly.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove inner bearing cup, place hub assembly flat on floor with outer bearing facing
                    up (toward you).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a long suitable steel punch placed through the hub bore. In most cases, the hub
                    assembly will have a couple of notches machined out of the hub assembly. These notches are there for
                    the removal of the bearing cup.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the punch in the notch on the cup. Strike the punch with a hammer. Move the punch
                    to the opposite notch and repeat procedure. Moving back and forth in the notches and striking the
                    cup will force the cup from the hub.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent eye injury, safety glasses should be worn at all times when assembling or
                            disassembling components.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If hub does not have removal notches machined into the hub assembly, use a suitable steel
                            punch with a flat end. Place punch on cup portion that is protruding from hub assembly.
                            Strike punch with hammer and work your way around cup in a criss-cross pattern, forcing cup
                            from hub.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>To remove outer bearing cup, place hub assembly on floor with brake drum/disc facing up
                            (toward you) and repeat steps 2 and 3 above.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
