<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AUTOMATIC POSITIVE LOCKING TRACTION DIFFERENTIALS
        (NOSPIN/DETROIT LOCKER) - REASSEMBLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1400306">
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="6">
            <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lay the ring gear and flanged half of the differential support case on a bench with the
                    bearing end of the case hub down and the inner case facing upward. BE SURE NO THRUST WASHERS ARE
                    INSIDE THE CASE.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the ground hub of a side gear into the bore of the case. Be sure the side gear
                    will rotate freely in the case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble one spring, spring retainer and driven clutch assembly.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Assembly procedures will differ depending upon the style of components used.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">External</emph>
                        spring and retainers:
                    </para>
                    <para>Assemble spring retainer over the side gear splines with the retaining lip pointed up. It
                        should seat against the side gear shoulder.
                    </para>
                    <para>Place spring over the side gear spline and against the retainer lip with the smaller diameter
                        of the spring against the retainer (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1400304">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1400304" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1400304" filename="../figg14/G1400304.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4. Place Spring Over Side Gear Spline</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Assemble driven clutch assembly over the spring with the teeth up (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1400305">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1400305" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1400305" filename="../figg14/G1400305.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5. Assemble Driven Clutch Assembly</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <emph type="bold">Internal</emph>
                        spring and retainers:
                    </para>
                    <para>Assemble spring over the inner hub of the side gear and against the spring seat of the side
                        gear.
                    </para>
                    <para>Place the cupped section of the spring retainer over the spring (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1400306">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1400306" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1400306" filename="../figg14/G1400306.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6. Place Cupped Section of Spring Retainer Over Spring</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Assemble driven clutch over the spring retainer with the teeth up.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Verify that the spring is functioning freely by compressing the driven clutch over the side
                        gear splines. Be sure the spring is not binding, that the coils do not overlap and that there is
                        good contact between the end coil and the spring retainer when the driven clutch and side gear
                        splines are fully meshed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the spider assembly or central driver assembly over the driven clutch
                    assembly.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Be sure the slot in the holdout ring is properly aligned over the long tooth of the spider
                            (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400307">Figure 7</hotlnk>and
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400308">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f1400307" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400307" filename="../figg14/G1400307.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Be Sure Slot in Holdout Ring is Properly Aligned Over Long Tooth of Spider
                    </caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1400308" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400308" filename="../figg14/G1400308.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Be Sure Slot in Holdout Ring is Properly Aligned Over Long Tooth of Spider
                    </caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the other driven clutch assembly on the spider assembly.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Be sure the slot in the holdout ring is properly aligned over the long tooth of the spider
                            (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400307">Figure 7</hotlnk>and
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400308">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the other retainer, spring and side gear as previously indicated.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the plain case half over the side gear and compress the springs. Be sure the side
                    gear splines are completely meshed with the driven clutch splines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold the case halves firmly together with the punch marks aligned. Install the case
                    bolts.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not release hand pressure until two or more bolts are in place and spring pressure has
                            been overcome. Failure to heed this warning can cause injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten case bolts to the torque specified by International/axle manufacturer. Check to
                    be certain of a snug fit between the two case halves at all points and between the trunnion mounts
                    in the case and the spider trunnions. Bolt the ring gear to the NoSPIN differential and case
                    assembly in the way recommended by International/axle manufacturer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400309">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400309" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400309" filename="../figg14/G1400309.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Bolt Ring Gear to NoSPIN Differential and Case Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow International's/axle manufacturer's instructions for re-installation of the ring
                    gear and differential assembly into the axle carrier.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
