<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>2 SPEED AXLE SHIFT UNIT: EATON - AIR SHIFT SYSTEM - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>In operation, the air shifter valve (in gear shift knob) supplies air through the quick release valve to
            the axle shift unit. Air pressure in the shift unit shifts axle to High range. To shift axle to Low range,
            air pressure is exhausted at shifter valve, which exhausts air pressure at quick release valve, allowing
            shift unit to return to Low range.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Low Range Operation</emph>
            - Shifter knob is in LO, shifter valve is closed and no air pressure is present to shift unit. Axle is held
            in Low range by shift unit return spring.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">High Range Operation</emph>
            - Shifter knob is in HI, shifter valve is opened to allow air pressure through quick release valve to shift
            unit. Axle is held in High range by air pressure in the shift unit.
        </para>
        <para>The shift unit is mechanically connected to the axle shift fork and shifts axle into Low or High range.
        </para>
        <para>The unit consists of an air chamber, piston, compression spring and mechanical linkage (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400224">Figure 24</hotlnk>). When air is admitted to the chamber or cylinder, the piston
            travels downward against a compression spring, transferring motion through a push rod and actuating lever to
            the shift fork, shifting the axle into High range. Exhaust of air pressure permits the heavy-duty spring to
            return the axle gearing to Low range.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1400224" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1400224" filename="../figg14/G1400224.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 24. Air Shift Unit Components</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A harsh environment kit (consisting of a vent filter and fittings) is available for shift units
                    operating in unusually wet or dirty conditions. For additional information, contact your
                    International dealer.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
