<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - CLEAN AND INSPECT - CLEAN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLEAN</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ground and Polished Parts</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a cleaning solvent to clean ground or polished parts or surfaces. Kerosene or diesel
                    fuel oil can be used for this purpose. DO NOT USE GASOLINE.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be careful when using cleaning solvents. Follow the solvent manufacturer's instructions
                            for safe use to prevent injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a tool with a flat blade if required to remove gasket material from parts. Be
                    careful not to damage the ground surfaces.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>DO NOT clean ground or polished parts in a hot solution tank, water, steam or alkaline
                            solutions.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rough Parts</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean rough parts the same as cleaning ground and polished parts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rough parts can be cleaned in hot solution tanks with a weak alkaline solution.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Parts must remain in hot solution tanks until completely cleaned.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be careful when using hot solution tanks and alkaline solutions. Follow the alkaline
                            manufacturer's instructions for safe use to prevent injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Parts must be washed with water until the solution is removed.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Axle Assemblies</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A complete axle assembly can be steam cleaned on the outside to remove dirt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before the axle is steam cleaned, close or put a cover over all openings in the axle
                    assembly. Examples of openings are breathers or vents in air chambers.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dry Parts That Have Been Cleaned</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Parts must be dried immediately after cleaning and washing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dry the parts using soft, clean, paper or cloth rags.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Except for bearings, parts can be dried with compressed air.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Damage to bearings can be caused if dried by rotating with compressed air.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Prevent Corrosion and Rust on Cleaned Parts</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply axle lubricant to cleaned and dried parts that are not damaged and are to be
                    assembled.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To store parts, apply a special material that prevents corrosion and rust to all
                    surfaces. Wrap them in a special paper that prevents corrosion and rust.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400628.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
