<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - REASSEMBLE - INSTALL THE DIFFERENTIAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1400623" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="4">
        <title>INSTALL THE DIFFERENTIAL</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean and dry the bearing cups and bores of the carrier legs and bearing caps.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply axle lubricant on the inner diameter of the bearing cups and on both bearing cones
                that are assembled on the case halves.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite Sleeve N' Mount No. 609 (Green) Adhesive in the bearing bores of the carrier
                legs and bearing caps. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400620.xml" xrefid="hl1400620">APPLICATION OF ADHESIVE IN BEARING
                    BORES</hotlnk>. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400698">Figure 98.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400698" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400698" filename="../figg14/G1400698.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Apply Loctite Adhesive in Bearing Bores of Carrier Legs and Bearing Caps</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ADHESIVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BEARING CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CARRIER LEG</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing cups over the bearing cones that are assembled on the case halves (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400699">Figure 99</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400699" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400699" filename="../figg14/G1400699.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Install Bearing Cups Over Bearing Cones</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BEARING CUP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEG BORE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Safely lift the differential and ring gear assembly and install into the carrier. The
                bearing cups MUST be flat against the bores between the carrier legs (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400699">Figure 99</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install both of the bearing adjusting rings into position between the carrier legs. Turn
                each adjusting ring hand tight against the bearing cup (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a0">Figure 100</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14006a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14006a0" filename="../figg14/G14006A0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Install Bearing Adjusting Rings Between Carrier Legs</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ADJUSTING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEG</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing caps over the bearings and adjusting rings in the correct location as
                marked before removal (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a1">Figure 101</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14006a1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14006a1" filename="../figg14/G14006A1.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 101. Install Bearings Caps Over Bearings and Adjusting Rings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BEARING CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MATCH MARKS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear safe eye protection. Do not hit steel parts with a steel hammer. Parts can break and
                        cause injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hit each bearing cap into position with a leather, plastic or rubber mallet. The caps MUST
                fit easily against the bearings, adjusting rings and carrier. DO NOT FORCE THE BEARING CAPS INTO
                POSITION.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If bearing caps are not installed in correct locations, the bores and threads in caps will not
                        match the carrier. You will have problems assembling the caps on the carrier and damage to parts
                        can occur. Do not force the bearing caps into position.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If bearing caps do not correctly fit into position, check the alignment of match marks
                between caps and carrier. Remove the caps and repeat Step 6.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the capscrews and washers that hold bearing caps to the carrier. Tighten the
                capscrews by hand four to six turns, then tighten the capscrews to the correct torque value. Refer to
                the
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_57.xml" xrefid="hl1400608">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not install the cotter keys
                        <ftnref xrefid="fn1400601"/>*, pins
                        <ftnref xrefid="fn1400601"/>* or lock plates
                        <ftnref xrefid="fn1400601"/>* that hold the bearing adjusting rings in position. Continue by
                        adjusting the preload of differential bearings, adjust backlash of the hypoid gear and check
                        tooth contact patterns.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_32.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400611.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
