<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - GENERAL PROCEDURES - APPLICATION OF ADHESIVE IN BEARING BORES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1400620" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>APPLICATION OF ADHESIVE IN BEARING BORES</title>
        <para>Use Loctite Sleeve N' Bearing Mount No. 609 (Green).</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the oil and dirt from outer diameters of bearing cups and bearing bores in the carrier
                and bearing caps. There is no special cleaning required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply axle lubricant to the bearing cones and the inner diameters of the bearing cups of the
                main differential. DO NOT get oil on the outer diameter of the bearing cup and DO NOT permit oil to drip
                on the bearing bores.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a single continuous bead of the adhesive to the bearing bores in the carrier and
                bearing caps. Apply the adhesive 360&#176; around the smooth, ground surfaces ONLY. DO NOT put adhesive
                on threaded areas (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400648">Figure 48</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400648" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400648" filename="../figg14/G1400648.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Apply Adhesive to Bearing Bores in Carrier</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ADHESIVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BEARING CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CARRIER LEG</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Loctite No. 609 adhesives will become hard (dry) in approximately two hours. The following
                        two steps of the procedure must be done in two hours from the time the adhesive was applied. If
                        two hours have passed since application, clean the parts again and apply new adhesive.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the main differential assembly, bearing cups and bearing caps into the carrier.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400610.xml" xrefid="hl1400610">ASSEMBLE THE MAIN DIFFERENTIAL AND RING GEAR
                    ASSEMBLY</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust preload of the differential bearings, backlash and tooth contact patterns of the gear
                set as required using the normal procedures. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400611.xml" xrefid="hl1400611">ADJUST PRELOAD OF DIFFERENTIAL
                    BEARINGS</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400607.xml" xrefid="hl1400607">ADJUST BACKLASH OF THE RING GEAR</hotlnk>
                , and
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400612.xml" xrefid="hl1400612">CHECK TOOTH CONTACT PATTERNS OF THE GEAR
                    SET</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400606.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400629.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
