<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES: SPICER S100-S, S105-S, S135-S, S150-S -
        INSTALL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
            <title>DIFFERENTIAL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install ring gear and differential assembly into carrier housing.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid damage of ring and pinion gears, care should be used when installing the ring
                            gear differential assembly into the carrier housing.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure side bearing cups are seated on bearing cones. Assemble differential bearing
                    caps, with match marks in proper location. Clean bearing cap bolts and washers and coat threads with
                    Loctite #277 or equivalent. Install bearing cap bolts and tighten enough to eliminate visible space
                    between differential bearing cap and carrier housing. Do not tighten the bearing cap bolts at this
                    time.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Differential assembly must be aligned within bearing bores before preload is applied or
                            damage to bearings can occur.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install adjusting rings. Tighten both adjusting rings until end play is eliminated and
                    there is backlash between the ring gear and pinion (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401728">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401728" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401728" filename="../figg14/g1401728.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. Tighten Both Adjusting Rings</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen adjusting ring on tooth side of ring gear 1 notch and tighten adjusting ring on
                    flange side of ring gear 1 notch. Repeat process until backlash is eliminated. Tighten adjusting
                    ring on tooth side of the ring gear until the ring gear and pinion backlash matches the backlash
                    etched on the ring gear. This adjustment sets both the backlash and the bearing preload.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check ring gear and pinion backlash in four equally spaced positions around the ring
                    gear with a dial indicator (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401729">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Acceptable backlash tolerance is &#177; .002 inch
                    from backlash etched on the ring gear.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401729" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401729" filename="../figg14/g1401729.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 29. Check Ring Gear and Pinion Backlash</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If backlash tolerance varies more than .003 inch (.080 mm) between the four positions,
                            remove the differential and determine the cause.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once backlash is set, tighten the differential bearing cap bolts to 115 to 135 ft-lbs.
                    (156 to 183 Nm). Check backlash after tightening the cap bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
