<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS -
        Specifications - Adjustments and Specifications
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Adjustments and Specifications</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drive Pinion Bearings - Preload</title>
            <para>Specification: New bearings - 5 to 45 in-lbs. (0.56 to 5.08 Nm) torque. Used bearings in good
                condition - 10 to 30 in-lbs. (1.1 to 3.4 Nm) torque
            </para>
            <para>Adjustment: Preload is controlled by the thickness of the spacer between bearing cones. To increase
                preload, install a thinner spacer. To decrease preload, install a thicker spacer.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drive Pinion - Depth in Carrier</title>
            <para>Specification: Install the correct amount of shims between the inner bearing cup of the drive pinion
                and the carrier. To calculate, use the old shim pack thickness and the new and old pinion cone numbers.
            </para>
            <para>Adjustment: Change the thickness of the shim pack to get a good gear tooth contact pattern.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hypoid Gear Set - Tooth Contact Patterns (Hand-Rolled)</title>
            <para>Specification: Toward the toe of the gear tooth and in the center between the top and bottom of the
                tooth.
            </para>
            <para>Adjustment: Tooth contact patterns are controlled by the thickness of the shim pack between the inner
                bearing cone of the drive pinion and the carrier and by ring gear backlash. To move the contact pattern
                lower, increase the thickness of the shim pack between the inner bearing cup of the drive pinion and the
                carrier. To move the contact pattern higher, decrease the thickness of the shim pack between the inner
                bearing cup of the drive pinion and the carrier. To move the contact pattern toward the toe of the
                tooth, decrease backlash of the ring gear. To move the contact pattern toward the heel of the tooth,
                increase backlash of the ring gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Differential Bearings - Preload</title>
            <para>Specification: 15 to 35 in-lbs. (1.7 to 3.9 Nm) torque OR Expansion between bearing caps - 0.003 to
                0.009 inch (0.08 to 0.22 mm) - 140 and 145 Series. 0.006 to 0.013 inch (0.15 to 0.33 mm) - 160 Series.
            </para>
            <para>Adjustment: Preload is controlled by tightening both adjusting rings after zero end play is reached.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Differential Bearings - Rotating Resistance</title>
            <para>Specification: 50 ft-lbs. (68 Nm) maximum torque applied to one side gear</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Output Bearing - End Play and Preload</title>
            <para>Specification: 0.001 to 0.004 inch (0.025 to 0.102 mm) bearing end play</para>
            <para>Adjustment: End play is controlled by the size of the snap ring in the output bearing cage. Increase
                end play by installing a thinner snap ring. Decrease end play by installing a thicker snap ring.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the end play on the output bearing measures zero (0), a thinner snap ring is required.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ring Gear - Backlash</title>
            <para>Specification:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>145 Series: Range: 0.008 to 0.018 inch (0.020 to 0.46 mm). Backlash Setting for New Gear Sets:
                        0.012 inch (0.30 mm).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>160 Series: Range: 0.010 to 0.020 inch (0.025 to 0.51 mm). Backlash Setting for New Gear Sets:
                        0.012 inch (0.30 mm).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Adjustment: Backlash is controlled by the position of the ring gear. Change backlash within
                specifications to get a good tooth contact pattern. To increase backlash, move the ring gear away from
                the drive pinion. To decrease backlash, move the ring gear toward the drive pinion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ring Gear - Run-Out</title>
            <para>Specification: 0.008 inch (0.020 mm) maximum</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Switch - Installation (Carriers with Differential Lock Only)</title>
            <para>Adjustment: Shift the differential to the locked position. Tighten the sensor switch into the carrier
                until the test light illuminates. Tighten the sensor switch one additional turn. Tighten the jam nut to
                the specified torque.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_58.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_60.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
