<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLE: INTERNATIONAL - ASSEMBLE - DIFFERENTIAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DIFFERENTIAL</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s14009_HL1400905.xml" xrefid="f1400914">Figure 14</hotlnk>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If ring gear was removed from differential case, reinstall at this time. Clean mating
                surfaces and bolt ring gear to differential case at 3 locations 120&#176; apart to help eliminate ring
                gear runout. Use hydraulic press and suitable riveting fixture, as shown. Pressure requirement per rivet
                is 45 to 50 U.S. tons (41 to 45 metric tons).
            </para>
            <para>The ring gear is properly installed when a .0015 (.038 mm) feeler gauge cannot be inserted between the
                differential case flange and the ring gear backface (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400938">Figure 38</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400938" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400938" filename="../figg14/g1400938.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Properly Installed Ring Gear</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Ring gear and pinion must be replaced as a matched set only.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install bearing cones to differential case halves. Place bearing cups on cones during
                remainder of assembly to prevent damage to bearings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use of press and proper adapter is required to eliminate possible damage to bearings.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a small amount of lubricant to all mating surfaces. This will keep thrust washers in
                place during assembly and provide initial lubrication.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place thrust washer and side gear in flange half differential case. Dimples in thrust
                washers go against side gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble differential pinions and thrust washers on cross shaft. Place assembly in flange
                half differential case.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place remaining side gear and thrust washers in position on differential pinions.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble case halves,
                <emph type="bold">making sure match marks are lined up.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install differential case bolts. Tighten alternately and evenly. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14009_43.xml" xrefid="hl1400901">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
