<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE SPEED REAR AXLE: INTERNATIONAL - REMOVE ( Figure 3 ) - CARRIER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CARRIER</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Steam clean axle assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove drain plug and drain lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect drive shafts at rear U-joint.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If pinion or pinion bearings are to be removed, break loose pinion nut at this time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove axle flange nuts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold a large brass drift or a brass hammer against the center of the axle shaft flange.
                Strike the drift sharp blows with a large hammer or sledge, until axle shaft separates from hub.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not strike axle flange directly with a steel hammer or sledge. This may crack and splinter
                        material, possibly causing serious or fatal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not pry or chisel axle flange away from hub or damage to sealing surfaces could occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the carrier assembly on a roller jack. Secure as necessary to prevent it from
                falling off the jack when removed from the housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the differential carrier-to-axle housing bolts. Remove all bolts except top two.
                These two bolts will prevent the carrier assembly from falling.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Separate carrier from housing, using removal slots as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400804">Figure 4</hotlnk>. Be certain carrier is balanced properly on jack, and remove
                top two carrier mounting bolts. Remove carrier assembly from axle housing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400804" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400804" filename="../figg14/G1400804.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Carrier</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount carrier assembly in a suitable rebuild stand. (Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14008t_31.xml" xrefid="hl1400802">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.)
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14008t_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14008t_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14008t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
