<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 2 SPEED REAR AXLES: SPICER - INSTALL - CARRIER ASSEMBLY
        INTO AXLE HOUSING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CARRIER ASSEMBLY INTO AXLE HOUSING</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thoroughly clean the inside of the carrier housing and inspect the housing mounting surface
                for nicks and general cleanliness. Stone the surface if necessary to remove burrs or nicks.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite 518 gasket eliminator material to the housing carrier mounting flange. A 1/8
                inch bead on the outside of all carrier mounting holes, and an additional bead around holes is required
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401540">Figure 40</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401540" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401540" filename="../figg14/G1401540.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Carrier Housing Lubrication</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thread two studs into housing so that they will extend at least one inch above the housing
                mounting face to serve as carrier assembly alignment guides. This procedure is necessary to avoid having
                to rotate the carrier once it is against the Loctite 518 coated mounting surface to align bolt holes.
                Such realignment can cause the Loctite seal to be broken, leading to in-service oil leakage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the carrier to the housing and install the carrier-to-housing bolts, replacing the
                two guide studs with mounting bolts. Tighten bolts to:
            </para>
            <table id="t1401508">
                <title>Carrier-to-Housing Bolt Torque</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="2.99in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Code</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Torque</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry>
                                <para>14CDA, 14130</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>100 to 120 ft-lbs. (136 to 163 N&#8226;m)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>14CDB, 14131, 14132,, 14133</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>240 to 260 ft-lbs. (325 to 352 N&#8226;m)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </step1>
        <para>Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s14015_38.xml" xrefid="hl1401515">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow one hour cure time for gasket material before adding hypoid lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove old axle flange gasket and clean mating surfaces of hub and axle flange.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert both axle shafts, using new shaft-to-hub gaskets and install the axle nuts and/or
                bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install the shift unit.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For servicing the shift unit, refer to Group 14 - REAR AXLE in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                        Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the drain plug after cleaning the magnet, the plug threads, and the area around the
                drain hole. Refill the axle housing to the proper level with proper hypoid lubricant, as recommended
                earlier. Replace the filler hole plug after cleaning the magnet, the plug thread, and the area around
                the fill hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
