<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE SPEED AXLE: SPICER - INSTALL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <svcproc id="hl1400710" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="5">
            <title>DIFFERENTIAL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The W Model carriers use three different differential cases, depending on the ratio. Two
                    of the cases have two oil pick-up plates attached. Clean and coat bolts with #271 Loctite or its
                    equivalent. Assemble and tighten bolts to 7 to 9 ft-lbs. (9 to 12 N&#8226;m) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400765">Figure 65</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400765" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400765" filename="../figg14/g1400765.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 65. Assemble and Tighten Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install ring gear and differential assembly into carrier housing. Tilt differential
                    slightly so ring gear clears straddle bearing support (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400766">Figure 66</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400766" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400766" filename="../figg14/g1400766.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 66. Install Ring and Differential Assembly into Carrier Housing</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid damage of ring and pinion gears, care should be used when installing the ring
                            gear differential assembly into the carrier housing.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure side bearing cups are seated on bearing cones. Assemble differential bearing
                    caps, with match marks in proper location. Clean bearing cap bolts and washers and coat threads with
                    Loctite #277 or equivalent. Install bearing cap bolts and tighten enough to eliminate visible space
                    between differential bearing cap and carrier housing. Do not tighten the bearing cap bolts at this
                    time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install adjusting rings. Tighten both adjusting rings until end play is eliminated and
                    there is backlash between the ring gear and pinion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen adjusting ring on tooth side of ring gear and tighten adjusting ring on flange
                    side of ring gear, equal amounts until backlash is eliminated. Tighten adjusting ring on tooth side
                    of the ring gear 2 or 3 notches or until proper backlash and side bearing preload are established (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400767">Figure 67</hotlnk>). (Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14007t_9.xml" xrefid="hl1400701">GEAR SET
                        <xref refid="hl1400701"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    , for backlash location on ring gear.)
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400767" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400767" filename="../figg14/g1400767.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 67. Tighten Adjusting Ring</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check ring gear and pinion backlash in four equally spaced positions around the ring
                    gear with a dial indicator as shown (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400768">Figure 68</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400768" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400768" filename="../figg14/g1400768.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 68. Check Ring Gear and Pinion Backlash</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If backlash tolerance does not vary more than .003 inch (.080 mm), the setting is
                            acceptable. If backlash tolerance varies more than .003 inch (.080 mm) between the four
                            positions, remove the differential and determine the cause.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once backlash is set, tighten the differential bearing cap bolts to specification. Check
                    backlash after tightening the cap bolts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400769">Figure 69</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400769" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400769" filename="../figg14/g1400769.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 69. Check Backlash After Tightening Cap Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
