<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES: SPICER S100-S, S105-S, S135-S, S150-S - INSTALL
        - RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401730">Figure 30</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1401730" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401730" filename="../figg14/G1401730.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 30. Ring Gear and Pinion Tooth Contact Pattern</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The following procedures are to be used to establish proper gear tooth pattern after assembly of the
            carrier is complete.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If matched sets are being reused, measure and record backlash before disassembly, and reassemble
                    to the same backlash. This will match ring and pinion gears to the established wear patterns. Hand
                    rolled patterns will cover less area than the wear pattern established by previous service.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Paint 1/4 ring gear with marking compound on both the drive and coast side.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate ring gear at least one complete revolution in both directions while load is being
                applied.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <title>Correct Gear Patterns</title>
        </para>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401731">Figure 31</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1401731" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401731" filename="../figg14/G1401731.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 31. Correct Gear Patterns</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Tooth contact pattern can be moved only by adjusting backlash. The tooth contact pattern can be
                    moved in the direction of heel-to-toe, and toe-to-heel; depth of the pattern cannot be adjusted. If
                    an acceptable tooth contact pattern cannot be established within limits of backlash, contact
                    International either by opening a Case File in Tech. Central, or by contacting a TSM.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
