<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS - WHEEL BEARING ADJUSTMENT -
        AXILOK&#174; UNITIZED SELF-LOCKING WHEEL BEARING ADJUSTING NUT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="4">
        <title>AXILOK&#174; UNITIZED SELF-LOCKING WHEEL BEARING ADJUSTING NUT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400138">Figure 16</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400138" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400138" filename="../figg14/G1400138.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Axilok Unitized Self-Locking Wheel Bearing Adjusting Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>International vehicles with 23,000 to 30,000 lb. single rear axles and 38,000 to 58,000 lb. tandem
                rear axles may have the Axilok unitized self-locking wheel bearing adjusting nut. The Axilok unitized
                self-locking nut enhances accurate, reliable wheel bearing adjustment. Its unitized design allows
                precise wheel bearing adjustment end play settings of .001 inch to .005 inch (.0254 to .127 mm) which
                provides for improved wheel seal and bearing life and meets the requirements of antilock brake systems.
            </para>
            <para>A 6 or 12 point 4 inch socket is required to depress the locking clips for the installation and
                removal of the Axilok wheel bearing adjusting nut.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Always use the correct socket. Do not use any other type of instrument to depress the locking
                        clips such as pliers, channel locks, etc.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never use an impact wrench to install or remove an Axilok.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before re-installing the Axilok, be certain the threads, locking tab, locking clips and
                        retaining washer are free of defects and are in proper working condition.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Be certain the socket is not worn or damaged to the point it will not fully depress the locking clips
                or properly engage the hex nut feature. Always use a properly calibrated torque wrench when installing
                an Axilok.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the 4 inch socket over the hex portion of the nut to depress the locking clips (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400139">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1400139" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400139" filename="../figg14/G1400139.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Depress Locking Clips</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn nut counterclockwise to remove. When removing the Axilok, it is required to
                    manually keep the retaining washer moving toward the end of the spindle with nut as nut is removed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400139">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a few drops of light weight lubricating oil through one of the holes of the
                    retaining washer. This will allow the nut and retaining washer to rotate freely during installation
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400140">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1400140" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400140" filename="../figg14/G1400140.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Apply Lubricating Oil</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The nut and retaining washer of the Axilok are locked together with two locking clips.
                    Place the 4 inch standard 6 or 12 point socket over the hex feature of the nut to depress the
                    locking clips, thereby releasing locking clips and allowing the nut to rotate freely within the
                    retaining washer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400141">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1400141" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400141" filename="../figg14/G1400141.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Release Locking Clips</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the tab on the retaining washer with the keyway in the spindle. Thread the nut
                    onto the spindle with the socket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After spoke/disc wheel hub, bearings, and Axilok unitized self-locking nut are
                    installed, rotate the assembly while tightening the self-locking nut to 200 ft-lbs. (271 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Back off Axilok unitized self locking nut to zero torque.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the spoke/disc hub assembly a minimum of one complete revolution while
                    retightening the Axilok unitized self locking nut to 50 ft-lbs. (68 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Back off the Axilok unitized self-locking nut 1/8 turn.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the socket from the Axilok allowing the spring clips to release and engage into
                    the holes in the retaining washer. If the tabs of the locking clips do not line up with the
                    retaining washer holes, rotate the Axilok counterclockwise until the locking clips engage into
                    locking holes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400138">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install axle shaft. Refer to GROUP 14 - REAR AXLES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual
                    for detailed information.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
