<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - GENERAL PROCEDURES - REPAIR AXLE BY WELDING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REPAIR AXLE BY WELDING</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repairing drive axle housing assemblies by welding is permitted ONLY in the following
                areas:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cover welds.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Snorkel welds.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Housing seam welds between the suspension attaching brackets.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Welding can be used when the crack or damaged area is within the old weld material.
                            Replace the axle housing if the crack extends into the metal next to the old weld. A housing
                            that has damage in the seam weld or cover weld because of overload conditions can be
                            repaired. A repaired housing must be used in correct applications.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Using wrong welding procedures or welding at locations other than the three areas
                            permitted will make the heat-treated component weak. A weak component will cause poor or
                            unsafe operation of the axle and early failure. The following procedure must be used.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Welding Procedure.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Drain the lubricant from the axle assembly.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shafts and differential carrier from the axle housing.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be careful when using a cleaning solvent. Follow the solvent manufacturer's instructions
                            for safe use to prevent injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the damaged area inside and outside the housing. Cleaning solvent can be used.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Grind the damaged weld to the base metal.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Warm the complete axle housing to a temperature of 70&#176;F to 80&#176;F (21&#176;C to
                    27&#176;C) or higher.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Before you start welding, heat the damaged area to be repaired to approximately 300&#176;F
                    (149&#176;C).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a 70,000 psi tensile weld material and the correct voltage and amperage for the
                    diameter weld rod used. Examples of weld rods that can be used are E-7018 or ER-705-3.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>If the E-7018 weld rod is used, the rod must be kept dry. Electrodes that are not stored
                            in the correct sealed containers must be heated at 700&#176;F (371&#176;C) for one hour
                            before welding. Wet electrodes must be dried at 180&#176;F (82&#176;C) for one to two hours
                            and then heated at 700&#176;F (371&#176;C) for one hour before welding.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill in the Weld Gap as Follows:</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not connect the ground cable at any point on the axle assembly that will put a bearing
                        between the ground cable and weld area. If a bearing is between the ground cable and weld, the
                        bearing will be damaged because of electricity arcing. A good location to connect the ground
                        cable is the spring mounting pad of the housing.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The snorkel weld MUST be a .375 inch (9.5 mm) fillet.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The opening in cover welds MUST be filled level with the old weld.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The opening in seam welds MUST be ground out to 70% of the wall thickness. The wall
                    thickness can be measured at the carrier opening of housing.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the new weld area. Carefully remove all the rough weld material.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the differential carrier and axle shafts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the axle assembly with the correct amount of lubricant. Refer to GROUP 10 -
                LUBRICATION.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400619.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
