<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - Driver
        Controlled Main Differential Lock - Installing the Carrier into the Axle Housing
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Installing the Carrier into the Axle Housing</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be careful when using cleaning solvent. Follow the solvent manufacturer's instructions for
                        safe use to prevent serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Clean the inside of the axle housing and the mounting surface where the carrier fastens. Use a
                        cleaning solvent and rags to remove the dirt. Blow dry the cleaned areas with compressed air.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect the axle housing for damage. If necessary, repair or replace the housing.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check for loose studs in the mounting surface of the housing where the carrier fastens. Remove
                        and replace the studs where required. Apply liquid adhesive to the holes. Install and tighten
                        the stud to 150 to 230 ft-lbs. (204 to 312 Nm).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the differential carrier into the housing using the Air Pressure or Manual Engaging
                        Method below.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x1401119">
            <title>Air Pressure Method:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before the carrier is installed into the housing, install the left-hand axle shaft
                    through the shift collar and into the side gear. (The axle shaft is being used as a spline alignment
                    tool.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A similar tool can be made from a damaged left-hand axle shaft by cutting off approximately 24
                        inches from the spline end.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the splines of the shift collar and differential case half by rotating the axle
                    shaft tool or drive pinion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not use your hands to hold the collar in position. Serious personal injury can result when
                        air pressure is applied to the actuator.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect an auxiliary air supply to the actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and hold pressure to the actuator assembly. The air pressure will move the shift
                    collar to engage the differential case half and lock the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the shift collar has not moved the full distance on the splines of the differential
                    case half, rotate the axle shaft tool to complete the shift.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shaft tool from the carrier.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Continue to hold the main differential in the locked (engaged) position with air pressure
                        until the carrier is completely installed in the axle housing. If no air supply is available,
                        use the "Manual Engaging Method" on this page to lock (engage) the differential.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply silicone gasket material to the mounting surface of the housing where the carrier
                    fastens. Recommended silicone materials are Dow Corning Silicone Rubber Sealant, No. 732 Black or
                    General Electric No. RTV-1473 Black.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the carrier into the axle housing. Follow steps 6 to 18 under
                    <hotlnk document="s14011_50.xml" xrefid="x1401117">DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER IN THE AXLE HOUSING</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the air pressure from the differential lock actuator and disconnect the
                    auxiliary air supply.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Proceed to Step 7 under Manual Engaging Method below.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x1401116">
            <title>Manual Engaging Method:</title>
            <para>If the differential is in the locked (engaged) position, held by the manual engaging bolt, start with
                Step 4.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the splines of the shift collar and the differential case half. This can be done
                    by hand or by installing the left-hand axle shaft through the shift collar and into the side gear.
                    See Step 1 and 2 of the "
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x1401119">Air Pressure Method</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the manual engaging bolt into the threaded hole in the center of the cylinder
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the manual engaging bolt to the right until the head of the bolt is approximately
                    1/4 inch from the cylinder cover. DO NOT turn the bolt beyond its normal stop. The bolt is now in
                    the service position and the main differential lock is completely engaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>There will be a small amount of spring resistance felt when you turn in the manual engaging
                        bolt. If a high resistance is felt before reaching the locked (engaged) position, STOP TURNING
                        THE BOLT or the cover, the fork and bolt threads will be damaged.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A high resistance on the bolt indicates that the splines of the shift collar and the
                    differential case half are not aligned or engaged.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Lift the shift collar as required and rotate to align the splines of collar and case
                    half while you turn in the manual engaging bolt. When the normal amount of spring resistance is
                    again felt on the bolt, the splines are engaged. Continue to turn in the manual engaging bolt.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and fasten the carrier into the axle housing. Follow Steps 7 and 8 of the "Air
                    Pressure Method" above.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug and gasket from the storage position. Remove the manual engaging bolt
                    from its service position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the manual engaging bolt is removed from the service position in the actuator, the main
                        differential lock becomes disengaged.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the plug, gasket, cylinder or cylinder cover, and threaded hole in the center of
                    the cylinder cover or cylinder.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plug and gasket into their operating position in the cylinder cover or
                    cylinder. Install the manual engaging bolt into its storage position (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011j6">Figure 196</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011j7">Figure 197</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f14011j6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011j6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 196. Bolt On Type Shift Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TOP SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DIFFERENTIAL LOCK ACTUATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CYLINDER COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WIRE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. OPERATING POSITION HOLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. BOTTOM SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011j7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011j7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 197. Threaded Type Shift Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SHIFT SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STORAGE OF MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT IN SHIFT TOWER LOCATION</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. INSERT MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT TO ENGAGE DIFF. LOCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SHIFT CYLINDER AND PISTON ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SHIFT FORK</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SENSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the plug to 44 to 55 ft-lbs (60 to 75 Nm) torque. Tighten the manual engaging
                    bolt to 15 to 25 ft-lbs (20 to 35 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the vehicle air line to the differential lock actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the electrical connection on the sensor switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the right and left-hand axle shafts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the jack stand from under the drive axle and lower the vehicle to the floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the axle to the fill hole level with a lube recommended in GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION
                    in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_54.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_56.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
