<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - REASSEMBLE - ADJUST PRELOAD OF DIFFERENTIAL BEARINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1400611" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="6">
        <title>ADJUST PRELOAD OF DIFFERENTIAL BEARINGS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400621.xml" xrefid="hl1400621">ADJUST PRELOAD OF DIFFERENTIAL BEARINGS
                </hotlnk>
                for the proper setting.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dial Indicator Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach a dial indicator on the mounting flange of the carrier.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the dial indicator so that the plunger or pointer is against the back surface of
                    the ring gear (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a2">Figure 102</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f14006a2" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14006a2" filename="../figg14/G14006a2.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 102. Adjust Dial Indicator</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When you turn the adjusting rings, always use a tool that engages two or more opposite
                            notches in the ring. A "T" bar wrench can be used for this purpose. If the tool does not
                            correctly fit into the notches, damage to the lugs will occur (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a3">Figure 103</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f14006a3" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14006a3" filename="../figg14/G14006a3.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 103. Loosen Bearing Adjusting Ring</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. T-BAR WRENCH</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ADJUSTING RING OPPOSITE RING GEAR</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the bearing adjusting ring that is opposite the ring gear so that a small amount
                    of end play shows on the dial indicator (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a3">Figure 103</hotlnk>). Move the differential and ring gear to the left and
                    right with pry bars while you read the dial indicator. Use the following Step A or B.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use two pry bars that fit between the bearing adjusting rings and ends of the
                        differential case. The pry bars MUST NOT touch the differential bearings (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a4">Figure 104</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f14006a4" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g14006a4" filename="../figg14/G14006a4.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 104. Use Pry Bars That Fit Between Bearing Adjusting Rings and Ends of
                            Differential Case
                        </caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use two pry bars between the differential case or ring gear and the carrier at
                        locations other than described in Step A. The pry bars MUST NOT touch the differential bearings
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a5">Figure 105</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f14006a5" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g14006a5" filename="../figg14/G14006a5.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 105. Use Pry Bars Between Differential Case or Ring Gear and Carrier</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the same bearing adjusting ring so that no end play shows on the dial indicator.
                    Move the differential and ring gear to the left and right as needed. Repeat Step A or B.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten each bearing adjusting ring one notch from the zero end play measured in Step
                    4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue by checking runout of the ring gear.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Micrometer Method</title>
            <para>A second method of checking preload is to measure the expansion between the bearing caps after you
                tighten the adjusting rings.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn both adjusting rings hand tight against the differential bearings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the distance X or Y between opposite surfaces of the bearing caps. Use a large
                    micrometer of the correct size (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a6">Figure 106</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14006a7">Figure 107</hotlnk>). Make a note of the measurement.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14006a6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14006a6" filename="../figg14/G14006a6.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 106. Measure Distance X or Y Between Opposite Surfaces of Bearing Caps</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f14006a7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14006a7" filename="../figg14/G14006a7.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 107. Use Correct Size Micrometer</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten each bearing adjusting ring one notch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the distance X or Y again. Compare the dimension with the distance X or Y
                    measured in Step 2. The difference between the two dimensions is the amount the bearing caps have
                    expanded.
                </para>
                <para>Example: Measurements of a Q-100 carrier.</para>
                <para>Distance X or Y before tightening adjusting rings = 15.315 inch (389.00 mm). Distance X or Y after
                    tightening adjusting rings =15.324 inch (389.23 mm)
                </para>
                <para>15.324 inch - 15.315 inch = .009 inch (.23 mm) difference.</para>
                <para>If the dimension is within specifications, continue by checking runout of the ring gear. If the
                    dimension is less than specifications, repeat Step 3 and 4 as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400623.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400625.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
