<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLES: SPICER J400-S, W460-S - ASSEMBLE - PINION ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="15">
        <title>PINION ASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400493">Figure 93</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1400493" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1400493" filename="../figg14/g1400493.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 92. Pinion Assembly Exploded View</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press inner pinion bearing cone onto the pinion gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400494">Figure 94</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400494" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400494" filename="../figg14/g1400494.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 93. Press Inner Pinion Bearing Cone onto Pinion Gear</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press roller bearing onto the pinion gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400495">Figure 95</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400495" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400495" filename="../figg14/g1400495.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 94. Press Roller Bearing onto Pinion Gear</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stake roller bearing in nine places, using a staking tool (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400496">Figure 96</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400496" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400496" filename="../figg14/g1400496.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 95. Stake Roller Bearing in Nine Places</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Make sure all cage bores are free of nicks, dirt, or any contamination.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install inner pinion bearing cup into pinion cage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400497">Figure 97</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400497" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400497" filename="../figg14/g1400497.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 96. Install Inner Pinion Bearing Cup into Pinion Cage</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install outer pinion bearing cup into pinion cage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400498">Figure 98</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400498" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400498" filename="../figg14/g1400498.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Install Outer Pinion Bearing Cup into Pinion Cage</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a feeler gauge or shim stock (.0015 approx.) to ensure bearing cups are completely
                seated in bearing bores. This is necessary for proper pinion position (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400499">Figure 99</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400499" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400499" filename="../figg14/g1400499.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Use Feeler Gauge to Ensure Bearing Cups are Completely Seated</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place selective preload spacer, that was removed during disassembly, onto pinion (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a0">Figure 100</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a0" filename="../figg14/g14004a0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Place Selective Preload Spacer onto Pinion</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place pinion cage onto pinion gear inner bearing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a1">Figure 101</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a1" filename="../figg14/g14004a1.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Place Pinion Cage onto Pinion Gear Inner Bearing</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install outer pinion bearing cone onto pinion (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a2">Figure 102</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a2" filename="../figg14/g14004a2.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 101. Install Outer Pinion Bearing Cone onto Pinion</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect rear carrier end yoke seal surface for grooves caused by lip of seal. If grooves can
                be detected with fingernail, it should be replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install gear onto pinion of forward carrier. Tighten castellated nut to 600 ft-lbs. (813
                Nm). If hole in pinion does not align with slots in nut, tighten nut until they are aligned. Do not
                install roll pin at this time (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a3">Figure 103</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a3" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a3" filename="../figg14/g14004a3.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 102. Tighten Castellated ></caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>On rear carriers, install end yoke onto pinion without seal to allow proper setting of bearing
                        preload. Tighten pinion nut to 900 to 1200 ft-lbs. (1220 to 1627 Nm).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Pinion cage should be rotated while tightening pinion nut to seat and align the pinion
                        bearings.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>There are two methods of measuring pinion bearing preload and both are acceptable. Mechanic's
                        preference and available tools determine which method will be used.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To measure preload with the spring scale, clamp the end yoke horizontally in a soft-jawed
                vise. Attach one end of cord to a bolt hole in the pinion cage, wrap cord around pinion cage and attach
                the other end of cord to the spring scale. Rotate pinion cage by pulling scale. Read scale during fourth
                revolution. Scale reading must be between 3 and 9 lbs. (1.4 and 4.0 kg) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a4">Figure 104</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a4" filename="../figg14/g14004a4.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 103. Measure Preload With Spring Scale</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To measure preload with the inch pound torque wrench, assemble pinion cage into the carrier
                housing and install two mounting bolts to anchor the unit. Rotate pinion gear with inch pound torque
                wrench as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a5">Figure 105</hotlnk>. Torque measurement will be taken during fourth revolution
                and must be between 10 and 30 in-lbs. (1.1 and 3.4 Nm) without pinion seal (rear).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a5" filename="../figg14/g14004a5.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 104. Measure Preload With Inch Pound Torque Wrench</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When preload reading does not fall within allowable limits, bearing load can be increased by
                        using a thinner spacer or decreased by using a thicker spacer.
                    </para>
                    <para>.001 inch (.025 mm) change in preload spacer thickness changes scale reading by approximately
                        10 lbs. .001 change in preload spacer will change torque to rotate by approximately 30 in-lbs.
                        (3.4 Nm). This is only a guide. Individual carriers may vary slightly. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s14004_HL1400402.xml" xrefid="hl1400402">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                        for available spacers.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Closer adjustment can be made by sanding next thicker spacer to desired thickness using emery
                        cloth on a flat surface.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Wash spacer thoroughly of emery cuttings before installing on pinion.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper preload is achieved, install new roll pin into forward carrier pinion. If roll
                pin cannot be installed, tighten pinion nut until roll pin can be installed. Pinion gear and cage
                assembly are now ready to be installed into the carrier housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a6">Figure 106</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a6" filename="../figg14/g14004a6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 105. Install New Roll Pin into Forward Carrier Pinion</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper preload is achieved on rear carriers, remove end yoke and install new seal.
                Apply a small amount of light grease on lip of sealing surface prior to installation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean and dry threads on pinion. Coat threads with Loctite #680 (green) adhesive compound or
                its equivalent. Install end yoke, washer, and new prevailing torque pinion nut. Tighten nut to 900 to
                1200 ft-lbs. (1220 to 1627 Nm) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004a7">Figure 107</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004a7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004a7" filename="../figg14/g14004a7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 106. Tighten Prevailing Torque Pinion Nut</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
