<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION, SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - WHEEL
        DIFFERENTIAL LOCK
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1401201">
        <title>WHEEL DIFFERENTIAL LOCK</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Eaton wheel differential lock is an optional feature for Eaton axles. In operation, it positively
                locks the wheel differential to provide improved traction under adverse road conditions.
            </para>
            <para>The differential lock is driver-controlled through an electric switch or air valve mounted in the cab.
                The locking mechanism is air-operated to engage a mechanical clutch and lock the wheel differential. It
                is spring-operated to disengage the lock and permit the wheel differential to function normally.
            </para>
            <para>The wheel differential lock consists of three major assemblies (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401251">Figure 51</hotlnk>):
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401251" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401251" filename="../figg14/g1401251.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. Wheel Differential Lock</caption>
            </figure>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A shift cylinder assembly which operates a shift fork and push rod assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A shift fork and push rod assembly which engages and disengages the differential lock curvic
                        clutch assembly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A curvic clutch assembly which consists of a sliding clutch splined to a double-splined axle
                        shaft and a fixed clutch which is splined to the differential case hub.
                    </para>
                    <para>The differential lock also includes a selector switch (electric) which senses clutch
                        engagement and sends an electrical signal to a cab-mounted indicator light (or an audible signal
                        device).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
