<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - REASSEMBLE - INSTALL TWO-PIECE SPIGOT BEARING ASSEMBLIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="5">
        <title>INSTALL TWO-PIECE SPIGOT BEARING ASSEMBLIES</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This procedure applies to some 160 Series single rear axles and rear rear tandem axles. These
                    axles may also use a one-piece spigot bearing with a snap ring retainer.
                </para>
                <para>The inner race of two-piece spigot bearings must be staked in place on RS series rear axles.
                    Before you stake the pinion, you must heat the pinion stem to soften it.
                </para>
                <para>A peen tool kit is available (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_58.xml" xrefid="hl1400605">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>) which includes
                    everything required to perform this procedure.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply two stripes of temperature indicating liquid on the pinion stem from the top to the
                bottom (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400661">Figure 61</hotlnk>). Apply a green stripe to indicate 400&#176;F and a blue
                stripe to indicate 500&#176;F
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400661" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400661" filename="../figg14/g1400661.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 61. Apply Temperature Indicating Liquid on Pinion Stem</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the heating shield over the pinion stem so that you can see the temperature indicating
                liquid through the hole in the shield (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400662">Figure 62</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400662" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400662" filename="../figg14/g1400662.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 62. Put Heating Shield Over Pinion Stem</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To protect yourself from injury, wear safety glasses when you do Steps 3-6. Wear heat
                        resistant gloves while you do Steps 3 and 4.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not heat the pinion stem without the heat shield in place. Also, do not overheat the pinion
                        stem or you will weaken the metal which can cause early failure. Correct heating will take
                        approximately 25-35 seconds, depending on how hot the torch is.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Light and adjust the torch until the white part of the flame is approximately 1/4 inch long.
                Keep the white part of the flame approximately 1/8 inch from the top of the stem (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400663">Figure 63</hotlnk>). Move the flame around the outer diameter of the top of
                the pinion stem. The green temperature indicating liquid will turn black before the blue liquid does.
                Heat the stem until the blue liquid turns black at a point in the middle of the window.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400663" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400663" filename="../figg14/g1400663.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 63. Keep White Part of Torch Flame 1/8 Inch From Top of Stem</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the flame and the heat shield from the pinion. Let the pinion air cool for 10
                minutes. Use a razor blade to remove the temperature indicating liquid.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not press or hit directly on the new inner race in Step 5 or you will damage the bearing.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a press, if available, or a brass hammer to install the new inner race. Use the old
                inner race as a sleeve. The race is completely seated when you cannot fit a 0.002 inch feeler gauge
                between the race and the pinion shoulder.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If you cannot hold the races in place, try using the staking tool instead of the old race to
                        start the new race on the stem. But, use the old race to completely seat the new race.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In Step 6, you do not need to use the plastigage for every stake. Just use it until you are
                        sure you are hitting the punch with the correct force.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the staking tool over the bearing race. Cut a one-inch piece from the green plastigage
                strip and put in between the punch and the staking tool (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400664">Figure 64</hotlnk>
                - View A). Hit the punch with a two-three pound brass hammer to upset the end of the pinion stem. Then,
                remove the strip and measure its thickness against the gauge on the wrapper that the strip came in. The
                strip must not be less than 0.003 inch thick. This thickness indicates that you are using enough force
                when you hit the punch. If the strip is too thin, then you must hit the punch harder so the stake will
                hold the race in place. Rotate the tool and repeat this procedure until there are six evenly spaced
                stake marks around the stem (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400664">Figure 64</hotlnk>
                - View B).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400664" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400664" filename="../figg14/g1400664.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 64. Put Plastigage Strip Between Punch and Staking Tool</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PUNCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PLASTIGAGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STAKING TOOL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BEARING INNER RACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. STAKES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With a press or a soft mallet and sleeve, install the outer race and roller assembly into
                its bore in the carrier. Use a sleeve that is the same size as the outer race and press the bearing
                until it is squarely against the shoulder in the bottom of its bore.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply axle lubricant on bearing cups in the cage and bearing cones.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the drive pinion into the bearing cage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing spacer or spacers on pinion shaft against the inner bearing cone (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400665">Figure 65</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400665" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400665" filename="../figg14/g1400665.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 65. Install Bearing Spacer(s) on Pinion Shaft</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BEARING SPACER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BEARING CAGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INNER BEARING CONE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DRIVE PINION</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. OUTER BEARING CONE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The spacer or spacers control the preload adjustment of the drive pinion bearings.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the outer bearing cone on pinion shaft against the spacer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400665">Figure 65</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT install pinion seal in bearing cage. Continue with adjusting preload of pinion
                        bearings.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
