<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - ASSEMBLE -
        OUTPUT YOKE OR FLANGE AND OIL SEAL FOR THE OUTPUT BEARING CAGE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OUTPUT YOKE OR FLANGE AND OIL SEAL FOR THE OUTPUT BEARING CAGE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply the lubricant that is used in the axle housing to the inner bore of the output bearing
                cage or the outer diameter of the new oil seal. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual for recommended lubes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Hold the seal only on the outer diameter. Do not touch the lips on the inner diameter of the seal.
                    If you touch the lips on the inner diameter of the seal, you will contaminate the lips and cause a
                    leak between the shaft and the seal.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the oil seal in the cage so that the flange is parallel to the top of the cage.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not apply pressure after the flange of the seal touches the top of the cage or you will
                        damage the seal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Observe all warnings and cautions concerning press operation to avoid serious personal injury and
                    possible damage to components.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a press and a sleeve, or a mallet and a sleeve, to install the seal in the cage. The
                seal is correctly installed when the metal flange of the seal seats on the top of the cage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011b8">Figure 118</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011b8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011b8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 118. Install Seal in Cage</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BEARING CAGE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. OIL SEAL</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SLEEVE</callout1>
                <callout1>4. PRESS</callout1>
                <callout1>5. FLAT METAL PLATE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the seal is installed, a gap of 0.015 to 0.030 inch (0.381 to 0.762 mm) can exist
                between the flange and the cage. The gap is a normal condition because of the flexible coating on the
                flange of the seal. Use a feeler gauge to measure the gap around the complete flange-to- cage area. If
                the gap varies more than 0.010 inch (0.254 mm) between the highest and lowest measurement, remove and
                reseat the seal (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011b9">Figure 119</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011b9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011b9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 119. Gap of 0.015 to 0.030 Inch Can Exist</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The gap cannot be measured in the RT-40-145. The seal seats below the lip.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the yoke surface for scratches, corrosion or a wear track from the previous oil
                seal. Replace the yoke if any of these conditions exist.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the lead chamfer of the yoke for nicks and burrs which may damage the sealing lip
                during installation. Repair nicks and burrs with emery cloth where necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not use a Speedi-Sleeve with Rockwell triple lip oil seals. The edge of the sleeve will catch
                    and roll the center dust lip and result in early seal leakage.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wipe clean the yoke sealing surface and face.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the splines in the yoke or flange and on the output shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply axle lubricant to the splines in the yoke or flange and the output shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not use a hammer or a mallet to install the yoke or flange. A hammer or mallet can damage the
                    yoke or flange and the bearings.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a press and a sleeve or an installation tool to install the yoke or flange on the output
                shaft. Make sure that the splines inside the yoke or flange are aligned with the splines on the output
                shaft. If a press and a sleeve are used, make sure that the output shaft is supported.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nut that fastens the output yoke or flange to the output shaft. Put a holding
                tool on the yoke, or flange and tighten the nut to 450 to 650 ft-lbs. (610 to 881 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_40.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_42.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
