<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLE: INTERNATIONAL - REMOVE - REAR CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REAR CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Steam clean axle assembly before removing rear carrier.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove drain plug and drain lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect drive shaft at rear U-joint.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If pinion or pinion bearings are to be removed, break loose pinion nut at this time.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove axle flange nuts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold a large brass drift or a brass hammer against the center of the axle shaft flange.
                Strike the drift with sharp blows from a large hammer or sledge, until axle shaft separates from hub.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not strike the axle flange directly with a steel hammer or sledge. This may crack and
                        splinter material, possibly causing serious or fatal injury. Do not pry or chisel axle flange
                        away from hub or damage to sealing surfaces could occur.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support carrier assembly on roller jack. Secure as necessary to prevent carrier from falling
                from jack when removed from housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen differential carrier-to-axle housing bolts. Remove all bolts except top two. These
                two bolts will prevent carrier assembly from falling.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Separate carrier from housing using removal slots (
                <hotlnk document="s14009_11.xml" xrefid="f1400905">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Be certain carrier is balanced
                properly on jack, and remove top two carrier mounting bolts. Remove carrier assembly from axle housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount carrier assembly in a suitable rebuild stand. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14009_43.xml" xrefid="hl1400901">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>p.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
