<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - REMOVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REMOVE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>- To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when doing maintenance or
                        service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc id="x1401112" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="7">
            <title>DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM THE AXLE HOUSING</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the vehicle is on a level surface.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle only supported by
                            jacks. Jacks can slip or fall over and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Properly discard lubricant that is removed from the axle housing. Lubricant that is
                            removed may be contaminated. Contaminated fluid may cause incorrect operation, damage and
                            serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the vehicle so that the wheels are off the ground. Support the vehicle with jack
                    stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the oil drain plug from the bottom of the axle housing and drain lubricant from
                    the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For axles without an oil pump, omit Steps 4, 5 and 6.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the oil filter shield from the input bearing cage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a filter strap wrench to remove the oil filter. Properly discard the filter and
                    replace it with a new filter at assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401107">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401107" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Install New Oil Filter</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>There can be approximately one pint of lubricant remaining in the filter. Be careful that
                            the oil does not spill when removing the filter.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, remove the oil filter adapter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On an axle with a driver controlled main differential lock, the differential lock must
                    be shifted into and held in the locked (engaged) position. The locked position gives enough
                    clearance between the shift collar and the axle housing to permit the removal of the carrier. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s14011_52.xml" xrefid="x1401101">REMOVE DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM THE AXLE
                        HOUSING</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <para>An alternate method to obtain clearance is to remove the cover of the air shift unit from the
                    differential carrier. Remove the piston. Remove the shift shaft and spring from the fork. The fork
                    and the clutch collar will fall into the carrier and the carrier can be removed in the normal
                    manner. Remember to remove the fork and the clutch collar after the carrier is removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1 id="x1401115">
                <para count="1">Remove the stud nuts or bolts and the washers from the flanges of both axle shafts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401108">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401108" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Remove Stud Nuts or Bolts and Washers From Axle Shaft Flanges</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. TAPERED DOWELS</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. GASKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. HUB</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. AXLE SHAFT</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. WASHER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If used, loosen the tapered dowels in the flanges of both axle shafts.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Wear safe eye protection. Do not hit the round driving lugs on the flanges of axle shafts.
                            Lugs can break and cause serious personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <title>Brass Drift Method</title>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>A 1.5 inch (38.1 mm) diameter brass hammer can be used for a drift.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Hold a 1.5 inch (38.1 mm) diameter brass drift against the center of the axle shaft,
                            INSIDE THE ROUND DRIVING LUGS (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401109">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1401109" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401109.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                     resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 9. Hold Brass Drift Against Center of Axle Shaft</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Hit the end of the drift with a large hammer (five to six pounds, 2.26 - 2.72 kg) and the
                            axle shaft and tapered dowels will loosen.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">
                        <title>Air Hammer Method</title>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Wear safe eye protection when using an air hammer. Power tools and components can
                                loosen and break and cause serious personal injury.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Use an air hammer (such as Chicago Pneumatic, CP-4181-PULER or equivalent) with a round
                            hammer bit to loosen the axle shaft.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Put the round hammer bit on the axle shaft between the studs. Operate the air hammer and
                            loosen the axle shaft and tapered dowels (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1401110">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1401110" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401110.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                     resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 10. Loosen Axle Shaft and Tapered Dowels</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <specpara>
                            <caution>
                                <para>Do not use a chisel or wedge to loosen the axle shafts and dowels. The chisel or
                                    wedge can damage the hub, axle shafts and, if used, the oil seals.
                                </para>
                                <para>Do not use a hammer to loosen or remove the yoke or flange. A hammer can damage
                                    the parts and cause alignment problems.
                                </para>
                            </caution>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If used, remove the tapered dowels. Remove both axle shafts from the axle assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401108">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the forward and rear drive shafts.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Always use a flange or yoke bar during removal and installation of the flange yoke nut to
                            prevent damage to the gearing.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach a flange bar to the flange or install a yoke bar over the yoke.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the air lines at the inter-axle differential shift unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the output shaft nut, washer and yoke or flange. Use a puller tool to remove the
                    yoke or flange from the shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401111">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401111" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Remove Yoke or Flange From Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the output shaft bearing cage bolts and washers. Pull the bearing cage, bearings
                    and shaft assembly from the axle housing. If necessary, loosen the cage from the housing with a soft
                    mallet (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401112">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401112" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401112.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Loosen Cage From Housing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a hydraulic roller jack under the differential carrier to support the assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401113">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401113" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg14/g1401113.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Put Hydraulic Roller Jack Under Differential Carrier</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all but the top two carrier-to-housing bolts or stud nuts and washers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401113">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen, but do not remove, the top two carrier-to-housing fasteners. The fasteners will
                    hold the carrier in the housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the differential carrier in the axle housing. Use a plastic mallet to hit the
                    mounting flange of carrier at several points.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the carrier is loosened, remove the top fasteners and washers that hold the
                    assembly in the axle housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove the carrier from the axle housing using the hydraulic roller jack. Use
                    a pry bar that has a round end to help remove the carrier from the housing.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When using a pry bar, be careful not to damage the carrier or housing flange. Damage to
                            these surfaces will cause oil leaks.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On axles with a driver controlled main differential lock, if air pressure is used to
                    shift the differential to the locked (engaged) position, release the air pressure. Disconnect the
                    air hose from the shift unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the differential carrier by the input yoke or flange and put the assembly in a
                    repair stand. Use a lifting tool for this procedure. DO NOT LIFT BY HAND.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
