<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION, SINGLE SPEED AXLES: SPICER D135-S,
        F155-S, F170-S SERIES - INSTALL - RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="8">
        <title>RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Gear tooth nomenclature (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401465">Figure 65</hotlnk>)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f1401465" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401465" filename="../figg14/g1401465.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 65. Gear Tooth Nomenclature</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">toe</emph>
            of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the end towards the center.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">heel</emph>
            of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the outer end.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">top land</emph>
            of a gear tooth is the surface of the top of the tooth.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and rotate with pinion to obtain correct pattern
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401466">Figure 66</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401466" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401466" filename="../figg14/g1401466.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 66. Marking Compound on Ring Gear Teeth</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring gear
                teeth shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401467">Figure 67</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401467" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401467" filename="../figg14/g1401467.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 67. Correct Tooth Contact</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401468">Figure 68</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Recheck backlash as described
                in
                <hotlnk document="s14014_24.xml" xrefid="hl1401412">INSTALL, DIFFERENTIAL</hotlnk>. To reduce backlash,
                loosen the right side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is within specifica- tion. The tooth
                contact pattern should now have the same general shape and location as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401467">Figure 67</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid reducing differential bearing pre- load excessively, further
                loosening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Place a dial indicator directly on each adjusting ring to measure the exact amount of
                additional adjustment. Decreasing backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401468" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401468" filename="../figg14/g1401468.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 68. Ring Gear Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401469">Figure 69</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Recheck backlash. To increase
                backlash, tighten the right side adjusting ring further until the measured backlash is within
                specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread more across the ring gear tooth as in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401467">Figure 67</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid increasing differential bearing preload excessively, further
                tightening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal loosening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Place a dial indicator directly on each adjusting ring to measure the exact amount of
                additional adjustment. Increasing backlash moves the ring gear away from the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401469" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401469" filename="../figg14/g1401469.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 69. Ring Gear In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401470">Figure 70</hotlnk>), the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be
                moved out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401467">Figure 67</hotlnk>. This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion bearing
                cage shim. Re-adjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting distance has
                been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401470" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401470" filename="../figg14/g1401470.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 70. Pinion In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401471">Figure 71</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and must be
                moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact pattern. This
                is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion bearing cage shim. Re-adjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash
                as required once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401471" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401471" filename="../figg14/g1401471.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 71. Pinion Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper ring gear pattern is achieved, again tighten the differential bearing cap bolts
                to 115 to 135 ft-lbs. (156 to 183 N&#8226;m). Install adjusting ring retainers and new cotter pins of
                proper size (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401472">Figure 72</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401472" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401472" filename="../figg14/g1401472.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 72. Tighten Differential Bearing Cap Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14014_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14014_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
