<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - DRIVER CONTROLLED MAIN DIFFERENTIAL LOCK - CHECK THE DIFFERENTIAL LOCK
        (IF EQUIPPED)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CHECK THE DIFFERENTIAL LOCK (IF EQUIPPED)</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shift the vehicle transmission to neutral and start the engine to get the system air
                pressure to the normal level.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not start the vehicle engine and engage the transmission with one wheel raised from the
                        floor. When the differential is in locked (engaged) position, power will go to the wheel on the
                        floor and cause the vehicle to move.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the differential lock switch (in the cab of the vehicle) in the unlocked (disengaged)
                position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drive the vehicle at 5 to 10 MPH (8 to 16 kmph) and check the differential lock indicator
                light. The light must be off when the switch is in the unlocked position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Continue to drive the vehicle and put the differential lock switch in the locked (engaged)
                position. Let up on the accelerator to remove the driveline torque and permit the shift. The light must
                be on when the switch is in the locked position.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the indicator light remains "on" with the switch in the unlocked position, the differential
                        is still in the locked position. Check to make sure that the manual engaging capscrew was
                        removed from the cylinder cover of the actuator assembly. See Steps 5 through 8 of
                        <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400632.xml" xrefid="hl1400630">INSTALL CARRIER INTO AXLE HOUSING,
                            Manual Engaging Method</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400632.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_44.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
