<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES: SPICER S100-S, S105-S, S135-S, S150-S - INSTALL
        - CARRIER INTO AXLE HOUSING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CARRIER INTO AXLE HOUSING</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thoroughly clean the inside of the carrier housing and inspect the housing mounting surface
                for nicks and general cleanliness. Stone the surface if necessary to remove burrs or nicks.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a 1/8 inch bead of Loctite 518 gasket eliminator onto the axle housing mounting flange
                and around each bolt hole (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401732">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401732" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401732" filename="../figg14/G1401732.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Apply Gasket Eliminator onto Axle Housing Mounting Flange and Around Each Bolt
                    Hole
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Thread 2 studs into housing 180 degrees apart. This will eliminate rotation of carrier
                assembly after it makes contact with the gasket material.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install carrier assembly into axle housing. Clean mounting bolts, coat with Loctite #277
                (red) or equivalent, and install. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICANTS AND SEALERS in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual. Tighten evenly in a cross pattern to 100 to 120 ft-lbs. (135 to 163 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow one hour cure time for gasket material before adding hypoid gear lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove old axle flange gasket and clean mating surfaces of hub and axle flange.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install new axle flange gasket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the axle shafts to proper location. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14017v_26.xml" xrefid="hl1401702">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                for proper torque specifications of axle flange nuts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean and install drain plug. Fill unit to proper level with hypoid gear lubricant.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14017v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
