<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Wheel bearings will either be grease or oil lubricated. Refer to the GROUP 10, LUBRICATION in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the correct type of lubricant to use.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="1">
            <title>STEEL HUB WITH DISC WHEELS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>As of the latter part of model year 1993, International vehicles with steel hubs and disc
                        wheels have an oil fill/drain capability through the axle mounting flange stud hole. One stud
                        was omitted and the hole drilled clear through, and a thread sealed capscrew used in place of
                        the stud (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1400137">Figure 39</hotlnk>). This design enables the service mechanic to
                        drain/fill and check the lube for contamination without removing the hub assembly. To drain or
                        remove some lube from the hub, place hub drain/fill screw at 6 o'clock position and remove
                        screw. Use container to catch lube. To fill hub with lube, place drain/fill screw at 12 o'clock
                        position.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1400137" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400137" filename="../figg14/g1400137.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Hub Drain/Fill Hole and Screw</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HUB ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRAIN/FILL HOLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREAD SEALED CAPSCREW (BOLT)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a small amount of lube was removed to check lube condition, replace same amount with
                    new lube fluid. If totally drained, add one quart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If hub assembly is removed from axle for any reason, after hub assembly is installed on
                    the axle, add one quart of lube fluid to each hub assembly that was removed from the axle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten drain/fill screw to 219 - 240 ft-lbs. (297 - 325 N&#8226;m).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check rear differential for proper lube fluid level. Add if necessary. Refer to GROUP 10
                    - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for correct fluid type.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14001t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
