<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AUTOMATIC POSITIVE LOCKING TRACTION DIFFERENTIALS
        (NOSPIN/DETROIT LOCKER)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s14003" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5217" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>AUTOMATIC POSITIVE LOCKING TRACTION DIFFERENTIALS (NOSPIN/DETROIT LOCKER)</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>14877</ucode>
                <ucode>14880</ucode>
                <ucode>14881</ucode>
                <ucode>14882</ucode>
                <ucode>14883</ucode>
                <ucode>14886</ucode>
                <ucode>14887</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>WARNINGS</title>
            <para>Text and illustrations provided by Dyneer Corporation.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to follow these instructions will result in property damage and personal injury.
                    </para>
                    <para>Any increase in the size of the vehicle's engine, tires, weight, etc., may prohibit use of a
                        NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differential in a previously approved application. Any such modifications
                        should be reviewed by International Engineering before continuing to use the product.
                    </para>
                    <para>Do not use heat to disassemble drive axles. To do so can destroy heat treat properties and
                        weaken or distort axle components.
                    </para>
                    <para>Turn the engine off and raise all driving wheels of a NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differential
                        equipped axle when servicing wheels, brakes, axles or tires to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        Axles equipped with NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differentials deliver power to both wheels-even when
                        only one wheel is on the ground.
                    </para>
                    <para>NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differentials have compressed springs. Use a retaining bolt or some
                        other restraining means when separating the differential case halves (refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s14003_9.xml" xrefid="hl1400301">RETAINING BOLT
                            <xref refid="hl1400301"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        ).
                    </para>
                    <para>When repairing NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differentials, if major components show excessive wear,
                        the complete differential should be replaced. If a part is replaced, mating parts should also be
                        replaced in that it is likely that they too are damaged. Use of worn or damaged components can
                        lead to a recurrence of the original problem. NOTE: Use only International approved parts when
                        repairing NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differentials.
                    </para>
                    <para>Do not operate the vehicle if both wheels of a NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differential equipped
                        axle are not driving. Power to only one wheel can cause serious steering problems. Perform the
                        installation and operation tests under
                        <hotlnk document="s14003_14.xml" xrefid="hl1400302">TEST
                            <xref refid="hl1400302"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        before putting the vehicle into service.
                    </para>
                    <para>Use extreme caution when accelerating or decelerating on slippery or unstable surfaces.
                        Vehicles/axles equipped with traction differentials are inherently more sensitive to side-slip
                        than vehicles equipped with conventional differentials.
                    </para>
                    <para>Distribute the load evenly side-to-side, do not exceed the vehicle's rated payload capacity,
                        and keep the diameter of the tires equal. Failure to observe these measures can create a
                        difference in individual wheel speeds which can cause the NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differential to
                        deliver power to only one side of the vehicle and thus cause steering problems.
                    </para>
                    <para>Operate in low gear when coasting downhill into a turn. Braking capacity is reduced when a
                        NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differential equipped vehicle makes a turn while coasting downhill in that
                        the inside wheel is then disconnected from the driveline.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
