<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE SPEED AXLE: SPICER - INSTALL - RING GEAR AND PINION
        TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="8">
        <title>RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1400770">Figure 70</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1400770" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1400770" filename="../figg14/g1400770.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 70. Ring Gear and Pinion Tooth Contact Pattern</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The toe of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the end towards the center.</para>
        <para>The heel of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the outer end.</para>
        <para>The top land of a gear tooth is the surface of the top of the tooth.</para>
        <para></para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Paint 1/4 ring gear with marking compound and rotate with pinion to obtain contact pattern.
                Apply drag load to ring gear while rotating (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400771">Figure 71</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400771" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400771" filename="../figg14/g1400771.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 71. Paint 1/4 Ring Gear With Marking Compound</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring gear
                teeth shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400772">Figure 72</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400772" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400772" filename="../figg14/g1400772.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 72. Correct Tooth Contact Patterns</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400773">Figure 73</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Recheck backlash as described
                in
                <hotlnk document="s14007t_24.xml" xrefid="hl1400710">Step 6
                    <xref refid="hl1400710"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . To reduce backlash, loosen the right side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is within
                specification. The tooth contact pattern should now have the same general shape and location as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400772">Figure 72</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid reducing differential bearing preload excessively, further
                loosening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Decreasing backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400773" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400773" filename="../figg14/g1400773.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 73. Ring Gear Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
            <para></para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400774">Figure 74</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Recheck backlash. To increase
                backlash, tighten the right side adjusting ring further until the measured backlash is within
                specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread more across the ring gear tooth as in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400772">Figure 72</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid increasing differential bearing preload excessively, further
                tightening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal loosening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Increasing backlash moves the ring gear away from the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400774" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400774" filename="../figg14/g1400774.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 74. Ring Gear In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400775">Figure 75</hotlnk>, the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be moved
                out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400772">Figure 72</hotlnk>. This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion position
                cage shim. Re-adjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting distance has
                been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400775" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400775" filename="../figg14/g1400775.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 75. Pinion In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400776">Figure 76</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and must be
                moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact pattern. This
                is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion position cage shim. Re-adjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash
                as required once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400776" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400776" filename="../figg14/g1400776.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 76. Pinion Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper ring gear pattern is achieved, again tighten the differential bearing cap bolts
                to 275 to 320 ft-lbs. (373 to 434 N&#8226;m). Install adjusting ring retainers and new cotter pins of
                proper size (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400777">Figure 77</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400777" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400777" filename="../figg14/g1400777.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 77. Install Adjusting Ring Retainers and New Cotter Pins</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
