<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AUTOMATIC POSITIVE LOCKING TRACTION DIFFERENTIALS
        (NOSPIN/DETROIT LOCKER) - TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1400302">
        <title>TEST</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSTALLATION TEST</title>
            <para>Refer to .</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine turned off, raise driving axle(s) until all tires are out of contact
                    with any surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the transmission in gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant on the opposite side, start the installation test by rotating both
                    wheels in a forward direction as far as possible (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400310">Figure 10</hotlnk>). (Both wheels should stop after rotating a short
                    distance.)
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400310" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400310" filename="../figg14/G1400310.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. Start Installation Test</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant firmly holding the right wheel forward (against the stop), rotate the
                    left wheel rearward while listening for an indexing or clicking sound (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400311">Figure 11</hotlnk>). (The right wheel must be held firmly against the stop
                    or the left wheel will not disengage freely.) Grasp the left wheel to stop its rotation, and move it
                    slightly forward (in the direction of the stop). The NoSPIN differential should lock up.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400311" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400311" filename="../figg14/G1400311.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Rotate Left Wheel Rearward While Listening For Indexing or Clicking Sound
                    </caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate both wheels rearward as far as possible (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400312">Figure 12</hotlnk>). (Both wheels should stop after rotating a short
                    distance.)
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400312" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400312" filename="../figg14/G1400312.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Rotate Both Wheels Rearward</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With an assistant on the opposite side firmly holding the right wheel rearward (against
                    the stop), rotate the left wheel forward, again listening for an indexing or clicking sound (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400313">Figure 13</hotlnk>). (Again, the right wheel must be held firmly against
                    the stop or the left wheel will not disengage freely.) Grasp the left wheel to stop its rotation,
                    and move it slightly rearward (in the direction of the stop). The NoSPIN differential should lock
                    up.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400313" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400313" filename="../figg14/G1400313.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Rotate Left Wheel Forward While Listening For Indexing or Clicking Sound
                    </caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Repeat Steps 3, 4, 5 and 6, except hold the left wheel against the stops and rotate the right
                    wheel, in both forward and reverse.
                </para>
                <para>If properly installed, the rotating (or overrunning) wheel should cam out easily by hand, rotate
                    freely in both directions and produce a soft indexing or clicking sound. The NoSPIN differential
                    should not re-engage until the direction of rotation is reversed.
                </para>
                <para>If you hear repeated loud indexing or clicking sounds when performing this installation test, one
                    of the driven clutch assemblies may not be properly assembled to the spider. Recheck
                    <hotlnk document="s14003_12.xml" xrefid="hl1400306">REASSEMBLE
                        <xref refid="hl1400306"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    steps.
                </para>
                <para>If either wheel does not rotate freely in both directions, recheck each installation step. Also,
                    check hand and foot brakes for possible drag caused by improper adjustment. Be sure that all thrust
                    washers have been removed from the standard differential support case.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
