<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS -
        Specifications - Welding
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Welding</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>To provide a commercial quality weld for truck applications, the following welding information should
                be followed for welding transverse torque rods to rear axle housings.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Welder Certification</title>
            <para>All welding on axle housings must be done by welders certified by an independent testing laboratory to
                meet the requirements of AWS D1.1 Structural Welding Code.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Surface Preparation</title>
            <para>Weld joints must be free from contamination, such as moisture, lubricants and rust. Paint must be
                removed since it will adversely affect the weld quality.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weld Joint Fit-up</title>
            <para>A slight grind to fit condition may exist between the housing and bracket due to axle housing and
                bracket tolerances. Grind the bracket to fit (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011j8">Figure 198</hotlnk>). The bracket should fit-up as close as possible to avoid
                excessive welding.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011j8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011J8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 198. Grind to Fit</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weld Lengths</title>
            <para>The effective weld length shall not include skips, off location welds and/or other conditions defined
                in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x1401120">Weld Quality</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weld Location</title>
            <para>All welds should be centered laterally in the joint in a manner to insure fusion between the parts
                being joined. Portions of the weld which are undersize, or do not meet the minimum requirements for weld
                quality (undercut, porosity, craters) shall be considered as skips and are not considered in the weld
                length.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weld Leg Size</title>
            <para>The minimum weld leg has to be at least as thick as the minimum thickness of the thinnest member of
                the bracket.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Throat Thickness</title>
            <para>The minimum throat thickness of fillet welds are to be equal to 60% of the shortest weld leg size.
                Maximum throat thickness is to be limited to 100% of the longest leg size (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011j9">Figure 199</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011j9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011J9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 199. Throat Thickness</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>X = SHORTEST LEG SIZE</callout1>
                    <callout1>Y = LONGEST LEG SIZE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Definitions</title>
            <para>The welding terms shall be interpreted in accordance with the definitions given in AWS - Weld
                (ANSI/AWS A2.4 latest issue).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symbols</title>
            <para>Welding symbols shall be interpreted in accordance with AWS Standard Welding Symbols (ANSI/AWS A2.4
                latest issue).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x1401120">
            <title>Weld Quality</title>
            <para>Unless otherwise specified, the following characteristics shall be permitted. No more than one of
                these characteristics shall be permitted in the weld if any other characteristic is at the maximum
                limit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Undercut:</emph>
                Shall not exceed .030 inch (0.8 mm).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Craters:</emph>
                Unfilled craters are not considered part of the effective weld length, and are therefore limited by the
                length of the weld tolerance for gaps. They can be properly filled and counted in the weld length.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cracks and Burn-Through:</emph>
                Cracks in the weld and holes burned through the base stock will not be permitted.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Visible Porosity - Frequency:</emph>
                No more than four (4) significant pores shall be permitted in any 1 inch (25mm) of weld length with the
                average limited to one (1) per 1 inch (25mm) of weld length.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Visible Porosity - Severity:</emph>
                The maximum diameter of the pores shall be 1/16 inch (1.6 mm) and shall be spaced at least 1/16 inch
                (1.6 mm) apart. Pores must be larger than 1/64 inch (0.4 mm) in diameter to be considered significant.
                Porosity shall not be permitted in any weld specified as oil tight.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Inclusions:</emph>
                Non-metallic inclusions shall be considered and judged as a gap.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Welding Recommendations</title>
            <para>The welding rod used shall produce a minimum tensile strength of 70,000 psi using an all-weld-metal
                test sample tested in accordance with AWS B4.0. Typical processes and electrodes which meet this
                requirement are as follows:
            </para>
            <table id="t1401105">
                <title>Typical Processes and Electrodes</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.55in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.45in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Process</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Electrode</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>1. Shielded metal-arc welding of carbon low alloy steels.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>A.W.S. (American Welding Society) E70XX (Ref. AWS-A5.1-91)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>2. Gas metal-arc welding of carbon and low alloy steels.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>A.W.S. E-70X-X (Ref. AWS-A5.18-93)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3. Submerged arc welding of mild and low alloy steels.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>A.W.S. F-72-XXXXX (Ref. AWS-A5.17-89)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Use the voltage and amperage recommended by the electrode manufacturer. This will provide the best
                fusion and strongest weld.
            </para>
            <para>Do not "test the arc" on the housing. Deposit the required amount of metal with the least number of
                passes - one pass is preferred. Where a second pass is required, thoroughly remove the slag from the
                weld between passes.
            </para>
            <para>On brackets that require welding all around, distortion and stress can be further controlled by
                welding on opposite sides of the bracket alternately.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011k0">Figure 200</hotlnk>
                shows the tack welding sequence. Tack welds must be cleaned prior to final welding.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011k0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011K0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 200. Tack Welding Sequence</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011k1">Figure 201</hotlnk>
                shows the sequence and direction of the final weld. Start weld at each end of bracket and work toward
                middle of bracket. Remove the slag from the weld. Cover the tack welds with the final welds.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011k1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011K1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 201. Final Weld Sequence and Direction</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>There is a notch in the end of the transverse torque rod bracket for use as a moisture drain. Do not
                weld in the area of the notch (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011k2">Figure 202</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011k2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011K2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 202. Do Not Weld in Area of This Notch</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If information on welding locations of transverse rods is required, call 1-800-44TRUCK.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_57.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_59.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
