<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM DRIVE AXLES: EATON - INSTALL - REAR DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REAR DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Before installing carrier assembly, inspect and thoroughly clean interior of axle housing using an
                    appropriate solvent and clean rag.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use silicone rubber gasket compound on axle housing mating surface as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401316">Figure 16</hotlnk>. Completely remove all old gasket material prior to
                    applying new material. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the
                    recommended gasket compound. Install carrier and axle housing cover before compound sets or reapply.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1401316" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401316" filename="../figg14/G1401316.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 16. Lubrication of Rear Differential Carrier</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install differential carrier assembly.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To assist in installing complete differential carrier, use two pieces of threaded rod threaded
                        into carrier bolt holes. Rod should be approximately 6 inches long. Use these to pilot the
                        carrier into the housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install carrier to axle housing. Tighten bolts to 160 to 176 ft-lbs. (217 to 239
                N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install axle shafts and axle stud nuts. (If used, also install lockwashers and tapered
                dowels.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add axle lubricant. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual
                for recommended lubricants. Fill to bottom of filler hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect inter-axle driveline, making sure all yokes are in phase. Lubricate U-joints.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
