<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLE: INTERNATIONAL - INSTALL - RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTRACT PATTERN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="7">
        <title>RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTRACT PATTERN</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Gear tooth nomenclature (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400948">Figure 48</hotlnk>)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f1400948" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1400948" filename="../figg14/g1400948.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 48. Gear Tooth Nomenclature</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">toe</emph>
            of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the end towards the center.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">heel</emph>
            of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the outer end.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">top land</emph>
            of a gear tooth is the surface of the top of the tooth.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To obtain correct contact pattern, paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and apply
                load while rotating pinion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring gear
                teeth shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400949">Figure 49</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400949" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400949" filename="../figg14/g1400949.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. Correct Tooth Contact</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400950">Figure 50</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Recheck backlash as described
                in
                <hotlnk document="s14009_HL1400910.xml" xrefid="hl1400910">DIFFERENTIAL</hotlnk>. To reduce backlash,
                loosen the differential case side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is within specification.
                The tooth contact pattern should now have the same general shape and location as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400949">Figure 49</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                backlash than normal is required.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400950" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400950" filename="../figg14/g1400950.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Ring Gear Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To avoid reducing differential bearing preload excessively, further loosening of the differential case
                side adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the flange side adjusting ring.
                Decreasing backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400951">Figure 51</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Recheck backlash. To increase
                backlash, tighten the differential case side adjusting ring further until the measured backlash is
                within specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread more across the ring gear tooth as in
                step 2. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more backlash than normal is required. To avoid
                increasing differential bearing preload excessively, further tightening of the differential case side
                adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal loosening of the flange side adjusting ring. Increasing
                backlash moves the ring gear away from the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400951" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400951" filename="../figg14/g1400951.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. Ring Gear In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400952">Figure 52</hotlnk>), the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be
                moved out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in step 2.
                This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion position cage shim. Readjust pinion-to-ring gear
                backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400952" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400952" filename="../figg14/g1400952.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 52. Pinion In Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400953">Figure 53</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and must be
                moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact pattern. This
                is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion position cage shim. Readjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash
                as required once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400953" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400953" filename="../figg14/g1400953.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 53. Pinion Out Too Far</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper ring gear pattern is achieved, again tighten the differential bearing cap
                bolts. Install adjusting ring retainers and bolts and tighten evenly to 20 to 30 ft-lbs. (27 to 41 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Assembly of carrier is complete for rear rear axles.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On forward rear axles, apply 1/8" bead of Loctite 518 onto mating surfaces (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400954">Figure 54</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400954" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400954" filename="../figg14/g1400954.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 54. Apply Loctite 518</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install inter-axle differential assembly onto carrier. Coat clean mounting bolts with
                Loctite #277 or its equivalent and tighten evenly. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14009_HL1400908.xml" xrefid="hl1400908">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                for the correct torque.
            </para>
            <para>Assembly of carrier is complete.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_HL1400904.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
