<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - DISASSEMBLE - REMOVE DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>REMOVE DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM AXLE HOUSING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before the differential carrier can be removed or installed, the differential lock MUST be shifted
                into and held in the locked (engaged) position. The locked position gives enough clearance between the
                shift collar and the axle housing to permit the removal or installation of the carrier.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the axle shafts were removed for towing with the differential in the unlocked (disengaged)
                        position, install the right-hand axle shaft into the housing before continuing. Follow steps 1
                        and 2 of
                        <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400601.xml" xrefid="hl1400601">INSTALL AXLE SHAFTS</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>To shift into the locked position, use either of the following
                <emph type="bold">Air Pressure</emph>
                or
                <emph type="bold">Manual Engaging</emph>
                methods.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1400604">
            <title>Air Pressure Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the drain plug from the bottom of the housing and drain the lubricant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the right hand wheel of the drive axle off the floor with a hoist or jack.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not start the vehicle engine and engage the transmission with one wheel raised from the
                            floor. When the differential is in locked (engaged) position, power will go to the wheel on
                            the floor and cause the vehicle to move and possibly cause personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a jack stand under the right-hand spring seat to hold the vehicle in the raised
                    position.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or tip over and cause
                            injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the driveline from the pinion input yoke.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the vehicle air line from the differential lock actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect an auxiliary air supply to the differential lock actuator assembly.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If an auxiliary air supply is not available, continue to
                            <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400602">Manual Engaging Method</hotlnk>
                            of locking the differential.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and hold air pressure to the actuator assembly. The air pressure will move the
                    shift collar to engage with the splines on the differential case half and lock the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure that the shift collar has moved the full distance on the splines of the
                    differential case half. Rotate the drive pinion or the right-hand wheel until the right-hand wheel
                    makes one complete rotation (forward or backward).
                </para>
                <para>Continue to hold the main differential in the locked position with air pressure until the carrier
                    assembly is completely removed from the axle housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shafts from the housing. Follow Steps 1 through 3 of
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400603.xml" xrefid="hl1400603">REMOVE AXLE SHAFTS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the carrier from the housing. Refer to Steps 7 through 14 of
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400602">Manual Engaging Method</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the carrier is removed from the axle housing, release the air pressure from the
                    actuator assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1400602">
            <title>Manual Engaging Method</title>
            <para>If an auxiliary air supply is not available or if the differential carrier is to be stored for later
                use, use this manual engaging method (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400605">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400605" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400605" filename="../figg14/g1400605.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Manual Engaging Method</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DIFFERENTIAL LOCK ACTUATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CYLINDER COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WIRE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. OPERATING PISTON HOLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. BOTTOM SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. MANUAL ENGAGING CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. TOP SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR MANUAL ENGAGING CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. DIFFERENTIAL (PLAIN) CASE HALF</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. AIR LINE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow Steps 1 through 5 of the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400604">Air Pressure Method</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug and gasket from the hole in the center of the cylinder cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the manual engaging capscrew from the top storage hole in the cylinder cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plug and gasket into the bottom storage hole in the cylinder cover.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The storage hole for the plug and gasket is the opposite end of the storage hole for the
                            manual engaging capscrew.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the manual engaging capscrew into the threaded hole in the center of the
                    cylinder cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the manual adjusting capscrew to the right until the head is approximately 1/4 inch
                    from the cylinder cover. DO NOT turn the capscrew beyond its normal stop. The capscrew is now in the
                    service position and the main differential lock is completely engaged.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>There will be a small amount of spring resistance felt when you turn in the manual
                            engaging capscrew. If a high resistance is felt before reaching the locked (engaged)
                            position, STOP TURNING THE CAPSCREW, or the cover and capscrew threads will be damaged. A
                            high resistance on the capscrew indicates that the splines of the shift collar and the
                            differential case half are not aligned or engaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>To align the splines, use the following procedure:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the drive pinion or right-hand wheel to align the splines of the shift collar
                        and case half while you turn in the manual engaging capscrew.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When the normal amount of spring resistance is again felt on the capscrew, the
                        splines are engaged. Continue to turn in the manual engaging capscrew until the head is
                        approximately 1/4 inch from the cylinder cover.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a hydraulic roller jack under the differential carrier to support the assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400606">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400606" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400606" filename="../figg14/g1400606.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Place Hydraulic Roller Jack Under Differential Carrier</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. WOOD BLOCK</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. HYDRAULIC JACK</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all but the top two carrier-to-housing capscrews or stud nuts and washers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the top two carrier-to-housing fasteners and leave attached to the assembly. The
                    fasteners will hold the carrier in the housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the differential carrier in the axle housing. Use a leather mallet to hit the
                    mounting flange of carrier at several points.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Some carrier models have threaded puller screw holes in the mounting flange. Puller screws
                            can be used to loosen and pull the carrier from the axle housing. If puller screws are used,
                            clean the threaded holes before the puller screws are installed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the carrier is loosened, remove the top two fasteners.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove the carrier from the axle housing using the hydraulic roller jack. Use
                    a pry bar that has a round end to help remove the carrier from the housing.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When using a pry bar, be careful not to damage the carrier or housing flange. Damage to
                            these surfaces will cause oil leaks.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard the carrier-to- housing gasket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the differential carrier by the input yoke or flange and put the assembly in a
                    repair stand (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400607">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Use a lifting tool for this procedure. Do not lift by
                    hand. The repair stand is available through P.D.C. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_58.xml" xrefid="hl1400605">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400607" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400607" filename="../figg14/g1400607.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Put Differential Carrier Assembly in Repair Stand</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. REPAIR STAND</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
