<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - SELF-STEERING AXLE ASSEMBLIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl14019060">
        <title>SELF-STEERING AXLE ASSEMBLIES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The self-steering axles reduce tire wear; but are more complex than fixed axles. Self-steering axles
                are similar to front, non-driving, steering axles. Like a front axle, the steering arms and knuckles at
                the ends of the self-steer axle are connected by a tie rod so that both tires on the axle track
                together. A spring-loaded self-centering mechanism keeps the tires aimed straight ahead until the drag
                created by cornering causes the tires to deflect, or steer, in the direction that creates the least
                rolling resistance. As the direction of travel straightens out the self-centering mechanism returns the
                tires to their straight ahead position.
            </para>
            <para>The self-steer axle currently used has a 13,200 pound load capacity. The self-steer axle may be used
                in any lift axle location and in any combination.
            </para>
            <para>Self-centering self-steering axles can only track while moving forward. Backing up with the auxiliary
                suspension in the down position can result in damage to the steering components of the axle; therefore,
                the self-steering lift axles must be lifted when the truck is in reverse. Factory installed
                self-steering lift axles include a control system that automatically raises all lift axle assemblies
                when the truck is put into reverse.
            </para>
            <para>Some features of the 13,200 pound capacity self-steering lift axle are:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>13,200 pound maximum load capacity</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a rubber bushed two pin axle connection</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>13.5 inches of axle travel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a preset caster</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>dual self-centering stabilizers</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a fabricated axle</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>cast hub-piloted wheel ends</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>integral air tank</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>standard hubs and drums are cast 10 hole - 11.25in bc unimount</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>standard brakes system includes 15x4 Meritor Q-Plus brakes, Type 20 MGM chambers, 931 - 162
                        Federal Mogul brake linings, and a Meritor slack adjuster.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
