<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - SYSTEM DESCRIPTION - AXLE TYPES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl14019021" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>AXLE TYPES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Two types of lift axles are available: fixed (non-steerable) axles, and self-steering axles.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FIXED AXLES</title>
            <para>Fixed axles do not allow the wheels to steer while cornering. This causes increased tire wear due to
                tire scrubbing while cornering, but it allows the axle design to be simple, requiring less maintenance.
                The fixed axle currently used has a 20,000 pound maximum load capacity and may be used as a tag axle or
                a single pusher axle.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019f">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>
                is an example of a fixed lift axle.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14019f" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g14019f" filename="../figg14/g14019f.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Example of a Fixed Lift Axle (Top View)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SELF-STEERING AXLES</title>
            <para>The self-steering axles reduce tire wear, but are more complex than fixed axles. Self-steering axles
                are similar to front, non-driving, steering axles. Like a front axle, the steering arms and knuckles at
                the ends of the self-steer axle are connected by a tie rod so that both tires on the axle track
                together. A spring-loaded self-centering mechanism keeps the tires aimed straight ahead until the drag
                created by cornering causes the tires to deflect, or steer, in the direction that creates the least
                rolling resistance. As the direction of travel straightens out the self-centering mechanism returns the
                tires to their straight ahead position.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019g">FIGURE 2</hotlnk>
                is an example of a self-steering lift axle.
            </para>
            <para>The self-steer axle currently used has a 13,200 pound maximum load capacity. The self-steer axle may
                be used in any lift axle location and in any combination.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14019g" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g14019g" filename="../figg14/g14019g.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Example of a Self-Steering Lift Axle (Top View)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
