<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - SYSTEM DESCRIPTION - SYSTEM CONTROLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl14019024" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SYSTEM CONTROLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The lift axle controls are available in two configurations. Either all of the controls are located
                inside the cab, or the controls are split between inside the cab and outside the cab. The same four
                controls are used in each of the configurations (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019j">FIGURE 5</hotlnk>)
                <xref refid="f14019j"/>. The lift axle controls consist of the following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>an
                        <emph type="bold">AXLE ENABLE</emph>
                        switch (one switch per truck) - to activate the remaining electrical controls of all the lift
                        axles on the truck,
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a Lift Axle UP/DOWN switch (a separate switch for each lift axle) - to raise and lower the
                        indicated lift axle,
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a Pressure Regulator control (a separate control for each axle) - to adjust the pressure in
                        the load air springs on the indicated lift axle,
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a Pressure Gauge (one gauge per axle for in-cab controls; two gauges per axle for mixed
                        controls) - to indicate the pressure in the load air springs on the indicated lift axle.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f14019j" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g14019j" filename="../figg14/g14019j.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Lift Axle Control Panel (Panel Shown is for Two Lift Axles with In Cab Controls)
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AXLE ENABLE SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AXLE 1 UP/DOWN SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. AXLE 1 AIR PRESSURE REGULATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. AXLE 1 AIR PRESSURE GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. AXLE ENABLE RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REVERSE LIFT RELAY (SELF-STEERING AXLES ONLY)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IN CAB CONTROLS ONLY</title>
            <para>In this configuration all of the axle controls are located on a floor mounted pedestal next to the
                driver's seat. The controls accessible from the driver's seat are the AXLE ENABLE switch, the Lift Axle
                UP/DOWN switch, the Pressure Regulator and the Pressure Gauge (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019k">FIGURE 6</hotlnk>). For a more detailed description of in-cab controls, refer
                to the
                <hotlnk document="s14019_34.xml" xrefid="hl14019072">IN-CAB CONTROLS</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl14019072"/>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14019k" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g14019k" filename="../figg14/g14019k.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Lift Axle Controls (Control Panels Shown are for Three Lift Axles)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MIXED CONTROLS - PRESSURE GAUGE AND SWITCHES IN CAB/PRESSURE GAUGE AND REGULATOR OUTSIDE</title>
            <para>In this configuration the AXLE ENABLE switch, the Lift Axle UP/DOWN switch and a Pressure Gauge are
                located on a floor mounted pedestal next to the driver's seat. The Pressure Regulator and a second
                Pressure Gauge are located on an external panel located at the rear of the cab (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019k">FIGURE 6</hotlnk>). This arrangement allows the load air spring pressure to be
                set from outside of the cab, while still allowing the control switches and Pressure Gauge to be
                accessible from the driver's seat. For a more detailed description of the mixed controls, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14019_35.xml" xrefid="hl14019073">MIXED CONTROLS</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl14019073"/>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
