<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLES: SPICER J400-S, W460-S - INSTALL - DIFFERENTIAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="5">
        <title>DIFFERENTIAL</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The W Model carriers use three different differential cases, depending on the ratio. Two of
                the cases have two oil pick-up plates attached. Clean and coat bolts with Loctite Lock N Seal (red) or
                its equivalent. Assemble and tighten bolts to 7 to 9 ft-lbs. (9 to 12 Nm) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004c6">Figure 126</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004c6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004c6" filename="../figg14/G14004c6.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 125. Assemble and Tighten Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install ring gear and differential assembly into carrier housing. Tilt differential slightly
                so ring gear clears straddle bearing support (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004c7">Figure 127</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004c7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004c7" filename="../figg14/G14004c7.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 126. Install Ring Gear and Differential Assembly into Carrier Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Care should be used when installing ring gear and differential into carrier housing so damage
                        to ring gear, pinion, bearings, or bearing bores does not occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure side bearing cups are seated on bearing cones. Assemble differential bearing caps,
                with match marks in proper location. Clean bearing cap bolts and washers and coat threads with Loctite
                #277 (red) or its equivalent. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION AND SEALER in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                Manual. Install bearing cap bolts and tighten enough to eliminate visible space between differential
                bearing cap and carrier. Do not tighten at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install adjusting rings. Tighten both adjusting rings until end play is eliminated, and
                there is backlash between ring gear and pinion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen adjusting ring on tooth side of ring gear, and tighten adjusting ring on flange side
                of ring gear, equal amounts until backlash is eliminated. Tighten adjusting ring on tooth side of ring
                gear 2 to 3 notches or until proper backlash and side bearing preload are established (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004c8">Figure 128</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004c8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004c8" filename="../figg14/G14004c8.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 127. Tighten Adjusting Ring</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1 id="hl1400405">
            <para count="1">Check ring gear and pinion backlash in four equally spaced positions around the ring gear
                with dial indicator (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004c9">Figure 129</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004c9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004c9" filename="../figg14/G14004c9.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 128. Check Ring Gear and Pinion Backlash</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the backlash tolerance does not vary more than .003 inch 0 mm), the setting is acceptable.
                        If backlash does vary more than .003 inch (.080 mm), remove differential and determine the
                        cause.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Once backlash is set, tighten the differential bearing cap bolts to 275 to 320 ft-lbs. (373
                to 434 Nm). Check backlash after tightening cap bolts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d0">Figure 130</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004d0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004d0" filename="../figg14/G14004d0.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 129. Tighten Differential Bearing Cap Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_HL1400404.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
