<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - INSTALL -
        Checking and Adjusting the End Play of the Input Bearing
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Checking and Adjusting the End Play of the Input Bearing</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f0">Figure 150</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f14011f0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 150. Checking and Adjusting End Play</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Specification:</emph>
            End Play of the Input Shaft: 0.002 to 0.008 inch (0.050 to 0.200 mm)
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install bolts, but not the washers, that fasten the input bearing cage to the carrier.
                Rotate the input shaft in each direction to make sure the bearings are correctly installed while hand
                tightening the bolts. DO NOT TIGHTEN THE BOLTS!
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a feeler gauge to measure the gap between the input bearing cage and the differential
                carrier housing. Check the gap at four equally spaced places on the cage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f1">Figure 151</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011f1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 151. Measure Gap</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add up the four measurements and determine the average gap between the cage and the carrier.
                Add 0.005 inch (0.13 mm) to the average gap measurement to determine the size of the shim pack between
                the cage and the carrier.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use at least three shims when building a shim pack, and always put the thickest shims in the
                middle of the shim pack.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolts that fasten the input bearing cage to the carrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect a lifting device to the input yoke. Remove the input shaft assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the shim pack under the bearing cage. Make sure that the hole pattern of the shim
                pack matches the hole pattern of the cage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f2">Figure 152</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011f2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 152. Install Shim Pack</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the shield for the oil filter in position on the bearing cage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bolts and the washers that fasten the cage to the carrier. Make sure the bolts
                are aligned with the holes in the shim pack. Tighten the bolts so that the threads engage in the holes
                of the carrier.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the input shaft assembly so that the cage and the shim pack are installed against the
                carrier. Remove the lifting device from the yoke or flange.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the bolts to 75 to 95 ft-lbs. (100 to 127 Nm) while rotating the input shaft in each
                direction to make sure that the bearings are correctly installed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a holding tool on the input yoke or flange and tighten the nut to the specified torque.
                Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14011_60.xml" xrefid="x1401104">Torque Chart.</hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the input shaft in each direction and push the yoke or flange toward the bearing
                cage. This makes sure that the input shaft assembly is at the bottom of its travel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a dial indicator with a magnetic base or a C-clamp base to check the end play of the
                input bearing. Make sure the pointer of the dial indicator is against the top of the input shaft. Set
                the dial indicator to zero (0) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f3">Figure 153</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011f3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 153. Set Dial Indicator to Zero (0).</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a pry bar and a support to push the yoke or the flange away from the carrier. Read the
                dial indicator. The reading must be in the 0.002 to 0.008 inch range (0.050 to 0.200 mm) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f4">Figure 154</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011f4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 154. Push Yoke or Flange Away From Carrier</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the end play of the input bearing is not within the 0.002 to 0.008 inch range (0.050 to
                0.200 mm), add or remove shims from the shim pack. Repeat Steps 5-16 of this procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <title>RT-145 Carriers without Oil Pump</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the input shaft assembly from the carrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid serious personal injury when doing Steps 18 and 19, be careful when using Loctite primer
                    N and #518 sealant. Follow the manufacturer's instructions for safe use to prevent irritation to
                    eyes and skin. Wash after skin contact. If the Loctite gets in the eyes, flush the eyes with water
                    for 15 minutes. Have eyes checked by a doctor.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Spray Loctite Primer N on the cage and carrier faces around the perimeter of the lube trough
                hole at the 2 o'clock position (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f5">Figure 155</hotlnk>). Allow the primer to dry 3 to 5 minutes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Loctite 518 to the cage and carrier faces around the lube trough hole (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011f5">Figure 155</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011f5" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/g14011f5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 155. Spray Loctite Primer N and Apply Loctite 518</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use guide studs to install the input shaft and cage assembly with the appropriate shim pack.
                Tighten the bolts to 95 ft-lbs. (128 Nm). Use the opposed sequence to tighten the bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow 4 hours for the Loctite 518 sealant to cure before returning the vehicle to service.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
