<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>2 SPEED AND DOUBLE REDUCTION SINGLE DRIVE AXLES: EATON - REMOVE - DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="5">
        <title>DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If gear set is to be reused, check tooth contact pattern and ring gear backlash before
                    disassembling differential carrier. Best results are obtained when established wear patterns are
                    maintained in used gearing. Omit this step if the gear set is to be replaced.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount differential carrier assembly in repair stand. Loosen but do not remove pinion nut.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove shift fork seal and spring. Remove expansion plugs, then working at the lower (or
                small) plug hole, drive out the shift fork shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401605">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401605" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401605" filename="../figg14/g1401605.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Shift Fork Shaft Removal</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear safe eye protection. Do not hit steel parts with a steel hammer. Parts can break and
                        cause injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When reusing gear set, punch mark bearing adjusters and bearing caps for location and easier
                        adjustment during reassembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">2-Speed Axles Only:</emph>
                Remove sliding clutch.
                <emph type="bold">Planetary Double Reduction Axles:</emph>
                A sun gear is used in place of sliding clutch gear. To remove sun gear, remove the retainer which holds
                gear in position, then remove sun gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401606">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401606" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401606" filename="../figg14/g1401606.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Sliding Clutch Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On teeth side of ring gear, cut lockwire and remove bearing cap bolts. Remove cap, adjuster
                and lock. On back side of ring gear, cut lockwire and remove bearing cap bolts. If the gear set is to be
                reused, remove bearing cap, adjuster and lock as an assembly. This will facilitate correct positioning
                of ring gear during reassembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401607">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401607" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401607" filename="../figg14/g1401607.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Removing Bearing Cap, Adjuster and Lock</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove bearing cups. Use a chain hoist to lift ring gear and differential assembly out of
                carrier (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401608">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401608" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401608" filename="../figg14/g1401608.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Differential Removal</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>During removal of drive pinion assembly, do not allow pinion to drop on hard surface.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position carrier in a stand with drive pinion up.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove pinion bearing cage bolts, invert carrier in stand, then drive pinion cage assembly
                out of carrier. If the gear set is to be reused, keep the shim pack intact for use during reassembly. If
                the original shims cannot be reused, record the number of shims in the pack and the size of each (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401609">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401609" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401609" filename="../figg14/g1401609.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Drive Pinion Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
