<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE SPEED AXLE: SPICER - SERVICE PROCEDURES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>MATERIAL DUST DURING BRAKE SERVICING</para>
                    <seqlist style="arabic">
                        <item>
                            <para>Studies have indicated that exposure to excessive amounts of brake material dust
                                (whether asbestos or non-asbestos, fiberglass, mineral wool, aramid, ceramic or carbon)
                                may be a potential cancer-causing health hazard. Even though the Occupational Safety and
                                Health Administration (OSHA) has not set any limits on non-asbestos dust exposure, there
                                is some medical opinion that such non-asbestos fibers can cause cancer as well. Since
                                most automotive friction materials normally contain a sizeable amount of this material,
                                it is important that people who handle brake linings be aware of the problem and know
                                the precautions to be taken.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Areas where brake work is done should be set aside, if possible, and should be posted
                                with a material dust exposure sign as follows:
                            </para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>BRAKE LINING FIBER DUST HAZARD</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>AVOID BREATHING DUST</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>WEAR ASSIGNED PROTECTIVE EQUIPMENT</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>DO NOT REMAIN IN AREA UNLESS YOUR WORK REQUIRES IT</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>BREATHING BRAKE LINING FIBERS MAY BE HAZARDOUS TO YOUR HEALTH</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as well as
                                for suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal
                                Regulations, Section 1910.1001.)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other operations.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service
                                procedures. Wear the respirator from removal of the wheels through assembly.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>NEVER use compressed air or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies. OSHA
                                recommends that you use cylinders that enclose the brake. These cylinders have vacuums
                                with high efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm sleeves. But, if such equipment is
                                not available, carefully clean parts and assemblies in the open air.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly, carefully place
                                all parts on the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use an industrial vacuum
                                cleaner with a HEPA filter system to clean dust from the brake drums, backing plates and
                                other brake parts. After using the vacuum, remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked
                                in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Grinding or machining brake linings. If you must grind or machine brake linings, take
                                additional precautions because contact with fiber dust is higher during these
                                operations. In addition to wearing an approved respirator, do such work in an area with
                                exhaust ventilation.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cleaning the work area. NEVER use compressed air or dry sweeping to clean the work
                                area. Use an industrial vacuum with a HEPA filter and rags soaked in water and wrung
                                until nearly dry. Dispose of used rags with care to avoid getting dust into the air. Use
                                an approved respirator when emptying vacuum cleaners and handling used rags.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking. Do not wear your
                                work clothes home. Vacuum your work clothes after use and then launder them separately,
                                without shaking, to prevent fiber dust from getting into the air.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Spicer Heavy Duty Single Reduction Rear Drive Axle is a full floating hypoid gear carrier assembly
                in one piece HSLA steel axle housing. The hypoid pinion is straddle mounted, having two tapered roller
                bearings ahead of the pinion teeth for forward and rear thrust, and also having a third bearing behind
                the pinion teeth for radial load. The differential itself uses four precision forged pinion mate gears,
                a forged cross, and precision forged side gears. A fresh supply of lube oil is fed to the differential
                assembly by the positive flow lube system. Axle shafts and drive pinion splines are of the rolled
                involute type.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14007t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
