<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES WITH CONTROLLED TRACTION
        DIFFERENTIALS: EATON - ADJUSTMENTS - CONTROLLED TRACTION DIFFERENTIAL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONTROLLED TRACTION DIFFERENTIAL</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>No specific adjustments are required for the controlled traction differential unit itself. If clutch
                plates are worn excessively, replace clutch pack.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Shifting Seasonal CTD</title>
            <para>Provisions are made for engaging or disengaging this type CTD with a simple manual shop adjustment (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401003">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401003" filename="../figg14/g1401003.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Shifting Seasonal CTD</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engaging-</emph>To engage, remove the shift fork cover retainer and adjusting screw
                assembly. Push the protruding end of the shift fork away from the carrier. If the shift fork will not
                move, lift both wheels off the ground (leave vehicle transmission in gear and release parking brake).
                While pushing on the shift fork, rotate the wheel on the shift fork side of the carrier very slowly. The
                shift fork should now be in the engaged position.
            </para>
            <para>To reassemble cover retainer, the adjusting screw must be backed out several turns. This is done so
                that the shift fork cover retainer bolt holes align with the studs on the carrier. Once the shift fork
                cover retainer is in place (adjusting screw facing carrier), tighten the shift fork cover retainer nuts
                to 55 to 61 ft-lbs. (74 to 82 N&#8226;m). Now turn the adjusting screw in until it contacts the shift
                fork. While holding the adjusting screw with a wrench, tighten the locknut to 30 to 40 ft-lbs. (41 to 54
                N&#8226;m).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Disengaging-</emph>To disengage, remove the shift fork cover retainer and adjusting
                screw assembly. Push the protruding end of the shift fork toward the carrier. If the shift fork will not
                move, lift both wheels off the ground (leave vehicle transmission in gear and release parking brake),
                then push on the shift fork. The shift fork should now move to the disengaged position.
            </para>
            <para>To reassemble, place the shift fork cover retainer on the carrier so that the adjusting screw is
                facing away from the carrier. The adjusting screw may need to be backed out of the shift fork cover
                retainer several turns so that the shift fork cover bolt holes align with the studs on the carrier. Once
                the shift fork cover retainer is in place, tighten the shift fork cover retainer nuts to 55 to 61
                ft-lbs. (74 to 82 N&#8226;m). Now turn the adjusting screw in until it contacts the shift fork. While
                holding the adjusting screw with a wrench, tighten the locknut to 30 to 40 ft-lbs. (41 to 54 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
