<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLE: INTERNATIONAL - SERVICE PROCEDURES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Text and illustrations provided by Spicer Heavy Axle and Brake Division, Dana Corporation.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>MATERIAL DUST DURING BRAKE SERVICING</para>
                    <para>1. Studies have indicated that exposure to excessive amounts of brake material dust (whether
                        asbestos or non-asbestos, fiberglass, mineral wool, aramid, ceramic or carbon) may be a
                        potential cancer-causing health hazard. Even though the Occupational Safety and Health
                        Administration (OSHA) has not set any limits on non-asbestos dust exposure, there is some
                        medical opinion that such non-asbestos fibers can cause cancer as well. Since most automotive
                        friction materials normally contain a sizeable amount of this material, it is important that
                        people who handle brake linings be aware of the problem and know the precautions to be taken.
                    </para>
                    <para>2. Areas where brake work is done should be set aside, if possible, and should be posted with
                        a material dust exposure sign as follows:
                    </para>
                    <para>BRAKE LINING FIBER DUST HAZARD</para>
                    <para>AVOID BREATHING DUST</para>
                    <para>WEAR ASSIGNED PROTECTIVE EQUIPMENT</para>
                    <para>DO NOT REMAIN IN AREA UNLESS YOUR WORK REQUIRES IT</para>
                    <para>BREATHING BRAKE LINING FIBERS MAY BE HAZARDOUS TO YOUR HEALTH</para>
                    <para>3. OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as well as for
                        suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal Regulations,
                        Section 1910.1001.)
                    </para>
                    <para>4. Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other operations.</para>
                    <para>5. Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service procedures.
                        Wear the respirator from removal of the wheels through assembly.
                    </para>
                    <para>6. NEVER use compressed air or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies. OSHA
                        recommends that you use cylinders that enclose the brake. These cylinders have vacuums with high
                        efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm sleeves. But, if such equipment is not available,
                        carefully clean parts and assemblies in the open air.
                    </para>
                    <para>7. Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly, carefully place all
                        parts on the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use an industrial vacuum cleaner with a
                        HEPA filter system to clean dust from the brake drums, backing plates and other brake parts.
                        After using the vacuum, remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked in water and wrung until
                        nearly dry.
                    </para>
                    <para>8. Grinding or machining brake linings. If you must grind or machine brake linings, take
                        additional precautions because contact with fiber dust is higher during these operations. In
                        addition to wearing an approved respirator, do such work in an area with exhaust ventilation.
                    </para>
                    <para>9. Cleaning the work area. NEVER use compressed air or dry sweeping to clean the work area.
                        Use an industrial vacuum with a HEPA filter and rags soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                        Dispose of used rags with care to avoid getting dust into the air. Use an approved respirator
                        when emptying vacuum cleaners and handling used rags.
                    </para>
                    <para>10. Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking. Do not wear your work
                        clothes home. Vacuum your work clothes after use and then launder them separately, without
                        shaking, to prevent fiber dust from getting into the air.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REBUILD FACILITIES</title>
            <para>A suitable holding fixture or carrier overhaul stand is desirable (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14009_43.xml" xrefid="hl1400901">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                ), but not necessary to rebuild these units. Alternately, a sturdy shop table of approximately 30 inches
                in height can be used with suitable means to hold the carrier securely for rebuild operations. A light
                chain hoist should be used to relocate the carrier housing and to install or remove the ring gear and
                support case assembly.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
