<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM DRIVE AXLES: EATON - LUBRICATION - WHEEL END LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>WHEEL END LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Following any servicing of wheel ends, the wheel hub cavities and bearings must be lubricated to
                prevent failure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Make sure the wheel ends are well lubricated with the same axle lubricant used in the axle
                        sump. Do not pack the bearings with grease before installation as grease will prevent the proper
                        circulation of axle lubricant and may cause wheel seal failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Eaton axles may be equipped with either of two wheel end designs:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Wheel ends
                        <emph type="bold">with</emph>
                        an oil fill hole
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Wheel ends
                        <emph type="bold">without</emph>
                        an oil fill hole
                    </para>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1401317">Figure 17</hotlnk>
                        for cutaway views of the two different designs.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f1401317" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401317" filename="../figg14/G1401317.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Wheel End Lubrication</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Ends With an Oil Fill Hole</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the wheel end hub until the oil fill hole is up.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the oil fill plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pour 1 pint of axle sump lubricant into each hub through the wheel end fill hole.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install oil fill plug and tighten to specified torque.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Ends Without an Oil Fill Hole</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401318">Figure 18 .</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401318" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401318" filename="../figg14/G1401318.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Wheel End Without Oil Fill Hole</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With axle level and wheel ends assembled, add lubricant through filler hole in axle
                    housing cover until fluid is level with the bottom of filler hole.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the left side of the axle 6 inches or more. Hold axle in this position for one
                    minute.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the left side.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the right side of the axle 6 inches or more. Hold axle in this position for one
                    minute.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the right side.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With axle on a level surface, add additional lubricant through housing cover oil filler
                    hole to raise lube to required level. For DS404 tandem axle, fluid is to be level with the bottom of
                    the hole.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Axles without wheel end fill holes will require approximately 2.5 additional pints of
                            lubricant to bring the lube level even with the bottom of the fill hole.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The use of ramps or making a full lock figure eight turning maneuver at low speed will
                            guarantee the wheel end is charged with lube. Refill axle to proper lube level.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
