<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLES: SPICER J400-S, W460-S - REMOVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REMOVE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER (WITH POWER DIVIDER)</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Steam clean axle assembly.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain lubricant from axle housing and power divider. To drain power divider, remove
                    plugs from bottom of inter-axle differential cover and bottom of power divider intermediate case.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove axle shafts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect power divider control air line.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect drive shafts from input and output shaft end yokes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove output shaft bearing retainer bolts. Use a soft hammer to loosen bearing retainer
                    from axle housing. Remove bearing cage and output shaft from axle housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen differential carrier-to-axle housing bolts. Remove all bolts except top two.
                    These two bolts will prevent carrier assembly from falling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support carrier assembly on roller jack. Secure as necessary to prevent carrier from
                    falling from jack when removed from housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two 1/2 inch-13 bolts into threaded holes provided in carrier housing flange.
                    Turn puller bolts in to break carrier away from housing. Be certain carrier is balanced properly on
                    jack, and remove top two carrier mounting bolts. Remove carrier assembly from axle housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Roll carrier assembly from under truck.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount carrier assembly in suitable rebuild stand (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400407">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400407" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400407" filename="../figg14/G1400407.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Mount Carrier Assembly in Suitable Rebuild Stand</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
