<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AUTOMATIC POSITIVE LOCKING TRACTION DIFFERENTIALS
        (NOSPIN/DETROIT LOCKER) - CLEAN AND INSPECT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wash all parts thoroughly with a non-flammable solvent that will not etch, scratch or
                oxidize the parts. Rinse in clean solvent and dry.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the splines on the driven clutches. Remove any burrs or small chips with an abrasive
                stone or electric burr grinder. If sections of the spline are broken away, replace the parts.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the teeth on the driven clutches. If wear or chipping is present, replace the part.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>In older models, which have two piece welded driven clutches, check the condition of the hydrogen weld
            attaching the cam rings to the clutches. Cams must be perfectly aligned with drive clutch teeth. If a weld
            failure has occurred, it will be possible to rotate the cam ring in the driven clutch by tapping lightly on
            the cams. If the weld has failed, the driven clutch assembly must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Check holdout rings for fractures and chipping or excessive wear of the teeth. Replace as required.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The holdout ring and driven clutch are serviced as an assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the teeth on the spider (or central driver) and center cam. If wear or chipping is
                present, replace the part.
            </para>
            <para>Check the center cam for free movement.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The spider and center cam are serviced as an assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the splines on the side gears. Remove any burrs or small chips. If splines are
                broken or badly chipped, or if hub walls are fractured, replace the part.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the side gear spline fit on its mating axle shaft. Be sure the splines do not bind.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the spring load at the operating height (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s14003_13.xml" xrefid="hl1400305">SPRING LOAD AT OPERATING HEIGHT
                    <xref refid="hl1400305"/>
                </hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully examine the differential case. If worn or scored, the case should be replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Examine the bearings, ring gear, ring gear bolts and nuts. Replace if necessary with new
                parts that meet International/axle manufacturer specifications.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If major components (e.g. spider assembly or driven clutch assemblies) show excessive wear,
                        the complete NoSPIN differential should be replaced. If a part is replaced, mating parts should
                        also be replaced in that it is likely that they too are damaged. Use of worn or damaged
                        components can lead to a recurrence of the original problem.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use only International approved parts when repairing NoSPIN/Detroit Locker differentials.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
