<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - INSTALL -
        Adjusting the Backlash of the Ring Gear
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Adjusting the Backlash of the Ring Gear</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Specification:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>140 and 145 Series Carriers: Range of Backlash Setting: 0.008-0.018 inch (0.20-0.46 mm)</para>
        <para>140 and 145 Series Carriers: Backlash Setting For New Gear Sets: 0.012 Inch (0.30 mm)</para>
        <para>160 Series: Range of Backlash Setting: 0.010-0.020 inch (0.025-0.51 mm)</para>
        <para>160 Series: Backlash Setting For New Gear Sets: 0.012 inch (0.30 mm)</para>
        <para>If the old gear set is installed, adjust the backlash to the setting that was measured before the carrier
            was disassembled.
        </para>
        <para>If a new gear set is installed, adjust the backlash to the correct specification for new gear sets.</para>
        <para>During the check of the tooth contact patterns, the backlash can be adjusted within specification limits
            to change the location of the pattern.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach a dial indicator on the mounting flange of the carrier (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d2">Figure 132</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011d2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 132. Attach Dial Indicator on Mounting Flange</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the dial indicator so that the plunger is against a tooth surface.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the dial indicator to zero (0).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold the drive pinion in position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While you read the dial indicator, rotate the differential and ring gear a small amount in
                both directions, against the teeth of the drive pinion. If the backlash reading is within specification,
                continue by checking tooth contact patterns. If the backlash reading is not within specifications,
                adjust backlash as needed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen one bearing adjusting ring one notch, then tighten the opposite ring the same amount
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d3">Figure 133</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011d4">Figure 134</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Backlash is increased by moving the ring gear away from the drive pinion.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Backlash is decreased by moving the ring gear toward the drive pinion.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When you adjust backlash, only move the ring gear. Do not move the drive pinion.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f14011d3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 133. Loosen Adjusting Ring One Notch, Then Tighten Opposite Ring One Notch</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f14011d4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011d4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 134. Loosen Adjusting Ring One Notch, Then Tighten Opposite Ring One Notch</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat Steps 2-6 until the backlash is within specifications. Record the setting for use
                when you adjust the preload of the pinion bearing
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_46.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
