<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - REASSEMBLE - ROTATING RESISTANCE CHECK OF DIFFERENTIAL GEARS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>ROTATING RESISTANCE CHECK OF DIFFERENTIAL GEARS</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Make a tool for checking the rotating resistance of the differential gears. The tool can be made
                    from an axle shaft that matches the spline size of the differential side gear (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400695">Figure 95</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1400695" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1400695" filename="../figg14/G1400695.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 95. Make Tool For Checking Rotating Resistance</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install soft metal covers over vise jaws to protect the ring gear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400696">Figure 96</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400696" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400696" filename="../figg14/G1400696.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 96. Install Soft Metal Covers Over Vise Jaws</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TOOL FOR CHECKING RESISTANCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOFT METAL COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put the differential and ring gear assembly in the vise.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the tool into the differential until the splines of the tool and one side gear are
                engaged (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400696">Figure 96</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach a torque wrench to the nut of the tool and rotate the differential gears. As the
                differential gears rotate, read the value indicated on the torque wrench (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1400697">Figure 97</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1400697" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1400697" filename="../figg14/G1400697.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Attach Torque Wrench to Nut of Tool and Rotate Differential Gears</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the torque value exceeds 50 ft-lbs. (67.8 N&#183;m) torque maximum applied to one side
                gear, disassemble the differential gears from the case halves.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the case halves, spider, gears and thrust washers for the problem that causes the
                torque value to exceed the specification. Repair or replace parts.
            </para>
            <para>After the parts are repaired or replaced, assemble parts and repeat Steps 1 to 6.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400610.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400623.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
