<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM AXLES: SPICER J400-S, W460-S - INSTALL - RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT
        PATTERN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="8">
        <title>RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Gear Tooth Nomenclature</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d1">Figure 131</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f14004d1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g14004d1" filename="../figg14/G14004d1.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 130. Gear Tooth Nomenclature</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">toe</emph>
                of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the end towards the center.
            </para>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">heel</emph>
                of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the outer end.
            </para>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">top land</emph>
                of a gear tooth is the surface of the top of the tooth.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To obtain correct contact pattern, paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and apply
                    load while rotating pinion (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d2">Figure 132</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d2" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d2" filename="../figg14/G14004d2.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 131. Paint Ring Gear Teeth With Marking Compound</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring
                    gear teeth shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d3">Figure 133</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d3" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d3" filename="../figg14/G14004d3.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 132. Correct Tooth Contact</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d4">Figure 134</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Recheck backlash as
                    described in
                    <hotlnk document="s14004_34.xml" xrefid="hl1400405">DIFFERENTIAL, Step 6</hotlnk>. To reduce
                    backlash, loosen the right side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is within specification.
                    The tooth contact pattern should now have the same general shape and location as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d3">Figure 133</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                    backlash than normal is required.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d4" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d4" filename="../figg14/G14004d4.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 133. Ring Gear Out Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>To avoid reducing differential bearing preload excessively, further loosening of the right side
                    adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the left side adjusting ring. Decreasing
                    backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d5">Figure 135</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Recheck backlash. To
                    increase backlash, tighten the right side adjusting ring further until the measured backlash is
                    within specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread more across the ring gear tooth as
                    in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d3">Figure 133</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more
                    backlash than normal is required. To avoid increasing differential bearing preload excessively,
                    further tightening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal loosening of the
                    left hand adjusting ring. Increasing backlash moves ring gear away from the pinion.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d5" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d5" filename="../figg14/G14004d5.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 134. Ring Gear In Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d6">Figure 136</hotlnk>), the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be
                    moved out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d3">Figure 133</hotlnk>. This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion
                    position cage shim. Re-adjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting
                    distance has been established.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d6" filename="../figg14/G14004d6.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 135. Pinion In Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d7">Figure 137</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and
                    must be moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact
                    pattern. This is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion position cage shim. Re-adjust
                    pinion-to-ring gear backlash as required once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d7" filename="../figg14/G14004d7.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 136. Pinion Out Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After proper ring gear pattern is achieved, again tighten the differential bearing cap
                    bolts to 275 to 320 ft-lbs. (373 to 434 Nm). Install adjusting ring retainers and new cotter pins of
                    proper size (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14004d8">Figure 138</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f14004d8" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14004d8" filename="../figg14/G14004d8.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 137. Tighten Differential Bearing Cap Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
