<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>2 SPEED AXLE SHIFT UNIT: EATON - AIR SHIFT SYSTEM - SHIFT UNIT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="5">
        <title>SHIFT UNIT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air line at shift unit cover. Remove nuts, flat washers and piston air shift
                    unit from differential carrier.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When shift unit is removed, provide container to catch the oil that escapes from the
                            reservoir.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shift fork seal and spring.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove capscrews, lockwashers, cover and gasket from housing. Drain lubricant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts, locknuts, and cover at piston end of housing. Remove O-ring.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>During the following procedure, the piston will pop out of the housing under spring
                            pressure. Exercise caution to prevent possible injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove locknut, flat washer, and piston from push rod. Remove O-ring and felt oilers
                    from piston (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400225">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400225" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400225" filename="../figg14/G1400225.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25. Disassemble Shift Unit</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove compression spring and piston stop from bore of shift unit housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400226">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400226" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400226" filename="../figg14/G1400226.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Remove Compression Spring and Piston Stop</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove clevis pin, then remove push rod from shift unit housing. Remove O-ring from push
                    rod.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove actuating lever and pin assembly from shift unit housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400227">Figure 27</hotlnk>). Do not disassemble actuating lever.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400227" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400227" filename="../figg14/G1400227.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. Remove Actuating Lever and Pin Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1400202">
            <title>Lubrication</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Lubricant:</emph>
                Use SAE 10 motor oil* for temperatures above 0&#176;F (-18&#176;C). For temperatures below 0&#176;F (-18&#176;C),
                mix three parts of SAE 10 motor oil with one part of kerosene. This cold weather mixture can be safely
                used up to 32&#176;F (0&#176;C).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Commercially available automatic transmission fluid may be used in place of SAE 10 motor oil.
                        Automatic transmission fluid can be used for all temperatures. Do not mix kerosene with
                        automatic transmission fluid.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Lubricant Check and Level:</emph>
                Each 20,000 miles or six months, remove pipe plug in shift unit housing cover to check lubricant level.
                Lube should be level with bottom of filler hole.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Lubricant Change:</emph>
                At least once a year, remove shift unit housing cover and drain old lubricant. Wash parts thoroughly and
                air dry. Reinstall cover. Remove pipe plug in cover. Fill through pipe plug opening until lube is level
                with bottom of filler hole.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspect</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Shift Fork Seal:</emph>
                Inspect shift fork seal for defects and tight fit on shift fork. A spring is used to assure a closer fit
                of seal around shift fork. If this spring is not present on axle being serviced, install one when
                reassembling unit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">O-Rings, Felt Oilers and Gasket:</emph>
                Replace O-rings, felt oilers and cover gasket when piston air shift unit is disassembled for repair.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Compression Spring:</emph>
                Inspect spring for distortion, cracks, or other visual defects. Replace a faulty spring.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Actuating Lever and Pins:</emph>
                Inspect lever pins and bearings for worn or grooved condition. Inspect actuating lever and push rod for
                worn or elongated holes at point where they are connected. Replace faulty parts.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Piston:</emph>
                Inspect piston friction surface for worn, grooved or damaged condition which will affect the piston
                movement in cylinder. Replace a faulty piston.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prior to reassembly, the piston felt oilers should be soaked in SAE 10 oil for one hour.
                        Lubricate O-rings with a high viscosity silicone oil or barium grease O-ring lubricant.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble pin to actuating lever and install this assembly in shift unit housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400228">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400228" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400228" filename="../figg14/G1400228.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. Piston and Push Rod Reassembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble O-ring and piston to push rod and fasten with flat washer and locknut. Tighten
                    locknut to 120 to 150 in-lbs. (14 to 17 N&#8226;m). Install felt oilers and O-ring on piston.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>During the following procedure using a press, make certain components are properly aligned
                            in press to prevent possible personal injury or damage to parts.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert piston stop and compression spring in shift unit housing. Place piston and push
                    rod assembly in housing. Position housing assembly in arbor press.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply pressure to piston until actuating lever is in alignment with push rod end (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1400229">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Install clevis pin. Release press.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1400229" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1400229" filename="../figg14/G1400229.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 29. Apply Pressure To Piston</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place cover gasket in position on shift unit housing, then install cover and bearing
                    assembly. Fasten with capscrews and lockwashers. If necessary, use a sealer on the threads of
                    capscrews to prevent any leaking. Tighten capscrews to 90 to 110 in-lbs. (10 to 12 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place O-ring in groove of shift unit housing, then install housing cover (piston end)
                    and secure with bolts and locknuts. Tighten locknuts to 108 to 132 in-lbs. (12 to 15 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill shift unit with SAE 10 oil or automatic transmission fluid. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400202">LUBRICATION</hotlnk>, when axle is installed in vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate shift fork. Slide seal and spring assembly over fork and place on differential
                    carrier studs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place shift unit on mounting studs and make certain shift fork actuating lever engages
                    slot in shift fork. Install flat washers and stud nuts. Tighten nuts to 55 to 61 ft-lbs. (74 to 82 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When axle is installed in vehicle, fill shift unit housing to level of filler plug with
                    SAE 10 oil. Coat threads of filler plug with sealer and install plug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air lines to shift unit cover.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
