<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION, TANDEM DRIVE AXLES: EATON - INSTALL - FORWARD AXLE HOUSING COVER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FORWARD AXLE HOUSING COVER</title>
        <para>If removed, install cover and fasten with nuts, bolts and lockwashers. Tighten to proper torque
            specifications
            <hotlnk document="s14013_25.xml" xrefid="hl1401302"></hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use silicone rubber gasket compound on axle housing mating surface as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401315">Figure 15</hotlnk>. Completely remove all old gasket material prior to
                    applying new material. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the
                    recommended gasket compound. Install carrier and axle housing cover before compound sets or reapply.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1401315" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1401315" filename="../figg14/G1401315.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 15. Lubrication of Forward Axle Housing Cover</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply silicone gasket compound. Install differential carrier assembly in the axle housing.
                Install nuts and lockwashers. Install bolts and tighten to correct torque.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install output yoke and output shaft shoulder nut. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s14013_25.xml" xrefid="hl1401302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                ..
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install axle shafts and axle stud nuts. (If used, also install lockwashers and taper
                dowels.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect inter-axle driveline. Ensure driveline is properly phased. Lubricate U-joints.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add axle lubricant. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual
                for recommended lubricants. Fill to bottom of filler hole; add two pints to power divider unit.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect differential lockout air line.</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When axle has been disassembled or housing, axle shafts or wheel equipment replaced, check
                        axle assembly for proper differential actions before operating vehicle. Wheels must rotate
                        freely and independently.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Road test vehicle to bring axle lubricant up to temperature. Re-check joints and drain and fill plugs
                for leakage. Re-tighten as necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
