<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - ROCKWELL TANDEM AXLE FORWARD REAR DRIVE UNITS - Driver
        Controlled Main Differential Lock - Remove Differential Carrier from Axle Housing
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1401101" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Remove Differential Carrier from Axle Housing</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before the differential carrier can be removed or installed, the differential lock MUST be shifted
                into and held in the locked (engaged) position. The locked position gives enough clearance between the
                shift collar and the axle housing to permit the removal or installation of the carrier.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the axle shafts were removed for towing with the differential in the unlocked (disengaged)
                        position, install the left-hand axle shaft into the housing before continuing. Follow steps 1
                        and 2 of
                        <hotlnk document="s14011_7.xml" xrefid="x1401109">BEFORE OPERATING THE VEHICLE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>To shift into the locked position, use either of the following "Air Pressure" or "Manual Engaging"
                methods.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x1401113">
            <title>Air Pressure Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the drain plug from the bottom of the housing and drain the lubricant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the left-hand wheel of the drive axle off the floor with a hoist or jack.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not start the vehicle engine and engage the transmission with one wheel raised from the
                        floor. When the differential is in locked (engaged) position, power will go to the wheel on the
                        floor and cause the vehicle to move and may cause serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a jack stand under the left-hand spring seat to hold the vehicle in the raised
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip or tip over and cause
                        serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the driveline from the input yoke.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the vehicle air line from the inter-axle differential and main differential
                    lock actuator assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect an auxiliary air supply to the differential lock actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an auxiliary air supply is not available, continue to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x1401110">Manual Engaging Method</hotlnk>
                        of locking the differential.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and hold air pressure to the actuator assembly. The air pressure will move the
                    shift collar to engage with the splines on the differential case half and lock the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure that the shift collar has moved the full distance on the splines of the
                    differential case half. Rotate the left-hand wheel until the left-hand wheel makes one complete
                    rotation (forward or backward). The differential is fully engaged at this time and will not be able
                    to rotate the wheel.
                </para>
                <para>Continue to hold the main differential in the locked position with air pressure until the carrier
                    assembly is completely removed from the axle housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shafts from the housing. Follow steps 1 and 2 of "
                    <hotlnk document="s14011_7.xml" xrefid="x1401111">Before Towing</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the carrier from the housing as described in Steps 8 through 23 under
                    <hotlnk document="s14011_8.xml" xrefid="x1401112">DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM THE AXLE
                        HOUSING</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the carrier is removed from the axle housing, release the air pressure from the
                    actuator assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x1401110">
            <title>Manual Engaging Method</title>
            <para>If an auxiliary air supply is not available or if the differential carrier is to be stored for later
                use, use this manual engaging method (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011g6">Figure 166</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14011g7">Figure 167</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f14011g6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011g6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 166. Bolt On Type Shift Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TOP SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. AIR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIFFERENTIAL LOCK ACTUATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CYLINDER COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. WIRE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. OPERATING POSITION HOLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. BOTTOM SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f14011g7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg14/G14011g7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 167. Threaded Type Shift Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SHIFT SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STORAGE OF MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT IN SHIFT TOWER LOCATION</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. INSERT MANUAL ENGAGING BOLT TO ENGAGE DIFF. LOCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SHIFT CYLINDER AND PISTON ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SHIFT FORK</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SENSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow steps 1 through 5 of the "
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x1401113">Air Pressure Method</hotlnk>."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug and gasket from the hole in the center of the cylinder cover or
                    cylinder.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the manual engaging bolt from the top storage hole in the cylinder cover or shift
                    tower of carriers with the threaded type shift assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011g6">Figure 166</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14011g7">Figure 167</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plug and gasket into the bottom storage hole in the cylinder cover, or in
                    the shift tower.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bolt On Shift Assembly - The storage hole for the plug and gasket is the opposite end of the
                        storage hole for the manual engaging bolt (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f14011g6">Figure 166</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the manual engaging bolt into the threaded hole in the center of the cylinder
                    cover or cylinder.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the manual adjusting bolt to the right until the head is approximately 1/4 inch
                    from the cylinder cover. DO NOT turn the bolt beyond its normal stop. The bolt is now in the service
                    position and the main differential lock is completely engaged.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>There will be a small amount of spring resistance felt when you turn in the manual
                            engaging bolt. If a high resistance is felt before reaching the locked (engaged) position,
                            STOP TURNING THE BOLT or the cover, the fork and bolt threads will be damaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A high resistance on the bolt indicates that the splines of the shift collar and the
                            differential case half are not aligned or engaged. To align the splines, use the following
                            procedure:
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the left-hand wheel to align the splines of the shift collar and case half
                        while you turn in the manual engaging bolt.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When the normal amount of spring resistance is again felt on the bolt, the splines
                        are engaged. Continue to turn in the manual engaging bolt until the head is approximately 1/4
                        inch from the cylinder cover.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the carrier from the axle housing as described in steps 8-23 under
                    <hotlnk document="s14011_8.xml" xrefid="x1401112">DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER FROM THE AXLE
                        HOUSING</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the differential lock by removing the manual engaging bolt and seal from the
                    cylinder cover or cylinder.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_51.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
