<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SINGLE REDUCTION CARRIERS: ROCKWELL - DRIVER CONTROLLED MAIN DIFFERENTIAL LOCK - INSTALL CARRIER INTO AXLE
        HOUSING (WITH DIFFERENTIAL LOCK)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1400632" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INSTALL CARRIER INTO AXLE HOUSING (WITH DIFFERENTIAL LOCK)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before using either the Air Pressure Method or the Manual Engaging Method to install the differential
                carrier into the housing, proceed with the following steps.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Preparation to Install Differential Carrier Into Housing</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the inside of the axle housing and the mounting surface where the carrier fastens.
                    Use a cleaning solvent and rags to remove the dirt. Blow dry the cleaned areas with compressed air.
                    Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400628.xml" xrefid="hl1400628">CLEAN AND INSPECT</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be careful when using solvent. Follow the solvent manufacturers instructions for safe use
                            to prevent injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the axle housing for damage. If necessary, repair or replace the housing. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400628.xml" xrefid="hl1400628">CLEAN AND INSPECT</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for loose studs in the mounting surface of the housing where the carrier fastens.
                    Remove and replace the studs where required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the differential carrier into the housing. Use one of the following
                    procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1400631">
            <title>Air Pressure Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before the carrier is installed into the housing, install the right-hand axle shaft
                    through the shift collar and into the side gear. (The axle shaft is being used as a spine alignment
                    tool.)
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A similar tool can be made from a damaged right-hand axle shaft by cutting off
                            approximately 24 inches from the spline end.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the splines of the shift collar and differential case half by rotating the axle
                    shaft tool or drive pinion.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not use your hands to hold the collar in position. Injury can result when air pressure
                            is applied to the actuator.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect an auxiliary air supply to the actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and hold pressure to the actuator assembly. The air pressure will move the shift
                    collar to engage the differential case half and lock the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the shift collar has not moved the full distance on the splines of the differential
                    case half, rotate the axle shaft tool or the drive pinion one complete rotation to the right or
                    left.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shaft tool from the carrier.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Continue to hold the main differential in the locked (engaged) position with air pressure
                            until the carrier is completely installed in the axle housing. If no air supply is
                            available, use the Manual Engaging Method to lock (engage) the differential.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply silicone gasket material to the mounting surface of the housing where the carrier
                    fastens. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400629.xml" xrefid="hl1400629">APPLICATION OF SILICONE GASKET
                        MATERIAL</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the carrier into the axle housing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400632">INSTALL DIFFERENTIAL CARRIER INTO AXLE HOUSING</hotlnk>, Steps 6 through
                    10.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the air pressure from the differential lock actuator and disconnect the
                    auxiliary air supply.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Proceed to Step 9 of Manual Engaging Method.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1400630">
            <title>Manual Engaging Method</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the splines of the shift collar and the differential case half. This can be done
                    by hand or by installing the right-hand axle shaft through shift collar and into the side gear. See
                    Steps 1 and 2 of the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400631">Air Pressure Method</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the manual engaging capscrew into the threaded hole in the center of the
                    cylinder cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the manual adjusting capscrew to the right until the head of the capscrew is
                    approximately 1/4 inch from the cylinder cover. DO NOT turn the capscrew beyond its normal stop. The
                    capscrew is now in the service position and the main differential lock is completely engaged.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>There will be a small amount of spring resistance felt when you turn in the manual
                            engaging capscrew. If a high resistance is felt before reaching the locked (engaged)
                            position, STOP TURNING THE CAPSCREW, or the cover, fork and capscrew threads will be
                            damaged.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>A high resistance on the capscrew indicates that the splines of the shift collar and the
                    differential case half are not aligned or engaged.
                </para>
                <para>Lift the shift collar as required and rotate to align the splines of collar and case half while
                    you turn in the manual engaging capscrew. When the normal amount of spring resistance is again felt
                    on the capscrew, the splines are engaged. Continue to turn in the manual engaging capscrew.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and fasten the carrier into the axle housing. Follow Steps 7 and 8 of the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1400631">Air Pressure Method</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug and gasket from their position.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When the manual engaging capscrew is removed from the service position in the actuator,
                            the main differential lock becomes disengaged.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the plug, gasket, cylinder cover, and threaded hole in the center of the cylinder
                    cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plug and gasket into their operating position in the cylinder cover. Install
                    the manual engaging capscrew into its storage position. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14006e7">Figure 147</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f14006e7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g14006e7" filename="../figg14/G14006e7.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 147. Install Manual Engaging Capscrew into Storage Position</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. TOP SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR MANUAL ENGAGING CAPSCREW</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. AIR LINE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. DIFFERENTIAL LOCK ACTUATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. CYLINDER COVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. WIRE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. OPERATING POSITION HOLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. BOTTOM SIDE STORAGE HOLE FOR PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>8. PLUG AND GASKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>9. MANUAL ENGAGING CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the plug to 44 to 55 ft-lbs. (60 to 75 N&#183;m) torque. Tighten the manual
                    engaging capscrew to 22 to 28 ft-lbs. (30 to 38 N&#183;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the vehicle air line to the differential lock actuator assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the electrical connection on the sensor switch located in the carrier, below the
                    actuator assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the right and left-hand axle shafts. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400601.xml" xrefid="hl1400601">INSTALL AXLE SHAFTS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the jack stand from under the drive axle and lower the vehicle to the floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_HL1400627.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t_43.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14006t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
