<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - SELF-STEERING AXLE ASSEMBLIES -
        ADJUSTMENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl14019064" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ADJUSTMENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AXLE ALIGNMENT</title>
            <para>Self-Steering axles are pre-aligned and normally require no axle alignment in the field. If an axle
                appears to be out of alignment (irregular tire wear), check for damaged components, worn bushings, or an
                incorrect wheel toe-in setting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WHEEL ALIGNMENT</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AXLE CASTER</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The axle caster is preset and is nonadjustable.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WHEEL TOE-IN</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Toe-in is the amount which the wheels point inward at the front. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f14019bj">FIGURE 20</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f14019bj"/>. This setting should be 1/32 inch &#177;1/32 inch. Toe-in should be rechecked
                after altering the tie rod, and after the axle has been subjected to heavy impacts; or anytime irregular
                tire wear (other than flat spotting) is noticed. Before checking toe-in, verify that the wheel and
                knuckle bearings are properly adjusted; and that the tires are inflated to the proper pressure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; verify that the transmission is
                        in PARK or NEUTRAL, and that wheel chocks are installed. This adjustment must be done with the
                        truck running.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the axle in the down position, pull the vehicle straight forward several feet. This
                    eliminates any play in the steering connections.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At the front of the tires and the rear of the tires, measure the distance between the
                    center of the tire treads at the height of the wheel centers. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f14019bj">FIGURE 20</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f14019bj"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The front dimension (B) must be 0 to 1/16 inch less than the rear dimension (A).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Toe-in adjustment is made by loosening the clamp bolts and nuts on each end of the tie
                    rod and turning the tie rod with a pipe wrench. After obtaining the correct toe-in, tighten the
                    clamp bolts and nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f14019bj" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g14019bj" filename="../figg14/G14019bj.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="272px"
                         resolution="200"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Toe-In Adjustment for Self-Steering Lift Axles</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
