<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LIFT AXLE SYSTEMS - INTRODUCTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This International Service Manual Section describes the correct service and repair procedures for the
                Watson &#38; Chalin lift axles available on the truck models listed on the front cover. The information
                contained in this manual was correct at the time of printing and is subject to change without notice or
                liability.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; whenever any component is
                        serviced or removed from the air system, be sure to set the parking brake and/or block the
                        wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving while the service is being performed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; when removing any component
                        attached to the lift axle air tank, be sure to drain all air from the axle tank to prevent
                        bodily injury. (This will also drain the air from the supply reservoir.) Draining of the primary
                        and secondary reservoirs is not required since they are protected by check valves.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; no welding of any of the
                        suspension components is permitted, except where specified in the manufacturer's documentation.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; do not weld on, drill, or bolt
                        through the bottom flange of the suspension frame rail or truck rail. Check with chassis
                        manufacturer for their warranty disclaimer on vehicle frame modifications.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; no alteration of any of the
                        suspension components is permitted.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; proper axle attachment is
                        required.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; set all UP/DOWN switches to the
                        UP position before enabling the system (pressing the AXLE ENABLE switch). If any axle UP/DOWN
                        switch is in the DOWN position when the ignition is switched off, the axle controlled by that
                        switch will automatically raise to its up position. Enabling the lift axle system with an axle
                        UP/DOWN switch in the DOWN position will cause that axle to be immediately lowered. The position
                        of the UP/DOWN switches should be checked carefully because the DOWN indicators on the switches
                        are always unlit (in either switch position) until the system is enabled.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or possible death; be aware of the Auto-Lift in
                        Reverse feature on trucks with self-steering lift axles. On trucks with self-steering lift
                        axles, any axle that is in the DOWN position when reverse is selected, will automatically raise
                        to its UP position;
                        <emph type="boldundersc">AND</emph>
                        that axle
                        <emph type="bold">will automatically return to the down position</emph>
                        when the transmission is shifted out of reverse.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not change the size of the air tank(s). Alterations to production air brake systems must be
                        approved by International Engineering prior to alteration or operation.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Always open a drain cock by hand. Never strike the handle with a hammer or any other
                        instrument, as the cock will be damaged and leakage will develop.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before drilling through the side of the frame rail, inspect the rail for any obstruction (fuel
                        line, wiring harness, or air lines) that might be located on the inside of frame rail.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Auxiliary self-steering liftable air ride suspensions may require toe-in and caster
                        adjustments.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
