<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES WITH CONTROLLED TRACTION
        DIFFERENTIALS: EATON - FUNCTIONAL CTD CHECK (AFTER REPAIR OR OVERHAUL) (SINGLE OR TANDEM AXLES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1401006" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FUNCTIONAL CTD CHECK (AFTER REPAIR OR OVERHAUL) (SINGLE OR TANDEM AXLES</title>
        <para>The following procedure can be used to determine whether the CTD is shifting in and out of the engaged
            mode. This functional check should be performed at any time the shift system components or axle CTD
            components are repaired or replaced.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block the vehicle wheels to prevent rolling.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place transmission in neutral and release parking brake.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Jack up both rear wheels of the drive axle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With CTD selector valve in the disengaged position, the wheels will roll independent of one
                another.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the CTD selector valve moved to the engaged position, the wheels will not turn
                independent of one another.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the wheels turn independently in Step 5, the CTD is not functioning. Proceed to check for
                full system air pressure at shift unit.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove shift unit and check to see if the shift unit pin and block were properly positioned
                into the shift fork opening.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If shift unit installation and alignment was correct in Step 7, check the unit itself for
                proper functioning. With the shift unit removed, check it for proper travel by cycling the CTD selector
                valve. Travel should be 15/16" (23.8 mm). With pin in each position, pry with a screwdriver against the
                pin. This pin should not move when applying moderate force.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If all of the above checks are made and found satisfactory, the failure of the CTD to
                properly engage involves internal axle parts. With the shift unit removed, the CTD can be shifted in and
                out of engagement manually. With the shift fork away from the carrier (engaged), the wheels should not
                rotate together.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
