<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES WITH CONTROLLED TRACTION
        DIFFERENTIALS: EATON - REASSEMBLE - CLUTCH PACK (MEDIUM-DUTY)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="9">
        <title>CLUTCH PACK (MEDIUM-DUTY)</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The clutch pack can be installed in differential and gear support case with wheel differential
                    assembled or disassembled. With differential assembled, proceed as follows:
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">All Medium-duty CTD.</emph>
                Place differential assembly on a work bench (clutch pack mounting area up). Install ring gear on support
                case flange, aligning bolt holes with two temporarily-installed alignment bolts.
            </para>
            <para>Remove alignment bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Install Friction Plates and Driver (Permanent CTD Only).</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Brush surface of each plate, as it is assembled, with a generous application of axle lube.
                        Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for recommended lubes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To assemble friction plates, one of two procedures can be used: Install driver and plates
                        individually (Step 3) or install driver and clutch pack as an assembly (Step 4).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Install Friction Plates Individually (Permanent CTD Only) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401020">Figure 20</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401020" filename="../figg14/G1401020.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Install Friction Plates Individually</caption>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If removed, install snap ring on friction plate driver. Then, install driver assembly
                    (snap ring down) in bore of support case, engaging teeth of differential side gear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one external-splined plate in ring gear bore (engaging gear internal teeth). Brush
                    plate with lube.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one internal-splined plate on driver splines and on top of the external-splined
                    plate. Brush plate with lube.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Repeat this procedure until fourteen (14) friction plates (seven internal- splined and
                    seven external-splined) are installed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the last external-splined plate and pressure plate. Then install springs and
                    cover (see Step 6).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Install Driver and Clutch Pack as an Assembly (Permanent CTD Only) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401021">Figure 21</hotlnk>)
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401021" filename="../figg14/G1401021.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Install Driver and Clutch Pack as an Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If removed, install snap ring on friction plate driver. Then, place driver (snap ring
                    down) on work bench.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one external-splined plate on driver. Brush plate with lube.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one internal-splined plate on top of the external-splined plate. Brush plate with
                    lube.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Repeat this procedure until fourteen (14) friction plates (seven external- splined and
                    seven internal-splined) are installed. Then install the last external-splined plate and pressure
                    plate.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Rotate external-splined plates as necessary to align the teeth. Then grasp the entire
                    assembly by hand and install it in the ring gear.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>As the assembly is installed, maneuver plates with external splines to align them with the
                            ring gear teeth. Also make sure the driver engages teeth of the differential side gear.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install compression springs and case cover (Step 6).</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Install Friction Plates (Driver- Controlled and Seasonal CTD Only).</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>During friction plate (internal- splines) installation, align each plate as it is installed in
                        ring gear, using the sliding clutch. If plates are not in alignment, it will be difficult to
                        install sliding clutch, after clutch pack is assembled. Also, as each plate is installed, brush
                        top of plate with a generous application of axle lube. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the
                        CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for recommended lubes. Proceed as follows:
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one external-splined plate in ring gear bore (engaging gear internal teeth). Brush
                    plate with lube (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401022">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401022" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401022" filename="../figg14/G1401022.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Place One External-Splined Plate in Ring Gear Bore</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place one internal-splined plate on top of the external-splined plate and brush plate
                    with lube. For alignment purposes, temporarily insert sliding clutch to engage side gear and plate
                    splines. Remove clutch (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401023">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401023" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401023" filename="../figg14/G1401023.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Temporarily Insert Sliding Clutch to Engage Side Gear and Plate Splines
                    </caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Repeat this procedure until fourteen (14) friction plates (seven internal-splined and
                    seven external-splined) are installed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the last external-splined plate and the pressure plate. And, again, insert
                    sliding clutch to make sure internal-splined plates are in alignment. Install springs and case cover
                    (see Step 6).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Install Compression Springs and cover (All Types CTD).</emph>
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install springs on pressure plate, positioning them in the smallest circle possible (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401024">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401024" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401024" filename="../figg14/G1401024.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24. Position Springs in Smallest Circle Possible</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place support case cover over springs and temporarily install two alignment bolts (heads
                    up) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401025">Figure 25</hotlnk>and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401026">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401025" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401025" filename="../figg14/G1401025.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25. Place Support Case Cover Over Springs</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1401026" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401026" filename="../figg14/G1401026.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Temporarily Install Two Alignment Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Temporarily install two clamping nuts and bolts (nuts up). Remove alignment bolts.
                    Alternately tighten clamping nuts until cover is in mounting position on ring gear (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401027">Figure 27</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401027" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401027" filename="../figg14/G1401027.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. Tighten Clamping Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install bolts and self-locking nuts that fasten cover to ring gear. Remove the
                    temporarily-installed clamping nuts and bolts, and install the remaining cover bolts and self
                    locking nuts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401028">Figure 28</hotlnk>). Tighten nuts to 275 to 300 ft-lbs. (373 to 407 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401028" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401028" filename="../figg14/G1401028.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. Install Cover Bolts and Self Locking Nuts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
