<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - 2 SPEED REAR AXLES: SPICER - INSTALL - RING AND PINION
        GEAR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl14015c1" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="6">
        <title>RING AND PINION GEAR</title>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1401513">
            <title>Contact Pattern</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401534">Figure 34</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401534" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401534" filename="../figg14/g1401534.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Gear Tooth Nomenclature</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">toe</emph>
                of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the end towards the center.
            </para>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">heel</emph>
                of the gear tooth is the portion of the tooth surface at the outer end.
            </para>
            <para>The
                <emph type="bold">top land</emph>
                of a gear tooth is the surface of the top of the tooth.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To obtain correct contact pattern, paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and apply
                    load while rotating pinion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring
                    gear teeth shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401535">Figure 35</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401535" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401535" filename="../figg14/g1401535.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 35. Correct Tooth Contact</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401536">Figure 36</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Recheck backlash as
                    described in
                    <hotlnk document="s14015_23.xml" xrefid="hl1401511">RING GEAR SUPPORT CASE ASSEMBLY</hotlnk>. To
                    reduce backlash, loosen the differential case side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is
                    within specification. The tooth contact pattern should now have the same general shape and location
                    as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401536">Figure 36</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                    backlash than normal is required. To avoid reducing differential bearing preload excessively,
                    further loosening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the
                    flange side adjusting ring. Decreasing backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401536" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401536" filename="../figg14/g1401536.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 36. Ring Gear Out Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401537">Figure 37</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Recheck backlash. To
                    increase backlash, tighten the differential case side adjusting ring further until the measured
                    backlash is within specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread more across the ring
                    gear tooth as in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1401513">step 2</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more
                    backlash than normal is required. To avoid increasing differential bearing preload excessively,
                    further tightening of the differential case side adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal
                    loosening of the flange side adjusting ring. Increasing backlash moves the ring gear away from the
                    pinion.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401537" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401537" filename="../figg14/g1401537.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 37. Ring Gear In Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401538">Figure 38</hotlnk>), the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be
                    moved out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl1401513">step 2</hotlnk>. This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion
                    position cage shim. Readjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting
                    distance has been established.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401538" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401538" filename="../figg14/g1401538.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 38. Pinion In Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1401539">Figure 39</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and
                    must be moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact
                    pattern. This is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion position cage shim. Readjust
                    pinion-to-ring gear backlash as required once proper pinion mounting distance has been established.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1401539" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1401539" filename="../figg14/g1401539.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 39. Pinion Out Too Far</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
