<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SINGLE REDUCTION AXLES WITH CONTROLLED TRACTION
        DIFFERENTIALS: EATON - CTD SHIFT SYSTEM - TANDEM AXLE SHIFT SYSTEMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>TANDEM AXLE SHIFT SYSTEMS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description and Operation</title>
            <para>The CTD shift system provides the option of operation with the Controlled Traction Differential
                engaged or disengaged with the use of an in-cab pneumatic valve.
            </para>
            <para>Two shift units (one on each axle) engage or disengage the Controlled Traction Differentials. A quick
                release valve in the system provides fast release of air pressure from the shift units.
            </para>
            <para>There are two types of CTD shift systems for tandem axles (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1401043">Figure 43</hotlnk>): (1) a one-selector valve system controlling operation of
                the inter-axle differential and both controlled traction differentials, or (2) a two-selector valve
                system which offers independent control of the inter-axle differential and the controlled traction
                differentials.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1401043" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1401043" filename="../figg14/g1401043.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. CTD Shift Systems - Tandem Axles</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Instructions in this manual are the same for both systems unless specified otherwise.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Engagement.</emph>
                When the selector valve lever is moved to the engaged position, the selector valve is opened and air
                pressure is applied to the shift unit (or units). Each shift unit is connected to a shift fork and
                sliding clutch. The sliding clutch moves to engage the controlled traction differential. In the engaged
                position, the wheel differential acts as a biasing differential.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In the one-selector valve system,</emph>
                the CTD and inter-axle differential are controlled by one valve and both are engaged when the selector
                valve is in the engaged position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In the two-selector valve system,</emph>
                both CTD differentials and the inter-axle differential are engaged independently.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Disengagement.</emph>
                When the selector valve lever is moved to the disengaged position, the selector valve is closed. Air
                pressure in the shift unit (or units) is exhausted. The sliding clutch retracts and disengages the
                controlled traction differential. In the disengaged position, the wheel differential functions with
                conventional differential action.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In the one-selector valve system,</emph>
                both CTD differentials and inter-axle differential are disengaged when the selector valve is in the
                disengaged position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In the two-selector valve system,</emph>
                both CTD differentials and the inter-axle differential are disengaged independently.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CTD Shift Unit.</emph>
                For detailed description and operation, refer to CTS-5166 in GROUP 14 - REAR AXLES of the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Inter-Axle Differential Lockout Shift Unit.</emph>
                For detailed description and operation, refer to the appropriate Eaton Axle Service Manual covering your
                axle model.
            </para>
            <para>Except where specified otherwise, the following instructions cover Controlled Traction Shift Systems
                with one or two selector valves.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Before starting a system check, make sure the inter-axle differential is disengaged. Also,
                        operate engine until full system air pressure (reservoir pressure) is built up in the system.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <para></para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disengage Inter-Axle Differential (One-Selector Valve System)</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with a system that engages both CTD differentials when the inter-axle
                differential is engaged, the following steps must be taken to make sure the inter-axle differential is
                disengaged before checking the CTD shift system.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start system check by releasing the parking brake and place transmission in neutral.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the inter-axle differential selector valve in the disengaged position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift both wheels of rear axle off the ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the inter-axle drive shaft. If drive shaft turns, the inter-axle differential is
                    disengaged. If it does not turn, the inter-axle differential shift mechanism is not functioning
                    properly. Refer to appropriate Eaton Axle Service Manual for disassembly and repair.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After confirming that the inter-axle differential is disengaged, disconnect the air line
                    connected to the inter-axle differential lockout shift unit and plug the end of the line.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>High pressure may be present when disconnecting air line. Exert caution to prevent
                            possible personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Disengage Inter-Axle Differential (Two</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">Selector Valve System)</emph>
                    For vehicles equipped with two selector valves, one for operating the inter-axle differential shift
                    unit and the other for the CTD shift units, the following steps must be taken to make sure the
                    inter-axle differential is disengaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the parking brake and place the vehicle transmission in neutral.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the inter-axle differential selector valve in the disengaged position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift both wheels of the rear axle off the ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the inter-axle drive shaft. If the shaft turns, the inter-axle differential is
                    disengaged. If it does not turn, the inter-axle differential shift mechanism is not functioning
                    properly. Refer to the appropriate Eaton Axle Service Manual for disassembly and repair.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Check Controlled Traction Differential Shift System</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Two-Valve System.</emph>
                    Start the System check by placing the CTD selector valve in the disengaged position (inter-axle
                    differential selector valve should still be in the disengaged position).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">One-Valve System.</emph>
                    Make sure the inter-axle differential selector valve is still in the disengaged position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Both Systems.</emph>
                Make sure the parking brake is released and the transmission is in neutral.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the wheel on the shift unit side of rear axle off the ground. Turn the wheel. Both
                    the wheel and the inter-axle drive shaft should rotate. If the wheel rotates, go to Step 6. If wheel
                    will not rotate, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>High pressure may be present when disconnecting air line. Exert caution to prevent
                            possible personal injury
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that there is no air pressure at the rear axle shift unit by removing the air
                    line. If air pressure is present, check for blockage of exhaust port at selector valve. If none is
                    found, the CTD selector valve (or inter-axle differential selector valve) is defective and needs
                    replacement.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no air pressure is present at the shift unit, remove the shift unit and have an
                    assistant move the CTD selector valve back and forth. The shift unit linkage should move
                    accordingly. If the linkage does not move, disassemble shift unit and repair. Refer to CTS-5166 in
                    GROUP 14 - REAR AXLES of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. If the shift unit functions properly,
                    proceed to Step 5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the shift unit removed, move the protruding end of the shift fork from side to
                    side. If the shift fork will not move, the problem is in the differential carrier assembly. Remove
                    carrier and inspect components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Two-Valve System.</emph>
                    Move the CTD selector valve to the engaged position.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">One-Valve System.</emph>
                    Move inter-axle differential selector valve to the engaged position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Both Systems.</emph>
                Turn the wheel that is off the ground. Neither wheel or the inter-axle drive shaft should rotate.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the wheel rotates, check to make sure that there is full system air pressure at the
                    rear axle shift unit by removing the air line. If no air pressure is present, the CTD selector valve
                    (or inter-axle differential selector valve) is defective and needs replacement.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air pressure is present at the shift unit, remove the unit by first placing the CTD
                    selector valve in the disengaged position. Once the shift unit is removed, have an assistant move
                    the CTD selector valve back and forth. The shift unit linkage should move accordingly. If the
                    linkage does not move, disassemble the shift unit and repair. Refer to CTS-5166 in GROUP 14 - REAR
                    AXLES of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. If the shift unit functions properly, move the
                    protruding end of the shift fork from side to side. If the shift fork will not move, remove
                    differential carrier and check components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use same procedure to troubleshoot forward axle controlled traction differential.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_18.xml" xrefid="hl1401006">CTD Functional Check
                                <xref refid="hl1401006"/>
                            </hotlnk>
                            .
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s14010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
