<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - DESCRIPTION - DUAL STEERING
        SYSTEMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DUAL STEERING SYSTEMS</title>
        <para>Two integral steering gear units are sometimes used where high front axle loads or installation space
            limitations are encountered.
        </para>
        <para>The secondary gear assembly differs from the master steering gear in that it does not have an actuating
            shaft, nor does the piston have an actuating valve. Both gears are connected to the steering linkage, drag
            links, pitman arms and rack and pinion gears.
        </para>
        <para>Pressure to operate the secondary, or slave gear, is passed through ports in the cylinder head and bearing
            cap of the master gear and is routed through high pressure lines to the proper end of the slave gear. Thus,
            as the actuating valve of the master gear is moved to cause pressure build-up on the piston of the master
            gear, pressure is also directed to the slave gear piston.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500402">Figure 2</hotlnk>
            illustrates a typical dual steering gear layout.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500403">Figure 3</hotlnk>
            illustrates a typical master gear and slave gear used in dual steering gear installations.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500402" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500402" filename="../figg05/G0500402.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Typical Dual Steering Gear Layout</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0500403" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500403" filename="../figg05/G0500403.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 3. Typical Master Gear and Slave Gear Used in Dual Steering Gear Installations</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Fluid exhausted from the low pressure end of the master gear is routed through the low pressure pinion
            gear area of the slave gear and then back to the reservoir.
        </para>
        <para>Early production dual gear systems routed the exhaust fluid from the master gear pinion gear area directly
            to the reservoir. Later systems route the exhaust fluid from the pinion gear area of the master gear through
            the pinion gear area of the slave gear and then to the reservoir. The later production method of oil return
            flow provides faster warm up of the slave gear and offers further assurance that air entrapment in the slave
            gear is avoided. The pressure relief check valve in the slave gear piston also allows entrapped air to
            escape to the lower pressure side of the piston and be purged from the system. Early slave gear pistons have
            two check valves. Present versions have only one check valve which might be found on either end of the
            piston, and is located in the piston end plug.
        </para>
        <para>Pressure relief valve plungers are not required on slave gears as pressure relief is provided by the
            master gear.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Wheel Shake Condition</title>
        </para>
        <para>When two integral steering gear units of the same size are applied to a single axle application, the
            geometry of the vehicle is critical. At no time may the effective length of the slave gear pitman arm be
            shorter than the master gear. If this situation does occur, the slave will surge power into the drag link
            and tie rod mechanism, creating a wheel shake, primarily on a left hand turn.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
