<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - DUAL STEERING SYSTEM - INTEGRAL SLAVE GEAR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>INTEGRAL SLAVE GEAR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-Series</title>
            <para>The major components in the slave gear are the power piston d the sector shaft assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05015c0">Figure 120</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05015c0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg05/G05002A5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 120. Power Piston and Sector Shaft Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Slave gear disassembly requires removal of cylinder heads and the sector shaft cover.</para>
            <para>The sector shaft assembly is removed and the piston is pulled out of the housing bore.</para>
            <para>The sector shaft bearings and the various seals are serviced using the same procedures as the master
                gear.
            </para>
            <para>On reassembly, the timing marks on the piston rack and the sector shaft must be carefully timed.
            </para>
            <para>The M-Series models use a seal ring on one end of the power piston. A new seal is installed by placing
                the back-up O-ring in the piston groove and installing the teflon seal ring over it.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The seal material will stretch as it is fitted to the ring groove. If you let the piston set
                        with the seal rings in place, it will become easier to install it in the piston bore. Use of a
                        ring compressor is best to limit damage to the piston ring (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f05015c1">Figure 121</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f05015c1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg05/G05002A6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 121. Fit Seal to Ring Groove</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The housing will have a beveled chamfer on one end of the piston housing. The piston is
                        installed through that end of the housing. Light taps with a soft hammer may be required on the
                        end of the piston to move it into the housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>To re-install piston, carefully work the piston ring past the pinion gear opening in the cylinder
                bore. While maintaining pressure on the end of the piston, press the piston seal into the ring groove.
                As the piston ring is compressed into the ring groove, the piston will slide further into the bore until
                the piston ring has passed through the pinion gear opening (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05015c2">Figure 122</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05015c2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg05/G05002A7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 122. Press Piston Seal into Ring Groove</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_X0501502.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
