<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - ADJUSTMENTS - RELIEF VALVE
        PLUNGERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500407" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>RELIEF VALVE PLUNGERS</title>
        <para>The relief valve plunger adjustment is provided to automatically reduce the steering pressure when the
            road wheels have reached their limits of turn. This keeps the supply pump from operating at maximum relief
            pressure when the road wheels are at their steering limits. System temperatures are therefore reduced and
            high stress loads on the mechanical components of the steering system are relieved.
        </para>
        <para>High pressure oil at either end of the piston will push the relief ball valve off its seat and fill the
            relief passage with oil at high pressure. At the opposite end of this passage, the relief ball valve is held
            against its seat and holds the high pressure in the relief passage. As the piston moves close to its limits
            of stroke, the adjustable relief plungers push the relief ball valve off its seat and the pressure is
            relieved. The distance the piston can move is dependent upon the total front axle/steering system geometry
            and tire size. The relief valve plungers are adjustable to allow for variations or changes in these areas.
        </para>
        <para>Adjust the relief valve plungers as follows (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004d4">Figure 134</hotlnk>):
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004d4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004d4" filename="../figg05/g05004d4.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 134. Adjust Relief Valve Plungers</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and allow it to operate at idle speed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With full weight of the vehicle on all wheels, turn the steering wheel in one direction
                until a high pressure hiss is heard or the axle stops contact.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the relief valve plunger in or out until the high pressure hiss is heard when there is
                1/8 to 3/16 inch clearance between the axle stops (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05004d5">Figure 135</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05004d5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05004d5" filename="../figg05/g05004d5.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 135. Turn Relief Valve Plunger In or Out Until High Pressure Hiss Heard</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat this procedure for the opposite direction of steer, and adjust the relief valve
                plunger on the opposite end of the steering gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Turning the plungers in will increase the space between the axle stops. Turning the plungers out will
            decrease the clearance between the stops. Do not turn the slotted plungers out beyond flush with the plunger
            boss or a leak will occur. Axle stops should only be adjusted in accordance with GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL
            SERVICE INFORMATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>After relief valve plunger adjustment, always check to ensure that the road wheels and tires have adequate
            clearance between suspension, brake and frame components.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_38.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_40.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
