<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - RE-PHASING COLUMN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500208" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>RE-PHASING COLUMN</title>
        <para>To check phasing of universal joints in the steering column, use an inch-pound graduated dial type torque
            wrench. With a socket on the steering wheel retaining nut, read the difference in the torque while steering
            from lock to lock. Variation of more than 15 in-lbs. (1.7 Nm) means improper phasing. Take the reading with
            the vehicle stationary and the engine running at idle.
        </para>
        <para>Phasing can usually be corrected by rotating the two piece intermediate shaft one spline at a time until
            the torque reading remains the same throughout the 360 degree rotation of the steering wheel.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Universal joints are designed to operate best when the angle between the drive and driven shaft is
                    a maximum of 20 to 25 degrees. Angles greater than this may upset steering performance.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Actuating shaft thread wear generally comes from improper lubrication or excessive manual
                    steering. Manual steering results from low pump pressure or flow or an overloaded front axle.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500202.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500203.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
