<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="4">
            <title>SHORT SERIES PISTONS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully reassemble the piston. Place two reversing springs on the center of the
                    adjusting nut in the piston. Put a new O-ring seal on the valve positioning pin and screw the pin
                    into the piston until the top of the pin is below the surface of the piston.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the actuating valve in the piston with the long locating slot in line with
                    the valve positioning pin. Turn the valve positioning pin until it lines up with the slot of the
                    valve and the valve slides into the reversing springs (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500483">Figure 83</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500483" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500483" filename="../figg05/G0500483.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 83. Re-install Actuating Valve</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Some 392 Short Series 3 and 4 pistons also use a tapered valve positioning pin, which is
                            adjustable. These pistons can be identified by the piston plug which uses seal rings. These
                            pistons will also have a control valve with a maximum inch and three quarter diameter (for
                            adjustment, refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_26.xml" xrefid="hl0500403">TAPERED VALVE POSITIONING PIN
                                <xref refid="hl0500403"/>
                            </hotlnk>
                            .
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the two reversing springs on the nose of the valve. Screw the adjusting nut into
                    the piston until the nut contacts the reversing springs and the valve has no end play. Now turn the
                    adjusting nut to line up your reference marks and the locking pin will enter the original pin holes
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500484">Figure 84</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500484" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500484" filename="../figg05/G0500484.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 84. Place Reversing Springs on Nose of Valve</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the lock pin will not enter the original holes, a second hole is provided and the
                    adjusting nut can be drilled and the pin installed in this position. The tip of the pin must be
                    below the surface of the piston (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500485">Figure 85</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500485" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500485" filename="../figg05/G0500485.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 85. Tip of Lock Pin Must be Below Surface of Piston</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring expander and a new square ring seal on the piston plug and install
                    the plug in the piston. Tighten plug securely. Drill and pin the plug to the piston. The tip of the
                    pin must be below the surface of the piston (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500486">Figure 86</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500486" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500486" filename="../figg05/G0500486.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 86. Install New O-Ring Expander and New Square Ring Seal on Piston Plug</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the relief valve seats, balls, springs.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
