<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - POWER STEERING SYSTEM TEST PROCEDURE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500603" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="1">
        <title>POWER STEERING SYSTEM TEST PROCEDURE</title>
        <para>This section presents a systematic method of diagnosing and troubleshooting the power steering hydraulic
            system. Start with Step 1 and move consecutively through the remaining steps completing every procedure, and
            if necessary, the correction described before moving on.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect pressure hose at pump or gear and connect power steering analyzer ZTSE-2780 in
                series with the pressure hose (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500603">Figure 3</hotlnk>). Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s05006w_19.xml" xrefid="hl0500604">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0500603" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500603" filename="../figg05/g0500603.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 3. ZTSE-2780 Power Steering Analyzer</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open valve on analyzer and start engine. Allow power steering system oil to reach normal
                operating temperature and check analyzer connections for leaks. Correct if necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check fluid level in system and add fluid as required.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put thermometer in the fluid reservoir.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine at idle, record flow and pressure. If pressure is in excess of 75 PSI, check
                hoses for restrictions and correct as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine at idle, partially close valve on analyzer to build 700 PSI and record flow.
                Subtract this flow from the flow recorded in step 5. Flow should not drop more than 1 GPM (3.8 L/MlN).
                If flow drops more than 1 GPM (3.8 L/MlN), check rotating group (cam ring, rolls and carrier), end plate
                seals and O-rings, and wear surfaces in pump. Correct as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close and partially open analyzer valve three times. Record the highest pressure each time
                the valve is closed.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not leave valve fully closed for more than 5 seconds as the pump could be damaged.</para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not allow the fluid temperature to exceed 180 degrees F (82.2 degrees C). Run each test at
                        between 125 degrees F (51.7 degrees C) and 135 degrees F (57.2 degrees C).
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>All three readings must be within the listed specifications in the table below, and must not vary more
                than 50 PSI. If readings do not meet this criteria, check for loose belt. If no problem exists with
                belt, replace pump flow control valve.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Increase engine speed until system is pressurized to the relief pressure value for your pump
                (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0500602">Relief Pressure Values Chart</hotlnk>) and record flow. If flow rate does not
                fall between specified flow range, remove flow control valve and clean. Check oil condition. If oil is
                dirty, disassemble pump and gear, clean and reassemble.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine idling, turn wheel slightly in both directions and observe pressure readings.
                Release wheel quickly; if pressure does not snap back, disassemble and clean gear hydraulic control
                valve. If oil is dirty, disassemble and clean gear and pump.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine idling, turn and hold wheel against wheel stops in both directions. A noticeable
                drop in pressure should occur as the wheel hits the stops. If no drop, or a rise in pressure occurs,
                adjust steering gear relief plungers (if so equipped) or replace steering gear relief valve (if so
                equipped) to correct.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <table id="t0500602">
            <title>Relief Pressure Values Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="5" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colname="SQCOLUMN1" colwidth="1.30in"/>
                <colspec colname="SQCOLUMN2" colwidth="1.30in"/>
                <colspec colname="SQCOLUMN3" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <colspec colname="SQCOLUMN4" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <colspec colname="SQCOLUMN5" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <spanspec namest="SQCOLUMN1" nameend="SQCOLUMN2" spanname="1to2"/>
                <spanspec namest="SQCOLUMN3" nameend="SQCOLUMN4" spanname="3to4"/>
                <thead valign="top">
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                            <para>PART NUMBER</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="3to4">
                            <para>FLOW RATE</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>RELIEF PRESSURE</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Eaton</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>International</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(L/Min.) GPM Min.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(L/Min.) GPM Max.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>kPa (PSI)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody valign="top">
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ER17225-1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1614025C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(15.2) 4.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(19.0) 5.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>14478 (2100)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ER16481-1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1647567C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(15.2) 4.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(19.0) 5.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>14133 (2050)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ER17246-1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1653357C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(19.0) 5.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(22.8) 6.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>14478 (2100)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ER17352-1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1654717C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(15.2) 4.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>(19.0) 5.0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>10341 (1500)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
