<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE - SWIVEL MITER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="4">
        <title>SWIVEL MITER</title>
        <para>The miter housing on the swivel miter input arrangement of the Sheppard integral power steering gear can
            be turned a full 360 degrees and clamped in the most desirable design location to complement the steering
            column and U-joint angles (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004c6">Figure 126</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004c6" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004c6" filename="../figg05/G05004C6.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 126. Miter Housing Can be Turned 360 Degrees</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A roll pin has been added in later models for locational purposes. This pin locks the miter clamp
                    and miter housing together.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>A clamping bar on each side of the miter housing clamps the housing to the bearing cap. Two or three bolts
            pass through each bar and the bearing cap and thread into the steering gear housing (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004c7">Figure 127</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004c7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004c7" filename="../figg05/G05004C7.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 127. Install Clamping Bar on Each Side of Miter Housing</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The steering should not be operated with these bolts removed or loosened. High operating pressures
                    may damage the bearing cap or bearing cap seals.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Reverse the order of disassembly to reassemble using new parts as required (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004c8">Figure 128</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004c8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004c8" filename="../figg05/G05004C8.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 128. Reassemble, Using New Parts as Required</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>After reassembly of the complete miter housing to the bearing cap, the backlash between the bevel gears
            must be checked. With the gears free of grease, turn the input shaft with the fingers to judge the clearance
            between the gears. Add or remove shims to obtain zero clearance (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004c9">Figure 129</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004c9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004c9" filename="../figg05/G05004C9.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 129. Turn Input Shaft to Judge Clearance Between Gears</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the correct grease for filling
            the miter housing.
        </para>
        <para>The steering gear bearing cap and high pressure oil seal are serviced in the same manner as the fixed
            miter gear assembly. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05004_34.xml" xrefid="hl0500405">FIXED MITER
                <xref refid="hl0500405"/>
            </hotlnk>
            for complete details.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
