<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE - SERIES 6 PISTON
        SEALS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="5">
        <title>SERIES 6 PISTON SEALS</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Series 6 pistons use teflon rings with backup O-ring seal. In addition, a slipper seal and backup
                    O-ring is used on the pressure supply orifice area.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>For servicing, remove the used teflon seals and backup O-rings, slipper seal and backup O-ring,
                    and replace with new seals and backup O-rings (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500490">Figure 90</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500491">Figure 91</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0500490" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500490" filename="../figg05/G0500490.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 90. Install New Seals and Backup O-Rings</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0500491" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500491" filename="../figg05/G0500491.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 91. Install New Seals and Backup O-Rings</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install backup O-rings on piston ends and slipper seal area. Carefully place teflon seals
                and slipper seal in position on cylinder (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500492">Figure 92</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500492" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500492" filename="../figg05/G0500492.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 92. Place Teflon Seals and Slipper Seal in Position on Cylinder</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a ring compressor to carefully install the piston in the gear housing.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">You will have to carefully work the piston ring past the pinion gear opening in the cylinder
                bore. While maintaining pressure on the end of the piston, use the blunt end of a wooden stick to press
                the piston seal into the ring groove. As the piston ring is compressed into the ring groove, the piston
                will slide further into the bore until the piston ring has passed the pinion gear opening (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500493">Figure 93</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500493" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500493" filename="../figg05/G0500493.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 93. Work Piston Ring Past Pinion Gear Opening in Cylinder Bore</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Due to the nature of the seal material, it will stretch as it is fitted to the ring groove. If
                        you let the piston set with the seal rings in place, they will contract and it will become
                        easier to install it in the piston bore. When installing the piston in the housing bore, use the
                        end of the housing with PA cast onto the housing. This end only contains a lead-in chamfer to
                        help guide the piston and teflon piston ring into the housing bore (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0500494">Figure 94</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0500494" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500494" filename="../figg05/G0500494.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 94. Install Piston in Housing Bore</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
