<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - TROUBLESHOOTING - FREE PLAY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FREE PLAY</title>
        <para>The movement of the shuttle type actuating valve within the piston, along with the normal clearances
            required between operating parts in the steering gear will produce a certain amount of unresponsive motion
            at the rim of the steering wheel. This unresponsive motion is inherent to the design and must be considered
            normal. With recent advances in technology and manufacturing methods, it has been possible to considerably
            reduce the amount of this unresponsive motion. Steering gears in service prior to July 1978 could be
            expected to have 3-1/2 to 4 inches of unresponsive motion. Current production Sheppard steering gears in
            service will have 1-1/2 to 2-1/2 inches of unresponsive motion. Various combinations of steering gear ratios
            and steering wheel diameters could effectively reduce these maximum allowances. Nominal unresponsive motion
            in Series 6 steering gears is 1/2 to 1-1/2 inches.
        </para>
        <para>Unresponsive motion is measured at the rim of the steering wheel. It must, therefore, be noted that any
            free play in the steering column and related components will affect your measurement. The steering gear
            mounting must be tight and steering linkage wear adjusted out or worn parts replaced.
        </para>
        <para>The vehicle should be standing on a smooth shop floor with the engine idling when unresponsive motion is
            checked. Measurement is made at the rim of the steering wheel, from initial tire and wheel movement left
            steer to initial tire and wheel movement right steer.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
