<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: TRW/ROSS-TAS 40, 55, 65 AND 85 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0500306">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>When the driver turns the steering wheel, he transmits force from the steering wheel to the steering
                gear input shaft. A torsion bar, pinned at its one end to the input shaft and at its other end to the
                worm shaft, turns with the input shaft and exerts a rotational force on the worm shaft. In response to
                this rotational force, the worm shaft, acting through the recirculating ball mechanism, tries to move
                the rack piston axially through the gear housing cylinder bore.
            </para>
            <para>The rack piston's axial movement is resisted by its engagement to the sector shaft, which is connected
                by linkage to the steered wheels. Because of this resistance, the torsion bar is twisted by the input
                shaft, thereby actuating the control valve. Pressurized fluid, directed by the control valve, assists in
                moving the rack piston axially through the cylinder bore. The rack piston then turns the sector shaft to
                steer the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SHOCK LOADS</title>
            <para>If the steered wheels receive a shock load, the shock forces are transmitted through the sector shaft
                to the rack piston, and on to the worm shaft. The internal geometry of the steering gear causes the
                control valve to send high pressure fluid to the correct cylinder cavity to resist the shock forces. By
                absorbing the shock forces hydraulically, the steering gear prevents objectionable kickback at the
                steering wheel.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
