<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - FLUID AND FILTER CHANGE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FLUID AND FILTER CHANGE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a clean, dry, solid surface. Set the parking brake, block the rear
                wheels and place the transmission in neutral. Make sure the engine is OFF.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the front end of the vehicle until the tires have cleared the surface using the
                hydraulic jack. Place front axle on floor stands.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being performed.
                    The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle with floor
                    stands.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tilt the hood or raise the cab.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the drain pan under the steering gear to catch fluid.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the pressure and return lines from the steering gear to drain fluid.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wipe off the area around the reservoir cap with a clean towel. Remove the cover bolt from
                canister type reservoirs. Remove the cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the filter from the canister and discard. If a spin on filter is used, remove the
                filter using the filter wrench and discard.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Discard only the filter element. The other parts may be used to retain the filter in the
                        reservoir assembly.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wipe the inside of the reservoir canister clean with a clean shop towel.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the hoses disconnected, slowly turn the steering wheel from full left to full right
                three or more times to purge oil from the steering gear. Make sure the drain pan will catch the oil from
                the steering gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the pressure and return lines to the steering gear and tighten.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new filter element in the reservoir. Follow the directions on the filter
                element.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the reservoir cap with an approved solvent. Remove the old gasket from the cap and
                replace it with a new gasket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the reservoir with new steering fluid to within 1 inch (25 mm) of the top of the
                reservoir canister. Install the reservoir cover and tighten the bolt. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500209.xml" xrefid="hl0500209">TYPES OF FLUID</hotlnk>
                for the correct type of fluid for the model vehicle being serviced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the vehicle and allow it to idle.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not allow the reservoir to empty during start up. Pump damage may result.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the fluid level and fill as needed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Steer the vehicle from full left to full right several times and check the fluid level
                again. Add fluid as needed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually check all fittings and hoses for external leaks.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not check for leaks by hand. Hydraulic oil under pressure can penetrate the skin and cause
                        severe injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the hand grease gun, purge the grease fitting in the input shaft cover of the steering
                gear. One pump will be enough.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shut the vehicle off. Remove the drain pan. Raise the vehicle and remove the floor stands.
                Lower the vehicle until the tires contact the surface and remove the jack.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the cab or hood.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500209.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
