<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING PUMP: VICKERS (LUK) V10NF AND V20NF - LUBRICATION/BLEED SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0500504">
        <title>LUBRICATION/BLEED SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Internal lubrication is provided by the system fluid. For lubrication requirements and intervals,
                refer to GROUP 10-LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Periodic inspection of the fluid condition and piping should be done in accordance with the schedules
                outlined in the GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION section of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. The following
                should be checked on a regular schedule.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>All hydraulic connections must be kept tight. Loose connections will result in fluid loss.
                        Loose suction or return lines draw air into the system, resulting in noisy and/or erratic
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check the reservoir at regular intervals for dirt or other contaminants. If the fluid becomes
                        contaminated, the system must be thoroughly cleaned (including the reservoir), and refilled with
                        new fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Filters must be checked and/or replaced regularly. A clogged filter results in a higher
                        pressure drop that forces particles through the filter that would otherwise be trapped. A
                        clogged filter may cause the fluid to bypass the filter entirely and result in a complete loss
                        of filtration.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A pump running excessively hot or noisy is a potential failure. The vehicle should be shut
                        down immediately and the problem corrected.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If fluid levels become so low as to uncover the inlet pipe opening in the reservoir, extensive
                        damage to the pump can occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ADDING FLUID TO THE SYSTEM</title>
            <para>When adding hydraulic fluid to the system always pour through a fine wire screen (200 mesh or finer).
                It is important that the fluid is clean and free of any contaminants that could cause improper operation
                or damage to the pump or other system components.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use cloth or similar substance to strain the hydraulic fluid as lint may get into the
                        system and cause damage to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
