<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - ADJUSTMENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ADJUSTMENTS</title>
        <svcproc id="hl0500409" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>BLEEDING AIR FROM SYSTEM</title>
            <para>The steering gear by design is self bleeding; however, in some installations where the gear is
                positioned at an odd angle or where the piston does not make a full stroke in the cylinder bore, air can
                be trapped in the steering gear. To avoid this possibility, the air should be bled from the system
                anytime the oil has been changed or the steering system is repaired.
            </para>
            <para>After re-installing the steering gear on the vehicle, but prior to connecting the drag link to the
                pitman arm, bleed the air from the steering system in the following manner:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill pump reservoir with recommended . It will be necessary to continue filling after
                    starting the engine and during the bleeding operation until correct oil level is maintained.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake or block wheels. Start engine and allow it to operate at fast idle
                    speed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With engine running, turn steering wheel from left to right and return, making three
                    complete cycles to remove all air from the steering system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Stop engine. Reconnect the drag link.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Following these procedures will ensure that the piston bottoms in both directions of steer, opens the
                relief valve in the piston, and allows the air to escape to the reservoir and into the atmosphere.
            </para>
            <para>Check and adjust the relief valve plungers as required.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_39.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
