<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500404">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                for the following operation descriptions.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500404" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500404" filename="../figg05/g0500404.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Steering Gear Operation</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The actuating shaft is connected to the steering column assembly. It is threaded with a heavy Acme
                thread having multiple starts.
            </para>
            <para>The actuating valve is contained within the piston and threaded to accommodate the input shaft. When
                the input shaft is turned, the valve travels over the shaft threaded area. Two ports on the valve
                outside diameter ontrol the oil flow through the piston. The valve has a linear motion, permitting the
                edges of the ports to seat against the mating edges on the inside of the piston.
            </para>
            <para>The piston is located within the housing. A rack on the piston engages the pinion gear on the output
                shaft. Ports in the piston function for either pressure or exhaust depending upon the direction of the
                valve travel. The piston centers itself over the valve to provide the steering action.
            </para>
            <para>The sector shaft/output shaft and pinion assembly, located in the housing, is turned by the piston
                rack. This provides rotating action at the pitman arm connected to the steering linkage.
            </para>
            <para>The Sheppard Integral Power Steering Gear provides full time hydraulic steering which is light and
                responsive. Only sufficient manual input effort to overcome the reversing springs and close the control
                valve to cause a pressure build-up is required. Full rated axle loads can be steered with ease.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500405">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                for the following operation description.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500405" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500405" filename="../figg05/g0500405.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Steering Gear Operation</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The actuating shaft is connected to the steering column and is threaded with an Acme type thread. The
                actuating valve is threaded to accommodate the actuating shaft and is centered within the piston by the
                reversing springs. The valve moves in a linear motion within the piston permitting the edges of the
                valve to overlap the mating edges on the inside of the piston. This causes high pressure oil to build up
                at one end of the piston. This higher pressure on one end of the piston causes the piston to move in the
                bore of the gear housing. The output shaft and pinion gear are engaged to a rack gear machined into one
                side of the piston. As the piston moves, the output shaft and pitman arm are rotated by the rack and
                pinion gear and steering operation is performed. When rotation or input from the actuating shaft ceases,
                pressure on, or movement of the actuating valve stops and the reversing springs at the ends of the valve
                center the valve in the piston, relieving the high pressure and power to the steering ceases. Movement
                of the actuating valve, to control oil pressure, is controlled by the deflection of the reversing spring
                at either end of the valve. Total movement of the valve is approximately .040 of an inch. Relief valve
                plungers or adjustable stops are provided at the bearing cap and cylinder head. When the plungers are
                adjusted properly, they will automatically unload the hydraulic system if the wheels are turned to
                either extreme direction.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine is running, there is constant oil flow through the steering gear at low pressure. This
                constant oil flow provides for instant response and absorbs road shock to help eliminate steering wheel
                kick and protect the steering gear. Pressure is equal throughout the steering gear and oil cooling and
                lubrication are assured. Care should be used in towing or moving a vehicle where the engine or hydraulic
                supply pump are inoperative. In this instance, the ability of the steering gear to protect itself is
                reduced and mechanical damages can be encountered.
            </para>
            <para>An optional pressure relief valve integral with the steering gear is available on the Series 5 and 6
                steering gears. This valve limits maximum steering system relief pressure at the steering gear, a point
                in the steering system which is farthest from the supply pump, pumping chamber. This effectively reduces
                system temperature by avoiding high pressure bypass and recirculation within the pump.
            </para>
            <para>The rack and pinion gear set does not require adjustment. There is no center point adjustment. The
                high pressure seal at the input/actuating shaft is the only seal which is exposed to high pressure and
                motion, unless the steering unit has the optional hydra max braking capability. With this option, the
                output shaft/sector also has a high pressure seal. The high pressure actuating shaft seal is protected
                by a dirt seal and salt seal which are separated by a grease pack that is flushed during lubrication.
                The clearance between the cylinder bore and the piston is closely controlled and with the Series 6
                steering gears, piston rings were added to efficiently use the hydraulic oil supplied from the power
                steering pump. With reasonable care and limited maintenance, the Sheppard steering gear will provide
                many miles of trouble-free and effortless performance.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
