<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - STEERING SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS - COMMON COMPLAINTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>COMMON COMPLAINTS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Wander</emph>
                - Wander is described as the vehicle not tracking properly on the road surface. The vehicle tends to
                drift side to side. Continual correction is required to keep the vehicle on the road.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe wander in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Squirrelly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Continually correcting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Constantly fighting the wheel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Can't hold it on the road</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All over the road.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>To determine if wander is present, drive the vehicle on a straight road with no traffic and carefully
                release the steering wheel. If the vehicle has a wander condition, the vehicle will tend to drift from
                side to side as described above. The most probable cause of wandering is looseness in mechanical
                components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Pulls</emph>
                - Pulling is a term used to describe a constant movement of the vehicle in one direction.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe pulling in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Won't track</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pushes to one side</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Wanders</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Drives one way</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Heads for the ditch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If a directional pull is present, the most probable cause will be misalignment of the rear axle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Binds</emph>
                - Binding is an increase in steering wheel effort that is momentary or intermittent.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe binding in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>High spot</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hangs up</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Locks up</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Catches when turning</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Seizes.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Binding is normally a result of some mechanical problem with steering components. Most often the bind
                will occur at the same position on the steering wheel while turning.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">No Return</emph>
                - No return is used to describe the lack of wheel coming back to center after a turn or correction is
                completed.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe no return in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The wheel won't come back</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hangs up in turns</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Wheel sticks.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>No return can result from a misaligned front axle or a bind in mechanical components external to the
                steering gear. Front axle caster angles should be checked in return complaints.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Hard Steering</emph>- Hard steering is experienced when steering wheel effort exceeds
                100 inch pounds (11.3 Nm) measured at the steering wheel retaining nut. Hard steering will remain
                constant through the full turn. Do not confuse hard steering with binding.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe hard steering in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>No power assist</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Steers like a manual gear</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Won't turn all the way.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Hard steering can result from hydraulic and/or mechanical problems. A complete mechanical and
                hydraulic diagnosis is necessary to determine the cause.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Excessive Free Play/Unresponsive Motion</emph>
                - Excessive free play is a condition where there is too much steering wheel movement before the steer
                tires move. A small amount of free play is considered normal.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe free play in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Too much slop in the wheel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Too much backlash</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Slack in the wheel.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Free play is normally a function of looseness in the linkage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Shimmy</emph>
                - Shimmy is a shake or vibration of the front tires that is transmitted through the steering wheel.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe shimmy in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Steering wheel shake</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cab shakes</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Steering wheel chatter.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Shimmy is a function of looseness in the steering linkage, looseness in front end components or
                unbalanced tires. Shimmy can also be caused by air trapped in the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Noise</emph>
                - Noise in the steering system can come from any number of components. Harmonics or hydraulic noise can
                be caused by fluid flow. Metallic or grinding noises come from component parts.
            </para>
            <para>The driver may describe noise in the following ways:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Growls</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Swishes</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pops when steering</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Moans.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When noise is present, you must first determine if it is a mechanical or hydraulic noise. Most
                mechanical noises are a result of looseness or wear in components. Hydraulic noise will normally be
                associated with problems in pump flow, such as cavitation or low fluid levels.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_X0501501.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
