<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - ADJUSTMENTS - BELT ADJUSTMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BELT ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <para>When adjusting a power steering pump belt, never pry against the pump reservoir or pull against the filler
            neck. To increase belt tension, move the pump outward by prying against the bracket pry lugs or against the
            pump housing casting extension directly behind the pump drive pulley.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When power steering pump is driven by a single belt:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen the pump attaching bolts and adjust the belt to correct tension by moving the
                    pump outward, away from the engine.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Snug all pump mounting bolts and remove pry bar.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tighten all pump mounting bolts to specifications in the
                    <hotlnk document="s05006w_18.xml" xrefid="hl0500605">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check belt tension.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the power steering pump is driven by two belts in a matched set: Follow same checking
                and adjusting procedure as in step 1 above, but if it is necessary to replace one belt, both must be
                replaced by a new matched set to equalize belt tension in both belts. Check tension in both belts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the power steering pump pulley is driven by one primary belt and is used as an idler
                for a second belt driving some other accessory:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Follow same checking and adjusting procedure for the primary power steering pump drive
                    belt as for above.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Recheck and adjust as necessary the pump belt tension after adjusting tension on belt
                    driving the other accessory.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
