<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMPS LUK VT73 AND LF93 - OPERATION - FLOW CONTROL AND RELIEF VALVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FLOW CONTROL AND RELIEF VALVE</title>
        <para>Maximum flow to the operating circuit and maximum system pressure are determined by the integral flow
            control and relief valve subassembly (when fitted) used on the pumps in this series (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500705">Figure 5</hotlnk>). An orifice in the housing limits maximum flow. A pilot-
            operated type relief shifts to divert excess fluid delivery back to the inlet, thus limiting system pressure
            to a prescribed maximum.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500705" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500705" filename="../figg05/g0500705.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 5. Flow Control and Relief Valve</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>View 3A of
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500705">Figure 5</hotlnk>
            shows the condition when the total pump delivery can be passed through the orifice. This condition usually
            occurs only at low drive speeds.The large spring chamber is connected to the pressure port through an
            orifice. Pressure plus spring load in this chamber slightly exceeds pressure at the other end of the relief
            valve spool and the spool remains closed.
        </para>
        <para>When pump delivery is more than the flow rate determined by the orifice, pressure drop builds up across
            the orifice and forces the spool open against the light spring. Excess fluid is throttled past the spool to
            the pump inlet as shown in View 3B,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500705">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>If pressure in the system builds up to the relief valve setting (View 3C,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500705">Figure 5</hotlnk>), the pilot poppet is forced off its seat. Fluid in the light
            spring chamber flows through the spool and out to the pump inlet. This flow through the small sensing
            orifice causes a pressure drop and prevents pressure in the light spring area from increasing beyond the
            relief valve setting. As pressure against the right end of the spool starts to exceed the relief valve
            setting, the pressure differential forces the spool to the right, against the light spring, porting the full
            pump flow to the pump inlet.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
