<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE - ACTUATING SHAFT
        AND BEARING CAP SEALS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>ACTUATING SHAFT AND BEARING CAP SEALS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the backup washer in the bearing cap with the undercut down as shown (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500498">Figure 98</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500498" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500498" filename="../figg05/G0500498.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Place Backup Washer in Bearing Cap</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Take a piece of round stock 2 inches long and turn to 1.615 inches O.D. and smooth on one
                end.
            </para>
            <para>Put the piece of round stock in the bearing end against the backup washer, or against the shoulder
                area for the high pressure seal if a backup washer is not used. Set the bearing cap on a press and
                evenly install the dirt seal, lip out from the other end until it rests against the backup washer or the
                round stock as shown (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500499">Figure 99</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500499" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500499" filename="../figg05/G0500499.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Evenly Install Dirt Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Evenly install the salt seal, lip out, into the bearing cap until flush with top.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn bearing cap over when replacing the high pressure seal as pictured above with a
                duplicate seal. The backup washer must be installed with the undercut down as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500498">Figure 98</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>When replacing the high pressure seal, the original backup washer must be discarded, as the new high
                pressure teflon seal kit has the backup washer built in.
            </para>
            <para>Evenly install the high pressure oil seal until it rests against the backup washer or the shoulder.
            </para>
            <para>Lubricate all three seals with grease before installing actuating shaft assembly.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the backup washer is not installed properly, an oil leak will occur on the first
                        application of pressure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the actuating shaft into the bearing cap. Re-install the bearing retainer. Tighten
                retainer securely to keep the bearing from having end play. Install a new lock pin and peen it in place
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05004a0">Figure 100</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05004a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05004a0" filename="../figg05/G05004A0.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Install New Lock Pin</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
