<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - CLEAN AND INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Each component except seals, should be washed in a mineral spirit solvent and air dried.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using
                <hotlnk document="s05006w_1.xml" xrefid="f0500602">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                as reference, inspect each component for excessive wear in a clean and well lighted work area as
                follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">BODY/BUSHING SUB-ASSEMBLY - Inspect the shaft bushing and ball bearing bore for burring,
                    scoring or wear condition. Replace the body/bushing sub-assembly, if necessary. The bushing is not
                    serviceable as a separate component.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">COVER/BUSHING SUB-ASSEMBLY - Inspect the shaft bushing for burring, scoring or wear
                    condition. Replace the cover bushing sub-assembly, if necessary. The bushing is not serviceable as a
                    separate component. Inspect the port face for excessive scoring, or pitting. Lapping or polishing of
                    face to remove up to 0.002 inch (0.050 mm) is acceptable, taking care to maintain flat polished
                    surface. Clean ports after refacing.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">SHAFT/BALL BEARING - Inspect the shaft for any wear, burring or scoring in the areas of
                    the bearings, seal and pulley mounting end. If any of these conditions exist, replacement is
                    required. The ball bearing should be checked with a dial indicator for excessive wear and radial
                    clearance. With dial indicator tip placed against bearings (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500615">Figure 15</hotlnk>) rotate bearing. The radial clearance should not exceed
                    0.010 inch (0.254 mm) maximum. Also inspect ball bearing grease seals for damage and replace bearing
                    if necessary.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500615" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="G0500615" filename="../figg05/G0500615.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Bearing Check</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">CAM - Inspect the internal surface of the cam for wear or scoring. Polish in some areas
                    is normal. Wear severe enough to raise a noticeable burr on the I.D. corner of the cam face usually
                    indicates replacement is required. The cam is serviced only as part of the pumping element kit.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">CARRIER SHAFT ASSEMBLY - Inspect the carrier on the ends and tooth drive faces for
                    excessive wear or scoring. If ends are worn or scored or wear pattern on any of the roll drive faces
                    is greater than 0.06 inch (1.52 mm) in width, the carrier must be replaced. The carrier is serviced
                    only as part of the pumping element kit.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">ROLL - Inspect each of the ten rolls for pitting, scoring or wear on the O.D. surface.
                    The rolls are serviced only as part of the pumping element kit.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">PORT PLATE - Polishing and minor scratching of surface is normal due to flexible plate
                    design. Excessive scoring or galling is not typical and can be hand polished if minor: 0.0001 inch
                    (0.002 mm) maximum material removal allowable. Replacement is required for more severe wear.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">END PLATE SEALS - The seals should not be disassembled from the plate unless cracking,
                    excessive swelling or extrusion is present. Replace all seals if any damage is noted.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">END PLATE - Inspect the end plate for cracks in the area of the sealing rings.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">VALVE ASSEMBLY - It is difficult to visually determine if internal valve components are
                    worn or damaged. If the complaint is one of low pressure, and the pumping elements show no sign of
                    excessive wear, it is possible that valve assembly requires replacement. The valve must move
                    smoothly in the valve bore. Minor polishing of valve O.D. up to 0.0001 inch (0.002 mm) material
                    removal is acceptable.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <para>The above parts represent all of the parts that require inspection and possible replacement due to wear.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
