<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING PUMP: VICKERS (LUK) V10NF AND V20NF - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
            <title>PUMPING CARTRIDGE</title>
            <para>The pumping cartridge produces the fluid flow (pressure). The action of the pumping cartridge is shown
                in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500504">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500504" filename="../figg05/g0500504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Pumping Cartridge Action</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CAM RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INLET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. OUTLET</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DRIVE SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ROTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. VANE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The rotor is driven within the ring by the drive shaft, which is coupled to the engine. As the rotor
                spins, centrifugal force on the vanes causes them to follow the egg-shaped inner surface of the ring.
            </para>
            <para>Radial movement of the vanes and turning of the rotor cause the chamber volume between the vanes to
                increase as the vanes pass the inlet section of the ring. This results in a low pressure condition which
                allows atmospheric pressure to force fluid into the chambers. (Fluid outside the inlet is at atmospheric
                pressure or higher.)
            </para>
            <para>This fluid is trapped between the vanes and carried past the large diameter or dwell section of the
                ring. As the outlet section is approached, the ring diameter decreases (more pressure is applied to the
                fluid) and the fluid is forced out into the system.
            </para>
            <para>System pressure is fed under the vanes, assuring their sealing contact against the ring during normal
                operation.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
