<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - ADJUSTMENTS - BLEEDING AIR
        FROM SYSTEM-DUAL STEERING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>BLEEDING AIR FROM SYSTEM-DUAL STEERING</title>
        <para>Refer to Figure
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004e1">141</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004e2">Figure 142</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004e1" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004e1" filename="../figg05/G05004E1.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 141. Dual Systems</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f05004e2" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004e2" filename="../figg05/G05004E2.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 142. Main Gear and Secondary Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To bleed the air from the steering system on the vehicle after installing the steering gears, the pitman
            arms may be installed if there is no clearance problem with the pitman arm striking any object using the
            full travel of the gear. Install them by aligning the timing mark on the output shaft with the timing mark
            on the pitman arm. For tightening, refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05004_33.xml" xrefid="hl0500406">PITMAN ARM
                <xref refid="hl0500406"/>
            </hotlnk>
            torquing assembly. Then proceed in the following manner.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill pump reservoir with recommended oil. Continue filling after starting the engine and
                during the bleeding operation until correct oil level is maintained.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set parking brake. Start engine and allow it to operate at fast idle speed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine running and drag links disconnected, turn steering wheel to the left and hold
                until the secondary (slave) gear pitman arm moves the full travel. Then turn to the right and hold until
                the secondary (slave) gear pitman arm again moves the full travel. Repeat this process three or more
                times.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the drag link to the master gear. Do not connect the secondary (slave) gear drag
                link at this time. Turn steering wheel to the left and hold until the ndary (slave) gear pitman arm
                moves the full travel. Then turn to the right and hold until the secondary (slave) gear pitman arm again
                moves the full travel. Repeat this process three or more times. Turn the steering wheel until the
                secondary (slave) gear pitman arm lines up with the drag link. Then install the pitman arm. DO NOT move
                the pitman arm by hand or air will be pulled back into the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_41.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_43.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
