<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMPS LUK VT73 AND LF93 - MAINTENANCE - HYDRAULIC SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HYDRAULIC SYSTEM</title>
        <para>When hydraulic fluid is added to replenish the system, it should always be poured through a fine wire
            screen (200 mesh or finer). It is important that the fluid be clean and free of any substance which could
            cause any improper operation or wear of the pump or other hydraulic fluids. Therefore, the use of cloth to
            strain the fluid should be avoided to prevent lint from getting into the system.
        </para>
        <para>To insure the hydraulic system is clean:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean (flush) entire new system to remove paint, metal chips, welding shot, etc.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Filter each change of fluid to prevent introduction of contaminants into the system.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Provide continuous fluid filtration to remove sludge and products of wear and corrosion
                generated during the life of the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Provide continuous protection of system from entry of airborne contamination by sealing the
                system and/or by proper filtration of the air.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Proper servicing of filters, breathers, reservoirs, etc. cannot be over- emphasized.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Good system and reservoir design will insure aeration of fluid is kept to a minimum.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
