<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TRW MANUAL STEERING GEAR - GENERAL INFORMATION - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check for wear in steering linkage and other system components before making adjustments to
                steering gear assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prevent internal bottoming of steering gear. Carefully check axle stops.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make periodic checks of lube level for steering gear and components to prevent malfunction
                due to inadequate lubrication.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make periodic checks for proper front end alignment.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Maintain correctly inflated tires.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always use a puller; never use a torch or hammer to remove steering arms.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully examine all steering parts which have been subject to impact and replace any that
                are questionable.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Investigate immediately and correct cause of any play, rattle, or shimmy in any part of the
                linkage or steering mechanism.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cause of steering column misalignment, and if necessary, elongate support bracket
                holes at dash.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Encourage all drivers to report any malfunction or accident that could have damaged the
                steering mechanism.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not attempt to weld any broken steering component. (Replace only with original
                equipment.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is not recommended to severely cold-straighten any steering system part.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is not recommended to hot-straighten or bend any steering system part.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always use new seals and O-rings during repairs and overhauls.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replacement of single bearing assemblies, or balls, if one or more make a "set" is not
                recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
