<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING PUMP: VICKERS (LUK) V10NF AND V20NF - TEST PROCEDURES - TEST 2:
        PUMP FLOW RATE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TEST 2: PUMP FLOW RATE</title>
        <para>Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s05005s_28.xml" xrefid="hl0500502">PUMP FLOW RATES</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>With the vehicle stationary, the engine idling and the power steering fluid at normal operating
            temperature:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close the shut-off or load valve until the system pressure is 100 psi and record the
                analyzer flow rate. The flow rate must be within the minimum/maximum range for the pump. Pump flow must
                not be less than the minimum rate or greater than the maximum rate specified.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fully close the shut-off valve until the pump is relieving, and immediately reopen it. Do
                this three times. The flow rate should instantly return to the minimum reading as listed in the
                <hotlnk document="s05005s_28.xml" xrefid="hl0500502">PUMP FLOW RATES</hotlnk>, for the pump being tested
                when the valve is opened. If the flow rate does not return to the minimum rate immediately, the pump is
                defective. Lower than normal flow will cause binding, uneven, or intermittently hard steering.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Flow rates should not exceed rates shown in
                        <hotlnk document="s05005s_28.xml" xrefid="hl0500502">PUMP FLOW RATES</hotlnk>. Excessive fluid
                        flow can cause high operating temperatures. Excessive flow, if allowed to continue, can cause
                        internal damage to the steering gear.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <para>Allow fluid temperature to return to normal operating temperature of 160 degrees to 200 degrees F (71
            degrees to 93 degrees C) before continuing tests.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
