<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE - INTEGRAL SLAVE
        GEARS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>INTEGRAL SLAVE GEARS</title>
        <para>On reassembly, the timing marks on the piston rack and the pinion gear must be carefully timed.</para>
        <para>Some Series 5 and all Series 6 slave gear models use seal rings on the ends of the power piston (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500495">Figure 95</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500495" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500495" filename="../figg05/G0500495.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 95. Some Series 5 and All Series 6 Slave Gears Use Seal Rings on Ends of Power Piston
            </caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">New seals are installed by placing the O-ring expander in the piston groove and installing
                the square cut seal ring over it (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500496">Figure 96</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500496" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500496" filename="../figg05/G0500496.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 96. Place O-Ring Expander in Piston Groove</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">You will have to carefully work the piston ring past the pinion gear opening in the cylinder
                bore. While maintaining pressure on the end of the piston, use the blunt end of a wooden stick to press
                the piston seal into the ring groove. As the piston ring is compressed into the ring groove, the piston
                will slide further into the bore until the piston ring has passed the pinion gear opening (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500497">Figure 97</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500497" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500497" filename="../figg05/G0500497.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Work Piston Ring Past Pinion Gear Opening</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Due to the nature of the seal material, it will stretch as it is fitted to the ring groove. If
                        you let the piston set with the seal rings in place, they will contract and it will become
                        easier to install it in the piston bore.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
