<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - TROUBLESHOOTING - EXTERNAL LEAKAGE DIAGNOSIS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTERNAL LEAKAGE DIAGNOSIS</title>
        <para>When diagnosing external leakage, always check for the possibility of system overheating. An indication of
            overheating is when the power steering fluid has decomposed and significantly darkened interior pump
            surfaces. Occasionally a "burnt" oil odor will be noticeable with overheated systems. Overheating is
            normally caused by restricted lines causing excessive back pressure or by severe operating conditions. A
            complete pump overhaul and/or addition of a cooler may be required.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check oil level. An over-filled pump reservoir can be a cause for leakage. The oil in the
                steering system expands as heated during normal usage. If over-filled, the excess is forced through the
                reservoir cap vent. Operate the engine and steering system until normal operating temperature of 170
                degrees F (80 degrees C) is reached. Remove the reservoir cap and check level. Adjust the oil level as
                required. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s05006w_16.xml" xrefid="hl0500601">LUBRICATE</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>If leakage persists with the oil level correct and the cap tight, replace the cap.</para>
            <para>Air in the system can also cause fluid level to rise, especially after system repair. Bleed the system
                as described in
                <hotlnk document="s05006w_17.xml" xrefid="hl0500602">BLEED SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace reservoir.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace reservoir gasket seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten fittings. If leakage persists, replace O-ring seal.</para>
            <para>If either the return hose or the pressure hose leaks, other than at the nut connections, replace the
                hose.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace drive shaft seal after inspecting and thoroughly cleaning the sealing surface.
                Replace drive shaft if wear is found at sealing locations. Always replace the seal if the shaft is
                replaced.
            </para>
            <para>On direct drive gear driven applications, leaks in this area will cause migration of engine oil into
                the pump. If the seal does not appear damaged or excessively hardened, correct excessive pressure
                condition in the engine pump mounting area cavity.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all gasket surfaces thoroughly and replace O-ring seal.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
