<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DIAGNOSTIC INFORMATION</title>
            <para>Complaints of faulty steering are frequently the result of problems other than the pump. Those areas
                of the steering system which can be easily checked and quickly corrected without disassembly and
                overhaul of any major components should be attempted first.
            </para>
            <para>Conditions such as hard or loose steering, road shock or vibrations are not always due to the steering
                gear or pump, but are often related instead to such factors as low tire pressure and front and rear
                axle(s) alignment. These factors should be checked and corrected before any adjustment or disassembly of
                the power steering pump is attempted.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES - GENERAL INFORMATION AND WHEEL ALIGNMENT INFORMATION and GROUP 03 -
                REAR SUSPENSION ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Many factors affect proper operation of the steering system, of which the most common are:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fluid level and condition.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive belt tension (if applicable).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loose component mountings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loose pump pulley nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>These factors must be checked and corrected before making any further diagnosis of the steering
                system. The need for proper diagnosis cannot be over-emphasized.
            </para>
            <para>After the source of the problem has been found, determine the cause. For example, if the oil level in
                the reservoir is found to be low, refill and check the entire hydraulic system for oil leaks. Refilling
                the reservoir will not necessarily correct the problem.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
