<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: TRW/ROSS-TAS 40, 55, 65 AND 85 - ASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0500315">
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="29">
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all seals, seal rings, and gaskets with new ones each time you disassemble the
                    gear.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new dirt seal into the trunnion end of the housing sector shaft bore and against
                    the bearing with the seal lip out (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500357">Figure 57</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500357" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500357" filename="../figg05/g0500357.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 57. Install Dirt Seal</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the second retaining ring, seating it firmly in the housing retaining ring
                    groove (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500358">Figure 58</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500358" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500358" filename="../figg05/g0500358.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 58. Install Second Retaining Ring</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install washer into the side cover side of the housing seal bore with small diameter
                    piloted into the retaining ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500359">Figure 59</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500359" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500359" filename="../figg05/g0500359.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 59. Install Washer</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble new seal onto bearing and seal tool so the lip with the garter spring is toward
                    the shoulder of the tool.
                </para>
                <para>Working from the side cover side of the housing, pilot the seal tool into the washer and bearing
                    and press with a force of 100 to 800 lbs. (445 to 3,560 N) until the seal is seated against the
                    washer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500360">Figure 60</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500360" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500360" filename="../figg05/g0500360.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 60. Assemble New Seal Onto Bearing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Liberally pack the area between the dirt seal and pressure seal including roller bearing
                    with clean, high temperature industrial grease (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500361">Figure 61</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500361" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500361" filename="../figg05/g0500361.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 61. Pack Grease</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lightly oil new seal ring and assemble in valve housing mounting face groove (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500362">Figure 62</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500362" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500362" filename="../figg05/g0500362.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 62. Oil New Seal Ring</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>TAS40, 55, 65: Oil new seal ring and assemble in valve housing mounting face groove.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>TAS85: Oil new seal ring and assemble in valve housing pilot groove.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new backup O-ring and then a new Teflon seal ring on the rack piston. Do not
                    over-stretch these rings as you install them. Do not allow the Teflon seal ring to be twisted (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500363">Figure 63</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500363" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500363" filename="../figg05/g0500363.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 63. Install New Back-up O-Ring</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply clean oil to housing cylinder bore. Place the rack piston in the housing piston
                    bore with ball return guide holes up (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500364">Figure 64</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500364" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500364" filename="../figg05/g0500364.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 64. Apply Oil to Housing Cylinder Bore</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the worm screw into the rack piston close to maximum depth, without the valve
                    housing making contact with the poppet stem. Insert two 7/16 inch-14 All Threads through valve
                    housing bolt holes and tighten into housing to support the worm screw. Line up rack piston ball
                    guide holes with the worm ball track grooves by rotating the input shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500365">Figure 65</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500365" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500365" filename="../figg05/g0500365.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 65. Line Up Piston Ball Guide Holes</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare the new ball guides with the guides removed from the gear; use the ones that
                    look the same. Left hand guides are copper plated, right hand guides are unplated. Assemble the new
                    ball return guide halves into the rack piston until seated, and rotate the input shaft slightly if
                    necessary (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500366">Figure 66</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500366" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500366" filename="../figg05/g0500366.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 66. Assemble Ball Return Guide Halves</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not seat guides with a hammer. Damage to guides can result in subsequent lockup or loss
                            of steering.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>If a new rack piston or a new input shaft, valve, worm subassembly is being installed, the
                            balls removed from the unit must be discarded and a service ball kit used. The balls in a
                            service ball kit are sized to function in the ball track guide path as altered by component
                            replacement.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When using the service ball kit, use the correct quantity of service balls: TAS40-29,
                            TAS55-31*, TAS65-32, TAS85-34.
                        </para>
                        <para>*TAS55 gears built prior to 338-89 were equipped with 30 balls.</para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold the ball return guides firmly in place during this entire procedure. Insert as many
                    of the steel balls as you can through the hole in the top of the ball return guides. Rotate the
                    input shaft to pull the balls down and around the ball track guide path. Continue until the correct
                    number of balls are in the ball track guide path (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500367">Figure 67</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500367" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500367" filename="../figg05/g0500367.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 67. Insert Steel Balls</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Hold down the ball return guides until cap or clip is reinstalled. Failure to hold the
                            guides will result in a trapped ball or balls, which could cause a vehicle accident. If the
                            ball guides become unseated (raise up) at any time, repeat the procedure starting at step
                            10.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The correct number of balls are required for proper gear operation. Count the balls and
                            insert each carefully as in step 12. The original and service number is the same for each
                            gear: TAS40-29, TAS55-31*, TAS65-32, and TAS85-34.
                        </para>
                        <para>*TAS55 gears built prior to 338-89 were equipped with 30 balls.</para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Do not allow valve housing to contact the poppet stem or move more than 2-1/2 inches
                            (69mm) from the upper end of the rack piston during these procedures. This could incorrectly
                            reset the poppet, or back out the worm beyond closed ball loop, trapping the balls.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If your gear is equipped with the ball return guide cap, grease a new ball return guide
                    cap seal and place it in the seal groove of the cap. Assemble the cap so the seal makes full contact
                    with the rack piston surface (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500368">Figure 68</hotlnk>). Install two new Allen or Torx head screws and tighten
                    each screw alternately to 18 ft-lbs. (25 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500368" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500368" filename="../figg05/g0500368.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 68. Assemble The Cap</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the gear is equipped with a ball return guide clip instead of a cap, install a new
                    clip so both bolt hole faces are in full contact with the rack piston surface. Install the two hex
                    head bolts. Tighten the bolts to 18 ft-lbs. (25 N&#8226;m). Finish by bending the guide clip locking
                    tabs up against the bolt head flats (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500369">Figure 69</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500369" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500369" filename="../figg05/g0500369.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 69. Install New Clip</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the input shaft from one end of travel to the other without contacting the poppet
                    stem to the valve housing, and without moving the valve housing face more than 2-1/2 inches (69 mm)
                    from the input end (upper end) of the rack piston (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500370">Figure 70</hotlnk>). If you cannot rotate the input shaft, remove the
                    balls and reassemble them.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500370" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500370" filename="../figg05/g0500370.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 70. Rotate Input Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If you install a gear on a vehicle with the worm shaft unable to rotate, the gear will not
                            function correctly. Steering and gear failure may result.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply clean oil to Teflon seal ring on the rack piston. Make sure there is a space of
                    3/8 to 1/2 inch (10 to 13 mm) between valve housing and poppet stem to prevent poppet contact at
                    either end. Remove the All Threads, and push the rack piston assembly into the housing with the rack
                    piston teeth toward the sector shaft cavity. Line up the valve housing cylinder feed hole with the
                    gear housing feed hole. Make sure both O-rings in the valve housing remain in position (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500371">Figure 71</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500371" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500371" filename="../figg05/g0500371.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 71. Line Up Holes</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not damage the seal ring while installing the rack piston into the housing. If the seal
                            ring end of the rack piston enters the housing first, the seal ring will be destroyed when
                            the rack is removed.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The poppet seat and sleeve assemblies must not bottom against the internal poppet stops in
                            the steering gear until the gear is installed on the vehicle and the poppet adjustment
                            procedures are performed.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate and install the four valve housing bolts into the housing. Tighten the TAS40,
                    55 and 65 bolts alternately to 80 ft-lbs. (109 N&#8226;m). Tighten TAS85 bolts to 118 ft-lbs. (160 N&#8226;m)
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500372">Figure 72</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500372" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500372" filename="../figg05/g0500372.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 72. Tighten Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the gear is equipped with a relief valve, assemble a new O-ring on the relief valve
                    cap. Assemble the small end of the tapered spring onto the pin on the relief valve cartridge and
                    insert the assembly (large end of tapered spring end first) into the relief valve cap cavity. Turn
                    the relief valve cap as assembled into the valve housing and tighten to 30 ft-lbs. (41 N&#8226;m) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500373">Figure 73</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500373" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500373" filename="../figg05/g0500373.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 73. Assemble New O-Ring</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">TAS40, 55, 65: Lightly oil DU bushing. Do not grease.</para>
                <para>TAS85 only: Apply a generous amount of industrial high temperature grease (do not substitute
                    another type of grease) to the caged bearing assembly inside the side cover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500374">Figure 74</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500374" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500374" filename="../figg05/g0500374.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 74. Apply Grease</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>This bearing is sealed and will receive no lubrication from the hydraulic fluid in the
                            gear. Failure to use the proper grease could result in premature bearing wear.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grease and assemble new seal onto installation tool so the side with the garter spring
                    is against the shoulder of the tool. Pilot the tool into the side cover with a force of 100 to 800
                    lbs. (445 to 3,560 N) until it is seated against the bearing or bushing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500375">Figure 75</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500375" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500375" filename="../figg05/g0500375.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 75. Assemble New Seal</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">TAS40, 55, 65: Lightly oil short bearing area of sector shaft. Do not grease.</para>
                <para>TAS85 only: Apply a generous amount of industrial high temperature grease or equivalent to the
                    short bearing area of the sector shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500376">Figure 76</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500376" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500376" filename="../figg05/g0500376.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 76. Apply Grease</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the sector shaft into the side cover subassembly and screw the sector shaft
                    adjusting screw counterclockwise into the side cover until the screw reaches solid height (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500377">Figure 77</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500377" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500377" filename="../figg05/g0500377.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 77. Inspect Sector Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Rotate the adjusting screw clockwise one half turn so the side cover will rotate freely on the
                    sector shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the sector shaft adjusting screw jam nut onto the sector shaft adjusting screw a
                    few threads. Final adjustment will be made later (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500378">Figure 78</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500378" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500378" filename="../figg05/g0500378.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 78. Install Jam Nut</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press the new vent plug into the hole provided in the side cover until the plug is
                    bottomed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500379">Figure 79</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500379" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500379" filename="../figg05/g0500379.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 79. Press In Vent Plug</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not weld or otherwise plug this hole in any permanent manner. This is a safety vent
                            which functions only if the side cover seal fails. If the seal fails and the plug cannot
                            vent, the steering gear may lock up or otherwise malfunction.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply clean grease to the new side cover gasket to hold it in place and assemble it onto
                    the side cover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500380">Figure 80</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500380" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500380" filename="../figg05/g0500380.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 80. Apply Grease</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">There are four teeth on the rack piston. Rotate the input shaft to position the rack
                    piston so the space between the second and third tooth is in the center of the sector shaft opening.
                    This will center the rack piston for assembly of the sector shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500381">Figure 81</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500381" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500381" filename="../figg05/g0500381.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 81. Rotate Input Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the rack piston is not centered when the sector shaft is installed, the gear travel
                            will be severely limited in one direction. This could result in an accident.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean off any old tape on the serrations. Reapply one layer of masking tape. Install the
                    sector shaft assembly into the housing. The center tooth of the sector shaft must engage the center
                    space (between the second and third tooth) of the rack piston, with the side cover gasket in place (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500382">Figure 82</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500382" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500382" filename="../figg05/g0500382.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 82. Install Sector Shaft Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>If the serrations are not properly taped, they will damage the output seal in the housing,
                            causing the seal to leak.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the special side cover bolts into the side cover and tighten them in the
                    sequence shown (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500383">Figure 83</hotlnk>). If bolts must be replaced, use bolts of the same
                    design, type and length as those you removed. Do not use a substitute. Tighten TAS40 bolts to 118
                    ft-lbs. (160 N&#8226;m), TAS55, 65, and 85 bolts to 170 ft-lbs. (230 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500383" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500383" filename="../figg05/g0500383.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 83. Side Cover Bolts - Tightening Sequence</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove tape from the sector shaft and pack the end of the housing trunnion area at the
                    sector shaft with clean, high temperature industrial grease. Apply more of the grease to the inside
                    of the new trunnion dirt seal and assemble it over the sector shaft and into the trunnion bore (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500384">Figure 84</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500384" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500384" filename="../figg05/g0500384.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 84. Apply Grease to Trunnion Seal</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pack the end of the valve housing bore around the input shaft with clean, high
                    temperature industrial grease. Apply more of the grease to the inside of a new dirt and water seal
                    and install it over the input shaft and seat it in the groove behind the serrations and against the
                    valve housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500385">Figure 85</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500385" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500385" filename="../figg05/g0500385.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="192px" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 85. Apply More Grease</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_HL0500313.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_HL0500316.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
