<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMPS LUK VT73 AND LF93 - ASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <para>Pumps can be assembled for right or left hand rotation as viewed from the shaft end. A pump made for left
            hand rotation (counterclockwise) is identified by an "L" and for right hand with an "R" in the model code.
            Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05007_2.xml" xrefid="hl0500701">IDENTIFICATION</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>These pumps must be driven in the direction of the arrows cast into the pump cam ring. If it is
                    desired to change the direction of drive rotation, it is necessary to replace the cartridge.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Never drive a pump in the wrong direction of rotation. Seizure may result, necessitating expensive
                    repair.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Immerse all parts in clean hydraulic fluid to facilitate assembly.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A shaft seal driver must be used to ensure installation of the shaft seal without damage. A length
                    of tubular round stock should be machined to proper dimensions. The ends must be square. The outside
                    diameter of the driver should be slightly smaller than the outside diameter of the shaft seal. The
                    inside diameter should be slightly larger than the shaft seal surface of the shaft. The length of
                    the driver should be long enough to press the seal fully in against the shoulder.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make a shaft seal driver as noted above. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s05007_13.xml" xrefid="f0500706">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                and position shaft seal with spring side of seal facing the flange. Press seal in place until it engages
                the shoulder within the flange. This shoulder acts as a positive stop for the shaft seal.
                <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                overpress as damage to the shaft seal will result.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the shaft with system fluid and slide the shaft assembly into the flange
                subassembly.
                <emph type="bold">Be careful</emph>
                not to damage the shaft seal and the bushing during installation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the large retaining ring into the retaining ring groove of the flange subassembly.
                This retaining ring holds the bearing and shaft in place within the flange subassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the woodruff key into the shaft and tap in place with a small hammer to seat the key,
                when applicable.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate O-ring and back-up rings and install around the O-ring bosses in the body. Place
                the housing over the cartridge. Line up housing screw holes with the flange and thread four screws with
                washers through the housing into the flange. Cross tighten the screws to 29 to 37 ft-lbs. (40 to 50 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the flow control relief valve with the hex head going last into the valve bore. Make
                sure not to scratch the valve bore.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Spool should slide gently. DO NOT force.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert spring into the control valve bore over the hex head of the spool. Install a new
                O-ring on the hexagon plug and place it over the spring. Compress the spring and screw the plug into the
                housing. Tighten to 33 to 40 ft-lbs. (45 to 55 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>In the following step if the flow control relief valve S/A is reversed in the cover bore, the
                        unit will malfunction and pressure will rise dangerously high. Make sure that you follow
                        instructions exactly as noted.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the body mounting flange into the bench vise with the shaft end down.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert pins into the flange and install wear plate with the bronze coated side up.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Obtain a seal kit for the unit. Lubricate and install O-rings into the grooves.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert vanes into the rotor with the radius edge toward the cam ring. Use an Arkansas stone
                on each vane edge and on each rotor edge to remove the burrs developed during handling. Make sure the
                vanes do not bind within the rotor. Lubricate and place the rotor and vanes on top of the flange with
                the rotor counterbore toward the flange.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the cam ring over the rotor and vanes. Check the model code for direction of rotation
                and position the arrow on the cam ring to agree with the model code (R-clockwise, L-counter- clockwise
                as viewed from the shaft end).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the pressure plate over the pins and up against the cam ring, rotor and vanes, with
                the bronze coated side towards the rotor.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
