<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING COLUMN ASSEMBLY, TILT/TELESCOPING - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL PROCEDURES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REMOVE AND INSTALL PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent vehicle damage, personal injury, or possible death, park the vehicle on a flat,
                        level surface. Make sure the engine ignition is in the off position and the transmission is in
                        neutral or in the park position if the vehicle is equipped with an automatic transmission. Set
                        the parking brake, chock the wheels, and disconnect the batteries at the negative terminal
                        before doing any service procedures on the engine or vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>All steering mechanisms are critical to personal safety. It is imperative that the
                        instructions in this section are followed exactly. Failure to observe the procedures and
                        instructions set out herein may result in loss of steering control.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>This adjustable steering column assembly has components under spring tension. The tilt
                        adjustment should be in the full up position to minimize spring tension before removal from the
                        vehicle. Wear eye protection and use caution to prevent injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always disconnect power source before working on electrical equipment.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Before performing any work on the steering components, be sure to perform these basic
                        procedures:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="arabic">
                        <item>
                            <para>Park the chassis on a flat, level surface.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Place transmission in neutral (or park, if automatic transmission).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Set the parking brake.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Turn off ignition.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Install wheel chocks.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Disconnect the battery.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </important>
                <important>
                    <para>The vehicle must be parked with the wheels in the straight-ahead position, and the wheels must
                        remain straight while performing the procedures in this service manual.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05018_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05018_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
