<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - STEERING SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS - GLOSSARY OF TERMS AND DEFINITIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500201" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GLOSSARY OF TERMS AND DEFINITIONS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Actuating Valve</emph>
                - Internal valve in the bearing cap of the steering gear. It is actuated by the steering wheel through
                the yoke connection of the steering column.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Back Pressure</emph>
                - The pressure found on the return side of the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Base Mounted Gear</emph>
                - The steering gear is mounted to the frame rail or bracket utilizing the eight mounting holes opposite
                the sector shaft cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Bearing Cap</emph>
                - End cap of the steering gear that houses the actuating shaft and valve.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Bearing Cap Cover</emph>
                - Small cover on the end of the bearing cap of the steering gear. The bearing cap cover houses the input
                shaft oil and salt seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Bleeder Screw</emph>
                - 1/8 inch AlIen screw located in the sector shaft bore of the steering gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Cavitation</emph>
                - Bubbles that form in the oil which keep the pump from supplying pressure and volume.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Contamination</emph>
                - Dirt or other foreign material in a fluid.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Cylinder Bore</emph>
                - Long bore of the steering gear where the steering gear piston is housed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Cylinder Head</emph>
                - The end cap of the steering gear bolted on the housing opposite the actuating shaft end of the gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Displacement</emph>
                - The volume of fluid that can pass through a pump or cylinder in a single revolution or stroke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Feedback</emph>
                - A transfer of energy from the output of a device to its input.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Fluid Flow</emph>
                - The stream or movement of a fluid, or the rate of its movement.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Piston</emph>
                - Is found in the cylinder bore and changes the hydraulic force to mechanical force in the steering
                gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Plunger</emph>
                - Slotted pins that are used to limit the travel of the steering gear piston under pressure. Plungers
                are located in the cylinder head and bearing cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Pressure Relief Valve</emph>
                - Optional pressure relief valve integral to the steering gear to limit system operating pressure.
                Identified by a large hex nut on the side of the bearing cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Pump</emph>
                - A device that converts mechanical force and motion into hydraulic fluid power.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Rack Teeth</emph>
                - The area on the piston that engages the sector shaft teeth.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Recirculating Ball Thread</emph>
                - The area of the rotary valve on which the 24 steel balls travel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Relief Valve</emph>
                - A pressure control valve used to limit system pressure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Sector Shaft</emph>
                - The shaft the pitman arm is attached to.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Sector Shaft Bore</emph>
                - Area of the steering gear that houses the sector shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Slave Gear</emph>
                - Right hand gear in a dual system application. Identifiable by a lack of an actuating shaft on either
                end of the steering gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Slave Ports</emph>
                - Threaded openings in the cylinder head, bearing cap and sector shaft bore to install the pressure
                lines to operate the slave gear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Tab - Lock Retainer</emph>
                - Bolt assembly used to provide initial torque when installing the pitman arm. Uses alignment tabs that
                fit into the pitman arm and restraining tabs to be locked into the head of the retainer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Volume Of Flow</emph>
                - The amount of fluid that passes a certain point in a unit of time. The volume of flow is usually
                expressed in gallons per minute for liquids.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
