<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: TRW/ROSS-TAS 40, 55, 65 AND 85 - ADJUST - POPPET RE-ADJUSTMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500322" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="7">
        <title>POPPET RE-ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <para>This resetting procedure will work in most cases with at least 1-3/4 hand-wheel- turns from each side of
            center. If you are making a large reduction in wheel cut and this procedure does not work, you may have to
            replace or internally reset the poppets using the procedure described in the
            <hotlnk document="s05003y_HL0500310.xml" xrefid="hl0500310">POPPET COMPONENT</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set the axle stops. Refer to GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL INFORMATION AND ALIGNMENT in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Start the engine and allow the vehicle to idle for 5 to 10 minutes to warm the hydraulic fluid. Shut
                off the engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If a new poppet adjusting screw and jam nut are being used, turn the screw into the
                non-sealing end of the jam nut until the drive end of the screw is flush with the nut (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003e5">Figure 145</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003e5" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003e5" filename="../figg05/g05003e5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 145. Drive End of Screw Flush With Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Your steering gear will have either a fixed stop bolt or an adjusting screw. If the adjusting screw is
                already part of the steering gear, back the jam nut off the adjusting screw until it is flush with the
                end of the adjusting screw.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the engine is off and the road wheels are in the straight ahead position. Remove
                and discard the poppet fixed bolt (if equipped) and washer (if equipped) from the lower end of the
                housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003e6">Figure 146</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003e6" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003e6" filename="../figg05/g05003e6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 146. Remove Poppet Fixed Bolt</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If the unit has a poppet adjusting screw and jam nut that need to be replaced, remove and discard
                them.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the adjusting screw and jam nut assembly, without rotating the nut on the screw, into
                the housing until the jam nut is firmly against the housing using 7/32 inch Allen wrench. Tighten the
                jam nut against the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003e7">Figure 147</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003e7" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003e7" filename="../figg05/g05003e7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 147. Tighten Jam Nut Against Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the drive end of the screw is below the face of the jam nut, the poppet seal flange will
                        break during step 7C.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refill the system reservoir with approved hydraulic fluid.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not mix fluid types. Mixing of transmission fluid, motor oil, or other hydraulic fluids
                        will cause seals to deteriorate faster.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a jack under the center of the front axle and jack up the front end of the vehicle so
                the steer axle tires are off the ground (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003e8">Figure 148</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003e8" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003e8" filename="../figg05/g05003e8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 148. Jack Under Front Axle</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and let it run at idle speed.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Note which output shaft timing mark is nearest the housing piston bore.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in the direction that makes this timing mark move toward the
                    adjusting screw just installed. Turn in this direction until axle stop contact is made.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Pull hard on the steering wheel (put up to 40 lbs. rim pull on a 20 inch diameter
                    steering wheel) after the axle stop is contacted.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in the opposite direction (end of timing mark away from adjusting
                screw) until the other axle stop is contacted.
            </para>
            <para>Pull hard on the steering wheel (put up to 40 lbs. rim pull on a 20 inch diameter steering wheel).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Release the steering wheel and shut off the engine.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the jam nut, hold with a wrench, and back the adjusting screw out until 1 inch is
                past the nut. Tighten the jam nut against the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003e9">Figure 149</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003e9" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003e9" filename="../figg05/g05003e9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 149. Tighten Jam Nut Against Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not hold the steering wheel at full turn for more than 10 seconds at a time; the heat
                        build-up at pump relief pressure may damage components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and let it idle.</para>
            <para>Turn the steering wheel in the original direction (end of timing mark toward adjusting screw) until
                axle stop contact is made (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003f0">Figure 150</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f05003f0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003f0" filename="../figg05/g05003f0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 150. Turn Steering Wheel</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Hold the steering wheel in this position (with up to 40 lbs. rim pull) for 10 seconds, then release.
                Repeat this hold and release process as many times as necessary while completing step 11.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With steering wheel held tightly at full turn, loosen the jam nut and hold it in place with
                a wrench.
            </para>
            <para>Turn the adjusting screw in (clockwise) using finger-pressure only (don't use a ratchet) until the
                Allen wrench stops (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f05003f1">Figure 151</hotlnk>). Do not attempt to turn it in further. Pause the
                turning-in process each time the driver releases the steering wheel; continue turning only while the
                wheel is held at full turn.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Back off the adjusting screw 3-1/4 turns and tighten the jam nut to 35 ft-lbs. (47 N&#8226;m).</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1"></para>
            <figure id="f05003f1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05003f1" filename="../figg05/g05003f1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 151. Turn Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The poppets have now been completely reset. Lower the vehicle. Check the reservoir and fill
                if required.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The length of the adjusting screw beyond the jam nut must be no more than 1-1/16 inch for
                        proper thread engagement.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The length of the adjusting screw beyond the jam nut may be different for each vehicle.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_HL0500317.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
