<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - ASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before reassembly all parts must be thoroughly cleaned.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="13">
            <title>BASE PUMP</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble a new shaft oil seal (steel cage side out) into the pump body bushing
                    sub-assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500616">Figure 16</hotlnk>). Use a socket or steel tubing approximately the size
                    of the seal O.D. to press the oil seal to the bottom of the bore (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500617">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Use caution not to cave in the oil seal's case due to
                    excessive assembly pressure. The seal must bottom in the bore, however. Direct drive pumps may have
                    two seals. The second seal will be installed with the steel cage side in.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500616" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500616" filename="../figg05/g0500616.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Shaft Oil Seal</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500617" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500617" filename="../figg05/g0500617.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. Shaft Oil Seal Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the ball bearing is replaced on pulley driven pumps, press shaft from old bearing and
                    replace by pressing new bearing onto shaft, supporting the press load on the inner race only.
                    Permanent damage and early failure will result if the outer race is loaded during pressing
                    operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to inserting the shaft sub-assembly for pulley driven pumps into the pump,
                    lubricate the oil seal and bushing with a generous amount of light grease. Do not use petroleum
                    jelly. Ensure that the shaft areas to be pushed through seal lips are free of burrs or sharp edges.
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500618">Figure 18</hotlnk>). Insert the shaft into position in the pump body,
                    using caution not to damage shaft seal lip. Assemble bearing retainer snap ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500619">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500618" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500618" filename="../figg05/g0500618.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18. Bushing Lubrication</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500619" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500619" filename="../figg05/g0500619.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19. Bearing Snap Ring Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The shaft for gear driven pumps is installed from the carrier side after the carrier and rolls
                        have been re-installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If end plate seals are to be replaced, assemble O-ring seal into the bottom of each
                    kidney-shaped seal gland (
                    <hotlnk document="s05006w_12.xml" xrefid="f0500611">Figure 11</hotlnk>). Assemble square
                    cross-section seal into each gland and stack on top of the O-ring. All seals should fit tightly to
                    gland wall.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine correct end plate and locating pin position as noted at the time of
                    disassembly, or see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500620">Figure 20</hotlnk>, and assemble end plate into body (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500621">Figure 21</hotlnk>). Assemble port plate (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500622">Figure 22</hotlnk>) in the same position as noted at disassembly or such
                    that the entire seal is covered by the port plate, and that the large O.D. port openings on port
                    plate and end plate align.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500620" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500620" filename="../figg05/g0500620.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Correct End Plate and Locating Pin Position</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CAM</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ARROW</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. LOCATING PIN</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500621" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500621" filename="../figg05/g0500621.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21. End Plate Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500622" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500622" filename="../figg05/g0500622.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Port Plate Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully assemble the cam ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500623">Figure 23</hotlnk>) into the pump body pocket and position it over the
                    locating pin. Be sure to assemble the cam ring in the original manner, noting the arrow direction.
                    Again, the large O.D. slot must align with large O.D. port openings on port plate.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500623" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500623" filename="../figg05/g0500623.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Cam Ring Installation</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. ARROW</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CAM RING</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point, lubricate the face of the port plate, the shaft bushing, and the I.D.
                    wall of the cam ring with a small amount of clean power steering fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble carrier drive pin into shaft keyway and assemble carrier in proper direction (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500624">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500624" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500624" filename="../figg05/g0500624.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24. Carrier Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For gear driven pumps, install shaft and key into carrier and pump housing from the
                    carrier side.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Prior to inserting the shaft sub-assembly into the pump, lubricate the shaft seal and
                            bushing with a generous amount of compatible grease and insert the shaft into position using
                            caution not to damage the shaft seal lip. A seal protector or "BULLIT" fitted to the shaft
                            end is recommended to avoid seal damage.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the 10 rolls into the carrier and lubricate the carrier face and shaft with a
                    small amount of the clean oil to be used in the steering system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble two seals to body face grooves, at the cam pocket-and-flow by-pass hole (
                    <hotlnk document="s05006w_12.xml" xrefid="f0500608">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate cover wear face (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500625">Figure 25</hotlnk>) and bushing with clean steering fluid and assemble to
                    pump body, over the shaft and dowel pin (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500626">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500625" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500625" filename="../figg05/g0500625.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25. Lubricate Port Plate</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500626" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500626" filename="../figg05/g0500626.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Cover to Body Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the valve bore with a small amount of oil. Insert the valve assembly into the
                    bore with the long small diameter end in first (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500627">Figure 27</hotlnk>). The valve must slide smoothly in the bore. Lubricate
                    and assemble the new seal to the valve cap. Assemble the flow control spring into the valve bore and
                    thread the valve cap in finger tight (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500628">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500627" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500627" filename="../figg05/g0500627.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. Valve Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0500628" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500628" filename="../figg05/g0500628.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. Control Spring and Cap Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the five 3/8-16 body to cover retaining bolts and install bracket in proper
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the flange (and bearing assembly) for gear driven pumps, noting the proper
                    index positions to the front of the pump using 3/8-16 bolts finger tight, and also installing new
                    flange O-rings or face gaskets if required being careful not to pinch or damage the O-ring. Tighten
                    the 3/8-16 body to cover bolts to 35 ft-lbs. (47.5 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clamp the pump mounting bracket or flange in a bench vise in such a manner as to
                    complete the assembly of the pump and reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the valve cap to 40 ft-lbs. (54.0 Nm).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The base pump is now assembled. Check the shaft to determine if it rotates freely and
                    smoothly. Maximum shaft turning torque is 10 in-lbs. (1.13 Nm). If torque is excessive, disassemble
                    pump and check for pinched O-rings, burrs or contamination. Relube and reassemble.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
