<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMPS LUK VT73 AND LF93 - DISASSEMBLE - VT73 ( Figure 6 )</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VT73 (
            <hotlnk document="s05007_13.xml" xrefid="f0500706">Figure 6</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <para>A clean work area is most essential for disassembly. A work bench (6 foot), bench vise (6 inch), cleaning
            tank and shop air are also useful. Lay clean kraft paper on the work bench for disassembled parts. Place
            parts in an orderly manner on the kraft paper to avoid mixing the parts during assembly. Discard the shaft
            seal, O-rings, and gaskets removed during disassembly.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Pumps have aluminum housing parts. Care should be taken when handling power steering pump unit to
                    avoid denting and chipping of contact surfaces and sealing areas.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain the reservoir and clamp pump mounting flange in a bench vise (housing end up), being
                certain to use protective jaws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the hexagon plug from the pump body.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Special attention should be exercised when working with spring loaded plug. Always wear safety
                        goggles as serious personal injury can result if not properly protected.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Remove spring and gently slide out the valve spool. Care should be taken to avoid scratching the valve
                bore. Do not allow the spring and control valve subassembly to fall from the bore.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove four screws from the pump housing. Remove the O-ring and back-up ring. Remove the
                pressure plate, pins, cam ring, vanes, rotor, wear plate and O-rings from the flange.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
