<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TRW MANUAL STEERING GEAR - ADJUSTMENTS - OUTPUT ROLLERSHAFT OR TOTAL MESH</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0501401" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OUTPUT ROLLERSHAFT OR TOTAL MESH</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After making correct worm preload adjustment, centralize the steering gear by rotating worm
                and input shaft assembly through full travel while counting the number of input shaft rotations. Then
                starting at one end of travel, rotate input shaft back half of the counted (total) rotations. This will
                place the roller of the output shaft in center of worm, or "straight ahead" position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the worm and input shaft assembly with appropriate torque wrench (approximately 180
                degrees) through center position. The required total mesh preload torque is:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>20 to 31 in-lbs. (2.3 to 3.5 Nm) without input shaft seals.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>23 to 34 in-lbs. (2.6 to 3.8 Nm) with input shaft seals.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Procedure for correcting output shaft or total mesh preload.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Loosen adjusting screw locknut.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn slotted adjusting screw as required to correct the total mesh preload, clockwise to
                    increase preload and counterclockwise to decrease the preload. Repeat this procedure until the
                    output shaft total preload is within specified torque limits stated in Step 2.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Hold adjusting screw in place and tighten locknut to 25 to 40 ft-lbs. (34 to 54 Nm).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check total mesh preload.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Replace lubricant, re-install filler plug, and install unit in vehicle.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If correct total preload cannot be achieved, disassemble steering gear and repair.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501403.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
