<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - STEERING SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS - HYDRAULIC DIAGNOSIS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>HYDRAULIC DIAGNOSIS</title>
        <para>Follow the procedures as outlined below. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500204.xml" xrefid="hl0500204">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>The Sheppard M-Series integral power steering gear is a reactionary part of the power steering system. By
            reactionary we mean that its operation is dependent on the proper supply of oil pressure and flow from the
            hydraulic supply pump. Also necessary for the gear to function is some external input to the gear; either
            from the steering wheel or the road wheels.
        </para>
        <para>When the steering wheel is turned, oil flow is applied to one end of the steering gear piston causing
            pressure to build. This pressure causes the piston to move. As the piston moves, it is displaced by a volume
            of oil under pressure. The speed the piston moves is dependent on the amount of oil flow or, Flow = Speed of
            steering.
        </para>
        <para>Maximum system relief pressure limits the amount of steering gear output available to steer your specific
            vehicle or, Pressure = The amount of work the steering gear can do.
        </para>
        <para>Keeping the basic formula of "Flow = Steering Wheel Speed" and "Pressure = Work" in mind will help you
            diagnose steering complaints.
        </para>
        <para>Oil pressure and flow requirements are set during the design of the steering system. When diagnosing
            steering complaints, oil pressure and flow must meet design specifications. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500204.xml" xrefid="hl0500204">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>System back pressure and operating temperature must be considered during the diagnosis of the steering
            system. High system back pressure will create heat.
        </para>
        <para>High system oil temperatures reduce overall efficiency of the steering pump and steering gear.</para>
        <para>Various types of pressure and flow meters are available to diagnose power steering problems. A pressure
            gauge rated at 3000 PSI and a flow meter with a capacity of 10 GPM are needed to check oil pressure and
            flow.
        </para>
        <para>A shutoff valve placed downstream from the pressure gauge allows the hydraulic supply pump to be isolated
            from the gear to check pump relief pressure. A simple thermometer placed in the reservoir will show system
            temperature.
        </para>
        <para>A Power Steering Test Kit is shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500209">Figure 9</hotlnk>. This is an excellent tool for troubleshooting power steering
            systems. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s05002y_41.xml" xrefid="hl0500205">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500209" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500209" filename="../figg05/G0500209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Power Steering Test Kit</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>This tester is a self contained, direct reading device to check system flow, pressure or both at the same
            time. It can detect worn components, check flow and pressure control settings or monitor overall system
            performance.
        </para>
        <para>Only one hose connection is broken, either at the pump output or at the pressure input to the power
            steering gear housing.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Oil under pressure can penetrate the skin causing severe injury. Never use your hands to check for
                    leaks.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>Using a pressure and flow tester, proceed with the evaluation of the hydraulic system. Record your
            findings on the
            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500203.xml" xrefid="hl0500203">Troubleshooting Checklist</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>All tests must be performed with the vehicle parked on a clean, dry, solid surface, with the
                    engine running and the
                    <emph type="bold">full weight of the vehicle on the front wheels.</emph>
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the pressure and flow tester in series with the pressure line of the pump.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the engine and check system oil level. Make sure the oil flow is in the proper
                direction as indicated by the arrow on the flow meter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place a thermometer in the reservoir.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Run the engine at idle speed. Slowly close the shut off valve until you have a pressure
                reading of 1000 PSI. Maintain this pressure until system temperature reaches 150 degrees Fahrenheit (65
                degrees C). Open the shutoff valve all the way when the temperature is 150 degrees.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Normal system back pressure will be between 50 and 100 PSI with the engine idling and the
                steering wheel stationary; dual systems will normally read slightly higher. Back pressure should be
                checked at normal operating temperature.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the engine running at specified idle speed, slowly turn the shutoff valve until it's
                closed and read the pressure at which the pressure relief valve opens. (Open the shutoff valve as
                quickly as possible to avoid heat build-up or possible damage to the steering pump.) This pressure
                reading should equal the maximum pump pressure. Refer to GROUP 05 - POWER STEERING PUMP in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual for the type of pump used on the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A bad pressure relief valve may not relieve pump pressure. Closing the shutoff valve may cause
                    severe pump damage or high pressure hoses to rupture. Watch the pressure gauge closely. If pressure
                    rises rapidly or goes above 2500 psi, stop! Do not continue to close the shutoff valve. Pump damage
                    or personal injury may result.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure oil flow under the following conditions. Record your findings on the
                <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500203.xml" xrefid="hl0500203">Troubleshooting Checklist</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Flow at idle with back pressure only</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flow at idle under a 1500 PSI load applied with the shutoff valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flow at full governed RPM with back pressure only</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flow at full governed RPM under a 1500 PSI load applied with the shutoff valve open.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually check for air mixed with the oil in the steering system. The oil should be clear.
                Any signs of frothing indicate air in the system and steering performance will be affected. Carefully
                check for leakage on the suction side of the steering pump. Drain, refill, and bleed the system. Follow
                the procedure for setting relief plungers under
                <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500206.xml" xrefid="hl0500206">SET RELIEF PLUNGERS</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Before any steering gear repairs are made, complete the hydraulic supply evaluation and make any
                repairs. Many times steering gears have been repaired or replaced needlessly because a hydraulic supply
                system evaluation had not been made.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Static Steering Pressure and Input Effort: Measure and record the pressure required to steer
                the vehicle from full left to full right while parked. Input effort is measured at the steering wheel
                retaining nut. Use a dial type inch pound torque wrench to check static steering.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
