<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - SUB-ASSEMBLY REPAIR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SUB-ASSEMBLY REPAIR</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>M-SERIES - OPTIONAL INTEGRAL RELIEF VALVE</title>
            <para>An optional, integral, pressure relief valve is offered with the Sheppard M-Series steering gear. The
                relief valve cartridge is located in the bearing cap. The valve limits the maximum operating pressure in
                the steering system. In most cases the hydraulic supply pump will have a maximum relief pressure setting
                higher than the integral relief valve in the steering gear.
            </para>
            <para>When maximum relief pressures are reached in the steering system, the excess pressure is relieved
                within the steering gear.
            </para>
            <para>When oil pressure exceeds the maximum relief pressure setting of the pilot operated relief valve, the
                valve opens. Excess pressure is bled off into the oil return circuit through the return port of the
                steering gear.
            </para>
            <para>The relief valve cartridge can be removed for cleaning and inspection. Remove the relief valve nut and
                cartridge assembly. At this time the strainer can also be cleaned and inspected.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The relief valve cartridge cannot be disassembled and must be replaced if bad.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The O-rings and strainer are replaceable and included as part of the complete seal kit.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never use old seals or O-rings. Use the complete seal kit.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>To install the relief valve cartridge in bearing cap, insert the cartridge assembly into the relief
                valve bore and tighten the valve nut to 35 ft-lbs. (47 Nm) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500274">Figure 74</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500274" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500274" filename="../figg05/g0500274.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 75. Insert Cartridge Assembly into Relief Valve Bore</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
