<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - DESCRIPTION - OPTIONAL
        INTEGRAL RELIEF VALVE SERVICING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPTIONAL INTEGRAL RELIEF VALVE SERVICING</title>
        <para>An optional integral pressure relief valve is offered with the Sheppard Series 5 steering gear. This valve
            is mounted externally on the steering gear and limits the maximum operating pressure in the steering system.
            In most cases the hydraulic supply pump will have a maximum relief pressure setting several hundred pounds
            higher than the relief valve integral with the steering gear. Therefore, when maximum relief pressures are
            reached in the steering system, the excess pressure is relieved at the steering gear and the supply pump is
            not subjected to high temperatures caused by normal pressure relief and recirculation within the supply
            pump.
        </para>
        <para>The optional pressure relief valve offered with the Sheppard Series 5 steering gear bolts externally to
            the steering gear housing and connects the high pressure supply circuit to the low pressure pinion gear area
            of the steering gear. When oil pressure exceeds the maximum relief pressure setting of the pilot operated
            relief valve, the valve opens and excess pressure is bled off into the oil return circuit through the pinion
            gear bore of the steering gear.
        </para>
        <para>One bolt and a square ring seal connect the exhaust side of the valve to the pinion gear housing of the
            steering gear.
        </para>
        <para>Two bolts and a square ring seal connect the high pressure side of the valve to the cylinder head of the
            steering gear.
        </para>
        <para>The valve is disassembled for cleaning and inspection by removing the valve end plug and withdrawing the
            relief valve and compensating spring.
        </para>
        <para>When the pressure relief valve is reassembled to the steering gear housing, it is important that attaching
            bolts are properly tightened to 20 to 30 ft-lbs. (27 to 41 Nm). The single bolt attaching the relief valve
            to the pinion housing of the gear must be installed and tightened to specifications first. The two bolts
            attaching the relief valve to the cylinder head are then installed and tightened. This procedure will avoid
            causing distortion which could lead to binding of the relief valve in its bore.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
