<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - ADJUSTMENTS - SWIVEL MITER
        AND T-BOX MITER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="4">
        <title>SWIVEL MITER AND T-BOX MITER</title>
        <para>The relief valve plunger used with the swivel and T-box miters uses an adjustable relief valve plunger.
            Access to this adjustment is gained by removing the two housing retaining clamps and lifting the housing off
            the steering gear bearing cap. To make the adjustment, the retaining clamp bars are re-installed and the
            bolts are tightened to specifications. Start the engine and turn the actuating shaft using a socket and
            ratchet on the actuating shaft nut. Use a screwdriver to turn the plunger in or out of the bearing cap until
            the proper clearance is obtained at the steering knuckle axle stop (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004d7">Figure 137</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004d7" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004d7" filename="../figg05/g05004d7.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 137. Obtain Proper Clearance at Steering Knuckle Axle Stop</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When the adjustment has been completed, stop the engine and re-install the miter housing at its original
            location (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004d8">Figure 138</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004d8" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004d8" filename="../figg05/g05004d8.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 138. Re-install Miter Housing at Original Location</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The miter housing in most cases will be indexed to the bearing cap with a roll pin which passes
                    through the clamping bar and enters a drilled hole in the miter housing. This ensures that the miter
                    housing is placed in its optimum position. The locating pin will also keep the housing from turning
                    in service. During reassembly, make sure that the locating pin is properly installed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f05004d9">Figure 139</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f05004d9" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004d9" filename="../figg05/g05004d9.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 139. Make Sure Locating Pin Properly Installed</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Re-tighten the actuating shaft nut to proper specifications as it may have loosened during the
                    adjustment procedures. Tighten the nut to 50 ft-lbs. (68 Nm) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f05004e0">Figure 140</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f05004e0" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004e0" filename="../figg05/g05004e0.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 140. Re-tighten Actuating Shaft Nut</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_40.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_42.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
