<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TRW MANUAL STEERING GEAR - ADJUSTMENTS - WORMING BEARING PRELOAD</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0501403" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WORMING BEARING PRELOAD</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measure Worm Bearing Preload</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly rotate input shaft to end of travel in either direction. Back off 1/4 of a
                    rotation and note backlash condition. There should be play (no contact) between output rollershaft
                    "roller" and input shaft "worm" gear teeth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the worm bearing preload by placing an in-lb. (Nm) torque wrench on the input
                    shaft. Torque required to rotate input shaft back and forth (oscillate) through 1/4 rotation at this
                    (no roller contact) lash position is:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Without input shaft (column) seal - 7 to 14 in-lbs. (0.8 to 1.6 Nm).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With input shaft (column) seal - 9 to 16 in-lbs. (1.0 to 1.8 Nm).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Integral long input shaft/steering wheel column type steering gears may not have input shaft
                        (column) seal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Procedure for Correcting Worm Bearing Preload</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove plug and drain lubricant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove worm cover bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove worm cover and input shaft seal if it is in worm cover. Discard seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shim pack and eliminate one shim at a time from the shim pack [normally a .002
                    inch (.05 mm) shim] to increase preload. The size of shim to remove depends on the amount of lash
                    detected. Do not remove .0075 inch (.191 mm) rubber-coated steel shims to adjust bearing preload.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The shims may be in five sizes: .002 inch (0.05 mm), .003 inch (0.08 mm), .005 inch (0.13
                            mm), .0075 inch (0.191 mm), .010 inch (0.25 mm), made of steel, paper, or rubber-coated
                            steel.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble worm cover, shims and worm cover bolts finger tight. Rubber-covered shims (if
                    applicable) must be assembled with the rubber-coated side against the housing and worm cover.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble new input shaft seal if seal was removed with worm cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be sure you have just a beginning (light) preload with cover bolts finger tight before
                        tightening cover bolts to specification.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten worm cover bolts to 45 to 55 ft-lbs. (61 to 75 Nm).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recheck preload. Repeat procedure with a different selection of shims if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501401.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
