<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - ASSEMBLE - INTEGRAL RESERVOIR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INTEGRAL RESERVOIR</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble new seals into the four grooves on the reservoir mounting pad (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500629">Figure 29</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500629" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="G0500629" filename="../figg05/g0500629.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 29. Integral Reservoir Seal Installation</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble a new O-ring into the groove on the reservoir stud.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note the four hole pattern in the bottom of the reservoir and reinforcement plate, and align
                holes with the pump reservoir pad, making certain that the intake vent is piloted into one hole and that
                all four seals remain in position. Assemble reservoir and reinforcement plate inside the reservoir to
                the body with two 5/16-18 bolts and one 3/4-16 stud.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Pilot the filter element onto the stud and push down over the seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the filter cap onto the 5/16-18 stud using care not to damage the sealing lip.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the filter stud through the filter I.D. and thread into the reservoir stud and
                tighten to 5 ft-lbs. (6.7 Nm). The filter cap must pilot and locate in the filter I.D. when properly
                assembled.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the filter relief spring over the stud and onto the filter cap.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the reservoir cover over the stud and compress the filter relief spring while
                assembling seal washer and wing nut onto stud.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align cover lip and reservoir O.D. to insure cover seal contact and tighten wing nut to 25
                in-lbs. (2.8 Nm). Replace filler cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the Woodruff drive key in the pump shaft. Make sure Woodruff key remains in shaft
                slot. Install the pulley or drive gear. The pulley or gear is a slip fit on the shaft except for the
                last 1/4 inch of engagement, which is a slight press fit. Use the pulley bolt and washer assembly to
                pull the pulley "home." Tighten pulley bolt to 20 ft-lbs. (27 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace O-ring seals onto pressure and return lines before attaching to pump.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
