<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMPS LUK VT73 AND LF93 - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>Periodic inspection of the fluid condition and tube or piping connections can save time-consuming
                breakdowns and unnecessary parts replacement. The following should be checked regularly.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All hydraulic connections must be kept tight. A loose connection in a pressure line will
                    permit the fluid to leak out. If the fluid becomes so low as to uncover the inlet pipe opening in
                    the reservoir, extensive damage to the pump may result. In suction or return lines, loose
                    connections permit air to be drawn into the system, resulting in noisy and/or erratic operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean fluid is the best insurance for long service life. Therefore, the reservoir should
                    be checked periodically for dirt or other contaminants. If the fluid becomes contaminated, the
                    system should be thoroughly drained and the reservoir cleaned before new fluid is added.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Filter elements also should be checked and replaced periodically. A clogged filter
                    element results in a higher pressure drop. This can force particles through the filter which would
                    ordinarily be trapped, or can cause the bypass to open, resulting in a partial or complete loss of
                    filtration.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A pump which is running excessively hot or noisy is a potential failure. Should a pump
                    become noisy or overheated, the machine should be shut down immediately and the cause of the
                    improper operation corrected.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
