<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - TROUBLESHOOTING - DIAGNOSIS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500408" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DIAGNOSIS</title>
        <para>The Sheppard integral power steering gear is dependent upon adequate supplies of oil pressure and volume
            of oil flow to enable the steering gear to operate as designed. Oil pressure reacting on a piston creates
            the force to cause the piston to move and assist steering effort.
        </para>
        <para>As the piston moves, it is displaced in the cylinder bore by a volume of oil under pressure. How fast the
            piston can be displaced is dependent upon adequate oil flow and volume.
        </para>
        <para>Oil pressure and oil flow requirements are engineering considerations that are established during the
            design of a total power steering installation. When diagnosing power steering problems, you must be able to
            determine that oil pressure and oil flow meet design specifications. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the
            CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>Back pressure and operating temperature are two additional factors that must be considered during the
            diagnosis of power steering problems. High back pressures will restrict the movement of the piston in the
            power steering gear and this back pressure must be overcome before steering power is available. Back
            pressure is caused by restrictions to oil flow. A clogged oil filter, undersized fittings and lines, pinched
            lines and high flow rates are possible causes of back pressure.
        </para>
        <para>High system oil temperatures reduce the overall efficiency of the steering pump and the steering gear.
            High temperatures are caused by restriction to flow or inadequate system oil capacity to allow for heat
            dissipation during normal operation. A supply pump which constantly operates at maximum pressure relief will
            also generate more heat than can be dissipated.
        </para>
        <para>Various types of pressure gauges and flow meters are available and can be used to diagnose power steering
            problems. A pressure gauge which reads at least 3000 psi and a flow meter with a capacity to 10 GPM are used
            to check pressures and oil flow. A shutoff valve downstream from the pressure gauge makes it possible to
            isolate the steering pump from the steering gear and by closing the valve, maximum pump relief pressure can
            be read.
        </para>
        <para>A simple thermometer in the reservoir will indicate system oil temperatures (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004e3">Figure 143</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004e3" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004e3" filename="../figg05/G05004E3.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 143. Thermometer in Reservoir Indicates System Oil Temperatures</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The gauge set illustrated (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05004e4">Figure 144</hotlnk>) will indicate pressure (psi) and flow (GPM) with a single
            connection in series with the high pressure line to the steering gear. A shutoff valve s included.
        </para>
        <figure id="f05004e4" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g05004e4" filename="../figg05/G05004E4.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 144. Gauge Set</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Using the equipment available to you, proceed with your evaluation of the hydraulic supply system. Refer
            to the
            <hotlnk document="s05004_46.xml" xrefid="hl0500412">TROUBLESHOOTING CHART
                <xref refid="hl0500412"/>
            </hotlnk>
            for further assistance.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make necessary gauge/meter connections.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start engine and check system oil level assuring that oil flow is in proper direction
                through the flow meter.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place thermometer in reservoir.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Run the engine at correct idle speed and steer from lock-to-lock several times to allow
                system to warm up (140 to 160 degrees F).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Pump maximum pressure relief.</emph>
                With the engine running at specified idle speed, slowly turn the shutoff valve until closed and read the
                pressure at which the pressure relief valve opens. (Open the shutoff valve as quickly as possible to
                avoid heat build-up or possible damage to the steering pump.) This pressure reading should equal the
                maximum pump pressure specified. Refer to GROUP 05 - STEERING in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for
                the type power steering pump used on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>A malfunctioning pressure relief valve may not relieve pump pressure and closing the shutoff
                        valve may cause severe pump damages or high pressure hoses to rupture. Constantly observe the
                        pressure gauge while closing the shutoff valve. If pressure rises rapidly or appears to be
                        uncontrolled, do not completely close the valve before inspecting the pump and pressure relief
                        valve.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Flow Test-Minimum Recommended Flow.</emph>
                With the engine running at a specified idle speed, vehicle stationary on the shop floor and with a
                normal load on the front axle, steer the wheels from full right to full left turn and observe the flow
                meter. The flow must not fall below the minimum GPM flow specification.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is important that flow be checked at normal operating temperature and with a load on the
                        front axle, or steering response complaints may not be found. Inadequate flow will cause
                        binding, uneven or intermittently hard steering.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Flow Test-Recommended Maximum</emph>. Increase the engine speed to approximately 1500
                RPM and note the flow rate with the steering wheel stationary. Check this reading against the maximum
                flow rate specifications. Excessive oil flow can cause high operating temperature, and sluggish heavy
                steering response.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Back Pressure. Normal system back pressure will be 50 to 75 psi with the engine idling and
                the steering wheel stationary. Back pressure is checked with the system at normal operating temperature.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Operating Temperatures</emph>. Steering system oil temperature is best checked after
                two hours of normal operation. Ideal operating temperature should range between 140 to 160 degrees F.
                Normal operation in this range will allow for intermittently higher temperatures which will be
                encountered during periods of heavy steering usage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Aerated Oil</emph>. Visually check for the presence of air mixed with the oil in the
                steering system. The oil should be clear. Any signs of frothing indicate air entry and steering
                performance will be affected. Carefully check for leakage on the suction side of the steering pump.
                Drain and refill the system and bleed for air following the procedure under
                <hotlnk document="s05004_38.xml" xrefid="hl0500409">BLEEDING AIR FROM SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl0500409"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Before any steering gear repairs are attempted, the above hydraulic supply evaluation must be completed
            and corrections made as required. Many times steering gears have been repaired or replaced needlessly
            because a hydraulic supply system evaluation had not been made.
        </para>
        <para>Additional references to pressure and flow testing are made in the
            <hotlnk document="s05004_46.xml" xrefid="hl0500412">TROUBLESHOOTING CHART
                <xref refid="hl0500412"/>
            </hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_48.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_50.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
