<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - SET RELIEF PLUNGERS - Service Procedure</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Service Procedure</title>
        <para>Anytime tire size or steering gears are changed, relief plunger adjustment will be necessary. A relief
            plunger is located in each end cap of the steering gear. One for right turn; one for left turn.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Never attempt to adjust relief plungers until axle stops are set. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLE,
                    General Information and Wheel Alignment section, in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the
                    procedure to set axle stops.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a clean, dry, solid surface, preferably concrete. Set the parking brake
                and block the wheels.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the transmission in neutral and start the engine.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow the engine to operate at idle speed.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is always best to have 2 people when setting plungers: 1 to steer the vehicle and 1 to set
                        and check adjustments.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the plungers.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Determine which plunger is used to adjust right and left turns based on direction of pitman
                arm travel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel to a full left turn and check the clearance using the steel flat
                stock as a feeler gauge between the axle stop bolt and the axle. If the clearance is not 1/8 inch (3.2
                mm), plunger adjustment will be necessary.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the stop bolt hits the axle under pressure, release the wheel immediately! Damage to
                        steering components may result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Return the front tires to the straight ahead position and release the steering wheel. Use
                the screwdriver to adjust the plunger for left turn. Turning the plunger in will increase the clearance
                between the stop bolt and the axle, while turning the plunger out will decrease the clearance.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never adjust the plunger beyond flush with the end cap. Leakage or personal injury may
                        result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel to a full left turn. Check the 1/8 inch (3.2 mm) clearance using the
                steel flat stock as a feeler gauge.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The flat stock is used as a feeler gauge only. Do not squeeze or pinch the flat stock between
                        the stop bolt and axle. Damage to parts may result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If further adjustment is required, repeat steps 7 and 8 until the 1/8 inch (3.2 mm)
                clearance is achieved.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat steps 6 thru 9 for the right turn.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500206.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
