<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - DUAL STEERING SYSTEM - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Pressure to operate the secondary or slave gear is passed through ports in either the cylinder head,
            sector shaft bore or bearing cap of the master gear. It is routed through high pressure lines to the proper
            end of the slave gear. When the actuating shaft of the master gear is moved, it causes a pressure build up
            on the piston of the master gear. This same pressure is directed to the opposite end of the slave gear
            piston (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05002a3">Figure 103</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05002a4">Figure 104</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f05002a3" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g05002a3" filename="../figg05/g05002a3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Figure 104. Typical Dual M-Series Steering Gear Layout</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f05002a4" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g05002a4" filename="../figg05/g05002a4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Figure 105. M-Series Master Gear</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05002a3">Figure 103</hotlnk>
            illustrates a typical dual M-Series steering gear layout. Fluid from the slave gear is returned to the
            master gear and back to the reservoir. The lines between the master gear and slave gear act as both pressure
            and return lines.
        </para>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f05002a4">Figure 104</hotlnk>
            illustrates an M-Series master gear and an older style M-292, M-392, or M-492 Series slave gear used in a
            dual steering gear installation. Fluid from the master gear is routed through the pinion gear area of the
            slave gear and then to the reservoir. This system requires the use of more hoses than the dual M-Series
            system.
        </para>
        <para>Pressure relief plungers are not required on slave gears. Pressure relief is in the master gear.</para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Bleeding of the dual system is critical whenever the oil has been changed, the system has been
                    opened, or whenever a steering gear is replaced. Follow the dual system bleeding procedures outlined
                    under
                    <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500210.xml" xrefid="hl0500210">BLEEDING, DUAL STEERING GEARS</hotlnk>.
                    Failure to bleed the steering system could result in an accident, injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
