<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING PUMP: EATON MODEL BB135 R, L - DISASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="11">
        <title>DISASSEMBLE</title>
        <para>Before disassembly of pump, remove reservoir filler cap and drain oil from reservoir by inverting the pump
            so oil may drain out the filler neck.
        </para>
        <para>After oil is drained from reservoir, cap should be replaced and the entire pump assembly washed in a
            non-toxic solvent to remove all dirt and prevent any foreign matter from contaminating pump components.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Examine exposed part of drive shaft. If it is corroded, use crocus cloth to remove corrosion
                    before disassembling pump. This will prevent damage to the shaft bushing which might require
                    replacement of the entire housing.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place pump in a bench vise using the mounting (gear driven pump) or mounting bracket (belt
                driven pump) to hold pump.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not clamp on the pump, reservoir or pulley.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Remove bolt and washers for retaining pulley or drive gear. Remove pulley or drive gear with universal
                three-arm puller. Remove Woodruff key from shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove spring loaded reservoir cover, wing nut and washer. Remove and discard gasket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove filter relief spring. Remove and discard filter cap and filter.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unscrew 5/16 inch cover stud.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove 1-1/8 inch hex reservoir stud. Remove and discard seal on stud (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500604">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500604" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500604" filename="../figg05/G0500604.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Stud Seal Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. STUD, RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SEAL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove 5/16 inch thread bolts and reinforcement plate from inside reservoir. Remove
                reservoir and discard seals from the pump reservoir mounting pad.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all reservoir components except filter and seals with a mineral spirit solvent.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen but do not remove 1-1/4 inch hex valve cap.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen but do not remove 3/8-16 bolts attaching bracket and/or pump body to cover (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500605">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Note bracket position for reassembly.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500605" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g05006005" filename="../figg05/G0500605.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Loosening Bracket Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove pump assembly from vise and then remove loosened bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a stable block or the pulley or flange previously removed, loosely piloted onto the pump
                shaft to steady the pump base for continued disassembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500606">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500606" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500606" filename="../figg05/G0500606.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Using Pulley As Base</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully remove cover casting by pulling and gently tapping cover casting (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500607">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Use caution not to allow pumping element components to be
                removed with cover.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500607" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500607" filename="../figg05/G0500607.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Cover Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove 1-1/4 inch hex valve cap and discard O-ring. Remove valve spring and combination
                (flow control and relief) valve from cover casting by shaking or gently striking the casting on a wood
                or padded surface. Do not use metal tools or instruments which may cause valve bore damage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove and discard body face seals (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500608">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500608" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500608" filename="../figg05/G0500608.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Body and Face Seal Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SEALS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully remove roller vanes from exposed pumping element in bay pocket (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500609">Figure 9</hotlnk>). This is best accomplished by using a clean magnet but
                demagnetize parts after using one. Do not use pliers or similar tools which may raise a burr.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500609" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500609" filename="../figg05/G0500609.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Roller Vane Removal</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The position and "UP" side of all remaining internal components must now be noted and marked
                        for reference at reassembly. Any marking method must not damage any surface. Use dye or other
                        semi-permanent marker.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the carrier by sliding it out over the exposed shaft end (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500610">Figure 10</hotlnk>). On gear driven pumps, carrier and shaft are held together
                by snap rings. Remove both as a complete unit. Make sure any gear drive key has been removed prior to
                shaft/carrier removal from body.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500610" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500610" filename="../figg05/G0500610.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Carrier Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove carrier drive key from shaft keyway.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Record and/or mark position of locating pin, cam (note the reference arrow direction), port
                plate, and end plate for reassembly reference.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the cam ring, locating pin, port plate, and end plate by sliding parts out of the
                pump body pocket. Note position of stacked end plate seals for reassembly. Then remove end plate seals
                from end plate pockets and save for possible reuse (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500611">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500611" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500611" filename="../figg05/G0500611.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. End Plate Seal Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. END PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SEAL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the shaft-bearing sub-assembly on pulley driven pumps by making certain the carrier
                drive key has been removed, and displacing the bearing snap ring retainer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500612">Figure 12</hotlnk>). Slide shaft and bearing out of the body casting (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500613">Figure 13</hotlnk>). Light tapping on the shaft end may be required. DO NOT
                use excessive force since bearing damage may result.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500612" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500612" filename="../figg05/G0500612.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Snap Ring Retainer Removal</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0500613" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500613" filename="../figg05/G0500613.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Shaft and Bearing Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the flange (and bearing assembly) on direct drive pumps by removing the three 3/8-16
                Allen head bolts and lockwashers. If required, carefully scrape gasket and sealant from the flange/pump
                mating surfaces.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully remove the shaft oil seal in the body casting, being careful not to damage the
                shaft bushing. A small diameter punch placed against the seal from the cam pocket side may be used to
                drive the seal out of the bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0500614">Figure 14</hotlnk>). Some direct drive pumps may have two opposite facing oil
                seals.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0500614" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500614" filename="../figg05/G0500614.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Shaft Seal Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05006w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
