<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING PUMP: VICKERS (LUK) V10NF AND V20NF - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>A thorough and orderly troubleshooting procedure will help you diagnose power steering troubles
                quickly. Troubles occur in many places, show up in various ways; but with this procedure, you can
                eliminate many possibilities immediately, narrow down the cause of trouble, then make correct repairs
                promptly.
            </para>
            <para>We have arranged the troubleshooting procedure into three steps:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Define the complaint.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>External inspection.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hydraulic system check.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>This procedure is an overall one. By following it step by step, you should be able to identify nearly
                every trouble which may occur in a hydraulic power steering system.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DEFINE THE COMPLAINT</title>
            <para>The first step is to define the complaint. Properly identifying the complaint will let you eliminate
                many possible causes at once.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When a driver brings in his truck with a complaint, ask him to explain the trouble in
                    his own words. (Sometimes a driver expects easier steering than his system is designed to give.)
                    Make notes of his comments, look the system over for obvious defects. You may spot such things as
                    uneven tire wear, evidence of leakage or a frame out of line. Determine the type and arrangement of
                    the power steering system.
                </para>
                <para>Here are some sample questions you should ask the driver:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">How does the steering act?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Does it act this way all the time?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Does it occur in only one direction?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Under what conditions does it usually occur?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Is it accompanied by unusual noises?</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If after talking with the driver you are still unable to define the complaint, ask him
                    to accompany you and drive the vehicle yourself.
                </para>
                <para>Observe steering action, think, visualize the system in operation.</para>
                <para>Perform actions in which the driver said condition occurred; try other steering actions too, to
                    give you a complete and accurate definition of the trouble.
                </para>
                <para>You may want to try these steering actions:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn steering wheel while standing or moving slowly. (Standing with vehicle loaded,
                        hydraulic power may not be sufficient.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Steer in both directions while moving.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn steering wheel rapidly one or two turns in both directions.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Observe action when traveling straight ahead.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
