<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TRW MANUAL STEERING GEAR - ASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>All components must be clean and well lubricated before assembling, preferably with an SAE No. 90
                lubricant.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be extremely careful when using any solvent to prevent personal injury or even death.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear eye protection and be sure to comply with OSHA or other maximum air pressure requirements
                        when using compressed air to blow components dry.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
            <title>WORM AND HOUSING ASSEMBLY</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble roller retainer assembly into bearing cup in housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert worm and input shaft assembly in housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place other roller bearing retainer assembly in place on worm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert worm bearing adjusting cup in housing bore.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select an assortment of steel and paper shims sandwiched between two .0075 inch (0.191
                    mm) rubber-coated shims with the rubber-coated sides out, to make a shim pack that will achieve the
                    correct worm bearing preload as stated in
                    <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501403.xml" xrefid="hl0501403">WORM BEARING PRELOAD</hotlnk>. This is
                    strictly a judgment and trial and error procedure. Assemble the shim pack, worm cover, and worm
                    cover screws. Tighten cover bolts finger tight.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble a new input shaft seal into housing or worm cover as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not final tighten cover bolts immediately. Rotate input shaft assembly with one hand while
                        slowly tightening bolts with the other hand to prevent damaging the bearing surfaces if the
                        initial amount of shims selected is inadequate.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add or remove shims as necessary to achieve a beginning (light) preload, felt as a
                    change in resistance to input shaft rotation, with the cover bolts finger tight. Final tighten worm
                    cover bolts to 45 to 55 ft-lbs. (61 to 75 Nm). Then, using a torque wrench on the input shaft, check
                    for correct worm bearing preload values:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Without input shaft (column) seal - 7 to 14 in-lbs. (0.8 to 1.6 Nm).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With input shaft (column) seal - 9 to 16 in-lbs. (1.0 to 1.8 Nm).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always recheck preload after final tightening of cover bolts.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
