<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - BLEEDING - DUAL STEERING GEARS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0501510" svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DUAL STEERING GEARS</title>
        <para>Bleeding the dual steering gear system is necessary whenever the system has been repaired or steering
            fluid has been replaced. Different gear sizes may be used together but the bleeding procedure is the same.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a clean, dry, solid surface, preferably concrete. Set the parking brake
                and block the wheels. Place the transmission in neutral. Make sure the engine is OFF.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Jack the vehicle up until the front wheels have cleared the surface. Set the front axle on
                floor stands.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                        performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle
                        with floor stands.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tilt the hood or cab.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the fluid level in the reservoir is at the full mark on the dipstick.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the drag links from the pitman arms of the master and slave gear. Refer to GROUP 05 -
                STEERING in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the correct procedure to remove the drag link for the
                vehicle being serviced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the vehicle and allow engine to idle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel to a full left turn and hold until the slave gear moves its full
                travel. Then turn the steering wheel to a full right turn and hold until the slave moves its full
                travel. Repeat this procedure three or more times.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the drag link to the master gear. Tighten the attaching nut to specifications in
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0501502">Table 2</hotlnk>following:
            </para>
            <table id="t0501502">
                <title>Dual Steering Gear Drag Link Nut Torque Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Stud Size</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Ft-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3/4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to 105</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>116 to 143</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7/8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>120 to 160</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>163 to 218</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not back off the nut when locating the cotter pin hole.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new cotter pin through the ball stud nut, then lock in place.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to install a new cotter pin in the ball stud after proper torque could result in an
                        accident, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the master gear drag link connected, turn the steering wheel to a full left turn and
                hold until the slave gear pitman arm moves its full travel. Then turn the steering wheel to a full right
                and hold until the slave gear pitman arm moves its full travel. Repeat this procedure three or more
                times.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the drag link to the slave gear by turning the steering wheel until the pitman lines
                up with drag link.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not move the pitman arm by hand during this operation. Air may get in the system.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the attaching nut to the specifications in
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0501503">Table 3</hotlnk>
                following:
            </para>
            <table id="t0501503">
                <title>Master Gear Drag Link Nut Torque Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Stud Size</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Ft-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3/4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to 105</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>116 to 143</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7/8</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>120 to 160</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>163 to 218</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not back off the nut when locating the cotter pin hole.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a new cotter pin through the ball stud nut, then lock in place.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to install a new cotter pin in the ball stud and nut after proper torque could result
                        in an accident, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Steer the vehicle full left to full right several more times.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the bleeder screw in the master gear located in the plug on the sector shaft bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0501547">Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0501547" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg05/g0500232.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Locate Bleeder Screw</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use an AlIen wrench to open the bleeder screw until a non-aerated fluid flows from the bleed
                screw.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not turn the steering wheel with the bleeder open.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat the procedure on the slave gear if an M-Series slave is used.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the fluid level in the power steering reservoir and fill if necessary.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shut the vehicle off.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the hood or cab.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the vehicle and remove the floor stands. Lower the vehicle until the tires contact the
                surface.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_X0501514.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y_X0501506.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05015y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
