<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - INPUT SHAFT SEAL REPLACEMENT BEFORE JULY
        1990
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="4">
        <title>INPUT SHAFT SEAL REPLACEMENT BEFORE JULY 1990</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Production prior to July 1990 - the input bearing cap will not have a grease fitting.</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not remove the steering gear for this procedure.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Before a seal can be replaced, you must identify the manufacturing date of the steering gear. This can
                be done by following the
                <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500207.xml" xrefid="hl0500207">steering gear identification
                    procedure</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to replace all seals, cotter pins, retainers and critical fasteners may result in an
                        accident, injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a clean, dry, solid surface, preferably concrete. Set the parking
                    brake and block the wheels. Place the transmission in neutral. Make sure the engine is OFF.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the hood or cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the pinch bolt on the lower end yoke of the steering shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the lower yoke from the steering gear input shaft. If necessary, secure the
                    steering shaft so it will not be in the way.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Do not pull the slip shaft out of the steering shaft. This would require re-phasing at
                            time of installation.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the drain pan under the power steering gear. Draining the system is not necessary,
                    but some fluid will be lost.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a ratchet and 15 or 16 mm socket to loosen and remove the 4 bearing cap cover bolts
                    and cover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500215">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0500215" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500215" filename="../figg05/g0500215.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Loosen and Remove Bearing Cap Cover Bolts</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not turn the input shaft during repairs. Turning the shaft or mixing components will cause
                        damage to the bearing cap and actuating shaft assembly.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The thrust washer may stick to the bearing cap cover. If this happens, re-install the thrust
                        washer in the steering gear (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0500216">Figure 16</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0500217">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0500216" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500216" filename="../figg05/g0500216.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Re-Install Thrust Washer in Steering Gear</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0500217" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500217" filename="../figg05/g0500217.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Re-Install Thrust Washer in Steering Gear</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discard the cover as a new type will be used.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of the teflon ring and energizer ring from the shaft is optional.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a light coat of white grease or similar substance to the input shaft and install
                    the cover. Make sure the plunger hole lines up.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The input shaft seal and cover O-ring are installed prior to shipment.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Slide the new cover on the shaft slowly to avoid damage to the seal.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the four (4) 10 x 1.5 mm mounting bolts and tighten to 53 to 63 ft-lbs. (72 to
                    85 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the instruction sheet with the kit and select the proper diameter salt seal. Slide
                    the salt seal over the shaft and push it into the seal bore with your fingers. Make sure the lip of
                    the seal is facing out (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500218">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0500218" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0500218" filename="../figg05/g0500218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Make Sure Lip of Seal is Facing Out</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the lower yoke of the steering shaft on the steering gear. Make sure the
                    pinch bolt hole in the yoke lines up with the whistle notch on the input shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the pinch bolt and nut and tighten. Refer to GROUP 05 - STEERING in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual for the proper torque value for the vehicle and type of column being service.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a hand grease gun to pump a small amount of grease into the grease fitting until
                    grease can be seen coming out around the salt seal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the fluid level in the power steering reservoir; make sure it is full.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean any fluid from the power steering gear and remove the drain pan.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the cab or hood.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
