<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING PUMP: VICKERS (LUK) V10NF AND V20NF - OPERATION - FLOW CONTROL AND
        RELIEF VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FLOW CONTROL AND RELIEF VALVE</title>
        <para>Maximum flow to the operating circuit and maximum system pressure are determined by the integral flow
            control and relief valve in a special outlet cover used on some V10 and V20 series pumps. This feature is
            shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500506">Figure 6</hotlnk>. An orifice in the cover limits maximum flow (View A,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500506">Figure 6</hotlnk>). A pilot-operated type relief shifts to divert excess fluid
            delivery to the tank, thus limiting system pressure to a prescribed maximum.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500506" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500506" filename="../figg05/g0500506.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 6. Flow Control and Relief Valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. LIGHT SPRING HOLDS RELIEF VALVE CLOSED WHEN PRESSURE IS EQUAL ON BOTH SIDES</callout1>
                <callout1>2. PILOT POPPET</callout1>
                <callout1>3. TO TANK</callout1>
                <callout1>4. SPOOL BLOCKS TANK PORT OFF</callout1>
                <callout1>5. RELIEF VALVE SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. DELIVERY FROM PUMPING CARTRIDGE</callout1>
                <callout1>7. ORIFICE DETERMINES FLOW RATE</callout1>
                <callout1>8. PRESSURE PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>9. SYSTEM PRESSURE SENSED IN SPRING CHAMBER THROUGH ORIFICE</callout1>
                <callout1>10. EXCESS FLUID THROTTLED PAST VALVE TO TANK</callout1>
                <callout1>11. PRESSURE IN SPRING CHAMBER LOWER THAN SYSTEM DUE TO PRESSURE DROP ACROSS SENSING ORIFICE
                </callout1>
                <callout1>12. SENSING ORIFICE</callout1>
                <callout1>13. POPPET FORCED OFF SEAT AS RELIEF VALVE SETTING IS REACHED</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>View A of
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500506">Figure 6</hotlnk>
            shows the condition when the total pump delivery can be passed through the orifice. This condition usually
            occurs only at low drive speeds.The large spring chamber is connected to the pressure port through an
            orifice. Pressure in this chamber equalizes pressure at the other end of the relief valve spool and the
            light spring holds the spool closed. Pump delivery is blocked from the tank port by the spool land.
        </para>
        <para>When the pump delivery is more than the flow rate determined by the orifice plug, a pressure build-up
            forces the spool open against the light spring. Excess fluid is throttled past the spool to the tank port as
            shown in View B,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500506">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>If pressure in the system builds up to the relief valve setting, (View C,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500506">Figure 6</hotlnk>), the pilot ppet is forced off its seat. Fluid in the large
            spring chamber flows through the spool and out to the tank. This flow through the small sensing orifice
            causes a pressure drop and prevents pressure in the large spring area from increasing beyond the relief
            valve setting. As pressure against the right end of the spool starts to exceed the relief valve setting, the
            pressure differential forces the spool to the left, against the light spring, porting the full pump flow to
            the tank.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05005s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
