<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD M-SERIES - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - CLEANING RELIEF VALVE SEATS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="5">
        <title>CLEANING RELIEF VALVE SEATS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not remove the steering gear for this procedure.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the driver complains of lack of power or hard steering in one direction, there is contamination
                under the plunger relief ball. The contamination will have to be removed before power steering can be
                restored.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a clean, dry, solid surface. Set the parking brake, block the rear
                    wheels and place the transmission in neutral.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the front end of the vehicle until the tires have cleared the surface, using the
                    hydraulic jack. Set the front axle on floor stands.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the drain pan under the steering gear to catch the fluid from the system.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Remove the pressure line from the center of the cap on dual steering systems (if
                            equipped).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make a reference mark on the end cap and a matching mark on the housing. Use the proper
                    size socket and ratchet to remove the four attaching bolts from the cylinder head end cap (the end
                    opposite the input shaft.) Remove the end cap.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Fluid will drain from the steering gear when the end cap is removed.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Be careful not to bend or break the plunger in the end cap.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly turn steering shaft until the steering gear piston comes to within 1 inch (25 mm)
                    of e open end of steering gear housing.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not allow any foreign material to enter the steering gear housing. Steering will be
                            affected and damage to the gear may result.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the Allen head valve seat in the end of the steering gear piston. Remove the seat
                    using an AlIen wrench (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500210">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500210" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500210" filename="../figg05/G0500210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Remove Allen Head Valve Seat</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Slight spring tension will be present. Care must be taken to prevent injury and loss of
                            parts. Always wear safety glasses.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When seat is removed, the plunger ball, spring, plastic insert and the plunger ball from
                    the opposite end of the piston will come out of the passage (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500211">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500211" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500211" filename="../figg05/G0500211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Plunger Ball, Spring, and Plastic Insert</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Depending on steering gear mounting, a magnet may be needed to remove the relief ball from
                            the passage.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a bottle brush large enough in diameter to clean the bore into the passage and
                    move it back and forth while turning it to clean the passage after the fluid has drained (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500212">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500212" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500212" filename="../figg05/G0500212.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Clean Bore in Passage</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If heavy contamination is present, find and fix the source of contaminants. Flush the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all removed parts in an approved fluid and blow dry using low pressure air.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Always wear safety glasses and use only low pressure air to clean parts.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the parts in the relief passage. Install one relief ball, the spring with
                    insert, the remaining relief ball and Allen seat. Use an Allen wrench to tighten the seat until it
                    bottoms (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500213">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500213" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500213" filename="../figg05/G0500213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Tighten Seat Until It Bottoms</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>It will be necessary to compress the spring during assembly. Use care to insure parts are
                            not lost during assembly. Always wear safety glasses to avoid injuries.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the end cap and attaching bolts; be sure to align the reference marks (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0500214">Figure 14</hotlnk>). Tighten the attaching bolts to 35 ft-lbs. (47 Nm).
                    Connect the pressure line in the center of the cap for dual steering systems (if equipped).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0500214" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0500214" filename="../figg05/G0500214.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Install End Cap and Attaching Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Be careful not to damage the plunger during reassembly.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the reservoir to the proper level. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500209.xml" xrefid="hl0500209">TYPES OF FLUID</hotlnk>
                    for the correct type of fluid for the model vehicle being serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the front axle and remove the floor stands. Slowly lower the front tires onto the
                    surface. Remove the jack and drain pan.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the transmission in neutral and start the vehicle. Allow it to idle while the
                    fluid circulates.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the system using the procedures listed in
                    <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500210.xml" xrefid="hl0500210">BLEEDING</hotlnk>
                    (Dual system only).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and refill the reservoir as needed.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>No plunger adjustment is necessary unless the adjustment was changed during disassembly or
                        reassembly. If it was changed, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s05002y_HL0500206.xml" xrefid="hl0500206">SET RELIEF PLUNGERS</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05002y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
