<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TRW MANUAL STEERING GEAR - ASSEMBLE - ROLLERSHAFT, SHAFT COVER AND HOUSING ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ROLLERSHAFT, SHAFT COVER AND HOUSING ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert adjusting screw into shaft cover from the bearing side of cover and draw rollershaft
                into the bearing until the shaft bottoms in the shaft cover, then reverse adjusting screw rotation one
                full turn.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position new gasket on shaft cover and insert the output shaft assembly with gasket and
                cover into housing and into mesh with worm. Align housing, gasket and cover bolt holes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To align a shaft cover that does not require alignment dowels, first assemble two shaft
                cover bolts with flat washers under the bolt heads, one in the top and bottom of the cover. Tighten the
                bolts snugly [3 to 5 ft-lbs. (4 to 7 Nm)]. Carefully assemble new shaft seal. Alternately rotate the
                INPUT SHAFT to 1/4 revolution from each end of travel. Lash must be present in each position. An OUTPUT
                SHAFT torque of 6 in-lbs. (0.7 Nm) or less must rotate the output shaft when in the lash positions with
                no perceptible binding. If a no-lash (a binding) condition exists at either or both of the stated lash
                positions, return the output shaft to center of travel position. Tap the edge of the shaft cover with a
                mallet to move the cover up or down, left or right. Then repeat the alignment checking procedure. Repeat
                the cover tapping and alignment check procedures until alignment is achieved. Then tighten the two cover
                bolts already in the assembly to approximately the final torque specification. Assemble the other cover
                bolts and tighten them to 45 to 55 ft-lbs. (61 to 75 Nm). Remove the two bolts that have the washers and
                reassemble them without the washers and tighten to 45 to 55 ft-lbs. (61 to 75 Nm). Again check the lash
                conditions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To align a reassembled shaft cover that requires alignment dowels, assemble all cover bolts
                and tighten finger tight. Install both dowels and drive dowels in for shaft cover alignment until 1/4 of
                each dowel is above the cover dowel boss. Tighten cover bolts to 45 to 55 ft-lbs. (61 to 75 Nm). Drive
                in both dowels flush with shaft cover. If the dowel fit is loose, reference procedure for installing
                oversize dowels per
                <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501402.xml" xrefid="hl0501402">REPAIR</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To install a new shaft cover that requires alignment dowels, follow Step 3 for aligning a
                shaft cover without dowels. When the cover bolts are tightened to specified final torque, and the proper
                alignment is achieved, ream through housing and shaft cover per
                <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501402.xml" xrefid="hl0501402">REPAIR</hotlnk>, and install the appropriate
                size dowels.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully press in new rollershaft seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble O-ring and adjusting screw locknut.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Follow the
                <hotlnk document="s05014_HL0501401.xml" xrefid="hl0501401">OUTPUT ROLLERSHAFT OR TOTAL MESH</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill gear housing to the proper lube level with the recommended lubricant. Refer to GROUP 10
                - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble filler and/or vent plugs.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
