<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>POWER STEERING GEAR: TRW/ROSS-TAS 40, 55, 65 AND 85 - ADJUST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0500321">
        <title>ADJUST</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>For this procedure to work correctly, you must have: a new gear or a used gear on which poppet seats
                have been replaced or reset during gear disassembly procedures. Also: fixed stop screw installed in
                housing or poppet adjusting screw installed so that it duplicates fixed stop screw length.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The axle stops and all steering linkage must be set according to specifications, and the
                        pitman arm must be correctly aligned on the sector shaft for poppets to be set correctly. Refer
                        to GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL INFORMATION AND ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine at idle and the vehicle unloaded, turn steering wheel to full travel in
                    one direction until axle stop contact is made. Maximum input torque to be applied during this
                    procedure is 40 lbs. (178 N) rim pull on a 20 inch (508mm) diameter steering wheel.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If you encounter excess rim pull effort, allow vehicle to roll forward or jack up the
                            vehicle at the front axle.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow the same procedure while turning the steering wheel in the other direction. The
                    poppets are now positioned to trip and reduce pressure as the steered wheels approach the axle stops
                    in either direction.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_HL0500319.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05003y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
