<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERIES 6 OPTIONAL INTEGRAL PISTON RELIEF VALVE</title>
            <para>An optional integral pressure relief valve is offered with the Sheppard Series 6 steering gear. This
                valve is mounted internally in the piston and limits the maximum operating pressure in the steering
                system. In most cases, the hydraulic supply pump will have a maximum relief pressure setting several
                hundred pounds higher than the relief valve integral with the steering gear.
            </para>
            <para>Therefore, when maximum relief pressures are reached in the steering system, the excess pressure is
                relieved at the steering gear and the supply pump is not subjected to high temperatures caused by normal
                pressure relief and recirculation within the supply pump.
            </para>
            <para>The optional pressure relief valve offered with the Sheppard Series 6 steering gear is an integral
                part of the piston. When oil pressure exceeds the maximum relief pressure setting of the pilot operated
                relief valve, the valve opens and excess pressure is bled off into the oil return circuit through the
                pinion gear bore of the steering gear.
            </para>
            <para>The valve is disassembled for cleaning and inspection by removing the valve end plug and withdrawing
                the relief valve and compensating spring. To remove the end plug, it will be necessary to drill out the
                locking pin.
            </para>
            <para>When the pressure relief valve is reassembled in the piston, re-align end plug with the locking pin
                hole after inserting the relief valve and compensating spring into the relief valve bore. Install a new
                locking pin to re-secure the end plug.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the test procedures for the
                <hotlnk document="s05004_37.xml" xrefid="hl0500401">INTEGRAL RELIEF VALVE
                    <xref refid="hl0500401"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
