<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - POWER STEERING GEAR: SHEPPARD MODEL 292, 392, 492 - REASSEMBLE - TAPERED VALVE
        POSITIONING PIN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0500403" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TAPERED VALVE POSITIONING PIN</title>
        <para>All Series 5 and 6 gears are equipped with tapered valve positioning pins. Late model Series 3 and 4
            pistons also use a tapered valve positioning pin, which is adjustable. These pistons can be identified by
            the piston plug which uses seal rings (
            <hotlnk document="s05004_25.xml" xrefid="f0500486">Figure 86</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <para>The valve positioning pin, which locates and guides the actuating valve in the piston of the Series 5
            gear, is tapered. This tapered valve positioning pin must be adjusted when the piston is reassembled.
            Install a new O-ring seal on the valve positioning pin and screw it into the piston until it is flush with
            the surface of the piston (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500487">Figure 87</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500487" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500487" filename="../figg05/G0500487.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 87. Install New O-Ring Seal on Valve Positioning Pin</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Make reference marks with a pencil on the piston and the pin and then install the actuating valve in the
            piston, lining up the long guide slot in the valve with the guide pin. When the valve positioning pin has
            entered the valve and the valve has bottomed, check the valve for radial movement and freedom of movement
            over the valve positioning pin (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500488">Figure 88</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500488" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500488" filename="../figg05/G0500488.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 88. Make Reference Marks on Piston and Pin</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The valve positioning pin is adjusted 1/4 turn at a time until the valve has no radial movement and slides
            smoothly over the valve positioning pin (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0500489">Figure 89</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0500489" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0500489" filename="../figg05/G0500489.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 89. Valve Positioning Pin Adjusted 1/4 Turn at a Time</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Each time the valve positioning pin is adjusted, the actuating valve will have to be pulled out of the
            piston far enough to disengage the valve positioning pin. When the valve positioning pin is properly
            adjusted, complete assembly of the piston as previously detailed for Series 5 steering gears.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s05004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
