<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: LEECE NEVILLE AND PRESTOLITE JN SERIES - REASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0802003" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="7">
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If slip ring end bearing has been removed, press a new bearing in place from the outside of
                the housing. Bearing should be installed with seal facing in toward slip rings. When properly installed,
                the manufacturer's part number stamped on the end of the bearing will be facing toward the outside of
                the housing.
            </para>
            <para>Press new roller bearing in bearing bore to dimension shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802020">Figure 20</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802020" filename="../figg08/g0802020.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Slip Ring End Housing</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall heat sinks in slip ring end housing. Be sure that upper and lower insulating
                washers are in their proper location. Install, but do not tighten, lower heat sink retaining screws,
                lockwashers, guard washers and insulating washers (
                <hotlnk document="s08020_5.xml" xrefid="f0802007">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Replacement heat sinks may differ
                in thickness or appearance from the original assemblies, but will fit and function interchangeably.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0802021">Figure 21</hotlnk>for installation of insulation bushings on 145 and
                        160 amp alternators.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0802021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802021" filename="../figg08/g0802021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Installation of Insulation Bushings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEAT SINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOCKWASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. GUARD WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INSULATION WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. INSULATION BUSHING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install terminal bolts and regulator lead wires. Red wire goes on positive heat sink and
                black wire goes on negative. WHITE GOES TO THE CENTER STATOR CONNECTION. Be sure that mating surfaces of
                heat sinks, terminals and terminal bolts are clean and free of paint to insure a good electrical
                connection (
                <hotlnk document="s08020_5.xml" xrefid="f0802005">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install two insulating bushings on each terminal bolt and install regulator housing. Be sure
                that red and black regulator leads are properly routed through cutaway section of end housing, and
                install and tighten nuts on terminal bolts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802022">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802022" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802022" filename="../figg08/g0802022.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Insulating Bushings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TEST PLATE #1</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TEST PLATE #2</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TERMINAL #3</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Newer alternators are internally grounded and do not use an insulator bushing in the NEGATIVE
                        output terminal hole. The Slip Ring End housing in these units have a raised surface around the
                        NEGATIVE output terminal hole (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0802023">Figure 23</hotlnk>). Before assembly, apply a coat of electrical joint
                        compound to the raised surface around the NEGATIVE output terminal hole.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0802023" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802023" filename="../figg08/g0802023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Raised Surface Around Negative Output Terminal Hole</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten lower heat sink screws and check all leads for proper routing, being sure that no
                lead is pinched under heat sink.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install stator, slide a stator terminal on each of the three AC studs and secure with the
                10-32 tenz nuts (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802024">Figure 24</hotlnk>). It is advisable to align the stator and housing by
                temporarily installing the through bolts.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802024" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802024" filename="../figg08/g0802024.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Mask Roller Bearing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AC STUDS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MASKING TAPE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mask roller bearing with masking tape and paint all internal electrical connections with
                Westinghouse B-6-665 Red Air Dry Epoxy paint (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802024">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press drive end bearing into housing and reinstall bearing retainer and four screws. When
                installing bearing, press on outer race to avoid transmitting force through the bearing balls which
                could brinnel the bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press drive end housing and bearing onto rotor shaft. Using a sleeve around the shaft, press
                on the inner race to avoid brinnelling the bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install rotor and housing assembly into stator and slip ring end housing assembly, being
                sure that mounting lugs are aligned.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install three through bolts and self locking nuts. Tighten to 50 to 60 in-lbs. (5.6 to 6.8 N&#8226;m).
                Place a small amount of grease (Chevron SRI 2 or equivalent) in housing and reinstall the metal dust cap
                by carefully pressing it into place.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert outer brush and spring assembly into housing and compress the brush spring with a
                small screwdriver or similar tool. While holding the spring compressed, insert a pin through the hole in
                the rear of the housing so that the spring will be held in a compressed position. (A suitable pin can be
                made from a piece of 1/16 inch [1.6mm ] drill rod.) Install and compress the remaining brush and spring
                assembly in a similar manner. Hold the spring in a compressed position by pushing the pin farther into
                the housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802025">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802025" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802025" filename="../figg08/g0802025.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Spring in Compressed Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRUSHES</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. RETAINING PIN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position regulator above regulator holder and install RED lead to regulator terminal marked
                R. Install the BLACK lead to regulator terminal marked B and attach. Attach the white lead to the W
                terminal (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802026">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802026" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802026" filename="../figg08/g0802026.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Attach Leads</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BLACK TO "B"</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WHITE TO "W"</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RED TO "R"</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Be sure that the red, black and white leads are properly routed through their slots in the regulator
                housing.
                <emph type="bold">Withdraw brush retaining pin before clipping the regulator.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install spacer, key, fan, pulley and nut. Tighten nut to 70 to 80 ft-lbs. (95 to 108 N&#8226;m).
                Due to the design of the alternator, a certain amount of shaft end play will be present in new or
                rebuilt units. This end play is designed into the unit and will vary between .004 and .012 inch (0.1 to
                0.3mm).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not force or pound pulley on shaft.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
