<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: LEECE NEVILLE AND PRESTOLITE JN SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Procedures</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the drive belts, wiring, and mounting hardware, and make sure that they are in
                    proper working order.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the batteries according to manufacturer specifications to insure that they are in
                    good condition. The batteries must be at least 95-100% charged. If necessary, charge or replace
                    batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To establish if the alternator is functioning properly, connect an accurate test
                    voltmeter to the alternator output terminals (use a voltmeter capable of measuring 1/100 of a volt).
                    With all electrical accessories off, run the engine at approximately 1000-1200 RPM. Voltage reading
                    should be within 13.8 to 14.2 volts.
                </para>
                <para>If the alternator is overcharging, continue with step 7. If a low output condition is noted, then
                    continue with step 4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove regulator from holder far enough to expose the two contact pads. If corrosion or
                    dirt is found, then clean contact pads with #600 (or finer) grade sandpaper.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Poor contacts between contact pads and brushes may cause a "low charge" condition.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Remove brushes and visually inspect them. If brushes appear burned, cracked, broken or if they are
                    worn to a length of 3/16 inch or less, then brushes must be replaced. Check shunt lead within the
                    brush spring. If the shunt lead is broken, then install new brushes. Clean brush contact caps with
                    #600 (or finer) grade sandpaper.
                </para>
                <para>Clean each brush contact cap and the two contact pads on the regulator.</para>
                <para>Reinstall the brushes and regulator as shown under
                    <hotlnk document="s08020_12.xml" xrefid="hl0802003">REASSEMBLE</hotlnk>
                    steps 12 and 13.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the test in step 3. If the output voltage is below 13.8 volts, the unit should be
                    full field tested as shown in step 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut off the engine and all electrical accessories. Measure the voltage at the battery
                    terminals and make a note of the reading. Connect a short jumper to the alternator NEGATIVE output
                    terminal and to a 1.5 to 2 inch piece of stiff wire (a piece of paper clip wire is suitable). Insert
                    the wire in the full field access hole as far as it will go (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802028">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0802028" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0802028" filename="../figg08/G0802028.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Full Field Access Hole</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Run engine at about 1000-1200 RPM with voltmeter connected to battery terminals and check the
                    voltage. If the voltage rises rapidly above the reading noted when the engine was off, the
                    alternator is OK. Continue with step 7.
                </para>
                <para>If the voltage rises slowly or remains the same, the alternator is defective. Continue with step
                    8.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If an "overcharging" condition exists, then:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect battery ground cable.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pry clamp (toward slip ring end of alternator) to free regulator. Disconnect the
                        three leads and replace regulator with a new one (refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s08020_12.xml" xrefid="hl0802003">REASSEMBLE</hotlnk>
                        for proper procedure).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect battery ground cable, and repeat "Output Test."</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If overcharge condition is still present after regulator replacement, then alternator
                                must be removed and disassembled. The problem may be caused by poor connections of the
                                red and black leads (sensing leads) to the rectifier assembly.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To establish which component is causing the alternator to malfunction, perform an AC
                    voltage test.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AC VOLTAGE TEST (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802029">Figure 29</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0802029" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802029" filename="../figg08/G0802029.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>AC Voltage Test</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TEST PLATE #1</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TEST PLATE #2</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TERMINAL #3</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Run engine at about 1200 RPM, and connect an AC voltmeter across alternator AC terminals 1 &#38; 2, 1
                &#38; 3, 2 &#38; 3 and compare each of the three AC voltage readings. If all three AC voltage readings
                are approximately the same (balanced), the stator is OK. While performing this test, alternator must be
                in the "full field" mode.
            </para>
            <para>The voltage regulator used in these alternators is a solid state device and for this reason will
                normally have an extremely long life. It can, however, be damaged by mechanical or electrical abuse.
            </para>
            <para>If the system polarity is inadvertently reversed by installing a battery backwards, boosting or jump
                starting with the jumper connected backwards, or reversing the positive and negative alternator output
                leads when changing an alternator, the voltage regulator will be damaged. Although the polarity reversal
                may only be momentary and may not damage the alternator diodes, the regulator will still be damaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
