<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9200, 9300, 9400 Models Built After January 1, 1995 - HEATER AND
        AIR CONDITIONER - OPERATION - Heater-Cab
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Heater-Cab</title>
        <para>When the ignition switch is ON, power flows in through circuit 13J and out through 13-GT to energize
            heater control relay (463-R5). Thus when control switch (11) is moved to the low speed position, power flows
            from fuse F1-A through circuit 75, 75H, relay (463-R5) contacts, circuit 75S, 75J, control switch, circuit
            75C, the whole resistor and thermo fuse assembly, circuit 75T, relay (462-R2) contacts, and circuit 75F to
            blower motor 1. The ground circuit for motor 1 is circuit 75-G and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When control switch (11) is moved to the low speed position, switch (12) is also moved to the low speed
            position, and power also flows from fuse F1-A through circuit 75, 75H, relay (463-R5) contacts, circuit 75S,
            75B, control switch, circuit 75L, the whole resistor and thermo fuse assembly, circuit 75R, relay (462-R3)
            contacts, and circuit 75P to blower motor 2. The ground circuit for motor 2 is circuit 75-GA and 11-GB to
            right dash panel ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When control switch (11) is moved to the medium position, switch (12) is also moved to the medium
            position, and power flows to the control switches as previously described, through circuit 75D and half of
            the resistor assembly for blower 1 and 75M and half of the resistor assembly for blower 2, to the thermo
            fuse assemblies and circuits previously described.
        </para>
        <para>When control switch (11) is moved to the high position, switch (12) is also moved to the high position,
            and power flows to the control switches as previously described, and through circuit 75E to energize high
            speed relay 1 for blower 1, and 75N to energize high speed relay 2 for blower 2.
        </para>
        <para>The ground path for high speed relay 1 is circuit 13-GA to ignition relay, and the ground path for high
            speed relay 2 is circuit 75-GB and 13-GA to ignition relay.
        </para>
        <para>When high speed relay 1 is energized, power flows through circuit 75A and fuse F1-A to supply blower
            circuits already described. When high speed relay 2 is energized, power flows through circuit 75K and fuse
            F1-C to supply blower circuits already described.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_300.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_302.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
