<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 25-SI SERIES, TYPES 400 AND 450 - REPAIR PROCEDURES - DIODE REPLACEMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIODE REPLACEMENT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacing a Diode In The Rectifier End Frame</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the rectifier end frame from the drive end frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the heat sink from the end frame by detaching from the heat sink the regulator
                    lead, the heat sink mounting screws and the alternator output terminal.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Note the round insulators under the heat sink mounting screws and the flat insulator
                            located behind the heat sink. The silicone grease on both sides of the flat insulator
                            provides the necessary heat transfer between heat sink and end frame. Re-apply silicone
                            grease to both sides of the flat insulator during assembly.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a suitable tool to pull the diode out of the end frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a suitable tool which fits over the outer diode edge to push the diode in, and
                    support the end frame with a suitable tool.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Diode replacement tools are available from various manufacturers normally supplying tools
                            and test equipment to the automotive industry.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not strike the diode as the shock may damage it and the other diodes. Use only those
                            diodes listed in the parts list for these units. Never use substitutes.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten heat sink mounting screws loosely, securely tighten output terminal, then
                    securely tighten the heat sink screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacing a Diode In the Heat Sink</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the rectifier end frame from the drive end frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the heat sink from the end frame by detaching from the heat sink the regulator
                    lead, the heat sink mounting screws and the generator output terminal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support heat sink and use an arbor press or vise to push the diode out.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a suitable tool which fits over the outer diode edge to push the diode in. Support
                    the heat sink with a suitable tool.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Diode replacement tools are available from various manufacturers normally supplying tools
                            and test equipment to the automotive industry.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not strike the diode as the shock may damage it and the other diodes. Use only those
                            diodes listed in the parts list for these units. Never use substitutes.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
