<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STARTING MOTORS - NO LOAD TEST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>NO LOAD TEST</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The no-load test (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0803612">Figure 12</hotlnk>) may point to specific defects which can verified with
                tests, when the motor is disassembled. Also, the no-load test can identify open or shorted fields, which
                are difficult to check when disassembled. The no-load test also can be used to indicate normal operation
                on a repaired motor before installation.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0803612" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803612" filename="../figg08/g0803612.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>No Load Test</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BATTERY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AMMETER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. VOLTMETER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CRANKING MOTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RPM INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. CARBON PILE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Connect a voltmeter from the motor terminal to the motor frame, and use an r.p.m. indicator to measure
                armature speed. Connect the motor and an ammeter in series with a fully charged battery of the starter
                specified voltage, and a switch in the open position from the solenoid battery terminal to the solenoid
                switch terminal. Close the switch and compare the r.p.m., current and voltage reading with
                Specifications.
            </para>
            <para>It is not necessary to obtain the exact voltage specified, as an accurate interpretation can be made
                by recognizing that if the voltage is slightly higher, the r.p.m. will be proportionately higher with
                the current remaining essentially unchanged. However, if the exact voltage is desired, a carbon pile
                connected across the battery can be used to reduce the voltage to the specified value. If more than one
                12-volt battery is used, connect the carbon pile to only one of the 12-volt batteries.
            </para>
            <para>If the specified current draw does not include the solenoid, deduct from the ammeter reading the
                specified current draw on the solenoid hold-in winding. Make disconnections only with the switch open.
                Interpret the test results as follows:
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
