<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - MAINTENANCE (IN VEHICLE)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE (IN VEHICLE)</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The battery is a perishable item and requires attention. With a reasonable amount of care, the life of
                a battery can be appreciably extended. Neglect and abuse will invariably cause shorter battery service
                life.
            </para>
            <para>The battery should be inspected at the time of chassis lubrication or other periodic services.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Battery maintenance includes the following:</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Battery Maintenance</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect battery and mounting.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If corrosion is found on the terminal posts, remove the cable terminals from the battery
                    (ground cable first) using the proper end wrench and a cable puller.
                </para>
                <para>A terminal cleaning brush can be used to clean tapered posts and the mating surfaces of the cable
                    clamps. Stud type terminals can be cleaned with a wire brush. The cable terminals should then be
                    cleaned with an acid neutralizing solution of baking soda and water. Clean dirt from the battery top
                    with a cloth moistened with baking soda and water. Then wipe with a cloth moistened with clear
                    water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A wire brush can be used to remove dirt, corrosion or rust from the battery tray or hold
                    down parts.
                </para>
                <para>After rust is removed, rinse with clear water, dry with air and repaint.</para>
                <para>After cleaning, reinstall battery and hold down parts as instructed under
                    <hotlnk document="s08022k_23.xml" xrefid="hl0802201">REMOVAL AND INSTALLATION</hotlnk>. Coat battery
                    and cable terminals with terminal grease and connect cables to battery terminals. Connect ground
                    cable last.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When servicing filler cap batteries, check electrolyte level in all cells. If necessary,
                    add clear water to bring the liquid level to the level indicator. If the battery does not have an
                    indicator, add water to bring the liquid level to 1/2" (13 mm) above the top of the separators. Do
                    not overfill any cell. Maintenance free type batteries do not require addition of water under normal
                    operating conditions. If loss of electrolyte is suspected, check electrolyte level as instructed
                    under
                    <hotlnk document="s08022k_15.xml" xrefid="hl0802202">TESTING</hotlnk>
                    and determine cause for low level.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
