<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - PROGRAMMING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0803502">
        <title>PROGRAMMING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The Speedo/Tach module can be programmed in the field using the Pro-Link 9000 EST or Ez-Tech, with the
                instrument cluster software, connected to the data link (electronic engines only) or by physically
                setting the DIP switches (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0803509">Figure 9</hotlnk>). Refer to the Pro-Link 9000 manual for the cartridge for
                instructions. Refer to the EZ-Tech instrument cluster software manual for programming instructions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Moving any of the DIP switches from the 0 position disables the speedometer/tachometer
                        programming. If a DIP switch is moved for re-programming or any other reason, then all of the
                        switches must be physically moved to the positions indicated on the module label (or lineset
                        ticket). If all of the switches are returned to zero, the original factory programmed settings
                        will be enabled.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Speedo/Tach module has two sets of DIP switches with eight switches in each bank. The switches are
                located on the top of the module.
                <emph type="bold">When programmed at the factory, all of the switches are physically in the zero
                    position.</emph>The zero position is with the switch positioned toward the front of the module, when
                viewing the top edge of the module. A label is placed on the module that provides the module part number
                and switch positions (electronically set to these positions although the switches are physically in the
                zero position).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0803509" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803509" filename="../figg08/g0803509.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Dip Switches</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
