<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 10-SI SERIES, TYPE 116 - REPAIR PROCEDURES - BEARING REPLACEMENT AND LUBRICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
        <title>BEARING REPLACEMENT AND LUBRICATION</title>
        <para>The bearing in the drive end frame is a sealed bearing and can be removed by detaching the retainer plate
            screws and then pressing the bearing from the end frame. If the bearing is in satisfactory condition, it may
            be reused and should be filled one-quarter full with lubricant specified in GROUP 10, LUBRICATION section of
            the Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>To install a new bearing, press in with a tube or collar that just fits over the outer race (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0801211">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0801211" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0801211" filename="../figg08/G0801211.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Drive End Bearing Installation</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. END FRAME</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SEALED BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>3. FAN</callout1>
                <callout1>4. PULLEY</callout1>
                <callout1>5. WASHER</callout1>
                <callout1>6. NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>7. ROTOR SHAFT</callout1>
                <callout1>8. COLLAR (OUTER)</callout1>
                <callout1>9. RETAIN PLATE SCREW</callout1>
                <callout1>10. COLLAR (INNER)</callout1>
                <callout1>11. RETAINER PLATE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The bearing in the slip ring end frame should be replaced if its grease supply is exhausted. No attempt
            should be made to re-lubricate and reuse the bearing. To remove the bearing from the slip ring end frame,
            press out with a tube or collar that just fits inside the end frame housing. Press from the outside of the
            housing towards the inside.
        </para>
        <para>To install a new bearing and seal, place a flat plate over the seal and press in from the outside towards
            the inside of the frame until the seal is flush with the outside of the end frame. Press the seal in with
            the lip of the seal toward the rotor when assembled, that is, away from the bearing. Place the flat plate
            over the bearing and push in both bearing and seal so bearing is flush with outside of end frame. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s08012_10.xml" xrefid="f0801210">Figure 10</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>Support the inside of the frame with a hollow cylinder to prevent breakage of the end frame. Use extreme
            care to avoid misalignment or otherwise placing undue stress on the bearing. Lightly coat the seal lip with
            oil to aid in assembly of the shaft into the bearing.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
