<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GENERAL INSTRUMENT ELECTRONIC PROGRAMMABLE SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER - TEST 2 - B+ VOLTAGE AND GROUND TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>TEST 2 - B+ VOLTAGE AND GROUND TEST</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To perform TEST 1 or 2 with Caterpillar 3406B engine with PEEC and Kysor engine shutdown, the
                    power to the speedometer/tachometer unit comes through the Run Relay when the run relay is activated
                    by starting the engine. To perform TEST 1 or 2, which require "key switch ON" in this section
                    without running the engine, install a jumper wire connecting the number 1 and number 3 terminals of
                    the Kysor control module. BE SURE TO REMOVE THE JUMPER BEFORE STARTING THE ENGINE.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0803309">Figure 9</hotlnk>
            for this test.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0803309" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0803309" filename="../figg08/g0803309.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Using Voltmeter To Check B+ Battery Voltage And Ground Circuit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. KEY SWITCH ON</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CHECKING B+ BATTERY VOLTAGE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. GOOD VEHICLE GROUND</callout1>
                <callout1>4. GROUND CIRCUIT TEST</callout1>
                <callout1>5. INSTRUMENT PANEL GROUND
                    <callout2>A. VEHICLE HARNESS SPEEDOMETER CONNECTOR</callout2>
                    <callout2>B. CIRCUIT 47 (B+ VOLTAGE) (CIR 97P WITH CAT 3406 W/PEEC)</callout2>
                    <callout2>C. CIRCUIT 11AG OR 47 G (GROUND CIRCUIT)(CIR 97 GG WITH CAT 3406 W/ PEEC</callout2>
                </callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>This test should be run when NEITHER the speedometer or tachometer pointer moves (dead) during TEST 1. The
            speedometer, tachometer and odometer rely on a single B+ voltage source and a single ground circuit. If
            either is defective the speedometer/tachometer unit will not function.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn the key switch to the OFF position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>This test requires the use of a DC voltmeter.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>This system operates ONLY with 12 volts DC. DO NOT CONNECT TO A 24 VOLT SUPPLY.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove speedometer/tachometer unit from instrument panel (see REMOVE AND INSTALL).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect instrument panel harness from all speedometer/tachometer unit connectors.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect (+) voltmeter lead to vehicle instrument panel harness speedometer connector at B+
                feed, circuit 47 or 97P. Connect (-) meter lead to good vehicle ground. Turn switch key to ON position.
                Meter should read 12-13 volts.
            </para>
            <para>If no voltage or low voltage is indicated, check the feed circuit for open condition or loose
                connection between the speedometer connection and the key switch. Correct condition and retest. Refer to
                circuit diagrams included in this section. Also verify batteries are fully charged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When B+ voltage is verified, perform the ground circuit test as follows. Connect (+) meter
                lead to vehicle instrument panel harness speedometer connector at B+ feed, circuit 47. Connect (-) meter
                lead to speedometer/tachometer unit ground circuit 11AG (96/9700) or 47-G (93/9400) or 97-GG (CAT 3406B
                W/PEEC) of instrument panel harness connector. Turn switch key to ON position. Voltage should read 12-13
                volts.
            </para>
            <para>If no voltage or low voltage is indicated, check ground circuit 11AG or 47-G or 97-GG for open
                condition or loose connections. Correct condition and retest. Refer to circuit diagrams in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If steps 3 and 4 show that the B+ circuits and the ground circuits are good, assure that the
                instrument panel harness speedometer connection to the speedometer/tachometer unit is good.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If steps 3, 4, and 5 of TEST 2 show that the B+ feed and ground circuits are good and the
                connection to the speedometer/tachometer unit is good go to TEST 7.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
