<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9200, 9300, 9400 Models Built After January 1, 1995 - ELECTRICAL
        TROUBLESHOOTING 1994-1995 DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 DDEC III ENGINES - DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING -
        DETERMINING FAULT CODES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DETERMINING FAULT CODES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ECM continuously monitors itself and other system components, including sensors, injectors,
                connectors and associated wiring.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The</emph>
                <emph type="bold">yellow Engine Warning Light is turned ON</emph>if a minor fault occurs. A fault code
                is also logged. This indicates the problem should be diagnosed as soon as possible.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The ECM turns ON the yellow Engine Warning Light and the red Stop Engine Light</emph>
                and stores a fault code if a major fault is detected. If this occurs, the vehicle should be brought to a
                safe stop and the engine shut down.
            </para>
            <para>A diagnostic check may be performed using the Diagnostic ON/OFF switch or Prolink EST.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic ON/OFF/Shutdown Override Switch</title>
            <para>The Diagnostic ON/OFF switch is used to activate the yellow Engine Warning light and the red Stop
                Engine light to flash codes. The red Stop Engine light will flash the ACTIVE codes and the yellow Engine
                Warning light will flash the INACTIVE codes.
            </para>
            <para>If no fault codes are logged, the code "25" will be flashed out on the yellow Engine Warning Light.
                For example, the yellow engine warning light blinks out: FLASH, FLASH. The first digit is a 2, then a
                half-second pause: FLASH FLASH, FLASH, FLASH, FLASH. The second digit is a 5. Code 25 is System OK.
            </para>
            <para>The Diagnostic ON/OFF switch is used to flash codes in the following circumstances:</para>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>When the engine is not running and the ignition switch is ON, toggling and releasing the
                        Diagnostic ON/OFF switch will flash out the engine codes. Toggling then releasing the Diagnostic
                        ON/OFF switch a second time will stop the ECM from flashing the codes.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the engine is idling and not in an "engine protection condition," toggling and releasing
                        the Diagnostic ON/OFF switch will flash out the engine codes. Toggling then releasing the
                        Diagnostic ON/OFF switch a second time will stop the ECM from flashing the codes.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All Series 60 fault codes are 2 digits.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Detroit Diesel Troubleshooting Manual contains flash code descriptions and diagnostic
                procedures.
            </para>
            <para>If the fault code(s) or symptoms indicate a need to troubleshoot a International installed circuit or
                component, procedures are included in this chapter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MPSI Prolink Electronic Service Tool (EST)</title>
            <para>The MPSI (Prolink) electronic service tool (EST) with a Series 60 cartridge can be used to read logged
                fault codes and monitor many of the system switches and operating parameters. Refer to the Prolink
                manual for information on using the EST.
            </para>
            <para>International vehicles include an 8-way and 12-way (for DDEC EST) diagnostic connector used to access
                the system with an EST.
            </para>
            <para>The troubleshooting charts in this section are not designed for specific symptoms, but designed to
                test those circuits and components installed by International. Use DDEC III diagnostics procedures to
                identify the suspect circuit or system, then use the procedures included in this section to troubleshoot
                the specific International circuit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NO TESTS in this section require testing "into" the DDEC ECM.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl08058bt">
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the vehicle batteries are fully
                            charged!</emph>Check battery cables and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage
                        and corrosion. Many of the voltage tests included in the procedures will give misleading
                        readings if the batteries are not fully charged.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting a particular circuit, inspect connectors for pushed back, loose or
                        damaged (spread or bent), or corroded terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. The wires and
                        connections must be free of damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white
                        residue will be present that must be removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect the suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections free
                        of damage or corrosion.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing Hella Relay</title>
            <para>International circuits use suppressed Hella relays for controlling power to load devices (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0805801">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The suppression feature (a resistor circuit parallel to
                the relay coil) prevents voltage spikes from damaging electronic components in the vehicle.
                <emph type="bold">These relays must be replaced with approved International parts.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0805801" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0805801" filename="../figg08/G0805801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Typical Hella Relay</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The part number and relay circuit diagram are embossed on the relay body. The terminals are numbered
                on the relay in the same manner as in the circuit diagrams.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Relay Test Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With relay removed, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87A. If resistance is
                    less than 5 ohms, go to step 2; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87. If resistance is 100K ohms or more, go
                    to step 3; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using 12V battery source and test leads, connect (+) lead to terminal 85 and (-) lead to
                    terminal 86. If relay energizes with an audible click sound, go to step 4; otherwise replace the
                    relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While relay is energized, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87. If resistance
                    is less than 5 ohms, go to step 5; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While relay is energized, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87A. If resistance
                    is 100K ohms or more, the relay is good; otherwise replace relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_114.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_116.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
