<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - ACTIVATING DRY CHARGED BATTERIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ACTIVATING DRY CHARGED BATTERIES</title>
        <para>Dry charged batteries provided for replacement installation must be "activated" before they can be used.
            Following the instructions outlined below will assure proper activation regardless of temperature and
            conditions of storage.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill each cell of the battery to the bottom of split ring with the correct battery-grade
                electrolyte as specified by the manufacturer's instructions. Using higher or lower specific gravity
                electrolyte than recommended can impair battery performance. Originally filling each cell to just above
                the top of the separators permits expansion of the electrolyte as battery is boost charged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Gently rock battery. This will help to force out trapped air and to saturate the plates with
                electrolyte.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Boost charge 12-volt batteries at 15 amps (12-volt heavy duty batteries at 30 initial amps)
                until the specific gravity of the electrolyte is 1.250 or higher and electrolyte temperature is at least
                15.5&#176;C (60&#176;F). BOTH CONDITIONS MUST BE MET. If electrolyte bubbles violently while charging,
                reduce charging rate until excessive bubbling action subsides, then continue charging until 1.250
                specific gravity and 15.5&#176;C (60&#176;F) are reached. If the ambient temperature is 0&#176;C (32&#176;F)
                or less, it is imperative that the above instructions be followed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check volume of electrolyte in all cells and adjust to prescribed level with additional
                electrolyte as required.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not add water at this point.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install battery in vehicle as instructed under
                <hotlnk document="s08022k_23.xml" xrefid="hl0802201">BATTERY REMOVAL AND INSTALLATION</hotlnk>. Be sure
                of proper polarity.
            </para>
            <para>Dry charged batteries may be placed in service immediately after activation. However, to insure good
                performance these additional steps are recommended.
            </para>
            <para>Check the specific gravity of all cells. Under good storage conditions, the electrolyte specific
                gravity on activating a dry-charged battery will drop approximately .010 and temperature will rise 4&#176;
                to 5.6&#176;C (7 to 10&#176;F) within twenty minutes of filling the battery. A battery under these
                conditions requires little boost charging. However, should the specific gravity drop .030 or more with a
                corresponding increase in temperature, the negative plates have been oxidized and the battery should be
                fully recharged before use. Also, the battery should be recharged if one or more cells gas violently
                after the addition of electrolyte. After electrolyte is added, check the open circuit terminal voltage
                of the battery. If a 12-volt battery reads less than 10 volts, this indicates a reverse cell or an
                "open" circuit and the battery should be replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>After the dry charged battery has been activated, it must be serviced, handled and kept charged like any
            other wet battery. After battery has been in service, add only distilled water. DO NOT ADD ACID.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
