<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TEST EQUIPMENT AND CONNECTOR REPAIR - ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The description of electrical operation in each section provides a discussion of what is happening in
                each circuit. The discussion includes power application, ground paths, and component operation. The
                explanation refers to circuit diagrams, and in some cases, to specific switch movement or components in
                a circuit. These specific points are often identified by letters or numbers as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801001">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801001" filename="../figg08/g0801001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Sample Circuit Components</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801001">Figure 1</hotlnk>shows a suppressed relay widely used in the vehicle
                electrical system. The relay connection points 85 and 86 are the coil connections. Power is applied to
                one side of the coil and ground to the other, causing the coil to energize. Energizing the coil switches
                the contact from the normally closed contact 87A to the normally open contact 87.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801001">Figure 1</hotlnk>also shows the symbol for an ignition key switch used on some
                International vehicles. Notice the points are labeled "A" for accessory, "S" for start, "I" for ignition
                and OFF. These correspond to the connections on the key switch in the vehicle. The "B" terminal is the
                power source point. Notice that the key switch is shown in the OFF position. When turned to ON
                (ignition) position, for example, all four switch arms move together.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
