<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 21-SI SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING - CHARGING SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CHARGING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Check electrical system wiring and battery terminals for poor connections or other obvious conditions
                that might result in shorts, opens, grounds, or high resistance. Correct as necessary.
            </para>
            <para>Check alternator drive belt for proper tension. Adjust to specifications.</para>
            <para>Check battery for state-of-charge. If low, recharge according to manufacturer's specifications and
                load test to establish serviceability. Refer to GROUP 08-MAINTENANCE FREE BATTERY. Further diagnostic
                tests require a known good, fully-charged battery for best results.
            </para>
            <para>With engine stopped and all electrical loads turned off, use voltmeter to check voltage across battery
                terminals. Record voltage.
            </para>
            <para>Start engine and run at moderate speed. Check voltage across battery terminals with engine running.
            </para>
            <para>If voltage reading at battery terminals is different from reading showing at vehicle voltmeter (should
                be close to 14.0 volts), locate and correct cause of incorrect reading.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator With No Output</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>NOTE: Test hole is provided in SRE housing to allow direct grounding of rotor field circuit (
                        <hotlnk document="s08017j_31.xml" xrefid="f0801732">Figure 32</hotlnk>). Grounding the brush tab
                        inside this hole bypasses the regulator and turns the alternator on in FULL FIELD mode. If
                        alternator output is observed with the brush tab grounded, the previous low output is due to
                        conditions within the regulator. In the full field mode the voltage is not regulated and can
                        exceed 16 volts.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If voltage is lower than reading previously recorded with engine stopped, there is no alternator
                output. Proceed to section on ,
                <hotlnk document="s08017j_8.xml" xrefid="hl0801702">REPAIR PROCEDURE
                    <xref refid="hl0801702"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>If voltage is higher than previous reading with engine stopped, alternator output is present. Proceed
                to section on
                <hotlnk document="s08017j_5.xml" xrefid="hl0801703">RATED OUTPUT CHECK
                    <xref refid="hl0801703"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>If battery is overcharged (as evidenced by excessive water use or electrolyte spewing from battery
                vents), light bulbs or other electrical equipment have shortened life due to suspected high system
                voltage, or system voltmeter reads above normal range, run engine at moderate speed with all electrical
                loads off. Voltage reading at the Alternator or battery should be between 13.5 -14.5 volts and never
                higher than 15 volts.
            </para>
            <para>If voltage is erratic or goes above 15 volts, replace regulator as described under
                <hotlnk document="s08017j_8.xml" xrefid="hl0801702">REPAIR PROCEDURE
                    <xref refid="hl0801702"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
