<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - DESCRIPTION - Shift Lever Selector</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Shift Lever Selector</title>
        <para>To move the shift lever (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0800305">Figure 5</hotlnk>) between "R," "N," and "D," a lockout must be disengaged by
            using the thumb release (detent unlock button) on the shifter handle. All other ranges can be selected by
            moving the lever without using the thumb release.
        </para>
        <para>The shift selector is equipped with a digital display. In the operating mode, the display indicates the
            range selected on the top and the range monitored on the bottom.
        </para>
        <para>Below the "range monitored" the display has an indicator which says MODE ON. This indicator has two
            meanings. In the normal operation of the transmission, it indicates that a secondary or special operating
            condition has been selected by the operator by depressing the MODE button. In the diagnostic mode, the MODE
            ON indicator means the displayed code is currently active. The shift selector contains a provision to sound
            a tone when required to indicate the occurrence of a diagnostic code at the same time that the DO NOT SHIFT
            light is illuminated.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0800305" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0800305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 5 - Shift Lever Selector</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. DETENT UNLOCK BUTTON</callout1>
                <callout1>2. RANGE SELECTED</callout1>
                <callout1>3. RANGE MONITORED</callout1>
                <callout1>4. MODE IDENTIFICATION</callout1>
                <callout1>5. MODE BUTTON LABEL</callout1>
                <callout1>6. DISPLAY MODE BUTTON</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The brightness control for the shift lever display illumination is controlled by the dash light control,
            through the ECU. The ECU monitors the voltage output of the vehicle panel light brightness control and if no
            voltage is sensed by the ECU, the shift selector is set to full intensity. If a lower than ignition voltage
            is sensed, the display is not fully illuminated. If full ignition voltage is sensed, the display is again
            lighted at full intensity.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
