<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - EMERGENCY (JUMPER) STARTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>EMERGENCY (JUMPER) STARTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The procedure outlined below should be followed exactly.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Both booster and discharged batteries must be treated carefully when using jumper cables. Be
                        careful not to cause sparks.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear goggles to shield eyes.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Any procedure other than that outlined below could result in (1) personal injury by
                        electrolyte squirting out the vent, (2) personal injury or property damage due to battery
                        explosion, (3) damage to the charging system of the booster vehicle or of the immobilized
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Make sure booster and discharged batteries are the same voltage.</para>
            <para>Make certain the stalled vehicle and the one containing booster battery do not touch. If the two
                vehicles are in contact, a ground connection could be established which could cause sparking when jumper
                cables are attached.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On both vehicles: Set parking brake. Place transmission in NEUTRAL or PARK. Turn lights,
                    heater and other electrical loads OFF. Make certain ignition key is turned OFF.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine the placement of the negative (-) and positive (+) terminals of both
                    batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a damp cloth over the vents of each battery. Make certain the cloth is clear of
                    fan blades, belts and other moving parts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802210">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0802210" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0802210" filename="../figg08/G0802210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="192px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Proper Jumper Cable Connections</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>A. CLOTH COVERING VENTS (BOTH BATTERIES)</callout1>
                        <callout1>B. GROUND AT LEAST 12 INCHES (30 CM) FROM BATTERY</callout1>
                        <callout1>1. BATTERY VENT LOCATION</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. BOOSTER BATTERY</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. JUMPER CABLES</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. DISCHARGED BATTERY</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach one end of the jumper cable to the positive (+) terminal of the booster battery
                    and the other end of same cable to positive (+) terminal of discharged battery (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802210">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach one end of the remaining jumper cable to the negative terminal of the booster
                    battery and the other end to a ground at least 12 inches (304 mm) from the battery of the vehicle
                    being started (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802210">Figure 10</hotlnk>). (DO NOT connect directly to the negative post of the
                    dead battery.) The ground connection must provide good electrical conductivity and current carrying
                    capacity.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Take care to be sure the clamps from one cable do not inadvertently touch the clamps on
                            the other cable.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not lean over the battery when making connections. Avoid touching hazards such as fans,
                            manifolds and spark plug terminals when connecting cables.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure everyone is standing away from vehicles. Start the engine of the vehicle with
                    the booster battery. Wait a few minutes, then attempt to start the engine of the vehicle with the
                    discharged battery.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not operate the starter for more than 30 seconds. Wait at least 30 seconds between
                    starting attempts to allow starter motor to cool. If the engine does not start after several
                    cranking attempts, check to be sure that the clamps are secure. If the engine will not start, refer
                    to the appropriate service manual for troubleshooting procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After starting, allow the engine to return to idle speed. Remove ground cable
                    connections from the vehicle with discharged battery. Then remove the other end of the same cable
                    from the booster battery.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the other cable by disconnecting from the discharged battery first and then
                    disconnect the opposite end from the booster battery.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard cloths covering battery vents.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
