<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ELECTRICAL OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This section describes the electrical operation of the International circuits and components used to
                connect the transmission to the vehicle electrical system and to the various International-installed
                controls.
            </para>
            <para>The operation description makes reference to connector and wire numbers in describing the system.
                <emph type="bold">For the purpose of the description, references will be from the circuit diagrams for
                    the 2000, 4000, 8000 models.</emph>The other models included in this section--the 3600, 3800 and
                3900FC--operate in the same manner, but harness configuration is different and some connector and
                circuit numbers are different.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the Circuit Diagrams for the 2000, 4000 and 8000 models located in this service
                        manual section for the following discussions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>WT ELECTRONIC CONTROL SYSTEM POWER SOURCE</title>
            <para>The WT electronic control system receives battery power at all times and ignition power when the key
                is ON.
            </para>
            <para>BATTERY POWER - Direct battery power from the B+ terminal of the cranking motor solenoid is delivered
                (circuit 329) to the Main Power fuse located in the Vehicle Interface Module (VIM). Power from the Main
                Power fuse is present at all times to the ECU, the Data Link Connector (419) and the shift selector
                (420).
            </para>
            <para>IGNITION POWER - With the key ON, ignition power from the key switch (63) is delivered (circuit
                13J/A303/303) to the ignition (IGN) power fuse, located in the VIM.
            </para>
            <para>The ignition voltage acts as an ON/OFF switch for the WT ECU and provides ignition power to selected
                relays located in the VIM.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
