<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GENERAL INSTRUMENT ELECTRONIC PROGRAMMABLE SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The speedometer/tachometer unit consists of four serviceable components: the unit housing which
                includes the printed circuit board that drives all of the meters, the speedometer and tachometer which
                are air core gauges, and the odometer.
            </para>
            <para>The speedometer/tachometer unit receives B+ voltage whenever the key switch is in the ON position
                (with Cat 3406B with PEEC and Kysor shutdown the engine must be started). The unit has a single power
                source and a single ground. The speedometer/tachometer unit wiring connections are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0803302">Figure 2</hotlnk>. Also refer to circuit diagrams in this section.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0803302" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803302" filename="../figg08/g0803302.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Speedometer/Tachometer Unit Connectors</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The speedometer/tachometer unit data link connector is not currently used in the vehicle operating
                system, but the assembly plants do use it to program the speedometer/tachometer unit dip switches
                electronically.
            </para>
            <para>The two-speed connector is present in all speedometer/tachometer units as it is used with a test
                harness (that is discussed later) to diagnose the speedometer/tachometer unit even if the vehicle does
                not have a two-speed axle.
            </para>
            <para>The speedometer/tachometer dash unit receives alternating current (AC) signals from the speedometer
                sensor located in the transmission, and the engine speed sensor located in the engine flywheel housing.
            </para>
            <para>The sensors contain a permanent magnet (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0803303">Figure 3</hotlnk>) that creates a magnetic field that when broken by a
                rotating gear, generates an A.C. voltage that is transmitted to the speedometer/tachometer unit. A
                computer module in the housing (printed circuit board) counts the impulses and computes the vehicle
                speed in miles-per-hour (or kilometers-per-hour) and the engine speed in revolutions-per-minute (RPM).
                This information is used to drive the air core speedometer and tachometer and the odometer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0803303" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803303" filename="../figg08/g0803303.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Speedometer Sensor Operation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SENSOR UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TRANSMISSION REAR BEARING COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SPEEDOMETER GEAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. MAGNETIC FIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SENSOR OUTPUT VOLTAGE (AC)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The low range of the speedometer/tachometer unit for two-speed axle applications is activated by the
                application of 12 volts (B+ voltage) on the single black lead of the speedometer/tachometer unit. The
                voltage source is a pressure switch located in the axle shift air line. When the voltage is delivered to
                the speedometer/tachometer unit, the computer divides the speedometer sensor input by 1.36 and the
                reading of the speedometer and odometer changes accordingly.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
