<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS - REMOVE AND INSTALL - INSTRUMENT CLUSTER COMPONENTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INSTRUMENT CLUSTER COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>It is recommended that the entire cluster be removed from the instrument panel to perform gauge
                removal and/or installation. This provides more work room and minimizes the risk of damaging the cluster
                or the instruments.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the cluster released from the instrument panel (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08034x_5.xml" xrefid="x0803401">COMPLETE CLUSTER, Remove</hotlnk>
                    ), remove the three (3) bezel screws that fasten the bezel to the cluster housing,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0803406">Figure 6</hotlnk>. Place the instrument cluster face up on a clean,
                    horizontal surface to prevent loss of unused gauge covers, gauges, etc.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0803406" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0803406" filename="../figg08/G0803406.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Bezel Removal</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bezel lens assembly from the housing and put it in a safe place to prevent
                    scratching. Take care not to damage the gauge pointers with the bezel or lens ,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0803406">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All gauges with the exception of the Air Pressure, Oil Pressure, Hourmeter and Odometer
                    are plug-in gauges. To remove, locate the hole in the back of the cluster behind the gauge and using
                    a small, blunt tool such as a small screwdriver handle, push the gauge out of the housing. Once the
                    gauge has cleared the retaining snaps it may be removed from the front.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Speedometer and Tachometer are plug-in gauges and are removed as described in 3.
                    above.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>After a gauge is removed from the cluster, it is important that the exposed pin terminals
                            attached to the circuit board are not touched or shorted across. Static electricity or
                            shorting between power and ground terminals can damage the cluster.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove the Hourmeter and/or Odometer, disconnect the wiring plugs from the circuit
                    board at the back of the cluster. At the front of the cluster, remove the adhesive-backed mask
                    covering the gauge, then retract the two fingers that hold the gauges in the cluster and lift the
                    gauge out of the cluster.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When removing or in stalling the hourmeter or odometer, do not touch the metal portion of
                            the leads that fasten to the circuit board. A static discharge could damage the cluster.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mechanical type air and oil gauges are front serviceable after the air and oil line
                    fittings and the retaining nuts have been removed from the rear of each gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Light bulbs are plug in type and are serviceable from the rear of the instrument
                    cluster,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0803407">Figure 7</hotlnk>. The gauge back lights are #936 bulbs and the turn
                    signals, high beam and warning lights are #37.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0803407" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0803407" filename="../figg08/G0803407.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Removing the Bulb and Socket From the Rear of the Cluster</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Individual gauge dials are not protected by a lens. When removing or installing gauges,
                            handle them by the edge of the dial face only. Do not touch the gauge pointer.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
