<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - MAINTENANCE (IN VEHICLE) - CHECKING SPECIFIC GRAVITY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0802203" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="3">
        <title>CHECKING SPECIFIC GRAVITY</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Specific gravity is a unit of measurement for determining the sulfuric acid content of the
                electrolyte. The specific gravity can be measured directly with a hydrometer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802201">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802201" filename="../figg08/g0802201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="152px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Battery Hydrometer</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The state-of-charge of a battery can be determined by the specific gravity of the electrolyte. The
                recommended fully charged specific gravity of most 12-volt batteries is 1.270 to 1.280 corrected to 26.7&#176;C
                (80&#176;F).
            </para>
            <para>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0802205">The Specific Gravity Readings Table</hotlnk>
                illustrates typical specific gravity values for a cell in various stages of charge. A fully charged
                specific gravity of 1.265 corrected to 26.7&#176;C (80&#176;F) is assumed.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Specific Gravity Readings</title>
            <table id="hl0802205">
                <title>Specific Gravity Readings Table</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Specific Gravity (Corrected to 26.7&#176;C or 80&#176;F)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>State of Charge</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>1.275</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Fully Charged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>1.240</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>75% Charged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>1.200</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>50% Charged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>1.170</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>25% Charged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>1.140</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Discharged</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Using A Hydrometer</title>
            <para>The barrel must be held vertically so the float is not rubbing against the side (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802202">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The electrolyte should be drawn in and out of the
                hydrometer barrel a few times to bring the temperature of the hydrometer float and barrel to that of the
                acid in the cell. Draw an amount of acid into the barrel so that with the bulb fully expanded, the float
                will be lifted free, touching neither the side, top nor bottom stopper of the barrel.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802202" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802202" filename="../figg08/g0802202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Checking Specific Gravity with a Hydrometer</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When reading the hydrometer, your eye should be on a level with the surface of the liquid in the
                hydrometer barrel. Disregard the curvature of the liquid where the surface rises against the float stem
                and the barrel due to surface tension. Keep the float clean. Make certain it is not cracked.
            </para>
            <para>Never take a hydrometer reading immediately after water is added to the cell. The water must be
                thoroughly mixed with the underlying electrolyte, by charging, before hydrometer readings are reliable.
                If a reading is being taken immediately after the battery has been subjected to prolonged cranking, it
                will be higher than the true value. The water formed in the plates during the rapid discharge has not
                had time to mix with the higher specific gravity acid above the plates.
            </para>
            <para>Because there are many different types of battery hydrometers available, always follow manufacturers
                instructions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Temperature Correction</title>
            <para>Hydrometer floats are calibrated to give a true reading at one fixed temperature only. A correction
                factor must be applied for any specific gravity reading made when the electrolyte temperature is not
                26.7&#176;C (80&#176;F) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802203" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802203" filename="../figg08/g0802203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="432px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Correcting Specific Gravity</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A temperature correction must be used because the electrolyte will expand and become less dense when
                heated. The float will sink lower in the less dense solutions and give a lower specific gravity reading.
                The opposite occurs if the electrolyte is cooled. It will shrink in volume, becoming more dense. The
                float will rise higher and read too high.
            </para>
            <para>A correction factor of .004 specific gravity (sometimes referred to as 4 "points" of "gravity") is
                used for each 5.5&#176;C (10&#176;F) change in temperature. Four "points of gravity" (.004) are added to
                the indicated reading for each 5.5&#176;C (10&#176;F) increment above 26.7&#176;C (80&#176;F) and four
                points are subtracted for each 5.5&#176;C (10&#176;F) increment below 26.7&#176;C (80&#176;F). This
                correction is important at extremes of temperature because it can become a substantial value.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802203">Figure 3</hotlnk>illustrates the correction for hydrometer readings when the
                acid temperature is above or below 26.7&#176;C (80&#176;F). For example, in cold weather, a partially
                discharged battery in a vehicle at 6.7&#176;C (+20&#176;F) might read 1.250 indicating it was almost
                fully charged. However, when the correction factor is applied, the true value is only 1.226. Electrolyte
                frequently reaches 43&#176;C (100&#176;F) in service in warm weather. The 1.235 specific gravity reading
                might indicate too low a state of charge to install in a vehicle or that there is a problem in the
                electrical system if the battery is in service. However, the true reading of 1.246 may not be
                unreasonably low depending on the length of storage of the battery or the type of service which it has
                been experiencing in the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
