<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GENERAL INSTRUMENT ELECTRONIC PROGRAMMABLE SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER - TEST 7 - SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER UNIT
        SELF DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TEST 7 - SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER UNIT SELF DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This test includes more complete self-test diagnostics than are performed in TEST 1. The
                speedometer/tachometer unit contains (4) serviceable (replaceable) components: the housing (includes the
                printed circuit board), the speedometer, tachometer and odometer (
                <hotlnk document="s08033_9.xml" xrefid="f0803308">Figure 8</hotlnk>). This test will determine which
                component(s) is defective and can be replaced without replacing the complete speedometer/tachometer
                unit.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Prior To Performing The Diagnostics Process:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The speedometer/tachometer unit must be removed from the instrument panel to perform
                    this test and all connections to vehicle wire harness disconnected (
                    <xref refid="x0803301"/>
                    <hotlnk document="s08033_6.xml" xrefid="x0803301">REMOVE AND INSTALL</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Write Down All Dip Switch Positions On The Speedometer/Tachometer Unit. The Positions Will Be
                        Either "1" Or "0" For Each Switch (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0803319">Figure 19</hotlnk>). There Are (2) Sets Of (10) Switches. Verify That
                        They Are Recorded Correctly Before Going On To Next Step.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0803319" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803319" filename="../figg08/g0803319.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Speedometer/Tachometer DIP Switches</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPEEDOMETER AND TACHOMETER DIP SWITCHES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set ALL DIP SWITCHES to the "0" position. If they are not set to "0" the following will
                    occur:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Odometer will not increment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The gauge pointer(s) will rotate up-scale and remain there on a gauge with a faulty DIP
                    switch or one that the DIP switch was not set at "0".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the Cluster Test Harness to the speedometer/tachometer unit (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0803320">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT PLUG INTO POWER SOURCE AT THIS TIME!</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0803320" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803320" filename="../figg08/g0803320.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Attaching Cluster Test Harness</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER UNIT CONNECT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CLUSTER DATA LINK CONNECTOR TO MATING TEST HARNESS CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CONNECT CLUSTER TACHOMETER SENSOR CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (HAS (1) FEMALE
                        TERMINAL)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CIGAR LIGHTER JACK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CONNECT CLUSTER SPEEDOMETER CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (HAS (3) FEMALE TERMINALS)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>6. MOMENTARY PUSH SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. CONNECT CLUSTER TWO SPEED CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (MUST BE CONNECTED EVEN IF THE
                        VEHICLE DOES NOT HAVE 2-SPEED AXLE)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0803321">Figure 21</hotlnk>
                    is a circuit diagram of the Cluster Test Harness. Refer to
                    <xref refid="x0803306"/>
                    <hotlnk document="s08033_27.xml" xrefid="x0803306">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                    for part number.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0803321" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803321" filename="../figg08/g0803321.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Cluster Test Harness Circuit Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Performing The Diagnostic Test:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To begin the diagnostic test requires that your depress the MOMENTARY PUSH SWITCH
                    repeatedly (at least 3 times) as rapidly as possible IMMEDIATELY (within 1 second) after inserting
                    the POWER PLUG into the cigar lighter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the cluster
                    <emph type="bold">is not defective</emph>, the speedometer and tachometer pointers will:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate in unison to the "0" position on the gauge face.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both pointers will then rotate in unison up-scale in ten equal steps to full scale
                        (85 mph/3500 RPM).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both pointers will then rotate in unison down-scale back to the "0" position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">As the speedometer and tachometer gauge pointers advance 10 steps in sequence b.
                        above the odometer will advance .1 mile for each of the 10 steps (1 mile up and then 1 mile
                        down).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The diagnostic process will continue to cycle as described until power is removed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If during the test, the speedometer or tachometer pointers or the odometer do operate
                    through the range as described above in Step 2:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove power and restart the test as instructed in Step 1 to be certain that the
                        start-up process was done properly. If after rerunning the test the speedometer, tachometer or
                        odometer do not operate as described in Step 2 review the following defective performance
                        indicators.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>If more than one of the 3 meters fails to properly move through the described range of movement in
                Diagnostic Test, Step 2 replace the unit housing.
            </para>
            <para>ANALYZING SPEEDOMETER PERFORMANCE DURING TEST CYCLE</para>
            <para>If during the test cycle:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">TACHOMETER POINTER advances correctly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step
                    2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ODOMETER increments properly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step 2.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SPEEDOMETER pointer is DEAD STILL or does not go through correct range of actions
                    described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove speedometer/tachometer unit face plate (see
                    <xref refid="x0803301"/>
                    <hotlnk document="s08033_6.xml" xrefid="x0803301">REMOVE AND INSTALL</hotlnk>) and switch the
                    speedometer and tachometer gauges in the unit and rerun the diagnostic test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the speedometer gauge operates properly in the tachometer position and the tachometer
                    doesn't operate properly in the speedometer position REPLACE the unit housing and retest to verify.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the Speedometer doesn't operate properly in the tachometer position BUT the
                    tachometer operates in the speedometer position, REPLACE the speedometer gauge and retest to verify.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>ANALYZING TACHOMETER PERFORMANCE</para>
            <para>If during diagnostic the test cycle:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SPEEDOMETER POINTER advances correctly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step
                    2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ODOMETER increments properly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step 2.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">TACHOMETER pointer is DEAD STILL or does not go through correct range of actions
                    described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove speedometer/tachometer unit face plate (see
                    <xref refid="x0803301"/>
                    <hotlnk document="s08033_6.xml" xrefid="x0803301">REMOVE AND INSTALL</hotlnk>) and switch the
                    speedometer and tachometer gauges in the unit and rerun the diagnostic test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the tachometer gauge operates properly in the speedometer position and the tachometer
                    doesn't operate properly in the speedometer position REPLACE the unit housing and retest to verify.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the tachometer doesn't operate properly in the speedometer position BUT the
                    speedometer operates in the tachometer position, REPLACE the tachometer gauge and retest to verify.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>ANALYZING ODOMETER PERFORMANCE</para>
            <para>If during diagnostic the test cycle:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SPEEDOMETER POINTER advances correctly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step
                    2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">TACHOMETER POINTER advances correctly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step
                    2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ODOMETER does not increment properly as described in Performing Diagnostic Test, Step
                    2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove odometer from speedometer/tachometer unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">MOMENTARILY apply 12 volt DC power across odometer leads. Each time power is applied,
                    the odometer should increment.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the odometer increments with power applied, REPLACE the speedometer/tachometer
                        housing and retest to verify.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the odometer does not increment, REPLACE the odometer and retest to verify.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>ANALYZING THE SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER UNIT HOUSING</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If during the Diagnostic Test the speedometer AND tachometer gauge pointers both only go
                    to 2/3 scale simultaneously, and the odometer increments with each sweep, then there is a problem
                    with the ATA data link circuitry. REPLACE the housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
