<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY CS-130 SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Trouble in the vehicle charging system will be indicated by one of the following conditions:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Undercharged or overcharged batteries.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Short life of light bulbs or other electrical equipment caused by abnormally high system
                        voltage.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>System voltmeter readings outside normal range.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>These conditions can be caused by:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Defective batteries.</para>
                    <para>Since the batteries may have an internal defect, they must be checked to determine their
                        condition. Refer to Group 08, BATTERY section of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for battery
                        test procedure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor circuit connections.</para>
                    <para>Poor circuit connections in the charging system can cause an undercharged condition only.
                        Carefully inspect all connections including ground between the alternator and battery for
                        cleanliness and tightness. Insure that the battery terminals are clean and tight and that the
                        batteries are dry and clean.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A defective alternator assembly.</para>
                    <para>If the battery and circuit connection checks are satisfactory, the alternator assembly should
                        or may be tested on the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>With the engine turned off, connect test equipment to charging system. Refer to Figure 5 for test
                equipment hookups as described in the following steps.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>VOLTAGE TEST</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Detach wiring harness connector from alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect negative (-) lead of a voltmeter to ground and the positive (+) lead to the "I"
                    terminal in the harness connector.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the voltmeter indicates battery voltage with the key on, the harness is okay.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the voltmeter indicates low or no voltage, locate and repair the poor connection
                        or open circuit between the batteries and the wiring harness connector.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect harness connector to alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery load tester to the alternator output terminal and ground, or battery
                    leads (alternator preferred).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Alternator output terminal is at battery voltage.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record voltage reading at load tester.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With all system electrical loads off, start engine and run at moderate speed (rpm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recheck and record voltage reading on load tester. Voltage should be higher than reading
                    in step 5 above, but below 15 volts. All International alternators are set at 14.2 volts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If reading (step 7) is lower than previous reading (step 5), or higher than 15 volts, replace the
                alternator.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08019_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08019_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
