<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The symptoms listed in this section relate to specific events rather than specific diagnostic codes.
                It is still a necessary first step to read (and note) any active or inactive diagnostic codes.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Will Not Start (Will Not Crank)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the following checks. If no defects are found, proceed to Step 2.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Shift Selector not in "N."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check vehicle starting system cables and wires for clean, tight connections. Check
                        circuit 136 connection to B+ terminal of crank motor solenoid for clean, tight connection.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check battery state-of-charge.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check ECU battery and ignition voltage and ECU grounds by performing TEST 1. If defects
                    are noted when performing this test, perform additional tests as directed (TESTS 1A, 1B, OR 1C).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery and ignition voltage to ECU are to specifications and the ground circuits
                        check good, proceed to Step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects were noted in battery, ignition or ground circuits to ECU, correct
                        defects and retest start system.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 2 - TESTING NEUTRAL START SYSTEM.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">IF neutral start system checks good, proceed to Step 4.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects were noted in neutral start system, correct defects and test for proper
                        engine starting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the Shift Selector circuits by performing TEST 3. (The shift selector may not be
                    communicating properly to the ECU that the shift selector is in the neutral position.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If shift selector circuits check good, go to Step 5.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects are noted in shift circuits, correct condition and test for proper engine
                        starting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the Shift Selector operation using the Pro-link DDR. If a Pro-Link DDR is not
                    available, and the shift selector circuits checked good (Step 4), replace the shift selector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the no-start condition is still present after performing steps 1 through 5, have an
                    Allison dealer continue the diagnosis.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"DO NOT SHIFT" Light Will Not Go Out At Startup</title>
            <para>The "Do Not Shift" light should be illuminated when the key is turned to the ON position and then go
                out when the vehicle is started. If a diagnostic code is registered because of a condition detected by
                the ECU that will "inhibit" transmission operation, the shift light should illuminate (refer to
                diagnostic code list for those codes that cause the "Do Not Shift" Light to illuminate).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine if transmission operation is inhibited.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If transmission operation is inhibited and diagnostic code is present, perform
                        diagnostics as indicated by the code.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If transmission is not inhibited, go to Step 2.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 4 - TESTING DO NOT SHIFT LIGHT GROUND CIRCUIT TO ECU.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ground circuit to ECU is defective, make necessary repairs.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ground circuit to ECU is not defective, have Allison dealer diagnose the ECU for
                        proper operation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"Do Not Shift" Warning Light Does Not Illuminate During Startup.</title>
            <para>Perform TEST 4 - TESTING THE DO NOT SHIFT LIGHT CIRCUIT.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Light Dimmer Does Not Control Electronic Shifter Light Intensity.</title>
            <para>Perform TEST 5 - TESTING PANEL LIGHT VOLTAGE TO ECU</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Backup Lights (Reverse Warning) Do Not Function.</title>
            <para>If power to the backup lights is not present at Junction Block J4-4, perform TEST 5 - TESTING BACKUP
                LIGHT RELAY SYSTEM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Speedometer Fails To Operate.</title>
            <para>If the speedometer fails to operate (tachometer operates normally) and the input signal is suspected,
                check for diagnostic codes from the ECU first.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no codes are present, perform TEST 7 - TEST FOR SPEEDOMETER SIGNAL FROM ECU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If codes are present refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800303.xml" xrefid="x0800303">TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC
                        CODES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WITH ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - If Transmission Will Not Go Into "Lockup" Mode (Or Transmission Retarder Will
                Not Engage If Equipped).
            </title>
            <para>If no diagnostic codes are present, check the ABS interface circuit by performing TEST 8 - TESTING WT
                TRANSMISSION TO ABS BRAKE CIRCUIT.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two-Speed Axle (Air Operated) With Allison WT</title>
            <para>The two-speed axle range is controlled the WT electronic control system by applying (or removing)
                voltage to the axle solenoid, which is a normally closed solenoid. Without voltage applied the axle
                solenoid is closed (no air applied to axle) and the axle will operate in low range. When voltage is
                applied to the solenoid, the solenoid energizes and air pressure through the solenoid causes the axle to
                shift to the high range.
            </para>
            <para>If the two-speed axle only operates in the low range, perform TEST 9.</para>
            <para>If the two-speed axle only operates in the high range, perform TEST 10.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Williams Blue Ox Exhaust Brake</title>
            <para>Engine brake application is controlled the WT electronic control system by applying (or removing)
                voltage to the exhaust brake air solenoid, which is a normally closed solenoid. Without voltage applied
                the exhaust brake air solenoid is closed (exhaust brake not applied). When voltage is applied to the
                solenoid, the solenoid energizes and air pressure through the solenoid causes the exhaust brake to
                operate.
            </para>
            <para>If the exhaust brake does not activate with the exhaust brake switch in the ON position, perform TEST
                11.
            </para>
            <para>If the exhaust brake operates with the exhaust brake switch in the ON position, perform TEST 12.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800303.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
