<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - OPERATION - FUEL LEVEL GAUGE, LIGHT, AND ALARM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0803511" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FUEL LEVEL GAUGE, LIGHT, AND ALARM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The input signal to the Speedo/Tach module for the fuel level gauge (and warning light and alarm)
                comes from the fuel gauge sender.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Gauge Sender</title>
            <para>The fuel gauge sender, located in the fuel tank, receives 12 volts from the Speedo/Tach module on
                circuit 36. The gauge sender is grounded through circuit 36-G to the J4 cab ground. The gauge acts like
                a variable resistor. When the fuel level is high, resistance is high and when the fuel level is low,
                resistance is low. This change in resistance creates the signal for the Speedo/Tach module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Level Gauge</title>
            <para>The Speedo/Tach module processes the signal from the sender and outputs signals to drive the gauge
                through connector (422) on circuits 36S(+), 36S(-), 36C(+) and 36C(-) to the right gauge cluster at
                connector (420). The fuel level gauge is a 4-pin electronically driven gauge that plugs into the gauge
                cluster.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Warning Light</title>
            <para>The fuel level warning light should turn ON and remain on as a bulb test, while the gauges go through
                the self test process with key ON and engine OFF.
            </para>
            <para>The low fuel warning light in the right gauge cluster receives ignition voltage (key ON) through
                cluster connector (420) from 10A fuse F4-A. The warning light ground path is through cluster connector
                (420) on circuit 36L to the Speedo/Tach module connector (421). In response to a fuel gauge sender input
                indicating the fuel level is less than 1/8 full, the module closes a ground switch causing the light to
                turn ON. The light remains ON as long as the fuel level is less than 1/8 of the tank.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm</title>
            <para>In response to sensor or ECM inputs indicating that fuel level is less than 1/8 capacity, the
                Speedo/Tach module causes the alarm to sound. The alarm will sound five short beeps when the low fuel
                light turns ON. The alarm is an internal feature of the Speedo/Tach module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm And Warning Light Trip Points</title>
            <para>The Speedo/Tach module is programmed to report low fuel (warning light and alarm). This trip point may
                be changed or turned OFF using the Pro-Link 9000 electronic service tool.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
