<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 10-SI SERIES, TYPE 116 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>A typical wiring diagram of the alternator is illustrated in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0801203">Figure 3</hotlnk>. The basic operating principles are explained as follows:
        </para>
        <figure id="f0801203" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0801203" filename="../figg08/G0801203.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Diagram of Internal Circuits</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. STATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>2. FIELD (ROTOR)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. REGULATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>4. RESISTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>5. SWITCH</callout1>
                <callout1>6. VOLTMETER</callout1>
                <callout1>7. BATTERY</callout1>
                <callout1>8. DIODE TRIO</callout1>
                <callout1>9. RECTIFIER BRIDGE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The No. 2 terminal is connected to the battery, and the base-emitter of transistors TR3 and TR1 is
            connected to the battery through resistor R5, thus turning these transistors on. Also, resistors R2 and R3
            are connected to the battery through terminal No 2, but the discharge current of the battery is very low
            because of the resistance values of R2, R3, R5, TR1 and TR3.
        </para>
        <para>When the switch is closed, current from the battery flows through the resistor to the No. 1 terminal,
            through resistor R1, and transistor TR3 and TR1 to ground, and then back to the battery. Also, current flows
            through the alternator field coil and TR1 back to the battery.
        </para>
        <para>With the alternator operating, A.C. voltages are generated in the stator windings, and the stator supplies
            D.C. field current through the diode trio, the field, TR1, and then through the grounded diodes in the
            rectifier bridge back to the stator. Also, the six diodes in the rectifier bridge change the stator A.C.
            voltages to a D.C. voltage which appears between ground and the alternator "BAT" terminal. As alternator
            speed increases, current is provided for charging the battery and operating electrical accessories. Also,
            with the alternator operating, the same voltage appears at the "BAT" and No. 1 terminals, and the voltmeter
            indicates that the alternator is producing voltage.
        </para>
        <para>If an open occurs in the No. 2 terminal circuit, TR3 and TR1 will turn off and no field current will flow
            to prevent overcharge. As the alternator speed and voltage increase, the voltage between R2 and R3 increases
            to the point where zener diode D1 conducts. Transistor TR2 then turns on and TR3 and TR1 turn off. With TR1
            off, the field current and system voltage decrease, and D1 then blocks current flow, causing TR3 and TR1 to
            turn back on. The field current and system voltage increase and this cycle then repeats many times per
            second to limit the output voltage to a preset value.
        </para>
        <para>Capacitor C1 smooths out the voltage across R3, resistor R4 prevents excessive current through TR1 at high
            temperatures, and diode D2 prevents high-induced-voltages in the field windings when TR1 turns off.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
