<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - WILLIAMS BLUE OX ENGINE BRAKE
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WILLIAMS BLUE OX ENGINE BRAKE OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Operation</title>
            <para>The Williams Blue Ox exhaust brake is available with the Allison WT transmission and International DT
                engines. The engine brake system uses spare output #4. This includes using spare input circuits, special
                function relay #4 (SF-4) and spare output #4. There are four major control components in this system:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The engine brake ON/OFF switch. The switch is a two-pole, single throw switch. One pole
                    provides the input signal (spare input) to the WT ECU and the other pole completes the circuit to
                    the exhaust brake air solenoid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The exhaust brake air solenoid (normally closed - closed when voltage is not applied).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The special function output relay #4 (SF-4) located in the VIM.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Allison WT ECU.</para>
                <para>The Williams Blue Ox exhaust brake is activated by turning the engine brake switch ON. Closing the
                    on/off switch completes the circuit between ECU terminal B29 (signal source) and ECU terminal B27
                    (signal ground). This tells the WT ECU that the engine brake switch is ON. The WT ECU will then
                    determine:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When the throttle is closed (using the throttle position sensor information).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When the transmission is in lockup mode of operation.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When these two conditions are present, a user-specified preselected shift schedule will
                    go into effect and the spare function relay #4 (SF-4) will be energized (WT ECU ground switch closes
                    grounding SF-4 relay circuit 125), which delivers power to energize the exhaust brake solenoid and
                    apply air pressure to the engine brake system.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Brake System Circuit Operation</title>
            <para>The circuit operation of the exhaust brake system is as follows:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the key is ON, ignition voltage from fuse F2 is applied to SF-4 relay, terminal 30.
                    Ignition voltage is also applied from the IGN fuse (located in VIM) to SF-4 relay, terminal 86.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The engine brake ON/OFF switch is a two-pole switch. With the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch
                    in the ON position (as shown in circuit diagram), it signals to the WT ECU that the engine brake is
                    in the ON position by closing the circuit between ECU terminals B29 (signal) and B27 (signal
                    ground).
                </para>
                <para>The other pole of the engine brake ON/OFF switch (in the ON position) completes the path between
                    SF-4 relay (terminal 87) and the exhaust brake air solenoid.
                </para>
                <para>The SF-4 relay is energized when a ground switch located in the ECU closes (when the conditions
                    discussed earlier are present). With the relay energized, voltage from F2 fuse goes through the
                    relay (terminal 30 to 87) then through the engine brake ON/OFF switch and to the exhaust brake air
                    solenoid.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
