<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9200, 9300, 9400 Models Built After January 1, 1995 - ELECTRICAL
        TROUBLESHOOTING CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Electric Window - Right
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electric Window - Right</title>
        <para>Refer to ELECTRIC WINDOW - RIGHT circuit diagram in CTS-5119S. The right side electric window is
            controlled by the driver's right side window switch. To operate the window, the key must be in the or
            position. The circuit includes the electric window relay (145), window switch (439) and the right window
            motor.
        </para>
        <para>Power to the window switch is supplied from the B1 battery stud to the common terminal (30) of the window
            relay (145). With the key in the or position, the relay is energized applying power to terminal 4 (and
            internally to terminal 3) at the electric window switch (439). Note that switch terminals 4 and 3 are always
            12V (key ON) and terminals 1 and 6 are always ground.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Window Down Operation</title>With the window switch in the down position, power from switch terminal
            5 is applied to the motor on circuit 83D. Circuit 83C from the motor to the switch terminal 2 becomes the
            ground circuit. With the switch in the down position, switch terminals 2 and 1 are connected, completing the
            path to ground.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Window Up Operation</title>With the window switch in the up position, power from switch terminal 2 is
            applied to the motor on circuit 83C. Circuit 83D from the motor to the switch terminal 5 becomes the ground
            circuit. With the switch in the up position, switch terminals 5 and 6 are connected, completing the path to
            ground.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
