<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9200, 9300, 9400 Models Built After January 1, 1995 - ELECTRICAL
        TROUBLESHOOTING LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION - HEADLIGHT SWITCH AND DIMMER SWITCH WIRING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HEADLIGHT SWITCH AND DIMMER SWITCH WIRING</title>
        <para>The headlight switch and dimmer switch wiring circuits along with the headlight relay, all covered in this
            section, regulate power to the headlights, tail lights, marker lights, fog lights and daytime running light
            circuits. When the headlight switch is placed in accessory or (ignition) position, power is available from
            B2 battery stud, through circuit 14H, 14D, fuse F8-A, circuit 50, headlights switch (465), and circuit 58E
            to the cab and trailer lights switch.
        </para>
        <para>If headlight switch is placed in (ignition) position, power is available from B2 battery stud, through
            circuit 14H, 14B, fuse F3-D, and circuit 50A to the headlights switch (465). If the headlight switch is ON,
            current will flow through the switch and circuit 50B to energize the headlight relay (462-R4). Circuits
            50-GB and 11-G complete the ground circuit.
        </para>
        <para>With the headlight relay energized, current flows from B2 battery stud, through circuit 14H, 14D, fuse
            F8-B, circuit 51, headlight relay (462-R4), and circuit 51A, to dimmer switch (42). In vehicles without
            daytime running lights (DRL), with the dimmer switch in the low position, current will flow through circuit
            53B to the headlamps, then the current will flow through circuit 52-GE, 52-GF, and 11-GF to ground stud at
            left dash panel. With the dimmer switch in the high position, current will flow through circuit 52F to the
            headlamps, then the current will flow through circuit 52-GE, 52-GF, and 11-GF to ground stud at left dash
            panel.
        </para>
        <para>With the USA DRL system, with the headlight switch OFF, power flows from the DRL module through circuit
            66B, 64C, and 53B to the headlamps. Current then flows from the headlamps in circuit 52-GF and 11-GF to the
            ground stud at the left dash panel.
        </para>
        <para>With the Canadian DRL system, with the headlight switch OFF, power flows from the DRL circuitry and
            circuits 66J, and 52-GE to the headlamps. Current then flows from the headlamps in circuit 52-GF, and 52-GD
            to J7 cab ground on 9300 model.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_187.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_189.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
