<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 21-SI SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING - RATED OUTPUT CHECK</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0801703" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>RATED OUTPUT CHECK</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Failure to disconnect negative battery cable at battery before removing or attaching alternator
                    "BAT" terminal lead may result in personal injury. If a tool is shorted at alternator "BAT"
                    terminal, the tool can quickly heat enough to cause a skin burn.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>With the engine turned off, connect test equipment to charging system. Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0801706">Figure 6</hotlnk>
            for test equipment hookups as described in the following steps.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0801706" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0801706" filename="../figg08/G0801706.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>System Check</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BATTERY LOAD TESTER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. ALTERNATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. VOLTMETER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With engine running at a moderate speed (rpm), turn carbon pile on and adjust to obtain
                maximum amperage output without allowing voltage on the battery load tester voltmeter to drop below 13
                volts. Record maximum ampere output on battery load tester ammeter.
            </para>
            <para>Maximum ampere output should be within 15 amps of output rating stamped next to part number on
                alternator end frame, or as listed in
                <hotlnk document="s08017j_31.xml" xrefid="hl0801704">SPECIFICATIONS
                    <xref refid="hl0801704"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>If alternator speed was 5000 rpm or higher and output was not within 15 amps of rating, repair or replace
            alternator.
        </para>
        <para>If reading is within 15 amps of rating and voltage is less than 15 volts, alternator is good.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the engine off, the ignition switch on, and the wire disconnected from the "I"
                terminal, check the voltage at the "I" terminal end of the wire. The voltage will be less than battery
                voltage as the wire from the "I" terminal to the engine side of the dash connector is a resistance wire
                with between 10 and 20 ohms built in. If no voltage is present, check the "I" terminal circuit for cause
                of voltage loss (resistor wire may be bad). Correct as necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the battery load tester to the alternator output terminal and ground, or battery
                leads (alternator preferred).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Alternator output terminal is at battery voltage.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Record voltage reading at load tester.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With all system electrical loads off, start engine and run at moderate speed (rpm).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recheck and record voltage reading on load tester. Voltage should be higher than reading in
                step 4 above, but below 15 volts. All 21-SI alternators are set at 14.2 volts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>If reading (step 6) is lower than previous reading (step 4), or higher than 15 volts, refer to section on
            <hotlnk document="s08017j_8.xml" xrefid="hl0801702">REPAIR PROCEDURES
                <xref refid="hl0801702"/>
            </hotlnk>
            . If the reading is between 13 and 15 volts, proceed with the following tests.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect a voltmeter from the alternator output (BAT) terminal to battery positive terminal
                (you may need a jumper wire to extend your voltmeter leads).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Load charging system with carbon pile to obtain 100 amps of current. Record the positive (+)
                voltage reading on the voltmeter. Turn carbon pile off.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect voltmeter leads from the alternator case to ground. Load charging system with carbon
                pile to obtain 100 amps of current. Record negative (-) voltage in ground circuit between alternator
                housing and ground. Turn carbon pile off.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The total voltage drop in the two readings must be less than 1 volt. If the volt difference
                between the two readings is greater than 1 volt, check system wiring and ground. Repair as necessary.
                Rerun test steps 7 through 9 to verify system is repaired.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08017j.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
