<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - DESCRIPTION - DIAGNOSTIC TELLTALES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC TELLTALES</title>
        <para>Several diagnostic features are included in the electronic control system to assist in troubleshooting
            malfunctions and/or to monitor specific operating parameters. These features include a "DO NOT SHIFT" LIGHT
            on the instrument panel and the Data Link Connector for using a Diagnostic Data Reader, such as the Pro-Link
            9000. When a malfunction is detected in the control system, a series of "diagnostic codes" are used to
            identify and clarify the nature of the malfunction.
        </para>
        <para>"DO NOT SHIFT" LIGHT - The red DO NOT SHIFT light is located in the instrument cluster. A system check is
            performed when turning the ignition key to the ON position to start the vehicle. The DO NOT SHIFT light is
            activated until the vehicle is started, then it will deactivate, unless a system fault is detected by the
            ECU.
        </para>
        <para>If a system fault that inhibits the transmission operation is detected by the ECU, the DO NOT SHIFT light
            will illuminate, accompanied by eight seconds of short beeps from the shift selector, indicating that
            transmission shifts are being restricted. The SELECT digit on the shift display will be blank. Vehicle
            operation may continue in order to reach service assistance. The ECU may not respond to shift selector
            requests, since operating limitations are being placed on the transmission; i.e., upshifts and downshifts
            may be restricted.
            <emph type="bold">Directional changes (forward to reverse for example) will not occur.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">If the shift lever is moved while DO NOT SHIFT is indicated, a continuous alarm will be
                sounded. The alarm will turn OFF when the lever is moved back into the position where the DO NOT SHIFT
                was first indicated.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>Any time the DO NOT SHIFT light has been illuminated, the ECU will register a diagnostic code. It may be
            identified on the shifter display (discussed in TROUBLESHOOTING) and/or using the Pro-Link service tool.
        </para>
        <para>Minor conditions can occur that will cause a diagnostic code to be registered in the ECU, but will not
            illuminate the DO NOT SHIFT light or restrict transmission operation.
        </para>
        <para>DATA LINK CONNECTOR/DIAGNOSTIC DATA READER (DDR) - The data link connector is used to connect the Pro-Link
            9000 Diagnostic Data Reader (DDR) to the transmission electronic control system. The DDR, diagnostic codes
            and other related information will be discussed in TROUBLESHOOTING in this service manual section.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
