<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - CHARGING - CHARGING INSTRUCTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CHARGING INSTRUCTIONS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before placing a battery on charge, clean the battery terminals if necessary. Add distilled water
                sufficient to cover the plates. Fill to the proper level near the end of charge. If the battery is
                extremely cold, allow it to warm before adding distilled water because the level will rise as it warms.
                In fact, an extremely cold battery will not accept a normal charge until it becomes warm.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>NEVER attempt to charge a frozen battery. Charging a frozen battery could result in an
                        explosion, causing serious personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Following instructions of charger manufacturer, connect charger to battery (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0802209">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0802209" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0802209" filename="../figg08/G0802209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Charging a Battery</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Connect the positive (+) charger lead to positive battery terminal and negative (-) lead to negative
                terminal. If the battery is in the vehicle, connect the negative lead to the engine block if the vehicle
                has a "negative ground" (negative battery terminal is connected to ground). Connect the positive lead to
                ground if vehicle has a "positive ground." "Rock" the charger lead clamps to make certain a good
                connection has been made.
            </para>
            <para>Turn the charger "ON" and slowly increase the charging rate until recommended ampere value is
                reached.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If smoke or dense vapor comes from the battery, shut off the charger and reject the battery.
                        If violent gassing or spewing of electrolyte occurs, reduce or temporarily halt the charging.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the engine does not crank satisfactorily when a battery is reinstalled, load test the battery as
                outlined under
                <hotlnk document="s08022k_15.xml" xrefid="hl0802202">TESTING</hotlnk>. If the battery passes the "Load
                Test," the vehicle's fuel, ignition, cranking and charging systems should be checked to locate and
                correct the problem. If it does not pass the load test, the battery should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Charging Checklist</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a wet cloth over battery vents during charging. Leave all filler plugs in place
                    (if so equipped) and tight during charging and load testing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not attempt to charge a frozen battery. Allow battery to warm to at least 15.5&#176;C
                    (60&#176;F) prior to engaging the charging device.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the charger is "OFF" when connecting charging cables to battery terminals.
                    Disconnect the charger from its power source if this condition cannot be positively determined.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Never break a "live" circuit at the battery terminals, or touch the charger leads when
                    the charger is "ON." This action may cause a spark which could ignite the explosive gases generated
                    during the charging cycle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn battery charger "OFF" prior to disconnecting charging leads.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
