<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GENERAL INSTRUMENT ELECTRONIC PROGRAMMABLE SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER - TEST 6 - SENSOR OUTPUT VOLTAGE TEST (AT
        SENSOR)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>TEST 6 - SENSOR OUTPUT VOLTAGE TEST (AT SENSOR)</title>
        <para>This test checks for proper voltage output at the sensor. Improper sensor adjustment will cause low or no
            voltage condition.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use a voltmeter with sufficient meter lead lengths to avoid contact with rotating shaft or vehicle
                    wheels.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>To test speedometer sensor rear axles are to be on floor stands and transmission In high
                            gear as in TEST 4.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>To test tachometer wheels will be blocked, vehicle park set and transmission will be in
                            neutral as in TEST 4.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>This test requires the use of an AC voltmeter.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0803318">Figure 18</hotlnk>
            for this test.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0803318" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0803318" filename="../figg08/g0803318.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Sensor Output Voltage Test (AC) At Sensor</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. AC VOLTMETER AT 0-10 VOLT RANGE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SENSOR CONNECTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SENSOR</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set AC voltmeter on 0-10 scale. Disconnect sensor unit lead from vehicle harness. Connect
                meter leads across sensor unit connector terminals.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or property damage pay strict attention to the following: Should it be
                    necessary to operate the rear wheels (with engine power) with the vehicle stationary and the rear
                    wheels raised from the ground, first disengage the front axle; otherwise the driving front axle will
                    pull the vehicle off its support. Parking brakes should be applied when the transmission and the
                    transfer case have been left in the neutral position with the engine running or not running.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not use a jack when working under a vehicle. It may give way, causing the vehicle to fall and
                    injure you. Always use floor stands to support the vehicle.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Checking Speedometer Sensor -</emph>
                With vehicle rear axles on floor stands and transmission in neutral, start engine at run at IDLE speed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Checking Tachometer Sensor -</emph>
                With wheels blocked, vehicle park brake set and transmission in neutral, start engine and run at IDLE
                speed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Read Volt meter. Voltage should be 2.0 volts minimum.</para>
            <para>If NO voltage, replace and adjust sensor, then retest to verify.</para>
            <para>If LOW voltage, adjust sensor and retest to verify. If adjustment fails to correct low voltage
                condition, replace sensor and retest to verify.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When defects corrected and verified in TEST 6, return to TEST 3 and rerun. If TEST 3 is not
                successful correct defect in vehicle wire harness between instrument panel connection and sensor.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
