<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 25-SI SERIES, TYPES 400 AND 450 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Typical wiring circuit diagrams for these units is shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0801403">Figure 3</hotlnk>. Basic operating principles are as follows:
        </para>
        <figure id="f0801403" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0801403" filename="../figg08/g0801403.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Negative Ground Circuit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BATTERY</callout1>
                <callout1>2. REGULATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. FIELD COIL</callout1>
                <callout1>4. DIODES</callout1>
                <callout1>5. STATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>6. OUTPUT TERMINAL</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>As the rotor begins to turn, A.C. voltages are generated in the stator windings. The voltages across the
            six diodes cause current to flow to charge the battery.
        </para>
        <para>Current from the stator flows through the three diodes to resistor R6 and the base-emitter of TR2 and TR1
            to turn these transistors on. Current also flows from the stator through the diode trio D1, D2 and D3, the
            field coil and transistor TR1, returning to the stator through the other three diodes. All stator current,
            except through the diode trio D1, D2 and D3, flows through the six diodes connected to the stator.
        </para>
        <para>Current flow through R1, R2 and R3 causes voltage to appear at zener diode D4. When the voltage becomes
            high enough due to increasing generator speed, D4 and the base-emitter of TR3 conduct current and TR3 turns
            on. TR2 and TR1 then turn off, decreasing the field current and the system voltage decreases. The voltage at
            D4 decreases, D4 and TR3 turn off, TR2 and TR1 turn back on and the system voltage increases. This cycle
            then repeats many times per second to limit the system voltage as determined by the setting of the
            potentiometer R2 and R3.
        </para>
        <para>Capacitor C1 protects the generator diodes from high transient voltages and suppresses radio
            interference.
        </para>
        <para>Resistor R5 prevents current leakage through TR3 at high temperatures. Diode D5 prevents high transient
            voltages in the field coil when the field current is decreasing. Resistor R7, capacitor C3 and resistor R4
            all act to cause transistors TR2 and TR1 to turn on and off more quickly.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014_HL0801402.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
