<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - OPERATION - REAR AXLE AND TRANSMISSION TEMPERATURE GAUGES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0803513" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REAR AXLE AND TRANSMISSION TEMPERATURE GAUGES</title>
        <para>The optional rear axle and transmission temperature gauges are 3-pin electrical gauges. The gauges are
            located in the right gauge cluster and they all receive ignition voltage at connector (420) terminal 3,
            circuit 28C, from 10A fuse F4-A. The cluster contains a printed circuit board which the axle and
            transmission temperature gauges plug into.
        </para>
        <para>The "I" gauge terminal for these three gauges receives ignition voltage through the cluster. The "G" gauge
            terminal of these three gauges is grounded through the circuit board and cluster connector (420) on circuits
            11-GJ/11-GQ/11-GF at the ground stud located at the left dash.
        </para>
        <para>The "S" gauge terminal of these gauges is connected to the gauge sender as follows:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The "S" terminal of the
                <emph type="bold">forward rear axle gauge</emph>
                is connected through connector (420) terminal 20 to the gauge sender. The gauge sender is grounded
                through the axle housing, which is grounded through circuit 32-G to J4 cab ground.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The "S" terminal of the
                <emph type="bold">rear rear axle gauge</emph>
                is connected through connector (420) terminal 19 to the gauge sender. The gauge sender is grounded
                through the axle housing, which is grounded through circuit 32-GA to J4 cab ground.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The "S" terminal of the
                <emph type="bold">transmission gauge</emph>
                is connected through connector (420) terminal 18 to the gauge sender. The transmission gauge sender is
                grounded through circuit 31-G to the engine ground stud.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>The temperature gauge sender for the axle and transmission acts like a variable resistor. When the oil
            temperature is high, resistance is LOW and when the oil temperature is low, resistance is HIGH. The change
            in circuit resistance provides the input to the gauge.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
