<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 10-SI SERIES, TYPE 116 - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0801202" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <para>Following the procedures in the order presented will lead to the location and correction of charging
            system defects in the shortest possible time. Usually, only a portion of these procedures need be performed.
            It is seldom necessary to perform all the procedures to locate the problem.
        </para>
        <para>To avoid damage to the electrical equipment, always observe the following precautions:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Do not polarize the alternator.</emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Do not short across or ground any of the terminals in the charging circuit except as specifically
                    instructed in this section.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Never operate the alternator with the output terminal open circuited.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Make sure the alternator and battery have the same ground polarity.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When connecting a charger or a booster battery to the vehicle battery, connect negative to
                    negative and positive to positive.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>Trouble in the charging system will show up as one of the following conditions:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>An undercharged battery, as evidenced by slow specific gravity readings.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>An overcharged battery, as evidenced by excessive water usage.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>To locate cause of trouble, proceed as outlined below:</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The following checks must be performed before removing alternator from vehicle.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insure that an undercharged condition has not been caused by accessories having been left on
                for extended periods.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the drive belt for proper tension.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Test condition of battery. Recharge or replace battery as needed. Refer TO GROUP 08, BATTERY
                section in the Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the wiring for defects. Check all connections for tightness and cleanliness,
                including the slip connectors at the alternator and engine cowl plus the cable clamps and battery posts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With ignition switch on and all wiring harness leads connected, connect a voltmeter from:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Alternator "BAT" terminal to ground.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Alternator No. 1 terminal to ground.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Alternator No. 2 terminal to ground.</para>
                <para>A zero reading indicates an open between voltmeter connection and battery. Repair if required.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With all accessories turned off, connect a voltmeter across the battery. Operate engine at
                moderate speed. If voltage is 15.5 volts or more, remove alternator for repair.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If previous Steps 1 thru 6 check out satisfactory, check alternator as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery ground cable.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect an ammeter in the circuit at the "BAT" terminal of the alternator.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Reconnect battery ground cable.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn on accessories. Connect a carbon pile across the battery.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Operate engine at moderate speed as required, and adjust carbon pile as required to
                    obtain maximum current output.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If ampere output is within 10 amperes of rated output as stamped on alternator frame,
                    alternator most likely is not defective; re-check Steps 1 thru 6.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If ampere output is not within 10 amperes of rated output, determine if test hole (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0801204">Figure 4</hotlnk>) is accessible. If accessible, go to Step H. If not
                    accessible go to Step l.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Ground the field winding by inserting a screwdriver into the test hole (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0801204">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0801204" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0801204" filename="../figg08/g0801204.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>End Frame Test Hole</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. END FRAME HOLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. TAB</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Tab is within 3/4 inch of casting surface. Do not force screwdriver deeper than one inch
                            into end frame as damage to the alternator could result.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Operate engine at moderate speed as required, and adjust carbon pile as required to
                    obtain maximum current output.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If output is within 10 amperes of rated output, as stamped on alternator frame,
                    alternator is good.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If output is not within 10 amperes of rated output, check the field winding, diode trio,
                    rectifier bridge, and stator as covered in
                    <hotlnk document="s08012_4.xml" xrefid="hl0801203">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If test hole is not accessible, disassemble alternator and make tests listed in
                    <hotlnk document="s08012_4.xml" xrefid="hl0801203">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
