<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STARTING MOTORS - ARMATURE SERVICING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ARMATURE SERVICING</title>
        <para>If the armature is worn, dirty, out of round, or has high insulation, the armature should be put in a
            lathe so the commutator can be turned down. The insulation should then be undercut 1/32 (.79375 mm) of an
            inch wide and 1/32 (.79375 mm) of an inch deep,and the slots cleaned out to remove any trace of dirt or
            copper dust. As a final step, the commutator should be sanded lightly with No.00 sandpaper.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The undercut operation must be omitted on cranking motors having Test Specifications 7104, 7113,
                    2412, 2415, 3501, 3564,3574 and 3599 as listed in
                    <hotlnk document="s08036_HL0803602.xml" xrefid="hl0803602">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>. DO NOT undercut
                    commutators on motors having these specifications.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The armature should be checked for opens, short circuits and grounds as follows:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Opens - Opens are usually caused by excessively long cranking periods. The most likely place
                for an open is at the commutator riser bars. Inspect for loose connections at the points where the
                conductors are joined to the commutator bars. Poor connections cause arcing and burning of the
                commutator bars. If the bars are not too badly burned, they can often be repaired by welding the leads
                in the riser bars (use rosin flux), and turning down the commutator in a lathe to remove the burned
                material. The insulation should then be undercut except as noted above.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Short Circuits - Short circuits in the armature are located with a growler. The armature is
                revolved with a steel strip (such as a hacksaw blade) held above it. The steel strip will vibrate above
                a short circuit location in the armature core. Shorts between the bars are sometimes caused by brush
                dust or copper between the bars. These shorts can be eliminated by cleaning out the slots.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Grounds - Grounds in the armature can be detected by the use of an ohmmeter. If resistance
                is shown one test point is placed on each commutator section and the other point on the core or shaft,
                the armature is grounded. Grounds occur as a result of insulation failure. This is often caused by
                overheating as the result of excessive over-cranking or by the accumulation of dust between the
                commutator bars and the steel commutator ring.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
