<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 26-SI SERIES - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>The voltage regulator limits the maximum voltage that the alternator will produce at the output battery
            terminal by controlling the magnetic field present in the rotor. The voltage produced allows enough current
            flow to satisfy the electrical loads placed on the system, up to a maximum current that the alternator is
            designed to provide.
        </para>
        <para>The system voltage will be maintained at the regulator set point unless the electrical load demand exceeds
            the capability of the alternator at that voltage. If that occurs, the system voltage will reduce and current
            demand increases. If the demand is so great that the system voltage falls below battery voltage, the battery
            will discharge to supplement the current needed to meet the demands of the system.
        </para>
        <para>A schematic of the alternator circuitry is shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0801803">Figure 3</hotlnk>. With the rotor turning, magnetic fields around the rotor induce
            voltages in the stator winding. The faster the rotor turns, the higher the induced voltage will be. The
            initial voltages will be generated by residual magnetism in the rotor.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0801803" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0801803" filename="../figg08/g0801803.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Alternator Circuitry</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. REGULATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>2. DIODE TRIO</callout1>
                <callout1>3. RECTIFIER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>4. STATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>5. FIELD COIL</callout1>
                <callout1>6. CONDENSER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>As speed and output increase, voltage available at the diode trio becomes sufficient to supply field
            current for normal operation. When the output voltage exceeds the battery voltage, the alternator begins to
            drive the system voltage.
        </para>
        <para>When the system voltage is below the voltage regulator setting, the regulator turns on the field current
            through the rotor and allows the alternator to produce as much output as possible for the alternator speed
            (rpm), temperature, and system voltage. When the voltage setting is reached, the regulator turns the field
            current off. When the field current is turned off, the magnetic field in the rotor collapses and the output
            voltage begins to fall. The falling voltage causes the regulator to turn the field current back on and the
            magnetic field to rebuild. This switching action of the regulator continues rapidly, keeping the output and
            system voltage very close to the voltage setting.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
