<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - OPERATION - TACHOMETER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x080356a" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TACHOMETER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Speed Sensor (Mechanical Engines Only)</title>
            <para>The engine speed signal is generated by the engine speed sensor (111) located in the flywheel housing.
                This sensor contains a permanent magnet that creates a magnetic field. The sensor is mounted so that the
                magnetic field is repeatedly broken by the flywheel teeth. As the field is broken, an AC (alternating
                current) pulse is generated.
            </para>
            <para>This signal is sent on circuits 48A and 48B to the Speedo/Tach module through connector (421).</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Speed Signal With Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>The Caterpillar, Cummins and Detroit Diesel electronic control systems include a sensor to determine
                engine speed, so the information is in the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends a signal in the form of a serial data transmission over the ATA data link circuit (a
                positive and negative pair of twisted wires) to the Speedo/Tach module through connector (421). The
                signal is also present at the ATA data link connector (137) and engine speed can be read using an
                electronic service tool (EST) connected to the data link. For additional information on the data link,
                refer to GROUP 08, Electronic Engine Controls, in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tachometer Gauge</title>
            <para>The Speedo/Tach control module processes the input signal and drives the 4-pin electronic tachometer
                gauge that plugs into the module. The speedometer and tachometer gauges are essentially the same except
                for the gauge markings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
