<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - BATTERY REMOVAL AND INSTALLATION - INSTALLATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTALLATION</title>
        <para>When replacing the battery, make sure that battery to be installed has sufficient capacity to cover the
            electrical requirements of the vehicle. Use of an under-capacity battery will result in poor performance and
            premature battery failure. The original equipment battery can be used as a minimal guide, but is often
            misleading since the vehicle owner may have installed additional electrical accessories on the vehicle.
        </para>
        <para>Be sure battery is at full charge when installed. If the battery has been in storage for some time or if
            the installation is being made in sub-freezing temperatures, the battery should be given a boost charge
            before being installed.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place battery in battery tray with terminals in proper position. Battery should rest level
                in tray.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install battery hold down hardware and tighten until battery is firm and secure.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten battery hold-downs. Overtightening could damage battery resulting in early
                        failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a light coat of terminal grease to battery and cable terminals to inhibit corrosion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect battery cables to battery. Check for proper battery polarity with respect to the
                vehicle. "Reversed" polarity may cause serious damage to the electrical system. Connect ground cable
                last.
            </para>
            <para>Tighten terminal fasteners as follows: DO NOT OVERTIGHTEN.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Side Terminals:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>60-90 in-lbs. or 5-7 ft-lbs. (7-10 N&#8226;m)</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Top Terminals:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>10-15 ft-lbs. (13-20 N&#8226;m)</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Taper Post Terminals:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>50-60 in-lbs. or 4-6 ft-lbs. (5.5-8 N&#8226;m)</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>New batteries must be coded to indicate months and year of installation.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start engine and check operation of vehicle's charging system. If necessary, adjust or
                repair charging system to obtain correct charging output.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install battery cover (where used).</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
