<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ANTILOCK BRAKE INTERFACE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ANTILOCK BRAKE INTERFACE</title>
        <para>On vehicles with both the Bendix Antilock Brake System (ABS) and the Allison WT Transmission, circuit
            154/94J directly links the WT ECU with the ABS ECU.
        </para>
        <para>With the vehicle in a normal operating mode, a 12V signal will be sent from the WT ECU to the ABS ECU. A
            ground switch located in the ABS ECM will remain OPEN during normal vehicle operation (or with key OFF).
            When the ABS ECU ground switch is OPEN, the WT ECU will permit the transmission lockup clutch (or
            transmission retarder) to be engaged in a normal manner.
        </para>
        <para>If the ABS brake system senses an impending wheel lockup condition and modulates the air brake system (to
            prevent wheel lockup), the 12V signal from the WT ECU will be turned ON when the ground switch (located in
            the ABS ECM) closes. With the circuit closed between the ABS and the WT electronic control units, the
            transmission lockup clutch (and transmission retarder if equipped) will be disengaged, and the transmission
            will "hydraulically" link to the drive wheels rather than mechanically.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
