<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - TWO-SPEED AXLE (AIR OPERATED)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TWO-SPEED AXLE (AIR OPERATED)</title>
        <para>The two-speed axle system uses spare output #1. This includes using spare input circuits, special function
            relay #1 (SF-1) and special output #1. With the Allison WT transmission, there are four major components in
            the two-speed axle control system:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The two speed shift switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Special function relay #1 (SF-1) located in the VIM.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air solenoid to shift the two-speed axle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The Allison ECU.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>The electrical operation of the two-speed control system is as follows:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the key ON, accessory voltage from F14 fuse is applied to the SF-1 relay terminal 30.
                Also, ignition voltage from the IGN fuse (located in the VIM) is applied to SF-1 terminal 85.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">With the two-speed shift switch in the HI position</emph>, the ECU ground switch is
                open (SF-4 relay not energized), and power from F14 fuse passes through the relay (terminal 30 to
                terminal 87A) to the axle solenoid, causing it to energize and apply air to the two-speed shifter. The
                axle will shift to high speed mode of operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the two-speed shift switch in the LO position, three events occur:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The two-speed switch is a spare input switch to the WT ECU. With the switch in the LO
                    position, the circuit between ECU terminals B19 and B27 is closed. This communicates to the ECU that
                    the driver wants low axle range operation.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">When the ECU determines that throttle position and transmission output speed are low,
                    the WT ECU closes a ground switch, grounding circuit 114 from SF-1 relay terminal 85. This energizes
                    SF-1 relay, and removes power from the axle solenoid. The axle solenoid, with power removed, closes
                    and the shifter is in the low range position.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With SF-1 relay energized, 12 volts from SF-1 relay terminal 87 is delivered (circuit
                    93A) to the speedometer cluster connector 27-13. Applying 12 volts to instrument cluster at
                    connector 27-13 causes the speedometer reading to adjust for the lower axle ratio.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
