<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 30-SI AND 30-SI/TR SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING - 30-SI SERIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0801606" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>30-SI SERIES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Trouble in the charging system will show up as one or more of the following conditions:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>An undercharged battery as evidenced by slow cranking and low specific gravity readings.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>An overcharged battery as evidenced by excessive water usage.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Undercharged Battery</title>
            <para>This condition, evidenced by slow cranking and low specific gravity readings, can be caused by one or
                more of the following conditions:
            </para>
            <para>The following steps should be done with the alternator in the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insure that the undercharged condition has not been caused by accessories having been
                    left on for extended periods.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the drive belt for proper tension.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a battery defect is suspected, check battery as instructed in GROUP 08, BATTERY
                    section of Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the wiring for defects. Check all connections for tightness and cleanliness,
                    including the cable clamps and battery posts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a voltmeter from "BAT" terminal on alternator to ground. A zero reading
                    indicates an open between voltmeter connection and battery.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If previous Steps 1 through 5 check satisfactorily, check alternator as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect battery ground cable.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect an ammeter in the circuit at the "BAT" terminal of the alternator.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect battery ground cable.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn on accessories. Connect a carbon pile across the battery.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Operate engine at moderate speed (to provide 4000 alternator rpm or more) and adjust
                        carbon pile as required, to obtain maximum current output.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>Initial voltage build-up is by residual magnetism in the rotor. Increase the speed as
                                required to obtain maximum current output.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ampere output is within 10 amperes of rated output, alternator is not
                        defective.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ampere output is not within 10 amperes of rated output, remove alternator and
                        repair as instructed under
                        <hotlnk document="s08016_HL0801605.xml" xrefid="hl0801605">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Overcharged Battery</title>
            <para>The following steps should be done with the alternator in the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check battery. Remember that an overheated battery may be overcharged even though no
                    charging circuit defects are present.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If battery is not defective or overheated, connect a voltmeter between alternator "BAT"
                    terminal and ground.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With all accessories turned off, increase engine speed as required to obtain maximum
                    voltage reading.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the voltage exceeds 15 volts on a 12-volt system, remove the alternator for repair as
                    instructed under
                    <hotlnk document="s08016_HL0801605.xml" xrefid="hl0801605">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08016_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08016_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
