<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC CODES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0800303" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC CODES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The tests in this section are written to be performed by reading the diagnostic codes using the shift
                selector and the Fluke 23 multimeter. In many cases a Pro-Link 9000 can be used for reading the codes
                and performing some system diagnostics if the proper Allison cartridge is available. Note that if
                battery power is not present at the VIM, the Pro-Link will not be able to read the codes or perform
                other diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>When beginning the troubleshooting process, always check for ACTIVE diagnostic codes first.
                <emph type="bold">The codes listed in this service section are only those codes that are likely to be
                    involved with International-installed components and harnesses.</emph>For a full listing of
                diagnostic codes, refer to the Allison WT Service Manual.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Low transmission oil levels, low battery power, battery power interruptions and intermittent
                        ground connections can cause many diagnostic codes to be registered.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before diagnosing any fault codes:</title>
            <para>Check transmission oil level.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 1. Look carefully for (and correct) conditions that can cause intermittent
                    conditions such as:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loose, dirty, corroded or painted connections.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check the VIM for loose, incorrect or over-heating relays and fuses.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check for damaged, chafing wires.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 13 Sub Code 12 or 23 - ECU Input Voltage</title>
            <para>This code means the ECU has detected either a high or low battery input voltage. The ECU monitors
                battery voltage levels at the ignition feed circuit connection to the ECU (circuit 146 at B12), not the
                battery feed circuit. LOW voltage is considered less than 8 volts, and HIGH voltage is considered more
                than 32 volts. Common causes for this code are usually vehicle wiring conditions, vehicle charging
                system and batteries, or poor ground conditions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECU turns OFF when voltage drops to approximately 6.5 volts.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 1 and if determined by TEST 1, perform TEST 1A, 1B OR 1C.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 21 Sub Code 12 or 23 - Throttle Position Sensor Fault Or Adjustment</title>
            <para>Main Code 21 Sub Code 12 indicates throttle position sensor failed LOW.</para>
            <para>Main Code 21 Sub Code 23 indicates throttle position sensor failed HIGH.</para>
            <para>This code indicates either the throttle position sensor has been pulled by its linkage into an error
                zone (HIGH or LOW), or a fault with the sensor or a fault with the wiring to the sensor.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Code 21 XX in combination with Code 33 XX indicates the loss of common ground wire, circuit
                        135 in transmission harness between the throttle and temperature sensors.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the throttle position cable assembly for proper routing and connection to fuel
                    pump arm (
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_4.xml" xrefid="f0800305">Figure 5</hotlnk>and
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_9.xml" xrefid="f0800306">Figure 6</hotlnk>).Be sure there is no
                    misalignment or obstruction to smooth movement of the throttle sensor cable assembly through the
                    full stroke (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0800307">Figure 7</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0800308">Figure 8</hotlnk>). There is no adjustment feature for this assembly at
                    the pump arm.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0800307" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg08/g0800307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7 - Throttle Position Sensor And Cable Installation</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. COTTER KEY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CLIP ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. THROTTLE POSITION SENSOR CABLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. MOUNTING BRACKET ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. 1/4 INCH FLAT WASHER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0800308" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg08/g0800308.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8 - Throttle Position Sensor Throttle Arm Connection</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. COTTER KEY</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CLIP ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. MACHINE HEX SCREW 10-24 X 1/2 (2)</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. THROTTLE POSITION SENSOR CABLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. MOUNTING BRACKET ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. 1/4 INCH FLAT WASHER</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check throttle position sensor electrical connection to transmission harness for clean,
                    tight connection, free of damaged wires, terminals etc.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If defects are not noted in Steps 1 or 2, have Allison dealer diagnose the TPS if fault
                    code is still active.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 22 Sub Codes 14, 15 and 16 - Speed Sensor/Circuit Fault</title>
            <para>This code indicates a fault with one of the speed sensors, or the wiring to one of the speed
                sensors.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check engine speed sensor connection at flywheel housing for clean, tight and undamaged
                    connection.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check output speed sensor connection at rear of transmission for clean, tight and
                    undamaged connection.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If defects were not noted in Steps 1 or 2 and code is still active, have Allison dealer
                    diagnose.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 23 Sub Code 12, 13, 23, and 24</title>
            <para>This code indicates a fault with the shift selector assembly or the harnesses that connect it to the
                ECU and the VIM.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 3 - TESTING SHIFT SELECTOR CIRCUITS.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If defects were not noted in Step 1, replace the shift selector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If Steps 1 and 2 have been completed and defect is still present, have the Allison
                    dealer diagnose.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 35 Sub Code 00 - Power Interruption</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the ECU detected a complete battery power loss before the ignition was turned
                OFF. This code cannot be displayed as an active code, but will be displayed only after power is
                restored.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform TEST 1 - CHECK BATTERY FEED/ IGNITION FEED AND GROUND CIRCUITS.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If defect is still present, have Allison dealer diagnose.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
