<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The troubleshooting charts in this service section focus on the International harnesses and
                components. The emphasis is determining if the International circuits and components that could cause
                the condition are functioning properly, and steps needed to correct any such conditions.
            </para>
            <para>If International-related circuits and components are determined to be functioning properly, and the
                condition still is present, an authorized Allison dealer should continue the troubleshooting process.
            </para>
            <para>The troubleshooting process includes the following:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Knowing the proper maintenance techniques and practices to prevent damage to the electronic
                        components during the troubleshooting process.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Checking the vehicle for conditions that are not part of the electronic control system for the
                        transmission that could cause the symptom or diagnostic code to be present.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use of shift selector or Pro-Link DDR to read and understand diagnostic codes that may be
                        present.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use of Troubleshooting Charts to systematically diagnose the various electrical circuits in an
                        efficient manner. It is often as important to know which circuits are functioning correctly as
                        it is to identify a circuit that is not operating correctly. Refer to the Operation description
                        before diagnosing a circuit. Understanding the circuit is key to proper troubleshooting.
                    </para>
                    <para>The troubleshooting charts are designed for the technician to use the Fluke 23 Digital
                        Multimeter. If a Pro-Link DDR and the correct cartridge are available, they can be used for
                        certain general systems tests, but the Fluke 23 is still necessary to isolate the defect to a
                        specific area.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When performing electrical checks on the harness connectors, do not insert the test meter
                        probes into the connectors. Use jumper wires for testing connectors.
                    </para>
                    <para>Fabricate jumper wires using the appropriate mating terminal--a short length of wire with an
                        alligator clip on the end without the terminal. Insert the terminal into the connector and
                        attach the meter leads with the alligator clip. For the Allison transmission harness, an Allison
                        Jumper Wiring Kit, part number J39197, is available from authorized Allison dealers.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>BEFORE BEGINNING TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The following must be read and understood before beginning the troubleshooting
                    process.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before welding on any vehicle with an electronic control module for the transmission, engine,
                        antilock brake system or other electronically-controlled components, it is mandatory to remove
                        all connectors going to the Electronic Control Module(s), including grounds. It is also
                        mandatory to disconnect the positive (+) and negative ( ) battery cables before connecting the
                        welder. Always attach welder ground cables as close as possible to the part being welded. Never
                        connect the welder ground cable to an ECM or ECM mounting bracket.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The engine and ignition must always be OFF before disconnecting or connecting any
                    harness connectors. When disconnecting a harness connector, the pulling force must be applied to the
                    connector and not pull the connector loose by pulling on the wires.
                </para>
                <para>If vehicle system power is turned on while a harness is disconnected, diagnostic codes will be
                    registered. After a harness is reconnected to the electronic control system, the computer
                    diagnostics should be ignored and cleared from memory.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all related connectors for damage. They may have damaged pins, loose wires or
                    terminals or may have lost the necessary spring to maintain proper connections.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the pins or sockets of the electronic control harness connections are dirty or
                    corroded, they should be cleaned using a good quality, non-residue, non-lubricating cleaning solvent
                    that does not contain petroleum distillates. The solvent should not conduct electricity (will cause
                    shorting between terminals) and should evaporate quickly, eliminating the possibility of
                    condensation within the connectors. ALWAYS remove any excess solvent before assembling a connector
                    to its mating component. Solvents trapped in a connector can damage the connector sealing
                    capabilities.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check transmission OIL LEVEL and ensure correct oil level. Improper oil level can create
                    conditions which cause diagnostic codes to be registered.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check battery state-of-charge. To perform diagnostics, the batteries must be fully
                    charged. Refer to GROUP 08- BATTERIES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for procedure to check
                    batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800301.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
