<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9200, 9300, 9400 Models Built After January 1, 1995 - ELECTRICAL
        TROUBLESHOOTING CATERPILLAR 3176B AND 3406E ELECTRONIC ENGINES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="s08057" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5211-06" date="06/09/1996">
        <title>ELECTRICAL TROUBLESHOOTING CATERPILLAR 3176B AND 3406E ELECTRONIC ENGINES</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1995</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1995</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1995</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>This section covers International installed components and circuits that directly interact
                        with the Caterpillar 3176B and 3406E engines.
                    </para>
                    <para>The
                        <emph type="underscr">Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting Guide</emph>
                        should be used to diagnose the engine control system.
                    </para>
                    <para>This section
                        <emph type="bold">does not provide</emph>engine diagnostics, but does provide step-by-step
                        troubleshooting charts for International installed components and circuits. The charts in this
                        section should be used when the
                        <emph type="underscr">Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting Guide</emph>
                        indicates a problem may be present in a International circuit or component.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Only systems that include International installed components and/or circuits
                            are discussed in this section.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>Refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service Literature for additional information.</para>
                    <para>Caterpillar, Inc. Literature Orders Section P.O. Box 5319 Morton, IL 61550</para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>OVERVIEW</title>
                    <para>The 3176B/3406E controllers provide engine and vehicle functions including:</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">ENGINE FUNCTIONS</emph>
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>Electronic Governing*</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fuel/Air Ratio Control*</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Injection Timing Control*</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Service Diagnostics**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Torque Rise Shaping*</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Trip Data Recording*</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <para>*Caterpillar System</para>
                    <para>**Caterpillar/International System</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">VEHICLE FUNCTIONS</emph>
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cruise Control**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Data Links**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine Brake Controls**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine Protection System**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Idle Shutdown Timer**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Progressive Shifting**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>PTO Controls**</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Vehicle Speed Limiting**</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <para>**Caterpillar/International System</para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Programmable Parameters</title>
                        <para>Certain programmable parameters that affect the engine electronic control systems may be
                            changed with electronic service tools.
                        </para>
                        <para>The parameters are stored in the system Electronic Control Module (ECM) and are protected
                            from unauthorized change by passwords. The programmable parameters are either "System
                            Parameters" or "Customer Parameters."
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">System Configuration Parameters</emph>are set at the factory and affect
                            emissions or horsepower ratings within a family of engines. Factory passwords must be
                            obtained and used to change System Configuration Parameters.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Customer Selectable Parameters</emph>are variable, and are used to specify
                            operating parameters for: cruise control, PTO operation, vehicle speed limits, progressive
                            shifting, type of engine protection system, RPM and horsepower ratings within the engine
                            family. Customer passwords are needed to change Customer Parameters.
                        </para>
                        <para>Since each 3176B/3406E control system is electronically programmable to individual owner
                            specifications,
                            <emph type="bold">the operating parameters will vary from vehicle to vehicle</emph>.
                        </para>
                        <para>Some of these parameters may cause the engine to operate in a way that the driver (or
                            service technician) does not expect, if proper training has not taken place. This may lead
                            to power or performance complaints and/or service time, when the engine is operating
                            correctly.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">EXAMPLE:</emph>If the driver attempts to drive 60 mph and the vehicle
                            speed limiting option has been programmed to limit vehicle speed to 55 mph, the driver may
                            complain of low power.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Passwords</title>
                        <para>"System Configuration Parameters" are protected by Caterpillar factory passwords. Factory
                            passwords are necessary to:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="arabic">
                            <item>
                                <para>Program a new ECM. When an ECM is replaced, the System Configuration Parameters
                                    must be programmed into the new ECM. These parameters are protected by Factory
                                    Passwords.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Rerate engine to another engine family. This requires changing the Personality
                                    Module Code, which is protected by Factory Passwords.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Read Customer Passwords. If the owner loses the customer password, customer
                                    parameters cannot be changed. Using Factory Passwords, the customer passwords can be
                                    read, which can then be used to change customer parameters.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Clear certain logged Diagnostic Codes. Engine Overspeed and Incorrect Engine
                                    Software fault codes can only be cleared using Factory Passwords.
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="underscr">Factory passwords are only available to authorized Caterpillar
                                        dealers.</emph>Whenever a system configuration parameter is changed, insure that
                                    all appropriate components (suspension, drivelines, etc.) are matched with the new
                                    change. This may adversely affect warranty coverage.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>For complete information on passwords, refer to the Caterpillar Electronic
                                    Troubleshooting Guide.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Self-Diagnostics</title>
                        <para>Caterpillar Electronic Engine Control systems have some ability to diagnose their own
                            circuits. The ECM communicates with the Driver using a Yellow Serv/Check Engine and Red
                            Engine Warning Light.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Yellow Oil/Water Warning Light</title>
                            <para>Caterpillar service literature refers to this light as the "Check Engine Light." This
                                light is used for two purposes. The light is used to notify the driver that an active
                                code has been logged or with the Idle Shutdown feature, the light flashes to indicate
                                that the shutdown timer is within 90 seconds of shutting the engine down.
                            </para>
                            <para>On power up (key ON and engine OFF), the Yellow Serv/Check Engine will come ON for
                                five seconds and turn OFF, indicating that the bulb circuit is working properly.
                            </para>
                            <para>When a problem condition is detected, an active diagnostic code is logged, which will
                                cause the Yellow Serv/Check Engine to turn ON for five seconds, then flash OFF, then
                                back ON for five seconds. It will repeat this until the condition is gone.
                            </para>
                            <para>The code is also logged (stored) in the ECM permanent memory. This memory is not lost
                                when turning the vehicle OFF or when disconnecting the batteries for a short period of
                                time.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Active and Inactive Codes</title>
                            <para>Codes representing current conditions are called
                                <emph type="bold">ACTIVE</emph>codes. They indicate that a problem of some type
                                currently exists. They should always be serviced.
                            </para>
                            <para>If a fault condition occurred and caused a code to be logged, but is no longer
                                present, the code is referred to as an
                                <emph type="bold">INACTIVE</emph>code. This can occur with an intermittent condition or
                                when repairs are made and the code is not cleared. Logged inactive codes don't always
                                mean something requires service. Some codes record events and not faults.
                            </para>
                            <para>Codes caused by intermittent conditions are automatically cleared, if after 100 hours
                                of ECM operation, the condition does not occur again. Codes that require a Factory
                                Password to clear do not automatically clear.
                            </para>
                            <para>With Engine Protection selected, the
                                <emph type="bold">Red Engine Warning light</emph>will be activated.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Electronic Service Tools</title>
                        <para>Electronic service tools are designed to help the service technician locate faults and/or
                            analyze problems within the 3176B/3406E systems. Diagnostic code reading and switch
                            monitoring can be done using the service tools. An electronic service tool is necessary to
                            read or change operating parameters.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Diagnostic Connector (137)</title>
                            <para>International provides a Diagnostic connector (137) for connecting an Electronic
                                Service Tool (EST) to the electronic engine control system. The Diagnostic connector is
                                located on the instrument panel left.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Caterpillar Service Tools</title>
                            <para>Caterpillar service tools are available for 3176B/3406E engines. The Electronic
                                Control Analyzer Programmer (ECAP) and the Digital Diagnostic Tool (DDT) both can
                                communicate with 3176B/3406E engines. Refer to Caterpillar Service Manual for complete
                                information needed to use these tools.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>MPSI Pro-Link 9000</title>
                            <para>The MPSI Pro-Link 9000 Electronic Service Tool is available with a single cartridge
                                that communicates with both the Caterpillar 3176B/3406E engines. The Pro-Link 9000
                                communicates with the engine ECM through the Diagnostic connector. A manual is provided
                                with the MPSI Caterpillar cartridge explaining its use.
                            </para>
                            <para>This section does not discuss engine diagnostics,
                                <emph type="bold">except as they relate to International installed circuits or
                                    components</emph>. Refer to the Caterpillar Engine Operators Manual furnished with
                                the vehicle and/or other Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting Manuals for additional
                                engine related information.
                            </para>
                            <specpara>
                                <note>
                                    <para>When referring to an electronic service tool (EST), this manual will make
                                        reference to the MPSI Pro-Link.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                            </specpara>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ELECTRICAL OPERATION</title>
                    <para>This section describes specific electrical operation of International installed circuits and
                        components, referencing specific circuits, connectors and components by number.
                    </para>
                    <para>Refer to circuit diagram CATERPILLAR 3176B/3406E - ENGINE CONTROLS in CTS-5119S.</para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
                        <para>The "Brain" of the 3176B/3406E Electronic Engine Control System is two components working
                            together: the Electronic Control Module (ECM) and the Vehicle Personality Module (VPM). The
                            ECM is mounted on the left side of the engine and the VPM is mounted on the ECM. The ECM is
                            the computer which controls the engine related vehicle functions. The VPM contains the
                            operating instructions (software) including owner selected parameters and other engine
                            information for the ECM to use, controlling how the ECM behaves.
                        </para>
                        <para>The International engine harness connector (400) connects to
                            <emph type="bold">Caterpillar 40-pin connector J1</emph>. All electronic communication
                            between the International electrical system and the Caterpillar engine control system go
                            through (400)/J1, the International/Caterpillar connection.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Switched Power To The ECM</title>
                            <para>With the key switch ON, the ECM receives (12 volt DC) operating power from the vehicle
                                batteries through International engine harness connector (400), terminal 6. The battery
                                power to the ECM is switched ON or OFF by the Run Relay (144), which is energized when
                                the key switch is in the IGN position.
                            </para>
                            <seqlist style="arabic">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Turning the key switch ON applies power from Ignition Adapter (494) to the
                                        control coil of the Run Relay (144), causing it to energize. The relay control
                                        coil circuit 13-GZ/11GT goes to ground through (506) Panel Light Ground Adapter.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Battery power from connector (497) B1 Battery Adapter is applied to Run Relay
                                        terminal 30. This circuit is protected by 20A fuse F9-B. With the relay
                                        energized, battery passes through the Normally Open (N.O.) relay contacts (87 to
                                        30) and is sent on circuit 97S to International ECM connector (400) terminal 6.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Unswitched Battery Power To ECM</title>
                            <para>Battery power from the B+ BATTERY terminal of the Cranking Motor Solenoid is always
                                applied on circuit 2FL/97F through connector (400) terminal 4 to the ECM. This circuit
                                is protected by a fusible link 2FL.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM uses this power to maintain a portion of memory used for customer trip data
                                accumulators. Disconnecting this circuit does not affect engine operation or
                                factory/customer parameters or logged diagnostic codes. Refer to the Caterpillar
                                Electronic Troubleshooting manual for additional information on this feature.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>ECM Inputs And Outputs</title>
                            <para>The ECM acts as 5V power supply for many Caterpillar and International components used
                                to monitor and control the engine/vehicle systems. The ECM also supplies operating power
                                to the Throttle Position Sensor (404), Low Coolant Sensor (402) and the Engine Fan Relay
                                (410).
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM is connected to the International installed switches that communicate with the
                                ECM. The switches are 2-way or 3-way switches and are either ON or OFF.
                            </para>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="underscr">EXAMPLE OF A 2-WAY SWITCH:</emph>Cruise Control ON-OFF Switch
                                (435)
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM needs to know if the Cruise ON/OFF switch is in the ON or OFF position. To
                                accomplish this, the Cruise ON/OFF switch is connected to the ECM with input circuit
                                97AE and "common" or ground circuit 97-GH.
                            </para>
                            <seqlist style="arabic">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Each International installed switch has an "input" circuit that is connected
                                        through connector (400) to an assigned ECM terminal. This circuit has 5 volts
                                        applied at the ECM terminal.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Each switch is also grounded through connector (400) terminal 29 to the ECM.
                                        ECM terminal 5 is grounded at the engine ground stud by circuit 97-GB.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>When the Cruise switch is OFF (switch open), the ECM sees 5 volts at ECM
                                        terminal 20. Placing the cruise switch to the ON position (switch closed) causes
                                        the ECM to see 0 volts (ground voltage will be 0 to 0.5 volts) at terminal 20.
                                        The ECM programming has established that the Cruise Control Switch is OFF when
                                        it sees 5 volts at connector (400) terminal 20 or cruise is ON when the ECM sees
                                        0 volts at terminal 20.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                            <para>EXAMPLE: The service brake switch (141) is connected by input circuit 97AL to
                                connector (400) terminal 14. Terminal 14 has a 5-volt signal present. With the brake
                                switch closed (pedal released), the circuit is complete between terminals 14 (input) and
                                29 (common or ground). This causes the 5 volt signal at terminal 14 to go to zero. This
                                tells the ECM that the service brake switch is closed (pedal released).
                            </para>
                            <para>This type of circuit is used to communicate switch and some sensor information to the
                                ECM. Some sensors receive a 5 volt signal and return a variable voltage indicating some
                                variable attribute. The ECM also uses 12 volt circuits to enable (energize) relays in
                                the system and
                                <emph type="underscr">supplies 8V power</emph>to operate the Throttle Position Sensor.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM receives "inputs" through International connector (400) from the following
                                International components:
                            </para>
                            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Throttle Position Sensor (TPS)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Service Brake Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clutch Pedal Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Coolant Level Sensor (CLS)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cruise Control ON/OFF Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cruise Control Set/Resume Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Engine Brake Selector Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>A/C Pressure Switch</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>ABS System.</para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                            <para>The ECM receives the AC signal from the Vehicle Speed Sensor and sends a signal to the
                                vehicle speedometer. The ECM also sends the signal to drive the vehicle tachometer.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Engine Protection</title>
                        <para>The 3176B/3406E engine control system includes an Engine Monitoring feature. This feature
                            monitors:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>Engine Oil Pressure*</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Coolant Temperature*</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Coolant Level**</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Intake Manifold Air Temperature*</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>*Installed by Caterpillar</para>
                        <para>**Installed by International.</para>
                        <para>The ECM can be programmed to four different customer selectable modes of engine
                            monitoring:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Warning Only (default)</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Warning and Derate</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Warning, Derate and Shutdown.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>Selecting any level except OFF activates the Red Engine Warning Light.</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">OFF MODE -</emph>The engine monitoring system can be turned OFF. If the
                            customer selects this option, the Red Engine Warning light is not functional (except for
                            reading codes), although the Yellow Serv/Check Engine will indicate if active fault
                            conditions are present. If Engine Monitoring is turned OFF, the diagnostic codes for the
                            following conditions are not enabled.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Very Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>High Coolant Temperature Warning</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Very High Coolant Temperature Warning</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Low Coolant Level Warning</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Coolant Level Sensor Fault (no sensor is installed)</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Very Low Coolant Level Warning.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Warning Only Mode</emph>(Default) - If the system is programmed for
                            Warning Only mode, the ECM will indicate the diagnostic codes for conditions listed in the
                            <hotlnk xrefid="t0805701">Code Description Table - Warning Only</hotlnk>, that are active,
                            using the Yellow Oil/Water Warning Light. The ECM will also turn ON the Red Engine Warning
                            Light when the necessary conditions exist.
                            <emph type="underscr">This is the engine protection mode programmed if no other option is
                                selected when ordering the vehicle.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <table id="t0805701" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                            <title>Code Description Table - Warning Only</title>
                            <tgroup cols="5" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="1.00in" colsep="1"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>CODE DESCRIPTION</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>RED Warning Light</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>45 MPH MAX</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>160HP</para>
                                            <para>MAX</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>1350 RPM MAX</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Low Coolant Level Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very Low Coolant Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>solid</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>no</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Derate Mode</emph>- If the system is programmed for the Derate mode, the
                            ECM will indicate that diagnostic codes for the conditions listed in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="t0805702">Code Description Table - Derate Mode</hotlnk>, that are active
                            using the Yellow Serv/Check Engine and also turn ON the Red Engine Warning Light when the
                            necessary conditions exist.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>Conditions causing active codes for
                                    <emph type="underscr">Low Oil Pressure Warning</emph>and
                                    <emph type="underscr">Low Coolant Level Warning</emph>will cause the Red Engine
                                    Warning light to come on solid (light stays ON).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Conditions causing active codes for
                                    <emph type="underscr">High Coolant Temperature</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very High Coolant Temperature</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very Low Oil Pressure</emph>will cause the Red Engine Warning
                                    Light to flash.
                                    <emph type="bold">The Red Engine Warning Light will FLASH whenever engine power is
                                        derated.</emph>When derated, the available engine power and vehicle speed will
                                    be limited (if due to Very Low Oil Pressure, engine RPM is also limited).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <table id="t0805702" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                            <title>Code Description Table - Derate Mode</title>
                            <tgroup cols="5" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="1.00in" colsep="1"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">CODE DESCRIPTION</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">RED WARNING</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">LIGHT</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">45 MPH</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">MAX</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>160HP</para>
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">MAX</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">1350 RPM</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">MAX</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Low Coolant Level Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Very Low Coolant Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>YES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Shutdown Mode</emph>- If the system is programmed to Shutdown mode, the
                            ECM will indicate that diagnostic codes for the conditions listed in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="t0805703">Code Description Table - Shutdown Mode</hotlnk>, that are active
                            using the Yellow Oil/Water Warning Light.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>Conditions causing active codes for
                                    <emph type="underscr">Low Oil Pressure Warning</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Low Coolant Level Warning</emph>will cause the Red Engine
                                    Warning Light to come on solid (doesn't flash).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Conditions causing active codes for
                                    <emph type="underscr">High Coolant Temperature</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very High Coolant Temperature</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very Low Oil Pressure</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very Low Coolant Level</emph>will cause the Red Engine Warning
                                    Light to flash (indicating derate).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If conditions causing active codes for
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very High Coolant Temperature</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very Low Oil Pressure</emph>or
                                    <emph type="underscr">Very Low Coolant Level</emph>continue to be present after
                                    derate, the engine will shut down.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <table id="t0805703" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                            <title>Code Description Table - Shutdown Mode</title>
                            <tgroup cols="5" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="0.75in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="0.75in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="1.49in" colsep="1"/>
                                <spanspec namest="3" nameend="4" spanname="sqspan3-4"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">CODE DESCRIPTION</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">RED WARNING</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">LIGHT</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">TIME</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">TO</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">SHUTDOWN</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>
                                                <emph type="bold">START</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">RESTART</emph>
                                                <emph type="bold">TIME</emph>
                                            </para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Very Low Oil Pressure Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>30 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>18 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Very High Intake Manifold Air Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Very High Coolant Temp. Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>20 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>60 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Low Coolant Level Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>SOLID</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>NO</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry colname="1">
                                            <para>Very Low Coolant Warning</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="2">
                                            <para>FLASH</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan3-4" align="center">
                                            <para>30 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="5">
                                            <para>80 SECONDS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Yellow "Oil/Water" Warning Light</title>
                            <para>On power up (key ON - engine OFF), the Yellow Serv/Check Engine light will come ON for
                                five seconds and then turn OFF indicating that the light circuit is working properly.
                                Any time there are active codes logged, the lamp will come ON for five seconds, blink
                                OFF, then turn ON for five more seconds. It will repeat this process until the condition
                                causing the code is corrected.
                            </para>
                            <para>The Engine Warning Light can be used to flash diagnostic codes so that the codes can
                                be read without using an electronic service tool.
                            </para>
                            <para>The Yellow Serv/Check Engine light receives power from 10A fuse F4-A when the key is
                                ON. Circuit 97AZ connects the ground side of the light to ECM connector (400) terminal
                                27. The ECM opens or closes a ground switch turning the light ON or OFF in response to
                                engine conditions.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Red Engine Warning Light</title>
                            <para>The Red Engine Warning light is active
                                <emph type="underscr">unless the customer has selected the OFF level of Engine
                                    Protection.
                                </emph>
                                If the OFF engine protection mode is selected, the Red Engine Warning light only is used
                                to read flash codes. The purpose of this light is to alert the driver that an engine
                                problem has been detected by the ECM, and that action may be taken by the ECM to protect
                                the engine.
                            </para>
                            <para>The Red Engine Warning light is ON continuously while in the Warning mode.</para>
                            <para>The Red Engine Warning light flashes while in the Derate mode. In this mode the light
                                flashes to indicate that the ECM is reducing available engine speed, vehicle speed or
                                horsepower.
                            </para>
                            <para>At power up (key ON - engine OFF), the light comes ON for two seconds and then turns
                                OFF to check the light bulb and circuit. If a low oil pressure condition is present at
                                start up, the light will stay ON for 15 seconds, before the ECM will log a Low Oil
                                Pressure Diagnostic code.
                            </para>
                            <para>The Red Engine Warning light receives power from 10A fuse F4-A when the key is ON.
                                Circuit 97AT connects the ground side of the light to ECM connector (400) terminal 22.
                                The ECM opens or closes a ground switch for this circuit turning the light ON or OFF in
                                response to engine conditions.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Coolant Level Switch (402)</title>
                            <para>The Coolant Level Sensor is a fluid- level-actuated switch that sends coolant low or
                                coolant high signal and provides a warning when coolant is being lost. It is mounted in
                                the coolant surge tank.
                            </para>
                            <para>It is an electronic switch that operates on the electrostatic or capacitance
                                principle,
                                <emph type="underscr">and cannot be tested with a multimeter</emph>. The probe extends
                                into the coolant and produces a change in capacitance when coolant displaces air
                                immediately surrounding the probe. This change is converted in the switch to an ON/off
                                solid state switch closure indicating the absence or presence of coolant. The switch is
                                electrically insulated providing a slick, non-fouling surface as well as good electrical
                                characteristics to prevent current flow into the coolant.
                            </para>
                            <para>The Coolant Level switch connects to a 4-pin connector (402) on the International
                                engine harness. All four Coolant Level Switch circuits go through the engine harness to
                                connector (400).
                            </para>
                            <seqlist style="arabic">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Coolant Level Switch terminal (C) receives VREF (5V) on circuit 34B from the
                                        ECM connector (400) terminal 36.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Coolant Level Switch terminal (B) is grounded through circuits 34-G/97-G at
                                        ECM connector (400) terminal 29.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>When the coolant level
                                        <emph type="bold"></emph>is NORMAL (above
                                        <emph type="bold"></emph>the probe), the ECM expects to see: a 5-volt signal
                                        (3.5V minimum) from sensor terminal D (circuit 34A) at connector (400) terminal
                                        2 AND a 0-volt signal (0.7V maximum) from sensor terminal A (34) at connector
                                        (400) terminal 23.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>When the coolant level
                                        <emph type="bold">is below the probe</emph>, the ECM expects to see: a 5-volt
                                        signal (3.5V minimum) from sensor terminal A (circuit 34) at connector (400),
                                        terminal 23 AND a 0-volt signal (0.7V maximum) from sensor terminal D (34A) at
                                        connector (400), terminal 2.
                                    </para>
                                    <para>To prevent false signals from coolant sloshing, a several second delay is
                                        built into the logic. For example: to log a Coolant Low Fault, the LOW signal
                                        must be seen by the ECM for several continuous seconds before the code is
                                        logged.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Oil Pressure Sensor (CAT Component)</title>
                            <para>The Caterpillar installed engine oil pressure sensor is part of the transducer module,
                                located below the rack actuator housing on the left side of the engine. To diagnose the
                                operation of this sensor, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service Manual.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor (CAT Component)</title>
                            <para>The Caterpillar installed engine coolant temperature sensor is located in the water
                                outlet housing. The engine sends a 5 volt signal to the sensor and a variable signal
                                (0.5 to 5.5 volts) is returned to the ECM. To diagnose the operation of this sensor,
                                refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service Manual.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2 id="x0805701">
                        <title>ATA Data Link Connector (137)</title>
                        <para>The six-pin ATA Data Link connector (137) allows Electronic Service Tools (EST) to
                            communicate with the ECM. The data link carries serial data transmissions between the ECM
                            and the electronic service tool and provides vehicle and engine speed information to the
                            speedometer/tachometer unit. The data link provides communication capabilities for:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>Engine parameter data transmission</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Diagnostics and troubleshooting</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Customer programming of vehicle parameters</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Field programming.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>Data Link connector (137) is located on left instrument panel. Four of the six connector
                            cavities have terminals. Those terminals and connecting circuits are as follows:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="arabic">
                            <item>
                                <para>Terminal A, circuit 98A(+) connects Data Link connector (137) to (514) Datalink
                                    Positive bus connector. Circuit 98(+) connects (514) Datalink Positive bus connector
                                    to ECM connector (400) terminal 7. Bus connector (514) is also connected by circuit
                                    47/48(+) through connector (421) to the Speedometer and Tachometer unit. Note that
                                    bus connector (514) acts like a splice, electrically connecting all circuits into
                                    the connector together.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Terminal B, circuit 98C(-) connects Data Link connector (137) to (515) Datalink
                                    Negative bus connector. Circuit 98B(-) connects (515) Datalink Negative bus
                                    connector to ECM connector (400) terminal 1. Bus connector (515) is also connected
                                    by circuit 47/48(-) through connector (421) to the Speedometer/ Tachometer unit.
                                    Note that bus connector (515) acts like a splice, electrically connecting all
                                    circuits into the connector together.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>The positive and negative data link circuits are twisted wire pairs (2 twists per
                                    inch, minimum). The twisting of the wires shields the wires from interference.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Terminal C, circuit 97DL supplies ignition voltage (12V) for electronic service
                                    tools, when the key is ON. Circuit 97DL receives power from the Run Relay (144). The
                                    circuit is protected by 5A fuse F9-C.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Terminal E, circuit 97-GR is grounded through circuit 11-GT at Panel Light Ground
                                    Adapter (506).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Cruise and PTO Controls</title>
                        <para>Refer to circuit diagram CATERPILLAR 3176B/3406E - CRUISE CONTROL in CTS-5119S.</para>
                        <para>The cruise control switches are used as PTO controls (if vehicle is so equipped) when the
                            vehicle road speed is not present (this is an owner selected parameter). Refer to the
                            Owner's Manual furnished with the vehicle for Cruise Control operating instructions.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Cruise ON/OFF Switch (435)</title>
                            <para>This is a lighted switch to allow for easy location in the dark. Cruise ON/OFF switch
                                circuit (97AE) is an input to the ECM through connector (400) terminal 20. The ground
                                side of the ON/OFF switch is connected through circuit 97-GH/97-GA/97-G to connector
                                (400) terminal 29. With the switch ON, the ECM sees 0 volts at connector (400) terminal
                                20. With the switch OFF, the ECM sees 5 volts at connector (400) terminal 20.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Cruise Set/Resume Switch (436)</title>
                            <para>This is a lighted switch to allow for easy location in the dark. SET/RESUME switch
                                terminal 2 is connected to the ECM through circuit 97-GD/97-GA/97-G to the connector
                                (400) terminal 29. SET/RESUME switch SET terminal 3 is an input (circuit 97AB) to the
                                ECM through connector (400) terminal 25. SET/RESUME switch RESUME terminal (1) is an
                                input (circuit 97AA) to the ECM through connector (400) terminal 15.
                            </para>
                            <para>With the SET/RESUME switch in the SET position, the ECM sees 0 volts at connector
                                (400) terminal 25 and 5 volts at terminal 15.
                            </para>
                            <para>In RESUME position, the ECM sees 5 volts at connector (400) terminal 25 and 0 volts at
                                terminal 15.
                            </para>
                            <para>In the SET/RESUME neutral position, the ECM sees 5 volts at both connector (400)
                                terminals 15 and 25.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Service Brake Switch (141)</title>
                            <para>Service brake switch circuit 97AL is an input to the ECM through connector (400)
                                terminal 14. The ground or common side of the Service Brake switch is connected through
                                circuit 97-GB/97-GA/97-G to connector (400) terminal 29. With service brakes
                                <emph type="bold">released</emph>(switch closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at connector
                                (400) terminal 14. Applying the brakes opens the switch, and the ECM sees 5 volts at
                                terminal 14.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Clutch Switch</title>
                            <para>The Clutch Switch is a normally open switch, that is adjusted to be
                                <emph type="bold">closed</emph>while the clutch pedal is RELEASED.
                            </para>
                            <para>The clutch switch connects to the cab harness at connector (294). Clutch switch
                                circuit (97AH) is an input to the ECM through connector (400) terminal 24. The ground
                                side of the clutch pedal switch is grounded through circuit 97-GE/97-GA/97-G to
                                connector (400) terminal 29. With the driver's foot off the clutch pedal (switch
                                closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at terminal 24. When the driver depresses the clutch pedal
                                (switch opens), the ECM sees 5 volts at terminal 24.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor (409)</title>
                            <para id="hl08057vs">The Vehicle Speed Sensor is located at the rear of the transmission.
                                The sensor contains a permanent magnet that creates a magnetic field that is interrupted
                                by the teeth on the speedometer output gear. As the rotating speedometer gear teeth
                                repeatedly interrupt the sensor magnetic field, a variable AC voltage is generated and
                                transmitted to the ECM. From sensor connector (409) circuits 97AJ and 97AK carry the
                                signal to ECM connector (400) terminals 12 and 18.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2 id="hl08057st">
                        <title>Speedometer/Tachometer inputs</title>
                        <para>The input signal to the speedometer and tachometer with the 3176B and 3406E Caterpillar
                            engines is provided by the ECM through the ATA data link circuits 98(+) and 98B(-) to
                            Datalink Positive bus connector (514) and Datalink Negative bus connector (515), then
                            circuit 47/48(+) from (514) and and 47/48(-) from (515) connect to the
                            speedometer/tachometer unit at connector (421). Refer
                            <hotlnk xrefid="x0805701">ATA Data Link Connector</hotlnk>for discussion of data link
                            circuits.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Speedometer/Tachometer Unit</title>
                            <para>Refer to Gauges And Warning Lights section in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000
                                Master Service Manual.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM receives and processes a signal from Engine Position sensor (Cummins
                                component) to determine
                                <emph type="underscr">engine speed</emph>and receives a signal from the vehicle speed
                                sensor to determine
                                <emph type="underscr">vehicle speed</emph>.
                            </para>
                            <para>To calculate vehicle speed from the vehicle speed sensor signal, the ECM is programmed
                                with certain vehicle parameters (refer to ECM Speedometer Programming, below.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECM provides a signal over the data link circuits that the vehicle speedometer and
                                tachometer cluster microprocessor uses to drive the gauges.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Positive Data Link Circuit To Speedometer And Tachometer</title>
                            <para>Positive data link circuit 98(+) connects ECM connector (252) terminal 27 to Datalink
                                Positive Connector (514) at terminal B. Datalink Positive Connector (514) terminal C is
                                connected by circuit 47/48(+) to speedometer/tachometer connector (421). Datalink
                                Positive Connector (514) terminal A is connected by circuit 98A(+) to the ATA Data Link
                                connector (137) terminal A. Connector (514) has a bus installed that connects all the
                                circuits in the connector together.ATA Data Link connector (137) can be used to access
                                information on the data link using an electronic service tool.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Negative Data Link Circuit To Speedometer And Tachometer</title>
                            <para>Negative data link circuit 98B(-) connects ECM connector (252) terminal 8 to Datalink
                                Negative Connector (515) at terminal B. Datalink Negative Connector (515) terminal C is
                                connected by circuit 47/48(-) to speedometer/tachometer connector (421). Datalink
                                Negative Connector (515) terminal A is connected by circuit 98C(-) to the ATA Data Link
                                connector (137) terminal B.
                            </para>
                            <para>Connector (515) has a bus installed that connects all the circuits in the connector
                                together. ATA Data Link connector (137) can be used to access information on the data
                                link using an electronic service tool.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>ECM Speedometer Programming</title>
                            <para>The ECM is programmed with vehicle component information, so that the signal from the
                                ECM to the speedometer/ tachometer unit causes the unit to display correct readings.
                            </para>
                            <para>If the vehicle tire size, axle ratio or number of teeth on the transmission
                                speedometer gear are changed,
                                <emph type="bold">the ECM will have to be reprogrammed with the new pulses per mile
                                    data.</emph>The speedometer/tachometer unit does not get reprogrammed. The Prolink
                                EST or Caterpillar EST can be used for the reprogramming. Refer to Caterpillar or
                                Prolink manual for this procedure.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Calculating Pulses Per Mile (PPM)</title>
                            <para>PPM= M x Ra x N</para>
                            <para>M = Tire revolutions per mile = 10085 divided by the tire radius. Also the following
                                table
                                <hotlnk xrefid="t0805704">Radial/Bias Tire Revolutions Per Mile Table</hotlnk>lists
                                revolutions per mile for various size tires. The table information is an average from
                                several tire manufacturers. Tire manufacturers can also provide specific information for
                                their tires.
                            </para>
                            <para>Ra = Rear axle ratio which can normally be found on the rear axle housing or on the
                                lineset ticket. With a 2-speed axle use the high range ratio.
                            </para>
                            <para>N = The number of teeth on the transmission speedometer output gear. International
                                installed transmissions, including Allison, have 16 teeth on the speedometer output
                                gear.
                            </para>
                            <para>EXAMPLE: If a vehicle has 10 x 22 tires and 3.70:1 rear axle:</para>
                            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Refer to the table, the revolutions per mile (M) = 476.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The formula is PPM = M x Ra x N</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>PPM = 476 x 3.70 x 16 = 28179</para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                            <para>The new pulses per mile then is programmed into the ECM using the Prolink EST. The
                                Caterpillar ECM will accept a number between 1716 PPM and 65,535 PPM.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Tachometer Programming</title>
                            <para>The Caterpillar Engine Speed/Timing sensor signal to the ECM is used to determine
                                engine speed (RPM). This information is transmitted over the data link circuits to the
                                speedometer/tachometer connector (421). The speedometer/tachometer unit is programmed at
                                the factory to operate on this type of signal.
                            </para>
                            <table id="t0805704" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                                <title>Radial/Bias Tire Revolutions Per Mile Table</title>
                                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.99in"/>
                                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.38in"/>
                                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.38in" colsep="1"/>
                                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="3" spanname="sqspan1-3"/>
                                    <tbody valign="top">
                                        <row>
                                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="sqspan1-3" align="center">
                                                <para>
                                                    <emph type="bold">RADIAL TIRE REVOLUTIONS PER MILE</emph>
                                                </para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>
                                                    <emph type="bold">SIZE</emph>
                                                </para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>
                                                    <emph type="bold">RADIUS</emph>
                                                </para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>
                                                    <emph type="bold">REV/MILE</emph>
                                                </para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>8.25 X 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>536</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>9.00 X 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.6</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>515</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 X 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>499</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 X 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>485</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 X 22</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>476</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 22</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>463</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 24</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>23.1</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>437</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.00 x 19.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.6</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>490</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>9.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>539</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.6</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>515</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.3</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>497</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>12.00 X 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>485</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>22.1</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>456</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 24.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.3</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>474</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>235/80R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>17.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>570</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>255/80R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>17.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>567</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>275/80R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>517</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>275/80R 24.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.1</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>502</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>285/75R 24.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>499</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>285/80R 24.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.1</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>502</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>295/75R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>512</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>295/80R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>504</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>315/80R 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.6</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>490</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="sqspan1-3" align="center">
                                                <para>
                                                    <emph type="bold">BIAS TIRE REVOLUTIONS PER MILE</emph>
                                                </para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>SIZE</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>RADIUS</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>REV/MILE</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>8.25 x 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>539.3</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>9.00 x 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.4</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>519.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 x 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>499.3</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 20</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>487.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 x 22</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>480.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 22</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>464.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 24</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>23.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>438.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.00 x 19.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>480.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>9.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>539.3</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>10.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>19.4</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>519.8</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>499.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>12.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>20.7</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>487.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>18.00 x 22.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>22.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>458.4</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row rowsep="1">
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>11.00 x 24.5</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>21.0</para>
                                            </entry>
                                            <entry>
                                                <para>480.2</para>
                                            </entry>
                                        </row>
                                    </tbody>
                                </tgroup>
                            </table>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Throttle Position Sensor (404)</title>
                        <para>Refer to circuit diagram CATERPILLAR 3176B - CRUISE CONTROL in CTS-5119S.</para>
                        <para>The pedal mounted Throttle Position Sensor (TPS) is used to provide a throttle signal to
                            the ECM. Sensor output is a constant frequency signal with a pulse width that varies with
                            throttle position. This output signal is referred to as either "Duty Cycle" or a "Pulse
                            Width Modulated" (PWM) signal and is expressed as a percentage between 0 and 100%.
                        </para>
                        <para>The pedal mounted Throttle Position Sensor is attached directly to the throttle pedal
                            assembly and requires no adjustment. This sensor can be replaced separately from the
                            throttle pedal assembly, however an incorrectly calibrated pedal mounted throttle position
                            sensor assembly cannot be calibrated- the pedal assembly must be replaced.
                        </para>
                        <para>The "soda can" style remote sensor is not used by International on 1995 engines and is not
                            discussed in this manual.
                        </para>
                        <para>The TPS connects to the cab harness at three-pin connector (404). When the ECM is powered
                            (key switch ON), the TPS
                            <emph type="underscr">receives operating voltage (8 volts)</emph>at terminal A on circuit
                            99E, which is connected to ECM connector (400) terminal 35. TPS terminal B is grounded by
                            circuit 99-G/97-GA/97-G through ECM connector (400) terminal 29.
                        </para>
                        <para>TPS terminal C outputs the variable throttle position signal on circuit 99 to ECM
                            connector (400) terminal 37.
                        </para>
                        <para>The pedal mounted TPS should produce a Duty Cycle of 10 to 22 percent at low idle and 75
                            to 90 percent at full throttle. An electronic service tool can be used to monitor the
                            signal. The percent duty cycle is translated in the ECM into a throttle position percentage
                            of 3 to 100%.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Engine Brake Controls</title>
                        <para>Refer to circuit diagram CATERPILLAR 3176B - ENGINE BRAKE in CTS-5119S.</para>
                        <para>This manual only discusses engine brake control circuits and components installed by
                            International: the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch (434), the Engine Brake Selector switch (433)
                            and the connecting circuits. The International installed Clutch Switch (294) and Service
                            Brake Switch (141) also provide inputs to the Engine Brake Control System and are discussed
                            in paragraphs 1.2.4.3 and 1.2.4.4 .
                        </para>
                        <para>For a complete description of Engine Brake Operation, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar
                            Service Manual.
                        </para>
                        <para>There are two owner selected Engine Brake operation modes, which are COAST and LATCH.
                        </para>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>COAST Operation Mode</title>
                            <para>If the COAST mode (standard mode) is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
                            <seqlist>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Engine speed is over 1000 rpm.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The driver's foot is off the throttle pedal (throttle position less than
                                        7%).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clutch pedal is not depressed.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The Service Brake pedal is depressed (engine brake only operates while service
                                        brake is applied).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The cruise control switch can be in the ON position, although it will be
                                        disabled by applying the service brake.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>LATCH Operation Mode</title>
                            <para>If the LATCH mode is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
                            <seqlist style="arabic">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Engine speed is over 1000 rpm.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The driver's foot is off the throttle pedal (throttle position less than
                                        7%).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clutch pedal is not depressed.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The cruise control switch must be OFF.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>The engine brake operates when the driver applies the service brake, but the
                                        engine brake continues to operate (LATCHES ON so to speak) after the driver
                                        takes his foot off the brake. The engine brake stays engaged (LATCHED ON) until
                                        one of the other ECM inputs changes: clutch pedal depressed, throttle pedal
                                        depressed, engine speed drops below 950 rpm or the brake pedal is depressed a
                                        second time.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Brake Control</title>
                            <para>Control of the engine brake is shared by the driver and the ECM. The driver turns the
                                engine brake ON or OFF and selects how much engine brake is desired (number of
                                cylinders). The ECM monitors certain engine parameters, then enables the engine brake
                                system when all conditions are acceptable.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Brake With Antilock Brake System</title>
                            <para>When Antilock Brakes (ABS) are installed with an Engine Brake also installed, the ABS
                                controller is connected to the ECM through J1922 connector (403). This connection allows
                                the ABS controller to communicate with the ECM by serial data circuits 98Z(+) and
                                98Y(-). These circuits are a twisted wire pair. This allows the ECM to TURN OFF the
                                engine brake when the ABS system detects that a vehicle wheel is encountering a slippery
                                road surface.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>ON/OFF Switch (434)</title>
                            <para>To enable (turn ON) the Engine Brake Control System, this switch must be ON (closed).
                                With the ON/Off switch closed, the circuit between ECM connector (400) terminal 29 and
                                the Engine Brake selector switch terminal 2 is complete.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Engine Brake Selector Switch (433)</title>
                            <para>The Engine Brake Selector Switch has three circuits, Low, Medium and a common or
                                ground circuit connected to the engine brake ON/Off switch.
                            </para>
                            <para>Selector switch terminal 2 is connected by circuit 24A to the Engine Brake ON/Off
                                switch (434) at terminal 5. When the ON/Off switch is ON, the circuit between the engine
                                brake selector switch (433) terminal 2 and ECM connector (400) terminal 29 is complete.
                            </para>
                            <para>With the Selector switch (433) in the
                                <emph type="bold">Low position</emph>, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector (400)
                                terminal 19 and a 5 volt signal at terminal 13.
                            </para>
                            <para>With the Selector switch (433) in the
                                <emph type="bold">Medium position</emph>, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector
                                (400) terminal 13 and a 5 volt signal at terminal 19.
                            </para>
                            <para>With the Selector switch (433) in the
                                <emph type="bold">High position</emph>, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector (400)
                                terminal 13 and 19.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Idle Shutdown Timer System</title>
                        <para>The idle shutdown timer is a feature which helps improve fuel consumption by limiting idle
                            time. The "shutdown time" is a customer specified parameter, and may be from 3 to 60
                            minutes. Programming the time to zero shuts the timer OFF.
                        </para>
                        <para>The timer is activated and the countdown (from the customer selected time) begins when:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist style="alphauc">
                            <item>
                                <para>The vehicle speed is zero.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>The engine is warmed up.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>The engine is not under load (with or without the park brake set).</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>Ninety seconds before the programmed time is reached, the Yellow Serv/Check Engine light
                            will begin to flash rapidly. If the driver moves the clutch or service brake pedal during
                            this 90-second time period, the timer will be overridden until it is reset. The timer is
                            reset and begins counting over by moving the vehicle a short distance.
                        </para>
                        <para>A code (Override of Idle Shutdown Timer) will be logged when the driver overrides the
                            timer within the 90-second time period. If the timer is activated and allowed to shut down
                            the engine, then a code (Idle Shutdown Timed Out) will be set. These codes record an event-
                            they do not indicate a fault in the system.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>Note that the system shuts the engine down, but does not turn off power to the
                                    vehicle.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_94.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051_96.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
