<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: LEECE NEVILLE AND PRESTOLITE JN SERIES - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Current is produced by rotating a magnet called a rotor inside a stationary winding called a stator (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0802002">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0802002" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0802002" filename="../figg08/G0802002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Exploded View</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BRUSH</callout1>
                <callout1>2. REGULATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. GROMMETED SENSING LEAD ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>4. SLIP RING</callout1>
                <callout1>5. ROTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>6. DRIVE END HOUSING</callout1>
                <callout1>7. STATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>8. NEGATIVE RECTIFIER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>9. POSITIVE RECTIFIER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>10. SLIP RING END HOUSING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The vehicle battery supplies excitation to the field coil (rotor coil) through the regulator and brushes,
            to create a magnetic field around the rotor and through the stator.
        </para>
        <para>When the rotor is set in motion, the moving magnetic field induces an alternating current (AC) in the
            stator windings. So alternating current is produced as the magnet poles of the rotor pass through the coil
            windings of the stator.
        </para>
        <para>For increased capacity, there are twelve (12) magnetic poles incorporated into the rotor and three (3)
            separate windings in the stator. Since alternating current is produced as the rotor passes the coil windings
            of the stator, increased engine speed produces more current.
        </para>
        <para>The battery stores only direct current and cannot use alternating current. So AC produced in the stator is
            converted to direct current (DC) by the positive and negative rectifier assemblies. The rectifier assemblies
            are connected to the alternator output terminals to provide DC output for charging the batteries and to
            satisfy the vehicle electrical loads. Rectifiers consist of silicon diodes which function as electrical
            switches and permit current flow in only one direction. The rectifier diodes are mounted in aluminum
            castings, called heat sinks, which are finned to dissipate heat.
        </para>
        <para>A built-in solid state voltage regulator controls alternator output and the battery's state of charge.
        </para>
        <para>The regulator senses when the battery has received sufficient charge and then reduces the "field"
            (magnetizing) current flow to the rotor. Reducing the field current flow, in turn, reduces alternator
            output.
        </para>
        <para>When headlights and/or accessories place a load on the battery, the regulator increases the field current
            flow to the rotor, thereby increasing alternator output.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
