<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BATTERY - CHARGING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CHARGING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Always follow battery charger manufacturer's instructions.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When possible, use a battery charger with alternator or polarity protection that prevents
                        charging the battery in reverse polarity.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The charge a battery receives is equal to the charge rate in amperes multiplied by the time in hours.
                Thus a five ampere rate applied to a battery for ten hours would be a 50 ampere-hour charge to the
                battery. To fully recharge a battery, you must replace the ampere-hours or ampere-minutes removed from
                it, plus an extra 20% charge. This is due to the fact that batteries are not 100% efficient on
                recharging.
            </para>
            <para>If time is available, lower charging rates in amperes are recommended.</para>
            <para>While battery is being charged, periodically measure the temperature of the electrolyte. If the
                temperature exceeds 51.6&#176;C (125&#176;F) or if violent gassing or spewing of electrolyte occurs, the
                charging rate must be reduced or temporarily halted. This must be done to avoid damage to the battery.
            </para>
            <para>There are two methods of recharging a battery, the Slow Charge Method and the Fast Charge Method.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT OVERCHARGE batteries. Overcharging causes excessive and needless loss of water from the
                        electrolyte.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SLOW CHARGING</title>
            <para>The Slow Charge method uses a low charging rate for a relatively long period of time. The recommended
                rate for slow charging is one ampere per positive plate per cell. If the battery has nine plates per
                cell, normally four of the nine will be positive plates. Therefore, the slow charge rate would be four
                amperes. Charging periods as long as twenty-four hours may be needed to bring a battery to full charge.
            </para>
            <para>Second method: 1% of the CCA rating 625A = 6.25 amps.</para>
            <para>The best method of making certain a battery is fully charged, but not overcharged, is to measure the
                specific gravity of a cell once per hour. The battery is fully charged when no change in specific
                gravity occurs over a three hour period or when charging current stabilizes (constant voltage type
                charger).
            </para>
            <para>If a maintenance free battery is to be recharged overnight (16 hours), a timer or voltage controlled
                charger is recommended. If the charger does not have such controls, a 3 ampere rate should be used for
                batteries of 80 minutes or less capacity and 5 amperes for above 80 to 125 minutes reserve capacity
                batteries. Batteries over 125 minutes reserve capacity should be charged at a rate of 6 amperes.
            </para>
            <para>Batteries that have stood in a discharged condition for long periods of time without a recharge have
                become sulfated and must be recharged at a low rate to avoid overheating and excessive gassing. It may
                require two or three days of slow charging to bring a sulfated battery to a fully charged condition.
                Care should be taken not to overcharge maintenance free type batteries.
            </para>
            <para>Some batteries are so badly sulfated they cannot be restored to normal operating condition, regardless
                of the rate of charge or the length of time the charge is applied. Therefore, if a battery cannot be
                restored to a fully charged condition by slow charging, it should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08022k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
