<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: DELCO-REMY 26-SI SERIES - TROUBLESHOOTING - RATED VOLTAGE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>RATED VOLTAGE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Preferably, alternator output should be checked at the "Rated Voltage" given in
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0801801">Table 1</hotlnk>. However, it is permissible to check the output in amperes
                at any voltage within the "Operating Range" listed in the table, since the current output will be quite
                close to the value that would be obtained at "Rated Voltage." The voltage should never be allowed to
                rise above the Operating Range for any length of time.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0801801">
            <title>Table 1</title>
            <table id="hl0801802">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>SYSTEM VOLTAGE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>RATED VOLTAGE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>OPERATING RANGE (VOLTAGE)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>12</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>14.2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>13.0 - 15.0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>It should be noted that the voltage may be below the "Operating Range" if the batteries are in a low
                state of charge. However, as the batteries receive a charge, the voltage will rise to some value within
                the "Operating Range."
            </para>
            <para>Trouble in the vehicle charging system will be indicated by one of two conditions:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Undercharged batteries are evidenced by low specific gravity readings and slow cranking.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Overcharged batteries are evidenced by excessive battery water usage.</para>
                    <para>These conditions can be caused by:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>A defective battery or batteries.</para>
                            <para>Since one or more of the batteries may have an internal defect, they must be checked
                                to determine their condition. Refer to GROUP 08, BATTERY in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                                Manual for battery test procedure.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Poor circuit connections.</para>
                            <para>Poor circuit connections in the charging system can cause an undercharged condition
                                only. Carefully inspect all connections including grounds between the alternator and
                                batteries for cleanliness and tightness. Insure that the battery terminals are clean and
                                tight and that the batteries are dry and clean.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Accessories left on for an extended period.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Incorrect tension on the drive belt.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>A defective alternator assembly.</para>
                            <para>If the batteries and circuit connection checks are satisfactory, the alternator
                                assembly can or may be tested on the vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Connect the battery load tester to the alternator output terminal and ground, or battery leads
                (alternator preferred) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801804">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801804" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801804" filename="../figg08/g0801804.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>System Check</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BATTERY LOAD TESTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ALTERNATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. VOLTMETER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Alternator output terminal is at battery voltage.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltage Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record voltage reading at battery load tester.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With all accessories and the carbon pile turned off, start engine and increase speed as
                    required to obtain maximum voltage reading on the battery load tester. Voltage should be higher than
                    reading in step 1 above, but below 15 volts. All 26-SI alternators are set at 14.2 volts. Turn off
                    engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If voltage exceeds 15 volts, remove alternator for repair as covered under
                    <hotlnk document="s08018_HL0801803.xml" xrefid="hl0801803">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If voltage does not exceed 15 volts, proceed as follows:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a voltmeter from the alternator output (BAT) terminal to battery positive
                    terminal (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0801804">Figure 4</hotlnk>) (you may need a jumper wire to extend your voltmeter
                    leads).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Load charging system with carbon pile to obtain 100 amps of current. Record the positive
                    (+) voltage reading on the voltmeter. Turn carbon pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect voltmeter leads from the alternator case to battery negative (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0801804">Figure 4</hotlnk>). Load charging system with carbon pile to obtain 100
                    amps of current. Record voltage drop in ground circuit between alternator housing and battery. Turn
                    carbon pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The total voltage drop in the two readings (steps 2 and 3) must be less than 1 volt. If
                    the voltage difference between the two readings is greater than 1 volt, check system wiring and
                    grounds. Repair as necessary. Rerun test steps 2 and 3 to verify system is repaired.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl080181a">
            <title>Alternator Has No Voltage Output</title>
            <para>If the alternator does not have any voltage output, run the following test to determine if the
                regulator is functioning.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rectifier plate cover (Item 2,
                    <hotlnk document="s08018_15.xml" xrefid="f0801805">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a voltmeter to the alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and operate the alternator at idle. With a screwdriver or short clip
                    lead, ground the field terminal illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0801806">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0801806" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0801805" filename="../figg08/g0801805.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Grounding Field Terminal</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is no voltage reading, replace the voltage regulator. The regulator can be
                    replaced without removing the alternator from the vehicle. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08018_HL0801804.xml" xrefid="hl0801804">REGULATOR REPLACEMENT</hotlnk>. If there
                    is a voltage reading, the voltage regulator is okay. Remove the alternator and repair as covered
                    under
                    <hotlnk document="s08018_HL0801803.xml" xrefid="hl0801803">REPAIR PROCEDURES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Amperage Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on accessories.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With engine running at a moderate speed (rpm), turn carbon pile on and adjust to
                        obtain maximum amperage output without allowing voltage on the battery load tester voltmeter to
                        drop below 13 volts. Record maximum ampere output on battery load tester ammeter.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>Initial voltage buildup is by residual magnetism in rotor. Increase the speed as
                                required to obtain maximum current output.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ampere output is not within 15 amperes of rated output as stamped on alternator
                        frame, remove alternator for repair. If ampere output is within 15 amperes of rated output as
                        stamped on alternator frame, alternator is not defective.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018_HL0801803.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
