<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - WT TRANSMISSION DIAGNOSTIC CODES - CODE READING AND CODE
        CLEARING PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CODE READING AND CODE CLEARING PROCEDURE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Diagnostic codes can be read and cleared by two methods: by using the Pro-Link 9000 diagnostic data
                reading (DDR) tool with the appropriate cartridge or by using the Shift Selector Display. The use of the
                Pro-Link service tool is described in the instruction manual furnished with each Pro-Link tool and
                cartridge, and will not be discussed in this manual. The method of reading and clearing codes described
                in this section refers to only entering the Diagnostic Display Mode by proper button and/or lever
                movement on the shift selector.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The diagnostic display mode on the shift selector may only be entered when the vehicle is
                        stopped. The vehicle is stopped when sensor output speed = zero and no output speed sensor
                        failure is active; OR if any output speed sensor failure is active (code 22 16) when turbine
                        speed = zero. Codes may only be cleared under the same circumstances.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following describes how to use the shift selector to read and clear codes. Only the shift lever
                type of selector will be discussed (not the push-button shift selector).
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reading Diagnostic Codes:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The vehicle must be stopped. The transmission should be shifted into neutral and the
                    vehicle park brake applied.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If a DO NOT SHIFT condition is present at this time, the lever should be left in the same
                            position that it was when the code occurred. If not, the shift selector continuous tone will
                            sound until the lever is returned to the original position.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Momentarily depress the DISPLAY MODE BUTTON on the shift selector. Read the first code
                    in the first of five code positions on the digital display on the shift selector. The digital
                    display shows the first code in three steps. For example, code 25 11 located in the first position
                    would be read as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">First the code list position is displayed as "d1."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Then two seconds later, the display will show the main code 25.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Then two seconds later, the display will show the secondary code 11.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Then, if no further action is taken, the display will rerun the cycle of A., B., C.
                        as described above.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To read the second position on the code list, press the MODE DISPLAY BUTTON momentarily
                    and the second code on the list will be displayed in the same manner as in Step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To read positions d3, d4, and d5, momentarily depress the MODE DISPLAY BUTTON as
                    explained in Step 3. Momentarily pressing the DISPLAY MODE BUTTON after viewing the fifth code will
                    cause the first code to be displayed again, etc.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When in the DIAGNOSTIC MODE, the MODE INDICATOR LIGHT will be illuminated when the code
                    being displayed is ACTIVE. When in a normal operating mode, the MODE INDICATOR LIGHT illuminates to
                    show that the transmission is in a secondary mode of operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Any code position in the list of five which does not have a diagnostic code logged will
                    display "--" for both the main and sub-code displays. Any code position in the list of five after
                    such a display will also be displayed in the same way (--) as they will not contain any data.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clearing Diagnostic Codes</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clearing of the "active indicator" is automatically done at ECU power-down (turn key
                    OFF) on all but one code (
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_24.xml" xrefid="t0800301">see Code Chart</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Some codes will clear the "active indicator" automatically when the condition causing
                    the code is not detected by the ECU (see
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800301.xml" xrefid="x0800301">WT DIAGNOSTIC CODE LIST</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Manual clearing is possible while in the diagnostic display mode and after the condition
                    causing the code is corrected.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To clear all active indicators, hold the MODE BUTTON down continuously until the
                        shift selector tone sounds for 0.5 seconds.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Release the MODE BUTTON to return to normal operation mode. If a code was not active
                        at the time, the active indicator will turn off.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
