<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS - CLUSTER FAILURE DIAGNOSIS - SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER AND HOURMETER DISPLAY FAILURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER AND HOURMETER DISPLAY FAILURE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>If any of the speedometer, odometer, tachometer or hourmeter displays is indicating a failure, the
                circuits serving the instrument in question must be checked for clean, tight, unbroken and non-shorted
                connections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure all relays in the vehicle are the suppressed type.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Make sure the accessory voltage to the cluster is within a range of 11 to 16 volts.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer and Hourmeter Failure Isolation</title>
            <para>The instrument cluster has self testing capabilities that will identify various failures in the
                electronic portions of the unit. The self testing diagnostics provide a strong indication of exactly
                what is wrong with the unit, without removing the cluster from the vehicle or spending a large amount of
                time troubleshooting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pass Indications</title>
            <para>The cluster will test itself each time the vehicle is powered up. If all tests pass, the unit will
                drive both the speedometer and tachometer needles through one complete sweep. This indicates that all
                input circuits are good and tells the driver that all output circuits driving the gauges are good.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fail Indications</title>
            <para>The cluster will provide failure indications in two ways:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Does not provide a proper gauge sweep on power up.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The speedometer and tachometer needles "wave" on power up.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>If the unit senses a circuit problem at power up, the speedometer and tachometer needles will
                simultaneously wave from 0 and one of the numbers on the speedometer and tachometer dial faces three
                times. Corrective action is defined in the fail indication table. The "bad" gauge will be parked at full
                scale and the other gauge will be operable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08034x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
