<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - PRO SLEEPER ELECTRICAL SYSTEM - HEATER/AIR CONDITIONER DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>HEATER/AIR CONDITIONER DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The heating and/or cooling source for the sleeper unit is the Blendaire heater/air conditioning unit
                located in the cab.
            </para>
            <para>The cab heater/air conditioning controls are used to select the heating and/or cooling mode (for cab
                and sleeper) and to select the amount of heating or cooling that is desired for the cab area. Additional
                controls (1.1 Standard or 1.2 Thermostat) are located in the sleeper unit, to adjust the bunk comfort
                levels independently from the cab area.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
            <title>MANUAL HEATER/A.C. TEMPERATURE CONTROLS</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0800701">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                for the following discussion. There is an air duct connecting the Blendaire unit to the sleeper. A
                blower motor in the sleeper draws air from the blendaire unit. The sleeper blower also includes a damper
                door to further control air flow to the sleeper.
            </para>
            <para>Standard sleeper heater/A.C. controls include a three-speed blower switch, manual temperature selector
                knob and winter/summer switch. The temperature selector knob controls the blower motor damper door
                position, allowing more or less heated/cooled air to be drawn into the sleeper. The selected blower
                speed and temperature selector knob position determine how much cooled or heated air is brought into the
                sleeper from the cab Blendaire system. The winter/summer switch electrically sets the temperature
                selector knob for either air conditioning (summer position) or heater (winter position).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0800701" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0800701" filename="../figg08/g0800701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 1 - Manual Sleeper Temperature Controls</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08007_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08007_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
