<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALTERNATOR: LEECE NEVILLE AND PRESTOLITE JN SERIES - COMPONENT TESTING - DIODE TESTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DIODE TESTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>These tests may be performed on heat sink assemblies without removing them from the end housing. If
                they are tested in this manner, remove the stator and be sure that the red and black leads are
                disconnected from the regulator and not touching each other. Disconnect the capacitor across the lower
                end of the heat sinks.
            </para>
            <para>Diodes are tested to insure that they only pass current in one direction. Diodes which do not allow
                current to flow in either direction are open while diodes passing current both ways are shorted. Diodes
                should be checked with a diode tester, but in emergencies where one is not available, an ohmmeter or a
                battery powered test light may be substituted.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Positive Heat Sink Tests</title>
            <para>The positive heat sink is the one to which the positive output terminal is connected. The square hole
                in the terminal end of the positive heat sink is larger than the terminal hole of the negative heat
                sink.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the positive lead of the diode tester, ohmmeter, or test light to the positive
                    heat sink and touch the negative test lead to each of the three diode terminals (Test 1,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802012">Figure 12</hotlnk>). A high resistance should be indicated and if a test
                    light is being used, it should not light. If any of the three diodes shows a low resistance, or the
                    test lamp lights, the diode is shorted. Refer to the following
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT</emph>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0802012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0802012" filename="../figg08/g0802012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Positive Heat Sink Test</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reverse the test leads so that the negative test lead is connected to the positive heat
                    sink. The positive test lead should now be touched to each diode terminal (Test 2,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802012">Figure 12</hotlnk>). A low resistance reading should be obtained. If a
                    high resistance reading is obtained, or the test lamp fails to light, an open diode is indicated.
                    Refer to the following
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Negative Heat Sink Tests</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the negative test lead to the negative heat sink and touch the positive test
                    lead to each diode terminal (Test 1,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802013">Figure 13</hotlnk>). If a low resistance reading is obtained, or if the
                    test lamp lights, the diode is shorted. Refer to the following
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT</emph>
                    .
                </para>
                <figure id="f0802013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0802013" filename="../figg08/g0802013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Negative Heat Sink Test</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reverse the test leads so that the positive test lead is connected to the negative heat
                    sink. Touch the negative lead to each of the three diode terminals (Test 2,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0802013">Figure 13</hotlnk>). A low resistance reading should be obtained, and if a
                    test light is being used, the lamp should light. If high resistance is indicated or the lamp does
                    not light, the diode is open. Refer to the following
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT</emph>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When making diode tests, some ohmmeters may indicate results opposite of those shown in
                            text (i.e., a high resistance when text calls for low resistance, etc.). Regardless of this,
                            each diode should give one high reading and one low reading. If both readings are the same,
                            diode is faulty.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>If a shorted or open diode is detected in the preceding tests, the entire heat sink assembly
                    should be replaced.
                </para>
                <para>Heat sinks supplied as service replacements may differ slightly in thickness or general appearance
                    from the original parts. This will in no way impair their interchangeability or reliability. To
                    obtain the maximum serviceability, several different assemblies may be used as replacements. These
                    will be listed in the appropriate parts list.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
