<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - BEGINNING THE TROUBLESHOOTING PROCESS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BEGINNING THE TROUBLESHOOTING PROCESS</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Review "BEFORE BEGINNING TROUBLESHOOTING" located above.</para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When beginning the troubleshooting process, check for diagnostic codes using either:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The shift selector display</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Or the Pro-Link 9000 Diagnostic Data Reader (DDR).</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Record all information relating to the logged diagnostic codes. If using the Pro-Link,
                    also note and record the number of occurrences for each code.
                    <emph type="italic">If not using a Pro-Link, "Clear" all codes from memory.</emph>
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Test drive vehicle to confirm code or performance complaint.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the code is active after the test drive, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800303.xml" xrefid="x0800303">TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC
                        CODES</hotlnk>for the appropriate test procedure.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the code is not "active" after the test drive, it may have been a momentary problem.
                    If the diagnosis is being performed with the Pro-Link DDR, note the number of occurrences for the
                    code. If the number of occurrences indicates that the code has been registered several times,
                    perform the diagnostics for the diagnostic code and concentrate on problem areas that could create
                    an intermittent condition.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If diagnostic codes are present that are not covered in this manual, perform the checks
                identified in BEFORE BEGINNING TROUBLESHOOTING. If no defects are noted that resolve the condition, have
                an Allison dealer diagnose the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003_X0800303.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
