<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TEST EQUIPMENT AND CONNECTOR REPAIR - ELECTRICAL TEST EQUIPMENT - OHMMETER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>OHMMETER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ohmmeter is used to measure resistance (ohms) in a circuit. Like the ammeter and voltmeter, there
                are both analog and digital meters available. It is recommended that the digital meter (Fluke 88 DMM) be
                used.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Some of the devices in an electronic control system are not capable of carrying any
                        appreciable amount of current. Therefore the test equipment used to troubleshoot an electronic
                        system must be especially designed not to damage any part of it. Because most analog meters (
                        <hotlnk document="s08010_13.xml" xrefid="f0801008">Figure 8</hotlnk>) use too much current to
                        test an electronic control system, it is recommended that they not be used, unless specified.
                        The use of any kind of battery-powered test light is not recommended when troubleshooting an
                        electronic circuit, since it, too, could damage an electronic control circuit.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The ohmmeter can only be used on circuits where power has been removed. The meter contains its
                        own low voltage power supply and the power from 12-volt systems may damage the meter.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Ohmmeters use a small battery to supply the voltage and current which flow through the circuit being
                tested. The voltage of the meter battery and the amount of current flow in the circuit are used with
                Ohms Law, and the meter calculates the circuit resistance which is displayed by the meter. With the
                Fluke 88 DMM, range selection and meter adjustment are not necessary.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measuring Resistance</title>
            <para>Resistance measurements determine:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Resistance of a load</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Resistance of conductors</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Value of resistors</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operation of variable resistors.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>To measure the resistance of a component or a circuit, power must first be removed from the circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The component or circuit that is to be measured must be isolated from all other components or circuits
                so that meter current (from probe to probe) only flows through the desired circuit or component or the
                reading will not be accurate.
            </para>
            <para>Notice in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801016">Figure 16</hotlnk>
                that if we wanted to measure the resistance of the load, most of the current flow from the meter would
                flow through the indicator lamp because it has less resistance. To measure the load, one connector to
                the load should be removed. It is not always apparent when a component must be isolated in such a
                manner, so it is usually a good practice to isolate the circuit or component by physically disconnecting
                one circuit.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801016" filename="../figg08/g0801016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Measuring Resistance</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ohmmeter leads are then placed across the component or circuit and the resistance will be
                displayed in ohms (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801017">Figure 17</hotlnk>). When checking a sensor or variable resistor such as fuel
                level gauge, heating the element or moving the arm should move the meter through a range of resistance
                that can be compared to a specification.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801017" filename="../figg08/g0801017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Placing Ohmmeter Leads Across a Component or Circuit</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking For Open Circuits</title>
            <para>Electrical circuits can be checked for opens using an ohmmeter. The circuit must first be disconnected
                from the power supply. The circuit to be checked must also be isolated from other circuits. Connect the
                meter to the open ends of the circuit as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801018">Figure 18</hotlnk>. A high reading (infinity) indicates there is an open in
                the circuit. A near zero reading is an indication of a continuous circuit. Notice also in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801018">Figure 18</hotlnk>that we disconnected the circuit between the light and the
                ground. This precaution prevents reading a circuit as complete that may be open at the load (light) and
                shorted to ground ahead of the load device.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801018" filename="../figg08/g0801018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Checking For Open Circuits</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. DISCONNECTED CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking For Short Circuits</title>
            <para>Checks for short circuits are made in a similar manner to that used to check for open circuits, except
                that the circuit to be checked must be isolated from both the power source and the ground point.
            </para>
            <para>Connecting the ohmmeter as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0801019">Figure 19</hotlnk>between an isolated circuit and a good ground point will
                allow checking the circuit for a short to ground. A short to ground will be indicated by a near zero
                reading, while a circuit not shorted to ground will cause the meter to read very high (near infinity).
                With the Fluke 88 DMM, an open circuit will read "OL" on the meter display.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0801019" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0801019" filename="../figg08/g0801019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Checking For Short Circuits</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
