<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STARTING MOTORS - NO LOAD TEST - INTERPRETING RESULTS OF TEST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INTERPRETING RESULTS OF TEST</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rated current draw and no-load speed indicates normal condition of the cranking motor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Low free speed and high current draw indicate:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Too much friction-tight, dirty, worn bearings, bent armature shaft or loose pole shoes
                    allowing armature to drag.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Shorted armature. This can be further checked on a growler after disassembly.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Grounded armature or fields. Check further after disassembly.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Failure to operate with high current draw indicates:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Direct ground in the terminal or fields.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">"Frozen" bearings (this should have been determined by turning the armature by hand).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Failure to operate with no current draw indicates:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Open field circuit. This can be checked after disassembly by inspecting terminal
                    connections and tracing circuit with a test lamp.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Open armature coils. Inspect the commutator for badly burned bars after disassembly.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Broken brush springs, worn brushes, high insulation between the commutator bars or other
                    causes which would prevent good contact between the brushes and commutator.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Low no-load speed and low current draw indicate: High internal resistance due to poor
                connections, effective leads, dirty commutator and causes listed under Number 4.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">High free speed and high current draw indicate shorted field. If shorted fields are
                suspected, replace the field coil assembly and check for improved performance.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
