<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STARTING MOTORS - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0803601" svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <para>All bearings, wicks and oil reservoirs should be saturated with oil. Place a light coat of lubricant on
            the washer located on the shaft between the armature and shift lever housing.
        </para>
        <para>Sintered bronze bearings used in these motors have a dull finish, as compared to early type machined, cast
            bronze bearings which had a shiny finish. Before pressing the bearing into place, dip it in oil. The tangent
            wicks must be soaked with oil. Insert the wick into place first, and then press in the bearing. For proper
            lubricants refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not drill, ream or machine sintered bearings in any way! These bearings are supplied to size.
                    If drilled or reamed, the I.D. (inside diameter) will be too large and the bearing pores will be
                    sealed over.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>It is not necessary to cross drill a sintered bearing when used with a tangent wick. Because the bearing
            is so highly porous, oil from the wick touching the outside bearing surface will bleed through and lubricate
            the shaft.
        </para>
        <para>Middle bearings are support bearings and prevent armature deflection during cranking. As compared to end
            frame bearings, the clearance between middle bearing and shaft is large and the clearance provides a loose
            fit when assembled.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
