<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - REMOVE AND INSTALL - SPEEDO/TACH MODULE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SPEEDO/TACH MODULE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0803501">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0803501" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0803501" filename="../figg08/G0803501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Speedo/Tach Module</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TURN AND HIGH BEAM INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PANEL LIGHT BULBS (FOUR PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOCATION FOR DIGITAL OR MECHANICAL ODOMETER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CONNECTOR (421) WHITE COLOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CONNECTOR (422) YELLOW COLOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ALARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPEEDO/TACH MODULE MOUNTING SCREW (FOUR PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. MODULE COVER RETAINING SCREWS (SIX - TWO TOP AND BOTTOM, AND ONE ON EACH SIDE)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>To remove this module, remove the screw in each of the four corners of the module and remove the
                module from the instrument panel far enough to disconnect the two 20-terminal, module connectors (421)
                and (422) to complete removal. The connector for (421) is white and the connector for (422) is yellow.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedo/Tach Module Face Plate</title>
            <para>The face plate is removed just like with the General Instrument/Pollak cluster that this module
                replaced.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the module removed from the instrument panel, remove six screws:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Two screws on the top side</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Two screws on the bottom side</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">One screw on the right and left side.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the face plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To install face plate, reverse the above process.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedometer Or Tachometer Gauge</title>
            <para>Remove the module face plate as outlined above. Then grasp the gauge and lift straight out. To
                install, reverse the process.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mechanical Odometer</title>
            <para>With the Speedo/Tach module removed, the mechanical odometer is fastened to the rear lower corner
                (behind speedometer) of the module by three screws.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the three screws and unplug J3 connector (marked J3 on circuit board).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing the odometer, align the odometer to the opening in the speedometer
                    gauge, before final tightening of the three screws. Be sure to plug the odometer in again before
                    installing the module.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm Buzzer</title>
            <para>The alarm (round shape) is fastened to the bottom side of the module by two screws. Remove the two
                screws, unplug connector J4 (marked J4 on circuit board) and remove. To install, reverse the process.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Digital Odometer</title>
            <para>Remove the front face plate from the control module by removing the six screws.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the speedometer gauge to access the odometer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four mounting screws. The digital odometer is mounted on four stand-offs,
                    separating it from the main circuit board.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect J3 connector (marked J3 on the circuit board). Remove the odometer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To install, reverse the process. (Note that the main memory of the circuit board stores
                    the information, so the new digital odometer will display the previous mile and hours data.)
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedo/Tach Module Light Bulbs</title>
            <para>The turn and high beam indicator light bulbs fit into connectors that snap into the turn indicator
                light housing.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn and high beam indicator bulbs are accessed by removing the connector from the light
                    housing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08035x_29.xml" xrefid="t0803501">Bulb Chart</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The orange leads go to the right turn indicator.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The blue leads go to the high beam indicator.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The yellow leads go to the left turn indicator.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The panel light bulbs are twist lock connectors. Turn counterclockwise to remove. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s08035x_29.xml" xrefid="t0803501">Bulb Chart</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08035x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
