<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER DIAGNOSTICS AND SERVICE - PROGRAMMING - PROGRAMMING, CALCULATION AND SWITCH SETTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0815430" svcproctype="program" graphiccount="1">
        <title>PROGRAMMING, CALCULATION AND SWITCH SETTING</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>These calculations and the Speedometer DIP Switch Setting Charts are not for use with
                    "electronically" controlled engines after Jan. 1, 1994. The component changes for those vehicles are
                    to be programmed through the Engine Control Module (ECM) or the Vehicle Personality Module (VPM)
                    (International engines), and not through the speedo/tach DIP switches.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The Speedo/Tach module is programmed for an input signal reflecting the number of pulses per mile from the
            vehicle speed sensor. The chart in this section factors in the speedometer gear pulse information, but the
            number of revolutions per mile of the propeller shaft (same as the output shaft) must be calculated.
        </para>
        <para>The calculation requires two numbers: the number of revolutions per mile for the vehicle tire size, and
            the rear axle ratio.
        </para>
        <para>The tire revolutions per mile can be obtained from:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>The tire supplier.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>International Sales Data Book - Components.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Calculating the figure using the measured distance (in feet) that the truck travels in exactly one
                    revolution of the wheels. 5280 divided by the measured distance = tire revolutions per mile.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>The axle ratio can be obtained from:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The lineset ticket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Axle data stamped on the differential carrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Counting the number (including fractions) of prop shaft revolutions for one tire
                revolution.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Prop revolutions per mile = axle ratio multiplied by the tire revolutions per mile.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">EXAMPLE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Tire Revs/Mile - 471 (12.00 R 20 tire) Axle Ratio - 3.70:1</para>
        <para>471 X 3.70 = 1742.7 Prop Revs per mile</para>
        <para>Look this number up in the
            <hotlnk document="s08154x_23.xml" xrefid="x0815446">Switch Settings Chart
                <xref refid="x0815446"/>
            </hotlnk>
            and use the switch settings in the column to the right of the prop rev/mile (1742 in the example) for the
            new switch positions. The setting for the speedometer switches in this example would be 0001011100 as shown
            in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0815424">Figure 24</hotlnk>, for a typical Medium Duty 16 DIP switch pattern.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0815424" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0815424" filename="../figg08/g0815424.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Switch Setting Example</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To determine 2-SPD, RPM, Tachometer Scale, and Odometer DIP Switch Settings, refer to the
                    appropriate DIP Switch Configuration section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
