<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - GENERAL SYSTEM
        COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>The ECM receives battery power directly from the vehicle batteries through the 6-way, ECM Power
                Harness Connector (131). Two in-line 15A fuses located near the battery connection protect the system.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM and engine control system components are grounded through the engine harness, which is
                connected with a one-way connector to the ECM Power Harness ground circuit which is connected to the
                negative battery terminal. (Refer to the DDEC Ground Composite located in this section.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic ON/OFF Switch (261)</title>
            <para>The Diagnostic ON/OFF switch is a 2-pole, normally open (N.O.), momentarily closed switch. One switch
                pole is connected to the ECM through connector (273) at location E1. This location has 5V present. The
                other side of the switch is ground through circuit 97-GB. Closing the switch causes the voltage state at
                ECM location E1 to change from 5V to ground, indicating the switch is in the ON position.
            </para>
            <para>For use of the Diagnostic switch, refer to the Detroit Diesel Engine Manual furnished with the
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The diagnostic switch must NOT be used when driving the vehicle. If the switch is used, the
                        diagnostic mode will be grounded, causing the engine to return to idle, affecting vehicle
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>International 8-Way Data Link Connector (137)</title>
            <para>Two data link connectors (137 and 281) are installed, providing the same circuits in two different
                connectors. Both data link connectors provide system access for an Electronic Service Tool (EST) to
                communicate with the Engine Control Module (ECM). Connector (137) is the standard International 8-way
                connector and connector (281) is the standard DDEC 12-way connector (discussed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814102">DDEC 12-Way Data Link Connector (281)</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>The International 8-way connector (137) has four cavities that are used.</para>
            <para>Cavity (1), circuit 98A(+), is the positive ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the J11 RED Positive Data Link bus to ECM connector (273), location C2.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (2), circuit 98C(-), is the negative ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the J10 BLUE Negative Data Link bus to ECM connector (273), location C1. The positive and
                negative ATA circuits are a twisted wire pair that provide the communications link between the ECM and
                the Pro Link EST.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (3), circuit 97DL, provides ignition power for the EST. With the key ON, this cavity receives
                power from the key switch through 5A fuse H1.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (5), circuit 11-GL, is a ground circuit for the EST. This circuit is grounded through circuits
                11-GL and 11-GA at J7 cab ground on the left side of instrument panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814102">
            <title>DDEC 12-Way Data Link Connector (281)</title>
            <para>This data link connector provides the same system access as Data Link connector (137), except it
                provides access through a 12-way connector common to other Detroit Diesel engine models.
            </para>
            <para>The 12-way connector (281) has four cavities that are used.</para>
            <para>Cavity (H), circuit 97DA, provides power for electronic service tools (EST) using this connector. With
                the key ON, this cavity receives power from the key switch through 5A fuse H1.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (A), circuit 97-GL, is a ground circuit for the EST. This circuit is grounded at J7 cab ground
                on the left side of instrument panel.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (K), circuit 98E(-), is the negative ATA communication link to the ECM. It is connected through
                the RED Negative (-) data bus J11 to ECM connector (273), location C2.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (J), circuit 97D(+), is the positive (+) ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the BLUE Positive (+) data bus J10 to ECM connector (273), location C1.
            </para>
            <para>The positive and negative ATA communications circuits are a twisted wire pair that provide the
                communications link between the ECM and Data Link connector (281).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
