<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - BATTERY, CHARGING AND
        CRANKING SYSTEMS - OPERATION - BATTERY POWER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BATTERY POWER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Vehicle batteries are connected in parallel with the positive battery cable connected to the cranking
                motor solenoid "B" terminal. Depending upon battery box location, some vehicles have two positive cables
                to the cranking motor. The additional cable reduces the voltage drop during cranking.
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are connected to the cranking motor ground terminal, which is connected
                to the frame rail. The engine and cab are also connected by ground cables to the cranking motor ground.
            </para>
            <para>An optional 3 +1 isolated battery system is available. Refer to POWER DISTRIBUTION AND GROUND SYSTEM
                for this system.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Start Terminal</title>
            <para>The remote start terminal allows an external battery power source to either charge the vehicle
                batteries or assist in cranking the engine. Connect the external source positive cable to the remote
                start terminal and the external source negative cable to vehicle frame rail.
            </para>
            <para>To use an external power source to charge the deep cycle battery (with 3+1 system) at the same time as
                the cranking batteries, a jumper must be used to connect the positive deep cycle battery terminal to the
                positive terminal of the cranking batteries.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_63.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_65.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
