<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - CRUISE/PTO CONTROL
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CRUISE/PTO CONTROL OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to the Operator's Manual for operating instructions.</para>
            <para>Cruise Control - Cruise control operates when vehicle speed is greater than 35 mph and engine speed is
                greater than 1200 rpm. Note that the engine speed signal used by the ECM in controlling the cruise
                system comes from the DDEC sensors. The International installed engine speed sensor inputs to the
                vehicle tachometer.
            </para>
            <para>PTO Control - The PTO operates when vehicle speed is zero AND the park brake is set, which opens the
                park brake switch (269). Releasing the park brake disables the PTO controls.
            </para>
            <para>The cruise control and PTO system share the same components which include:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise/PTO ON/OFF Switch (262)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise/PTO Selector Switch (263)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Service Brake Switch (277)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park Brake Switch (269)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Pedal Switch (295)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Speed Sensor (250)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814104">
            <title>Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</title>
            <para>The Cruise Control Brake/Clutch relay is used to enable and disable the cruise and PTO controls.
            </para>
            <para>CRUISE CONTROL MODE - For the cruise control to operate, the Cruise Control Brake/Clutch relay must be
                <emph type="bold">energized</emph>. Depressing the clutch pedal, applying the service brakes or setting
                the park brake will cause the relay to de-energize, disabling the cruise control.
            </para>
            <para>PTO CONTROL MODE - The PTO only operates when the Cruise Control Brake/Clutch relay is
                <emph type="bold">de-energized</emph>
                by applying the Park Brake.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay is a suppressed relay to prevent voltage spikes from
                        entering the electrical system when the relay is de-energized. ONLY replace this relay with
                        correct part. All relays in the International system are suppressed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Energizing The Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0814101">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                for the discussion on energizing relay (272). Ignition power (12V) from the key switch through 20A fuse
                F3 goes through the clutch switch (with pedal released) and through the service brake switch (service
                brakes not applied) and through the park brake switch (park brake not set) to the control coil of the
                cruise control brake/clutch relay, causing it to energize. With the relay energized, the relay contact
                toggles closing the circuit between 30 and 87, opening the circuit between 30 and 87A.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0814101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0814101" filename="../figg08/G0814101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Ignition Power To The Cruise Brake/Clutch Relay</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise/PTO ON/OFF Switch (262)</title>
            <para>The Cruise/PTO ON/OFF switch receives an ECM signal on circuit 97AG from the Cruise Control
                Brake/Clutch Relay (272). The ECM signal will enable either the Cruise Control mode OR the PTO Control
                mode.
            </para>
            <para>CRUISE CONTROL MODE - With the Cruise Control Brake/Clutch relay energized, the ECM signal is sent
                through the ECM connector (273), location G2 on circuit 97AR to the relay, then through the normally
                open contacts (87 to 30) and on circuit 97AG to the Cruise ON/OFF switch. Placing the ON/OFF switch in
                the ON position completes the circuit to ground indicating to the ECM that the Cruise/PTO Switch is in
                the ON position.
            </para>
            <para>PTO CONTROL MODE - With the Cruise Control Brake/Clutch relay
                <emph type="bold">de-energized</emph>, the ECM signal is sent through the ECM connector (273), location
                J2 on circuit 97AS to the relay, then through the normally closed contacts (87A to 30) and on circuit
                97AG to the Cruise/PTO ON/OFF switch. Placing the ON/OFF switch in the ON position completes the circuit
                to ground indicating to the ECM that the Cruise/PTO ON/OFF Switch is in the ON position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Momentary Cruise Control Selector Switch</title>
            <para>Refer to the Owner's Manual for operational instructions.</para>
            <para>The momentary cruise control selector switch receives signals on four circuits from the ECM through
                connector (273). When the Cruise Control ON/OFF switch is in the ON position, the ground path for these
                four circuits is through circuit 97AE and the ON/OFF switch to ground.
            </para>
            <para>Placing the selector switch in each of the four positions completes the following circuits:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>With the switch in the SET ON position, the circuit between ECM connector (273), location J1
                        and ground is complete.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the switch in the RESUME ON position, the circuit between ECM connector (273), location
                        G3 and ground is complete.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the switch in the ACCEL position, the circuit between ECM connector (273), location F2
                        and ground is complete.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the switch in the COAST position, the circuit between ECM connector (273), location F1
                        and ground is complete.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Depending upon the enabled mode of operation (Cruise or PTO), the completed circuits will cause the
                ECM to perform some cruise or PTO function (SET, RESUME etc.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor (250)</title>
            <para>The vehicle speed sensor is a dual coil sensor with two leads (two wires in each lead). The speed
                sensor is located at the rear of the transmission. One speed sensor lead sends a variable alternating
                current (AC) from engine harness connector (250) on circuits 97AJ and 97AK through ECM connector (273)
                locations E2 and E3 to the ECM. The other lead sends the same signal through the chassis and cab harness
                to the speedometer unit, located in the instrument panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Switch (295)</title>
            <para>The clutch switch is a normally open switch, adjusted to close when the clutch pedal is in the
                released position. Depressing the clutch pedal 0.5 inch should cause the switch to open. Clutch switch
                operation is discussed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814104">Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brake Switch (277)</title>
            <para>The service brake switch is an air actuated switch. It is closed when the service brakes are not
                applied, and opens when the service brakes are applied. Service brake switch operation is discussed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814104">Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Park Brake Switch (269)</title>
            <para>The park brake switch is an air actuated switch. It is closed with the park brakes released, and opens
                when the park brakes are set. Switch operation is discussed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814104">Cruise Control Brake/Clutch Relay (272)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
