<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER DIAGNOSTICS AND SERVICE - PROGRAMMING - 9800 MODEL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="0">
        <title>9800 MODEL</title>
        <svcsubproc id="x0815423">
            <title>January 1996 and Later - Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>The speedo/tach cluster has two sets of DIP switches with ten switches in each bank. The DIP switches
                are located at the top, rear of the cluster and can be used to manually program the speedo/tach
                microprocessor to receive data link signals generated by the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM) (
                <hotlnk document="s08154x_19.xml" xrefid="f0815421">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>Information on engine, axle ratio, tire revolutions per mile, number of teeth on the transmission
                speedometer gear, etc. are programmed into the engine ECM and not the speedo/tach module.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The original speedo/tach cluster microprocessor is electronically programmed, when the vehicle
                        is built, to receive data link signals generated by the engine ECM. However, the physical
                        positions of all the DIP switches remain in the "0" position.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The original electronically programmed settings are shown on the vehicle linesetting ticket in the
                010000 code, Speedo &#38; Misc - last twenty (20) digits (
                <hotlnk document="s08154x_19.xml" xrefid="f0815422">Figure 22</hotlnk>). DIP switch settings can also be
                determined by following the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0815445">DIP Switch Configuration
                    <xref refid="x0815445"/>
                </hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Physically moving any of the DIP switches from the "0" position disables all electronically
                        programmed settings of the cluster. If any DIP switch is moved for any reason, then ALL of the
                        DIP switches must be physically moved to the appropriate positions shown on the vehicle
                        linesetting ticket or determined by following the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x0815445">DIP Switch Configuration
                            <xref refid="x0815445"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        section. Physically moving all the DIP switches back to the "0" position, of an electronically
                        programmed cluster, will enable the original programmed settings.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Component Changes</title>
            </para>
            <para>If there are any changes in vehicle components, such as tire size or axle ratio etc., the engine ECM
                must be reprogrammed with correct data.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The speedo/tach module microprocessor or DIP switches do not get reprogrammed.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>An electronic service tool (EST) such as the Pro-Link 9000 or the EZ-Tech, with the authorized engine
                manufacturer's software must be used for reprogramming the engine ECM. Refer to the Pro-Link manual or
                the engine manufacturer's service literature for instructions.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Cluster Replacement</title>
            </para>
            <para>If a cluster is to be replaced, the service cluster must be programmed either electronically or
                manually.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Electronic Programming</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An electronic service tool (EST) such as the Pro-Link 9000, with the Instrument Panel
                        Cartridge Kit or the EZ-Tech, with the instrument cluster software, are used to program the
                        speedometer/tachometer module microprocessor, through the J1708 data link . Refer to the
                        Pro-Link or EZ-Tech instrument cluster software manual for instructions. This method requires
                        that all of the DIP switches be physically set in the "0" position.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Manual Programming</title>
            </para>
            <para>If manually programming the cluster, the DIP switches should be physically set to the positions shown
                on the vehicle linesetting ticket or can be determined by following the DIP Switch Configuration section
                below.
            </para>
            <para id="x0815445">
                <title>DIP Switch Configuration</title>
            </para>
            <para>The physical settings of the DIP switch positions for electronic engines is as follows:</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Ten Speedometer Switches</emph>
                - 1111111111 (All ten (10) positions on left bank).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Eight Tachometer Switches</emph>
                - 11111111 (First eight (8) positions on right bank).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Switch number 9 is not active</emph>
                - 0.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">One Odometer Switch</emph>
                - 0 or 1 (Number ten (10) on right bank) "0" for miles or "1" for kilometers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
