<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - HEATER AND AIR
        CONDITIONER - OPERATION - Air Conditioner-Cab With Pro Sleeper
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Air Conditioner-Cab With Pro Sleeper</title>
        <para>When the ignition switch is on, power flows in through circuits 13H and 13AK and out through 13-GT to
            energize heater control relay (463-R5). Thus, when the heater control is set to low, medium or high, power
            will flow through circuit 77 to the A/C On/Off switch. If the A/C switch is on, the switch indicator switch
            will illuminate. The ground path for the lamp is circuits 77-GK and 11-GB. Power from the switch will
            continue on circuits 77S and 77K to energize A/C control relay (144).
        </para>
        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with a sleeper A/C On/Off switch, A/C control relay (144) can also be energized
            when the bunk heater blower switch (593) is not in the off position and the sleeper A/C switch (905) is on.
            The switch will illuminate when it is on. Power flows from switch (593) on circuits 77L, 77AB and 77AC
            through switch (905) to circuits 77M and 77K to energize the relay.
        </para>
        <para>Power from fuse F1-B will flow through the relay to circuit 77H where it can split at connector (162).
            From (162) it can flow through circuit 77C to feed the low pressure safety switch, circuits 77C and 77E to
            feed the high pressure safety switch, and 77B to feed the freeze switch. If the refrigerant pressure is
            greater than the low pressure cut off switch, and less than the high pressure cut off switch, circuits 77J
            and 77F remain de-energized. Thus, A/C relay (463-R6) normally closed (N.C.) contacts remain closed and if
            the freeze switch contacts close, power will flow from the freeze switch through circuit 77F, A/C relay
            (463-R6) contacts, and circuit 77C to energize the refrigerant compressor clutch.
        </para>
        <para>When the evaporator temperature cools to below 30&#176; &#177; 2&#176; (-1&#176; &#177; 1&#176;C), the
            freeze switch contacts will open cutting off the flow of power to the compressor clutch. This will keep the
            evaporator from freezing over. If either of the safety pressure switches close, the A/C relay will energize
            and its contacts will open breaking power to the compressor clutch.
        </para>
        <para>With the air conditioning relay (463-R6) energized, power is interrupted to the refrigerant compressor
            clutch, and power is applied to circuit 77D going to the air conditioning relay coil. Thus, the compressor
            is shut down and latched (locked) out by the air conditioning relay, and will not restart until the
            refrigerant pressure is back within operating range and the A/C on/off switch or the blower control switch
            is moved to the off position and then on.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_349.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_351.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
