<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CUMMINS M11 AND N14
        ENGINES - OPERATION - CRUISE CONTROL
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRUISE CONTROL</title>
        <para>The cruise control system has three modes of operation: off, standby and active. The off position of the
            on/off switch turns cruise control off. The standby mode occurs when the driver switches the cruise control
            on/off switch to the on position. the driver can then achieve the active mode by toggling the set/resume
            switch after reaching the desired road speed.
        </para>
        <para>Once the system is active, the driver can accelerate beyond the set speed by depressing the accelerator
            pedal. When the pedal is released, cruise control is reactivated when the vehicle speed reaches the
            previously set speed.
        </para>
        <para>Cruise is deactivated and returns to the standby mode in several ways: the brake or clutch pedal is
            depressed, the engine speed (rpm) drops below 1000 rpm, or the vehicle speed (mph) drops below 30 mph.
        </para>
        <para>The resume switch can be used to reactivate cruise at the previous set speed or the set switch can be used
            to establish a new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the coast feature is used to decrease vehicle speed and establish a new lower
            set speed. By holding select switch in the coast position, vehicle speed decreases until the switch is
            released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the accelerate feature is used to increase the vehicle speed and establish a new
            higher speed. By holding the select switch in the accel position, vehicle speed increases until the switch
            is released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted cruise control on/off switch (435) receives a ground signal on circuits 97-GC, 97-GA,
            connector (259), circuits 97-GA, 97-G and 11-G from the negative battery terminal. In the on position, a
            ground signal is sent from the switch on circuit 97AE, connector (190) and circuit 97AE to ECM connector
            (252) terminal 2. This indicates to the ECM that the cruise control switch is in the on position. In the off
            position, circuit 97AE returns to its 12 volt value, indicating to the ECM that the switch is off.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted cruise set/resume switch is a momentary switch. This switch receives a ground signal on
            circuits 97-GB, 97-GA, connector (259), circuits 97-GA, 97-G and 11-G from the negative battery terminal.
            The cruise selector switch sends a ground signal from the switch on circuit 97AB, connector (190) and
            circuit 97AB to the ECM connector (252) terminal 12 while in the set/accel position. In the resume/coast
            position, the switch sends a ground signal by way of circuit 97AA, connector (190) and circuit 97AA to the
            ECM connector (252) terminal 22.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_155.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_157.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
