<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE CONTROLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0813825" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE CONTROLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This manual only discusses engine brake control circuits and components installed by International,
                including: the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813802">Engine Brake ON/OFF switch (188)</hotlnk>, the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813803">Engine Brake Selector switch (187)</hotlnk>
                and the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813802">Engine Brake Enable Relay (239)</hotlnk>. The International installed Clutch
                Switch and Service Brake Switch also provide inputs to the Engine Brake Control System and are discussed
                in paragraphs
                <hotlnk document="s08138_27.xml" xrefid="x0813804">Clutch Switch</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk document="s08138_28.xml" xrefid="x0813805">Service Brake Switch</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>For a complete description of Engine Brake Operation, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service
                Manual.
            </para>
            <para>There are two owner selected Engine Brake operation modes, which are COAST and LATCH.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813806">
            <title>COAST Operation Mode (Standard Mode)</title>
            <para>If the COAST mode is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed is over 950 rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The driver's foot is off both the throttle and clutch pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Service Brake pedal is depressed (engine brake only operates while service brake is
                        applied).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The cruise control switch can be in the ON position, although it will be disabled by applying
                        the service brake.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813807">
            <title>LATCH Operation Mode</title>
            <para>If the LATCH mode is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed is over 950 rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The driver's foot is OFF both the throttle and clutch pedals.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The cruise control switch must be OFF.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The engine brake operates when the driver applies the service brake, but the engine brake
                        continues to operate (LATCHES ON so to speak) after the driver takes his foot off the brake. The
                        engine brake stays engaged (LATCHED ON) until one of the other ECM inputs changes: clutch pedal
                        depressed, throttle pedal depressed, engine speed drops below 950 rpm or the brake pedal is
                        depressed a second time.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813808">
            <title>ECM/Driver Engine Brake Control</title>
            <para>With PEEC III and 3176 engines, control of the engine brake is shared by the driver and the ECM. The
                driver turns the engine brake ON or OFF and selects how much engine brake is desired (number of
                cylinders). The ECM monitors certain engine parameters, then enables the engine brake system when all
                conditions are acceptable.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM enables the Engine Brake System by energizing the
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813802">Engine Brake Enable Relay (239)</hotlnk>
                after verifying that the following conditions are present:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="alphalc">
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch switch must be closed (pedal released).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic throttle pedal is in the IDLE position (pedal not depressed).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise control must be OFF (see COAST option in paragraph
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x0813806">Coast Operation Mode (Standard Mode)</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed must be greater than 950 rpm.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>With Antilock Brakes (ABS) installed, the ignition power from the Engine Brake Enable Relay (239) to
                the ON/OFF switch is controlled by the ABS system Engine Brake Relay (286). This allows the ABS system
                to TURN OFF the engine brake when the ABS system detects that a vehicle wheel is encountering a slippery
                road surface.
            </para>
            <para>To summarize the engine brake controls, the ECM sends a 12 volt signal (when conditions are correct)
                to energize the engine brake relay (239), and the driver must turn the engine brake ON to ground the
                engine brake relay and to deliver ignition voltage from the relay to the engine brake solenoids. The ABS
                system has the ability to turn the engine brake OFF if wheel lockup is about to occur.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813802">
            <title>Engine Brake Enable Relay (239) AND ON/OFF Switch (188)</title>
            <para>To ENABLE (turn on) the Engine Brake Control System, the Engine Brake Enable Relay (239) must be
                energized. To energize the relay two things must occur:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM must supply battery voltage through OEM connector (191), terminal 22, to energize the
                        Engine Brake Enable Relay control coil.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch (188) must be in the ON position to complete the Engine Brake
                        Enable Relay (239) control coil ground path.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Turning the Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch to the ON position completes the ground path (24Y/24-G) for the
                Engine Brake Enable Relay (239) to the cylinder head ground. When all conditions are correct (paragraphs
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813807">Latch Operation Mode</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813808">ECM/Driver Engine Brake Control</hotlnk>), the ECM applies 12 volts on circuit
                24Z to the Engine Brake Enable Relay (239) energizing coil (terminal 85) causing the relay to energize.
            </para>
            <para>Energizing the Engine Brake Enable Relay causes the relay switch to toggle, closing the circuit
                between the normally open relay contacts (30 and 87). The Engine Brake Relay common terminal (30) has
                ignition voltage from 20A fuse F4 present whenever the key is ON. With the relay energized, the ignition
                power is delivered (circuits 24B/24L) through the closed contacts of the Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch to
                the Engine Brake Selector Switch on circuit 24C.
            </para>
            <para>With ABS brakes note that the power from the Engine Brake Enable Relay (circuit 24B) must pass through
                the Normally closed contacts (30 - 87A) of the ABS Engine Brake Relay (286), then circuit 24L delivers
                the power to the Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch. If the ABS system senses a possible wheel lockup condition,
                ABS Engine Brake Relay (286) will energize, turning OFF the Engine Brake System.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813803">
            <title>Engine Brake Selector Switch (187)</title>
            <para>The Engine Brake Selector Switch receives power from the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch on circuit 24C.
            </para>
            <para>With the
                <emph type="bold">PEEC III 3406C engine</emph>, the selector switch directs ignition power through the
                cab and engine harness to either the front (circuit 24D), rear (circuit 24E) or both engine brake
                solenoids.
            </para>
            <para>With the
                <emph type="bold">3176 Engine</emph>, the selector switch directs ignition power through the cab and
                engine harness to all three engine solenoids (full brake), or center solenoid only (circuit 24F), or
                only to the front and rear solenoids (circuit 24D and 24H).
            </para>
            <para>International installs the harness to the solenoids, and the engine brake solenoids are installed by
                Caterpillar.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Note the Diode Assembly (two diodes) at connector (240) in the JACOBS BRAKE Circuit diagram.
                        The diodes prevent voltage spikes (spikes are created when the engine brake solenoid field
                        collapses) from entering the electrical system causing damage to electronic components.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
