<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992-1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - ENGINE PROTECTION
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE PROTECTION SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Each Series 60 engine includes a standard engine protection system to prevent engine damage. All
                International installed Series 60 engines can be programmed to one of two modes of operation. The
                <emph type="bold">default</emph>
                (standard) setting is for warning lights only.
            </para>
            <para>The optional method is the Engine Power Reduction/Shutdown Feature. This feature includes warning
                lights, engine derating and engine shutdown.
            </para>
            <para>The programmable parameter sheet included in the "Drivers Information Package" with this truck
                indicates which mode of engine protection this vehicle is programmed for.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Protection System</title>
            <para>Series 60 equipped vehicles have a yellow Check Engine Light (CEL) and a red Stop Engine Light (SEL)
                located in the telltale lights in the instrument cluster. Each time the key switch is turned to the ON
                position, the CEL and SEL lights will come on for several seconds as a system self-test and then go out.
                <emph type="bold">If the lights remain on,</emph>
                it means that
                <emph type="bold">the ECM has detected a problem.</emph>
                A diagnostic check may be performed using the "Diagnostic ON/OFF Switch." See
                <hotlnk document="s08146_16.xml" xrefid="x0814601">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>With either the standard "Warning Lights Only" system or the programmable "Engine Power
                Reduction/Shutdown" option, the system monitors the following three inputs:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine Coolant Level**</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine Oil Pressure*</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine Oil Temperature*</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* DDEC Circuit and Components</para>
            <para>** International Circuit and Components</para>
            <para>If during vehicle operation (or when starting the vehicle), any of the above inputs goes outside of a
                limit set by Detroit Diesel, both the yellow CEL and red SEL will be turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>If the optional Engine Power Reduction/ Shutdown feature is enabled (customer selected) and one of the
                three monitored parameters goes outside the limits, the warning lights will turn ON and the engine power
                will gradually be reduced until the engine is shutdown 30 seconds later. There is a Shutdown Override
                switch which, when momentarily held in the ON position, provides an additional 30 seconds of engine
                operation to allow the vehicle to be brought to a safe stop.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Yellow Check Engine Light (CEL)</title>
            <para>If the yellow "Check Engine Light" (CEL)
                <emph type="bold">remains on, it means the ECM has detected a problem. Take the vehicle to a service
                    center as soon as possible.</emph>Some engine features may be lost while the light is on.
            </para>
            <para>The CEL receives ignition power from M11 (15 AMP) circuit breaker through J18 Ignition Feed Adapter
                and is grounded through an ECM controlled ground at terminal B1. The ECM "enables" or "disables" the
                ground (turning CEL ON or OFF) by applying 12 volts or 0 volts to terminal B1, depending on engine
                conditions. With terminal B1 LOW (zero volts), the CEL is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Red Stop Engine Light (SEL)</title>
            <para>If the red "Stop Engine Light" (SEL) comes on while operating the vehicle, the vehicle should be
                brought to a safe stop and the engine SHUT DOWN.
            </para>
            <para>The red SEL receives power from M11 (15 AMP) circuit breaker through J18 Ignition Feed Adapter and is
                grounded through an ECM controlled ground at terminal B2. The ECM "enables" or "disables" the ground by
                applying 12 volts or 0 volts to terminal B2, depending on engine conditions. With terminal B2 LOW (zero
                volts), the SEL is turned ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Override Switch (332)</title>
            <para>The normally open, momentary ON, engine override switch receives a signal from ECM terminal G1.
                Momentarily closing this switch completes the ground path through the ECM power connector, pulling ECM
                terminal G1 to ground. The ECM senses the change in voltage at terminal G1 and provides 30 seconds of
                additional engine run time.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Using the override switch excessively may cause addi tional damage to occur. Use the en gine
                        override only in an emergency.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DDEC Low Coolant Module (343) And Probe (372)</title>
            <para>The DDEC coolant module (installed by International) is connected to the International engine harness
                at connector (343). Circuit 34B provides ignition power from B3 (10 AMP) circuit breaker to the DDEC
                coolant module terminal (5). The module is grounded from terminal (3), on circuit 34-G, through the ECM
                power cable.
            </para>
            <para>Low Coolant Module, terminal 1, sends a very low current signal on circuit 34 to the internally
                grounded Low Coolant Probe. When coolant level is above the probe, the signal is conducted through the
                probe to ground on circuit 34-GA. If the coolant level is
                <emph type="underscr">below the probe</emph>
                (for several seconds to prevent false signals from sloshing) the probe circuit is open, which is
                detected by the Low Coolant Module and a signal is sent to the ECM. The ECM then activates the Engine
                Protection system.
            </para>
            <para>Low Coolant Module signal terminal (4) is connected by circuit 34A to ECM terminal H3. The ECM can
                receive several different signals from the Low Coolant Module including one signal when coolant is above
                the probe and another signal when coolant is below the probe. Additionally the ECM monitors (using
                signals on 34A) voltage levels it uses in setting diagnostic fault codes.
                <emph type="bold">This manual does not recommend trying to bench test the DDEC coolant module using a
                    Fluke DOM as internal circuits may be damaged.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
