<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER DIAGNOSTICS AND SERVICE - CLUSTER FAILURE DIAGNOSIS - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9300, 9400, 9900
        MODELS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>5000, 9100, 9200, 9300, 9400, 9900 MODELS</title>
        <svcsubproc id="x0815425">
            <title>January 1989 to January 1991</title>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, or Tachometer Display Failure</title>
            </para>
            <para>If any of the speedometer, odometer, or tachometer gauge displays is indicating a failure, the
                circuits serving the instrument in question must be checked for clean, tight, unbroken and non-shorted
                connections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure all relays in the vehicle are the suppressed type.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Make sure the accessory voltage to the cluster is within a range of 11 to 16 volts.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to table below for possible conditions and corrective actions.</para>
            <table id="t0815411">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="SQCOLUMN1" colwidth="2in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="SQCOLUMN2" colwidth="2.25in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="SQCOLUMN3" colwidth="2.25in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>First Action</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Second Action</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. With ignition key ON, the speedometer dial pointer is not at 0 to 1 MPH
                                    (Km/h)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove gauge and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to the gauge.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace speedometer.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2. With ignition key ON, gauge dial pointer is at 0 to 1 MPH (Km/h), but
                                    speedometer does not work.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove gauge and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to the gauge.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check speedometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal levels. Refer
                                    to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL. If OK, replace speedometer.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. With ignition key ON, the tachometer dial pointer is not at 0 to 1 RPM.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove gauge and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to the gauge.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace tachometer.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4. With ignition key ON, gauge dial pointer is at 0 to 1 RPM, but tachometer does
                                    not work.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove gauge and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to the gauge.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check tachometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal levels. Refer
                                    to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL. If OK, replace tachometer.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>5. Odometer does not work.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace speedometer.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0815426">
            <title>January 1991 to June 1994</title>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, or Tachometer Display Failure</title>
            </para>
            <para>If any of the speedometer, odometer, or tachometer gauge displays is indicating a failure, the
                circuits serving the instrument in question must be checked for clean, tight, unbroken and non-shorted
                connections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure all relays in the vehicle are the suppressed type.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Make sure the accessory voltage to the cluster is within a range of 11 to 16 volts.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, and Tachometer Failure Isolation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The instrument cluster performs a brief self-test when the key switch is turned ON that indicates
                whether the cluster is functioning properly.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Operation and accuracy of the speedometer and tachometer can be verified with an EST without
                        removing the cluster. The Pro-Link 9000 with the Instrument Panel Cartridge Kit, or the EZ-Tech
                        with the instrument cluster software can be used to exercise the speedometer/tachometer, through
                        the J1708 data link . Refer to the Pro-Link or EZ-Tech instrument cluster software manual for
                        instructions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Pass Indications</title>
            </para>
            <para>The cluster will test itself each time the vehicle is powered up and indicates by pointer movement if
                the cluster is performing properly. The pointers should perform as follows:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The unit will drive both the speedometer and tachometer needles to the 9 o'clock position for
                        about 2 seconds and return to the "0" position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Both pointers will then advance through one complete smooth sweep and proceed back to the "0"
                        position. This indicates that all output circuits are good and tells the driver that the gauges
                        are good.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Fail Indications</title>
            </para>
            <para>The cluster will provide failure indications in two ways:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The speedometer and tachometer pointers do not move on power up.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The speedometer and tachometer pointers do not provide a proper gauge sweep or exhibit erratic
                        pointer movement on power up.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>If either of the above failures occurs, the speedo/tach cluster must be removed from the instrument
                panel and all connections to the vehicle wire harness disconnected for further testing. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s08154x_14.xml" xrefid="x0815409">REMOVE AND INSTALL
                    <xref refid="x0815409"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>Conditions and corrective action are defined in the Speedometer, Odometer, and Tachometer Failure
                Chart below.
            </para>
            <table id="t0815412">
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, and Tachometer Failure Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="SQCOLUMN1" colwidth="2in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="SQCOLUMN2" colwidth="2.25in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="SQCOLUMN3" colwidth="2.25in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>First Action</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Second Action</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Speedometer and tachometer needles do not move on power up test.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove cluster and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to the cluster.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2. Speedometer or tachometer needle moves erratically or sweep is incomplete on
                                    power up test.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Perform
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0815447">Self Diagnostics Test
                                        <xref refid="x0815447"/>
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    .
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. Speedometer pointer is DEAD STILL or does not go through proper sweep when
                                    performing the Self Diagnostics Test.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch the speedometer and tachometer in the cluster. Rerun test. If the defect
                                    follows the meter, replace the meter.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If the defect stays at the same meter location, replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4. Tachometer pointer is DEAD STILL or does not go through proper sweep when
                                    performing the Self Diagnostics Test.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Switch the tachometer and speedometer in the cluster. Rerun test. If the defect
                                    follows the meter, replace the meter.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If the defect stays at the same meter location, replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5. Odometer does not increment properly as described in Performing the
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0815447">Self Diagnostics Test, Step 2, B
                                        <xref refid="x0815447"/>
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    .
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove odometer from cluster. MOMENTARILY apply 12 volt DC power across odometer
                                    leads. If odometer increments with power applied, REPLACE the cluster.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If odometer does not increment, REPLACE the odometer.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6. Speedometer or tachometer does not work while driving.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check speedometer or tachometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal
                                    levels. Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>7. Speedometer or tachometer does not work or operate inaccurately while
                                    driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Manually program the cluster by physically setting all DIP switches. Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s08154x_19.xml" xrefid="x0815410">PROGRAMMING
                                        <xref refid="x0815410"/>
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    . Check operation. If condition is corrected, leave the DIP switch settings in the
                                    new positions.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prior to performing the Self Diagnostics process:</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove speedo/tach unit from instrument panel and disconnect all connections to vehicle
                    wiring harness. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08154x_14.xml" xrefid="x0815409">REMOVE AND INSTALL
                        <xref refid="x0815409"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Write down all DIP switch positions on the speedo/tach unit. The positions will either
                    be a "1" or "0" for each switch. There are two sets of ten switches in each set. Verify the
                    positions are recorded correctly. Switch settings must be set back to the original positions when
                    diagnostics is completed in order for the cluster to work properly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set all of the DIP switches to the "0" position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach Cluster Test Harness SE4365 to the speedo/tach unit (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0815425">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0815425" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0815425" filename="../figg08/g0815425.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Attach Cluster Test Harness to Speedo/Tach Unit</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CONNECT CLUSTER DATA LINK CONNECTOR TO MATING TEST HARNESS CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CONNECT CLUSTER TACHOMETER SENSOR CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (HAS (1) FEMALE
                        TERMINAL)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CIGAR LIGHTER JACK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CONNECT CLUSTER SPEEDOMETER CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (HAS (3) FEMALE TERMINALS)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>6. MOMENTARY PUSH SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. CONNECT CLUSTER TWO-SPEED CONNECTOR TO MATING CONNECTOR (MUST BE CONNECTED EVEN IF THE
                        VEHICLE DOES NOT HAVE 2-SPEED AXLE)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0815447">
            <title>January 1991 to June 1994 - Performing the Self Diagnostics Test:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">IMMEDIATELY after inserting the POWER PLUG into the cigar lighter, depress the MOMENTARY
                    SWITCH repeatedly (at least three times) as rapidly as possible (within one second).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If unit is not defective, the speedo/tach unit pointers should:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate in unison to the "0" position on the gauge face.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both pointers will then rotate in unison up-scale in ten equal steps to full scale
                        (85 mph/3500 rpm). The odometer will advance .1 mile for each of the ten steps.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both pointers will then rotate in unison down-scale back to the "0" position.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If unit fails to perform as described in the Self Diagnostics Test, continue on with the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="t0815412">Speedometer, Odometer, and Tachometer Failure Chart
                        <xref refid="t0815412"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0815415">
            <title>June 1994 and Later</title>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer or Hourmeter Display Failure</title>
            </para>
            <para>If any of the speedometer, odometer, tachometer or hourmeter displays is indicating a failure, the
                circuits serving the instrument in question must be checked for clean, tight, unbroken and non-shorted
                connections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure all relays in the vehicle are the suppressed type.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Make sure the accessory voltage to the cluster is within a range of 11 to 16 volts.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer and Hourmeter Failure Isolation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The instrument cluster has self-testing capabilities that will identify various failures in the
                electronic portions of the unit. The self testing diagnostics provide a strong indication of exactly
                what is wrong with the unit, without removing the cluster from the vehicle or spending a large amount of
                time troubleshooting.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Operation and accuracy of the speedometer, tachometer, fuel, oil pressure, water temperature
                        and voltmeter can be verified with an EST without removing the cluster. The Pro-Link 9000 with
                        the Instrument Panel Cartridge Kit, or the EZ-Tech with the instrument cluster software can be
                        used to exercise the speedometer/tachometer, through the J1708 data link . Refer to the Pro-Link
                        or EZ-Tech instrument cluster software manual for instructions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Pass Indications</title>
            </para>
            <para>The cluster will test itself each time the vehicle is powered up. If all tests pass, the unit will
                drive both the speedometer and tachometer needles through one complete sweep. This indicates that all
                input circuits are good and tells the driver that all output circuits driving the gauges are good.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Fail Indications</title>
            </para>
            <para>The cluster will provide failure indications in two ways:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Does not provide a proper gauge sweep on power up.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The speedometer and tachometer needles "wave" on power up.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>If the unit senses a circuit problem at power up, the speedometer and tachometer needles will
                simultaneously wave from 0 and one of the numbers on the speedometer and tachometer dial faces three
                times. The "bad" gauge will be parked at full scale and the other gauge will be operable.
            </para>
            <para>Conditions and corrective action are defined in the Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer and Hourmeter
                Failure Chart below.
            </para>
            <table id="t0815413">
                <title>Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer and Hourmeter Failure Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="SQCOLUMN1" colwidth="2in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="SQCOLUMN2" colwidth="2.25in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="SQCOLUMN3" colwidth="2.25in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>First Action</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Second Action</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Speedometer and tachometer needles do not move on power up.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove cluster and verify ignition voltage and ground are provided to cluster.
                                    Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2. Speedometer or tachometer needle moves erratically on power up sweep.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove cluster and swap the speedometer and tachometer in the cluster. If the
                                    defect follows the meter, replace the meter.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If the defect stays at the same meter location, replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. Speedometer and tachometer needles sweep three times between 0 and 500 RPM and
                                    0 and 14 MPH.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Speedometer input circuit failure. Replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4. Speedometer and tachometer needles sweep three times between 0 and 1000 RPM and
                                    0 and 25 MPH.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Tachometer input circuit failure. Replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5. Speedometer and tachometer needles sweep three times between 0 and 1500 RPM and
                                    0 and 38 MPH.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>J1587/J1708 Data Link failure. Insure that the vehicle Data Link is not shorted or
                                    wired incorrectly. With the ignition on, voltage from Positive data link circuit to
                                    ground should be approximately 4 volts. Voltage from Negative data link circuit to
                                    ground should be approximately 1 volt. Refer to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAM MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify data from the ECM by using an electronic service tool (EST), such as the
                                    EZ-Tech&#8482; or Pro-Link&#174; 9000, with the applicable engine software. If data
                                    is present replace cluster.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6. Speedometer and tachometer needles sweep three times between 0 and 2000 RPM and
                                    0 and 50 MPH.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Mechanical odometer drive circuit failed. Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7. Speedometer and tachometer needles sweep three times between 0 and 2500 RPM and
                                    0 and 65 MPH.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Mechanical odometer is disconnected, or the odometer circuit has an open. Insure
                                    odometer connector is properly seated to the printed wiring board connector.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Disconnect odometer connector. Momentarily connect 12VDC across odometer wires. If
                                    odometer advances, replace cluster. If odometer does not advance, replace odometer.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8. Speedometer or tachometer gauge pointer goes to the 6 o'clock position and
                                    sounds three long beeps.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Sensor fault is indicated. Use an EST to check for engine fault codes that relate
                                    to sensor defects.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>9. Speedometer or tachometer gauge pointer makes less than full sweep but is not
                                    at 6 o'clock position.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gauge circuit fault is indicated. Remove cluster and swap the speedometer and
                                    tachometer in the cluster. If the defect follows the meter, replace the meter.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If the defect stays at the same meter location, replace the cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>10. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but speedometer
                                    does not work when driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check speedometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal levels. Refer
                                    to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to Step 12.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>11. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but tachometer
                                    does not work when driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check tachometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal levels. Refer
                                    to ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MANUAL.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to Step 12.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12. Speedometer or tachometer does not work or operates inaccurately while
                                    driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Manually program the cluster by physically setting all DIP switches. Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s08154x_19.xml" xrefid="x0815414">PROGRAMMING
                                        <xref refid="x0815414"/>
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    . Check operation. If condition is corrected, leave the DIP switch settings in the
                                    new positions.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>13. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but mechanical
                                    odometer does not work when driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove mechanical odometer and momentarily touch leads across battery voltage. If
                                    the odometer operates, replace the cluster.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace the odometer.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>14. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but digital
                                    odometer/hourmeter does not work when driving.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify odometer/hourmeter is plugged in securely to the module circuit board.
                                    Check for unswitched battery voltage at circuit 14G, terminal 9 of connector (421).
                                    Replace digital display unit.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>15. Digital odometer/hourmeter has missing display segments or extra lighted
                                    display segments.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace digital display unit.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
