<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - THROTTLE POSITION
        SENSOR (267)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0814108" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>THROTTLE POSITION SENSOR (267)</title>
        <para>The throttle position sensor (TPS) is an electronic accelerator pedal. The pedal acts like a
            potentiometer. A five volt signal is sent from the ECM through ECM connector (273), location A3 on circuit
            99A(5V) to the TPS. As the pedal position changes, the wiper inside the TPS connected to circuit 99, returns
            a variable signal through ECM connector (273), location D2, to the ECM. The signal voltage range of the
            pedal is from 0 to 5.0 volts.
        </para>
        <para>The signal on circuit 99 is the input to the ECM that represents pedal position. The ECM regulates engine
            speed proportional to the throttle pedal position. The TPS is grounded on circuit 99-R through ECM connector
            (273), location C3 to the ECM.
        </para>
        <para>The MPSI Prolink Electronic Service Tool (EST) will display throttle position as a percent of throttle (0
            to 100%) or as "counts". The EST displays "counts" as a digital value of throttle position, and the range is
            0 to 256 counts. One count = 19.5 mV input signal to the ECM.
        </para>
        <para>On a Series 60 engine, with a Williams pedal, normal operation:</para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>Idle is 20-30 counts</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Normal acceleration is 31-214 counts.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wide open throttle is 215-235 counts.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Counts from 0-19 and from 235-256 are for diagnostics. If the pedal enters the diagnostic range,
                    it will log a fault. The use of "counts" as a diagnostic tool is discussed in
                    <hotlnk document="s08141_14.xml" xrefid="x0814103">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>The TPS is self-calibrating. The ECM monitors the signal from the pedal each time the vehicle is started
            and automatically compensates for wear. If a new pedal is installed, it does not need to be calibrated. The
            TPS is not adjustable.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
