<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - DIAGNOSTICS - DETERMINING FAULT CODES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DETERMINING FAULT CODES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>MPSI (Pro Link) or Caterpillar electronic service tools (EST) can be used to identify logged fault
                codes. Refer to the EST manual for operating instructions.
            </para>
            <para>The yellow "Engine Warning" light can be used to read fault codes by following the procedure in
                paragraph Reading Flash Codes below.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813810">
            <title>Reading Flash Codes</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">KEY ON - ENGINE OFF PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the key is turned to the ignition position, the yellow "Engine Warning" light turns ON for
                approximately 6 seconds, then turns OFF for several more seconds, then begins to FLASH any logged fault
                codes.
                <emph type="bold">All Caterpillar flash codes are two digit numbers.</emph>
                If there are no logged fault codes, the ECM will FLASH a code 55.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">ENGINE RUNNING PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin procedure with Engine OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and allow to run at low idle for about 30 seconds.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn Cruise ON/OFF switch to OFF position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold Cruise SET/RESUME switch in RESUME position until codes begin to FLASH, then
                    release.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All Caterpillar flash codes are two digit numbers.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Engine Warning light will FLASH the first digit. At the end of first digit
                    there is a one or two second pause.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Engine Warning light will FLASH the second digit. At the end of the second
                    digit there will be a two or three second pause before the next fault code number is FLASHED.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The second and all successive fault codes will FLASH until all codes have been FLASHED.
                    It will stop FLASHING after the last code has been flashed. To see the fault codes again, repeat
                    steps 4 through 8.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Caterpillar fault codes are listed in the Caterpillar Engine Manual that comes with the
                    truck. The codes are also listed in the Prolink Caterpillar Cartridge Manual and Caterpillar Service
                    literature.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
