<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - GENERAL INFORMATION - 1991 - CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</title>
        <figure id="f0812701" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0812701" filename="../figg08/G0812701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Circuit Identification Code</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The circuit diagrams included within show the circuits and components that are part of the electronic
            engine systems covered in this section. By eliminating circuits and components not related to the systems
            being covered, the circuit diagrams are greatly simplified.
        </para>
        <para>Each circuit component is named and may show a connector number (in parentheses), if applicable. All
            circuits are identified by a circuit number, wire gauge, and abbreviated wire colors. Circuits that are not
            numbered can be identified by a wire color and/or wire gauge.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0812701">Figure 1</hotlnk>
            shows an example of a circuit identification code and color abbreviations used in the circuit diagrams.
        </para>
        <para>Connector end views (viewed from mating end) of harness connectors are shown in many cases to help with
            testing. These connector end views are shown near the component location illustrations included in this
            section. Connectors are identified by a "C" along with a number; C102, for example.
        </para>
        <para>Components that work together are shown together. For example, all electrical components used in any
            circuit are shown on that diagram. The circuit breaker, fuse, or power source is shown in most cases at the
            top of the page. All wires, connectors, and other components are shown so the signal flows to ground at the
            bottom of the page (or the circuit). Only that portion of the component used in the circuit is shown. A
            reference is added to the circuit explaining where the complete component is shown.
        </para>
        <para>The symbols used on the circuit diagrams are conventional symbols (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0812702">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Switch and relay positions as shown in circuit diagrams
            <emph type="bold">indicate normal position with the ignition off</emph>
            unless noted.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0812702" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0812702" filename="../figg08/G0812702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Electrical Symbols</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08127_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08127_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08127.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
