<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - CUMMINS CELECT - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - GENERAL SYSTEM
        COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL SHUTOFF VALVE (CUMMINS COMPONENT)</title>
            <para>The fuel shutoff valve is controlled totally by the ECM. The valve opens providing fuel when the
                vehicle switch key is ON and closes when the key is OFF. The valve is also closed by the ECM if the
                engine speed goes above 2730 rpm. When the engine speed drops below 2275 rpm, the valve opens, resuming
                normal operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813516">
            <title>ACCELERATOR PEDAL ASSEMBLY (309)</title>
            <para>CELECT engines use an electronic accelerator pedal assembly that provides electrical signals to the
                ECM in response to the driver's request for engine power. The assembly includes an
                <emph type="bold">Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</emph>
                and an
                <emph type="bold">Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</emph>. The accelerator pedal assembly is not serviceable
                and if defective, must be replaced and recalibrated with the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) (309)</emph>
                - The APS is a potentiometer attached to the accelerator pedal. Movement of the pedal results in a
                variable D.C. signal being sent to the ECM. Twisted pair wires are used for this interface.
            </para>
            <para>The 5V signal supplied to the APS at terminal "A" is from ECM connector (320) at terminal #18. The
                wiper (variable signal depending on pedal position) signal is sent through APS terminal "B" to ECM
                terminal #11. The APS ground is through APS terminal "C" to ECM terminal #19.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Any time the accelerator pedal sensor (APS) is disconnected from the ECM with the key switch
                        ON, the APS and ECM must be recalibrated (refer to paragraph
                        <hotlnk document="s08135_15.xml" xrefid="x0813501">Accelerator/ECM Calibration</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Idle Validation Switch (IVS) (321)</emph>
                - The idle validation switch detects the position of the accelerator at the low idle position. A 5 volt
                signal from ECM terminal 10 is applied to the IVS connector (321) at terminal "B". The IVS sends a 5V
                signal to ECM terminal #6 when the accelerator is in low idle position. The signal is sent to ECM
                terminal #9 when the throttle is not in the idle position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VEHICLE SPEED SENSOR (VSS)</title>
            <para>The VSS is located in the rear of the transmission housing. The VSS has two coils and two leads. One
                coil is connected to the International engine harness and transmits the signal through ECM connector 320
                to the ECM. The other lead is connected through the chassis and cab harness to the vehicle
                speedometer/tachometer unit.
            </para>
            <para>The resistance of the two sensor coils is different. One coil should be 900-1100 ohms and the other
                coil should be 1250-1400 ohms. The two sensor leads are interchangeable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08135_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08135_X0813515.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08135.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
