<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This section includes Troubleshooting Charts for International installed circuits and components that
                are part of the Caterpillar electronic engine control system.
            </para>
            <para>To begin the process, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar troubleshooting manual and follow their
                directions. If the Caterpillar diagnostics indicate that a International circuit is suspect, use the
                troubleshooting charts included in this section for a step-by-step procedure.
            </para>
            <para>The Pro Link EST with the Caterpillar cartridge can be used to read fault codes, customer and engine
                parameters, and monitor various switches and sensors.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>IMPORTANT STEPS BEFORE TESTING</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Gather information</emph>
                by talking to the driver if possible. Try to determine the exact symptoms by gathering relevant
                information:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">What happened, and when?</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Under what conditions?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">When did the symptoms begin?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">What else occurred at that time?</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Verify the problem</emph>. Is the complaint due to misunderstood customer selected
                    parameters? Use Prolink EST to review customer selected parameters.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for and record any logged fault codes.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Do the logged codes correlate to probable causes?</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Were the codes logged about the same time as the symptoms appeared? Were the codes
                        logged repeatedly?
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Are the logged codes related to other symptoms? Do they have a common cause?</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Avoid Preconceived Ideas!</emph>
                    Eliminate any non-electrical causes for the problem first (contaminated fuel, clogged air filters
                    etc.).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
