<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CAB ACCESSORIES -
        OPERATION - Mirrors - Motorized
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Mirrors - Motorized</title>
        <para>Refer to ACCESSORY POWER in POWER DISTRIBUTION AND GROUND SYSTEM for description of accessory power
            circuits to A3 accessory adapter (501). Refer to RIGHT MOTORIZED MIRROR, DUAL MOTORIZED MIRRORS and DUAL
            AXIS MOTORIZED MIRRORS circuit diagrams in CTS-5119W or CTS-5273W, for the following discussion.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Right Motorized Mirror -</emph>The right motorized mirror switch (437) receives power from
            A3 accessory adapter (501) through 10A fuse F5-A when the key is in the on or accessory position.
            Momentarily positioning the switch down from the neutral position closes the circuit between switch contacts
            1 - 2 and 4 - 5. This applies voltage to the motor on circuit 78F and grounds the motor through 78E.
            Momentarily positioning the switch up from the neutral position closes the circuit between switch contacts
            2-3 and 5-6. This applies voltage to the motor on circuit 78E and grounds the motor through 78F.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Dual Motorized Mirrors -</emph>The right mirror circuits in the dual motorized mirror
            configuration are exactly the same as those for the single right motorized mirror. The left switch (823)
            receives power from A3 accessory adapter (501) through 10A fuse F5-A when the key is in the on or accessory
            position. Momentarily positioning the switch down from the neutral position closes the circuit between
            switch contacts 1-2 and 4-5. This applies voltage to the motor on circuit 78F and grounds the motor through
            78E. Momentarily positioning the switch up from the neutral position closes the circuit between switch
            contacts 2-3 and 5-6. This applies voltage to the motor on circuit 78E and grounds the motor through 78F.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Dual Axis Motorized Mirrors -</emph>
            The dual axis motorized mirror switch 1137 receives power from the A3 accessory adapter (501), through 10A
            fuse F5-A, on circuit 78C, through connector (1137), when the key is in the on or accessory position.
            Twisting the mirror control switch knob selects which mirror will be controlled. Positioning the L/R switch
            to the Left or Right position will cause the controlled mirror to move to the Left or Right. Positioning the
            U/D switch to the Up or Down position will cause the controlled mirror to move Up or Down. Ground for the
            circuits is supplied from GND Adapter (456) on circuit 78-GA through connector (1137).
        </para>
        <para>Use the DUAL AXIS MOTORIZED MIRROR circuit diagrams, in CTS-5119W or CTS-5273W, to determine which
            circuits are energized to move the mirrors.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_36.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_38.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
