<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEHR POWER
        SYSTEMS/POWERLINE ALTERNATORS USED ON EMERGENCY VEHICLES - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The Hehr Power Systems/Powerline 25 Series alternators (Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0817001">Figure 1
                <xref refid="f0817001"/>
            </hotlnk>
            ) are 14 volt, heavy-duty, belt-driven, air cooled units designed for clockwise operation (viewed from
            pulley end) in emergency vehicle diesel engine applications.
        </para>
        <para>These units feature an internal voltage regulator, fully enclosed brushes, heavy-duty bearings, built-in
            rectifier assemblies with extra large heat sinks, a dynamically balanced rotor, and heavy-duty stator.
        </para>
        <para>The alternators incorporate a large ball bearing at the drive end and a roller bearing at the slip ring
            end. The alternators have a two leg swivel mounting, one leg of which is equipped with a slideable bushing.
        </para>
        <para>The brushes and voltage regulator are located in a waterproof housing and may be removed for replacement
            or inspection without dismantling the entire alternator.
        </para>
        <para>Silicon diodes mounted in heat sinks convert alternating current from the delta wound stator into direct
            current.
        </para>
        <para>On the Series 25-32 and -34 alternators, the positive and negative diode assemblies are mounted inside the
            alternator.
        </para>
        <para>On the Series 25-35 and -41 alternators, the positive diode assemblies are mounted inside the alternator
            and the negative diode assemblies are mounted externally on the slip ring end.
        </para>
        <para>The negative output terminal on the 25-35 and -41 alternator is internally grounded to the slip ring end
            (SRE) housing.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0817001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0817001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 1 - Power Line Alternators</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
