<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3176 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0812901" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <para>All 3176-powered vehicles have a yellow "Engine Warning" light located in the instrument cluster. Every
            time the key switch is turned to the ignition position, the warning lights should come on for approximately
            10 seconds, then turn off. If the "Engine Warning" light remains on and flashes a code number, it is an
            indication that the ECM has detected a problem. Consult the Caterpillar 3176 manual furnished with the
            vehicle for further information.
        </para>
        <para>To determine the fault codes, use the following procedure:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Begin the procedure with the engine off.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start and run engine at low idle for about 30 seconds.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Ignition key switch must be in the RUN position (not crank).</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Caterpillar 3176 engine diagnostics must be performed with the engine RUNNING.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn cruise ON/OFF switch to the OFF position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Hold cruise SET/ACCEL - RESUME/COAST switch in the RESUME position for 2 seconds and then
                release.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Yellow "Engine Warning" light will flash first digit of fault code.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">There will be a one to two second pause.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Yellow "Engine Warning" light will flash the second fault code digit.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">There will be two to three seconds pause between fault codes if more than one fault code is
                present.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>All Caterpillar fault codes are 2 digits.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The second and all successive fault codes will flash until all codes have been shown.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To stop the diagnostics procedure, do nothing. To see the fault codes again, repeat steps 5
                to 10.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>EXAMPLE - Yellow warning light flashes:</para>
        <para>FLASH - FLASH - FLASH - FLASH - FLASH</para>
        <para>Digit 1 = 5. Then there will be a one to two second pause.</para>
        <para>FLASH - FLASH - FLASH - FLASH - FLASH</para>
        <para>Digit 2 = 5. Another pause.</para>
        <para>The fault code displayed was 55.</para>
        <para>If a problem should occur with the 3176 system, use the Electronic Control Analyzer Programmer (ECAP), the
            Digital Diagnostic Tool (DDT), and the Caterpillar Service Manuals for further diagnostic procedures. The
            ECAP is available at the nearest Caterpillar Service Center.
        </para>
        <para>The vehicle diagnostic connector (8-pin connector) can be utilized by the diagnostic tools to interface
            with the ECM by using an adapter cable available from Caterpillar dealers (Part Number 7X1403).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The ECAP and DDT must contain the new electrical memory chips for the 3176 engines. The PEEC
                    memory chips will not work on the 3176 engine.
                </para>
                <para>The ECAP service tool is sensitive to upper and lower case letters. Use "CAP LOCKS" to switch back
                    and forth.
                </para>
                <para>The DDT can do numerical passwords only. Vehicles with alphanumeric passwords must use the ECAP
                    for programming.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
