<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60
        ENGINES - OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE</title>
        <para>The driver controls the engine brake on/off and selector switches, but the ECM enables or disables the
            system by way of a relay in response to the engine throttle position. The ECM enables the relay whenever the
            engine speed is 150 rpm greater than idle rpm, and the throttle is in the idle position.
        </para>
        <para>The engine brake can provide braking when the vehicle is in the cruise control mode. For example, if the
            vehicle is in the cruise control mode, going down hill, and the engine brake is selected, the ECM will
            control the engine brake with respect to the cruise control set speed. The amount of braking will not exceed
            the number of cylinders selected at the brake selector switch.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted two position engine brake on/off switch (434) receives a ground signal on circuits 24-GA and
            97-GA, connector (262), circuits 97-GA and 97-G, connector (N/L), circuits 97-G and 11-G, connector (N/L),
            and circuit 11-G to the negative terminal of the batteries. In the on position a ground signal is sent from
            the switch on circuit 24AJ to the engine brake selector switch (433).
        </para>
        <para>When switch (433) is placed in the first position, a ground is applied to circuit 24AE, connector (190)
            and circuit 24AE to the ECM (273). This tells the ECM to enable the brake solenoid for two of the cylinders.
        </para>
        <para>When switch (433) is placed in the second position, a ground is applied to circuit 24AF, connector (190)
            and circuit 24AF to the ECM (273). This tells the ECM to enable the brake solenoids for four of the
            cylinders.
        </para>
        <para>When switch (433) is placed in the third position, a ground is applied to circuit 24AE, connector (190)
            and circuit 24AE to the ECM (273) and circuit 24AF, connector (190), and circuit 24AF to the ECM (273). This
            tells the ECM to enable the brake solenoids for all six of the cylinders.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_134.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_136.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
