<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3176 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - GENERAL SYSTEM COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (191)</title>
            <para>The ECM (terminal 1) receives 12 volt battery power from the Run Relay (when activated) through G4
                (15A) fuse.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends low voltage signals (approximately 5 volts, see Caterpillar Manuals for exact
                information) to many of the engine control system components which are grounded back to the ECM
                (terminal 2).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Run Relay (182)</title>
            <para>With the ignition key in the ON position, ignition power from J1 ignition connector on circuits
                19A/19P/97A activates the Run Relay which closes the circuit in the Run Relay between contacts 30 and
                87. See
                <hotlnk document="s08129_5.xml" xrefid="x0812902">Kysor Engine Shutdown</hotlnk>
                in this section for additional information for vehicles with that system.
            </para>
            <para>With the Run Relay activated, the Run Relay supplies power to the ECM (191), the Diagnostic Connector
                (137), the Throttle Position Sensor (158), the Vehicle Speed Buffer (193) and the Engine Brake System to
                energize the engine brake solenoids.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic Connector (137)</title>
            <para>The Diagnostic Connector is an 8-pin connector, but only four pins are used. The circuits are as
                follows:
            </para>
            <para>Pin 1 is circuit 98A(+) which is connected through J24 Red Data Link Connector to the ECM (terminal
                32).
            </para>
            <para>Pin 2 is circuit 98C(-) which is connected through J6 Blue Data Link Connector to the ECM (terminal
                21).
            </para>
            <para>Pin 3 is circuit 97DL which provides 12 volt battery voltage when the Run Relay is activated with the
                key switch in the ON position (engine must be started with Kysor Engine Shutdown).
            </para>
            <para>Pin 5 is ground circuit 11-GL which is connected at the ECM (terminal 2).</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil/Water Warning Light</title>
            <para>The Oil/Water Warning Light receives ignition power from J1 ignition feed stud and is grounded through
                the ECM (terminal 12). The ECM opens or closes the ground turning the light off or on in response to
                engine conditions. The Oil/Water Warning light will come on when oil pressure or engine coolant
                temperature is not within specified limits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Yellow "Engine Warning" Light</title>
            <para>The yellow "Engine Warning" light indicates that the ECM has detected a problem with the engine
                control system and that the vehicle requires service as soon as possible. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s08129_8.xml" xrefid="hl0812901">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>. The yellow "Engine Warning"
                light receives 12V power from ignition connector, J1 on circuit 28A, and is grounded to the ECM
                (terminal 29). The ECM opens and closes the ground, turning the light off or on in response to engine
                conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08129.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
