<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - DESCRIPTION - ELECTRONIC SERVICE TOOLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0813826" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ELECTRONIC SERVICE TOOLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Electronic service tools are designed to help the service technician locate faults and/or analyze
                problems within the PEEC III and 3176 systems. Diagnostic code reading and switch monitoring can be done
                using the service tools. An electronic service tool is necessary to read or change operating parameters.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Data Link Connector (137)</title>
            <para>International provides a Data Link connector (137) for connecting an Electronic Service Tool (EST) to
                the PEEC III or 3176 system. The Data Link connector is located on the instrument panel left.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Caterpillar Service Tools</title>
            <para>Caterpillar service tools are available for PEEC III and 3176 engines. The Electronic Control Analyzer
                Programmer (ECAP) and the Digital Diagnostic Tool (DDT) both can communicate with PEEC III and 3176
                ECM's. Refer to Caterpillar Service Manuals for complete information needed to use these tools.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MPSI Pro-Link 9000</title>
            <para>The MPSI Pro Link 9000 Electronic Service Tool is available with a single cartridge that communicates
                with both the Caterpillar PEEC III and 3176 engines. The Pro Link 9000 communicates with the engine ECM
                through the Data Link connector. A manual is provided with the MPSI Caterpillar cartridge explaining its
                use.
            </para>
            <para>This section does not discuss engine diagnostics,
                <emph type="bold">except as they relate to International installed circuits or components</emph>. Refer
                to the Caterpillar Engine Operators Manual furnished with the vehicle and/or other Caterpillar Service
                Literature for additional engine related information.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When referring to an electronic service tool (EST), this manual will make reference to the
                        MPSI Pro Link.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
