<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - HEATER AND AIR
        CONDITIONER - OPERATION - Heater-Bunk With Pro Sleeper With Thermostat Temperature Control
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="idcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Heater-Bunk With Pro Sleeper With Thermostat Temperature Control</title>
        <para>When key switch (40) is moved to the ignition position, power is applied to I2 ignition adapter (495),
            circuit 13AT, and the coil of auxiliary blower relay (147). The ground path for the auxiliary blower relay
            is circuits 13-GAT, 75-GH, 75-GN and 11-GBD to ground adapter (454). This energizes the auxiliary bunk
            blower relay (147) and allows power to flow from (B2) battery stud through circuits 14AK, 14AU, 15A fuse
            F10-B (location may vary), circuit 75AX, auxiliary bunk relay (147) N.O. contacts, circuit 75AS, connector
            (906), circuits 75AS and 75AR to bunk heater blower switch (593).
        </para>
        <para>When the bunk heater blower switch (593) is moved to the low speed position, power flows through circuit
            75AC, connector (N/L), circuit 75AC, resistor and thermofuse assembly, circuit 75AT, connector (48), circuit
            75AT, sleeper high speed relay (584) N.C. contacts, circuit 75AF, connector (48) and circuit 75AF to the
            sleeper blower motor. This causes the blower motor to run at low speed. The blower motor ground path is
            circuit 75-GA, connector (48), circuits 75-GA and 11-GBD to ground adapter (454).
        </para>
        <para>When the bunk blower switch (593) is moved to the medium speed position, power flows through circuit 75AN
            to the sleeper medium speed relay (585). The ground path for the sleeper medium speed relay (585) is
            circuits 75-GN and 11-GBD to ground adapter (454). This energizes the sleeper medium speed relay (585) and
            allows power to flow from (B2) battery stud through circuits 14AK, 14AU, fuse F10-A, circuits 75AW, 75AB,
            sleeper medium speed relay (585) N.O contacts, circuit 75AM, connector (48), circuit 75AM, resistor and
            thermofuse assembly (N/L), circuit 75AT, connector (48), circuit 75AT, sleeper high speed relay (584) N.C.
            contacts, circuit 75AF, connector (48) and circuit 75AF to sleeper blower motor. This causes the blower
            motor to run at medium speed. The blower ground path is circuit 75-GA, connector (48), circuits 75-GA and
            11-GBD to ground adapter (454).
        </para>
        <para>When the bunk blower switch (593) is moved to the high speed position, power flows through the switch,
            circuit 75AH to the sleeper high speed relay (584). The ground path for the sleeper high speed relay (584)
            is circuits 75-GH, 75-GN and 11-GBD to ground adapter (454). This energizes the sleeper high speed relay
            (584) and allows power to flow from (B2) battery stud through circuit 14AK, 14AU, 30A fuse F10-A (location
            may vary), circuits 75AW, 75AD, sleeper high speed relay (584) N.O. contacts, circuit 75AF, connector (48)
            and circuit 75AF to sleeper blower motor. This causes the blower motor to run at high speed.
        </para>
        <para>The blower ground path is circuit 75-GA, connector (48), circuits 75-GA and 11-GBD to ground adapter
            (454). When the key switch (40) is moved to the ignition position, power is also made available by the
            auxiliary bunk relay (147) to circuit 75AS, connector (80), circuits 75AS and 75AL to sleeper automatic
            temperature control connector (592). The ground path for the sleeper temperature control is through
            connector (592), circuits 75-GS to sleeper ground stud and 11-GAN to B-pillar ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When the bunk heater blower switch (593) is moved to the high, medium or low positions, power flows
            through circuit 75AL to the auto temperature control module (592). This allows the voltage from the auto
            temperature control module to control the heater box flat pack.
        </para>
        <para>Power to the heater box damper flat pack is made available by the auxiliary bunk relay (475) to circuit
            75L, connector (162) and circuit 75L. The heater box damper flat pack is grounded through circuit 75-GL,
            connector (161), circuits 75-G and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud. The flat pack receives a variable
            voltage from the sleeper automatic temperature control through connector (592), circuit 75K, connector
            (906), circuit 75K, connector (162) and circuit 75K. Thus the damper blends hot and cold air as selected by
            the sleeper temperature control.
        </para>
        <para>When the key switch (40) is in ignition position and the bunk heater blower switch (593) is in low, medium
            or high position, power is applied to circuit 77L and the sleeper A/C On/Off switch (905). When the switch
            is moved to the on position, the switch indicator lamp illuminates. The ground path for the lamp is through
            circuits 75-GBB, 75-GBA and 77-GL to the sleeper ground stud. When the switch is moved to on position, power
            is also supplied to the A/C control relay (144) by way of the blocking diode, connector (905), circuit 77M,
            connector (906) and circuits 77M and 77K. Thus, the A/C compressor will engage, if it is not already running
            (the compressor will cycle with the freeze switch), and cooling will be available for the sleeper blower.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This is the optional thermostat temperature control circuit. The output of the system changes with
                    changes in temperature to maintain the temperature of the sleeper at the thermostat setting.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_353.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_355.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
