<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE (ECM)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ELECTRONIC CONTROL MODULE (ECM)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The "Brain" of the PEEC III and 3176 engine control system is two components working together: the
                Electronic Control Module (ECM) and the Vehicle Personality Module (VPM). The ECM is mounted on the left
                side of the engine and the VPM is mounted on the ECM. The ECM is the computer which controls the PEEC
                III and 3176 engine. The VPM contains operating instructions (software) including owner selected
                parameters and other engine information for the ECM to use, controlling how the ECM behaves.
            </para>
            <para>The International engine harness connects to the Caterpillar engine harness using International 40-pin
                OEM connector (191). OEM connector (191) connects to
                <emph type="bold">Caterpillar engine harness 40-pin connector J7</emph>. All electronic communication
                between the International electrical system and the Caterpillar engine control system go through
                (191)/J7, the International/Caterpillar connection.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM receives operating power (12 volt DC) from the vehicle batteries through International engine
                harness OEM connector (191) when the ignition key switch is in the IGN position. The ECM is intended to
                operate on 12V, but will tolerate voltage as low as 6 volts during cranking, or 9 volts during normal
                engine operation. The ECM is protected against power surges on the 12 volt power supply due to
                alternator load dumps, air conditioner clutches, etc. and for jump starting.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM acts as 5V power supply for many Caterpillar and International components used to monitor and
                control engine/vehicle systems.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inputs And Outputs</title>
            <para>The ECM is connected to the International installed switches that communicate with the</para>
            <para>ECM. The switches are 2-way or 3-way switches and are either ON or OFF.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">EXAMPLE OF A 2-WAY SWITCH:</emph>
                Cruise Control ON-OFF Switch (195)
            </para>
            <para>The ECM needs to know if the Cruise ON/OFF switch is in the ON or OFF position. To accomplish this the
                Cruise ON/OFF switch is connected to the ECM with an input circuit 97AE and a "common" or ground circuit
                97-GH.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Each International installed switch has an "input" circuit that is connected through OEM
                        connector (191) to an assigned ECM terminal. This circuit has 5 volts applied at the ECM
                        terminal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Each switch is connected to a "common" or ground circuit that is connected through OEM
                        connector (191) terminal #2 to ECM ground (part of Caterpillar harness).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the Cruise switch is OFF (switch open), the ECM sees 5 volts at ECM terminal 10. Placing
                        the cruise switch to the ON position (switch closed) causes the ECM to see 0 volts (ground
                        voltage will be 0 to 0.5 volts) at terminal 10. The ECM programming has established that the
                        Cruise Control Switch is OFF when it sees 5 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal 10 or cruise
                        is ON when the ECM sees 0 volts at terminal 10.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>EXAMPLE: The service brake switch (141) is connected by input circuit 97AL to OEM connector (191)
                terminal 30. Terminal 30 has a 5-volt signal present. With the brake switch closed (pedal released) the
                circuit is complete between terminals 30 (input) and 2 (common or ground). This causes the 5 volt signal
                at terminal 30 to go to zero. This tells the ECM that the service brake switch is closed (pedal
                released).
            </para>
            <para>This type of circuit is used to communicate switch and some sensor information to the ECM. Some
                sensors receive a 5 volt signal and return a variable voltage indicating some variable attribute. The
                ECM also uses 12 volt circuits to enable (activate) relays in the system.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM receives "inputs" through OEM connector (191) from the following International components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) through the Speed Buffer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Throttle Position Sensor (TPS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Service Brake Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Pedal Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Level Sensor (CLS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park Brake Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise Control ON/OFF Switch</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The ECM also receives and processes information from Caterpillar sensors and switches used to control
                engine operation including: rack and timing, the fuel shutoff valve, and other engine components. For
                information on engine operation, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813813">
            <title>KEY ON - Battery Power To ECM</title>
            <para>The ECM receives battery power from OEM connector (191) terminal #1 whenever the Ignition Key Switch
                is in the IGN position.
            </para>
            <para>The battery power to the ECM is switched ON or OFF by the Run Relay (182), which is energized when the
                key switch is in the IGN position.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Turning the key switch to the IGN position applies power from fuse F3 on circuit 19A/97A to
                        the Run Relay control coil. This energizes the Run Relay (182), closing the normally open (N.O.)
                        relay contacts (30 - 87). The Run Relay control coil ground path is circuit 11-DB to J7 cab
                        ground.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Run Relay common terminal 30 has battery power present from the ACC Magnetic switch on circuit
                        97C. With the relay energized, battery power goes through the N.O. terminals (30 to 87) on
                        circuit 97B to 15A fuse H4. From H4, circuit 13D delivers the battery power to OEM connector
                        (191), terminal 1.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>It is important to note that 12V battery power from Run Relay is also distributed to: the Throttle
                Position Sensor (158), the Data Link connector (137), and the Vehicle Speed Buffer (193).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813824">
            <title>Power To ECM While Cranking Engine (PEEC III ONLY)</title>
            <para>Depressing the start button energizes the Start Magnetic Switch sending battery power on circuit 17E
                to 15A fuse H2. Power from H2 goes on circuit 17F through OEM connector (191) terminal 4 to the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM uses this power to energize the Fuel Shutoff Solenoid (dual coil solenoid) during the cranking
                process. When the starter is released, the ECM supplies hold-in voltage keeping the shutoff solenoid
                energized and no voltage is present from the vehicle on circuit 17F. When the starter button is
                released, the voltage at OEM connector (191) terminal 4 is turned off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Manual Fuel Shutoff Lever</title>
            <para>There is a manual shutoff lever located on the fuel pump. The shaft has a spring to keep it in the
                neutral position. The shaft can be manually rotated counter-clockwise to shut fuel OFF or clockwise to
                manually turn fuel ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
