<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - INSTRUMENTS
        (New Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - INSTRUMENT CLUSTER JUMPER USAGE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INSTRUMENT CLUSTER JUMPER USAGE</title>
        <para>The speedometer jumper pins are used to set up the cluster for MPH or KPH as the primary speedometer
            readout, and to select axle ratios. They are located at the top edge of the cluster and can be accessed by
            pulling the cluster out of the instrument panel (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0815520">Item 3, Figure 20</hotlnk>). All other speedometer and tachometer parameters are
            programmed electronically through the data link into the engine ECM.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0815520" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0815520" filename="../figg08/g0815520.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Jumper Pin Location</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. CLUSTER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. WIRING HARNESS CONNECTORS</callout1>
                <callout1>3. RECEPTACLE PINS FOR JUMPERS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. ENGLISH-METRIC CONVERSION SPEEDOMETER AND ODOMETER JUMPER PINS (MPH/KPH)</callout1>
                <callout1>5. ONE AXLE RATIO SETTING JUMPER PINS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>There may be two jumpers visible. The left jumper is for setting the odometer from English to metric
            readings (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0815520">Item 4, Figure 20</hotlnk>). For miles per hour (MPH), the jumper is not
            installed. For a kilometers per hour (KPH) speedometer, the jumper is installed.
        </para>
        <para>The right jumper (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0815520">Item 5, Figure 20</hotlnk>) is for calibration of the two available two-speed axle
            ratios. These are 1.36:1 (jumper not installed) and 1.39:1 (jumper installed). If the vehicle does not have
            a two-speed axle, the jumper setting is inactive and a jumper is not needed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>For the speedometer and tachometer to function properly when tire sizes and/or rear axle ratios
                    are changed, the engine ECM must be reprogrammed so that it will send the correct data to the
                    instrument cluster.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
