<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CATERPILLAR C-10, C-12
        AND 3406E ENGINES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This section describes specific electrical operation of International installed circuits and
                components, referencing specific circuits, connectors and components by number.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to circuit diagram CATERPILLAR C-10, C-12 or 3406E - ENGINE CONTROLS IN CTS-5119W or
                CTS-5273W.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ECM POWER CIRCUITS</title>
            <para>With the key switch on, the ECM receives (12 volt DC) operating power from the vehicle batteries
                through International engine harness connector (400) terminal 70. The battery power to the ECM is
                switched on or off by the run relay (201), which is energized when the key switch is in the ignition
                position.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Turning the key switch on applies power from ignition adapter (494) to circuit 13Z and the
                        control coil of the run relay (201), causing it to energize. The relay control coil is grounded
                        through circuits 13-GZ and 11-GT going to ground through (506) panel light ground adapter.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Battery power from connector (497) B1 battery adapter is applied to run relay terminal 30.
                        This circuit is protected by 20A fuse F6-D. With the relay energized, battery voltage passes
                        through the Normally Open (N.O.) relay contacts and is sent on circuits 97L to International ECM
                        connector (400) terminal 70.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Battery power from the (+) battery terminal of the cranking motor solenoid is always applied on
                circuits 97 and 97A through connector (400) terminals 52 and 53 to the ECM. These circuits are protected
                by fuses (217) and (218).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM uses this power to maintain a portion of memory used for customer trip data accumulators.
                Disconnecting this circuit does not affect engine operation or factory/customer parameters or logged
                diagnostic codes. Refer to the Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting Manual for additional information
                on this feature.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_92.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_94.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
