<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CATERPILLAR C-10, C-12
        AND 3406E ENGINES - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Before beginning these test procedures, make sure the vehicle batteries are at 75% state of
                        charge (SOC) or higher. This represents an open circuit voltage (OCV) of 12.4 volts. Batteries
                        with an OCV of 12 volts or less are either completely discharged or have a dead cell.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before beginning these test procedures, check any light or indicator lamp filaments that are
                        suspected of being open (burned out). This is done to avoid unnecessary extensive circuit
                        checks.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before beginning these test procedures, inspect all connectors for loose or damaged pins,
                        wires, etc. Refer to TEST EQUIPMENT AND CONNECTOR REPAIR section in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the
                        CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the technician determines that a fuse is blown, while checking its condition, he is
                        directed to locate the cause of the overload condition and to repair it. While no further
                        instruction on this procedure is listed in the diagnostic tables, the common procedure is as
                        follows: isolate sections of the circuit by disconnecting connectors, and measure the resistance
                        to ground to find the circuit that is shorted to ground. Then locate the damaged spot in the
                        wire or connector and repair.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics for circuits that are malfunctioning by sticking in the on position are generally
                        not covered in detail. It is assumed that the technician knows to check for a malfunctioning
                        switch, relay, or solenoid.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>During normal vehicle start-up, turning the key to the on position causes the Serv/Check Engine light
                to come on as a system test. The light remains on for about six seconds, then goes off. If the
                Serv/Check Engine light stays on after the initial start-up, the ECM has detected a problem with the
                system.
            </para>
            <para>All C-10, C-12 and 3406E equipped vehicles have a yellow Serv/Check Engine light located in the left
                gauge cluster. This light communicates engine status.
            </para>
            <para>If during vehicle operation, the Serv/Check Engine light comes on, that indicates an active fault is
                present. The light will remain on, but blink approximately every five seconds for a brief 1/2 second.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_106.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_108.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
