<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - GENERAL INFORMATION - 1992 - 1993 - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The electronic engines in this service section will to some extent diagnose the engine control systems
                and provide diagnostic codes that can be read through the data link connector, using electronic service
                tools, such as the ProLink.
            </para>
            <para>The chapters also include diagnostic charts to assist in troubleshooting specific International
                circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DATA LINK CONNECTOR</title>
            <para>The data link is a data communications system that transfers electronic information between various
                components on and off the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>On 9600/9700 Series vehicles the data link connector allows interfacing between on-board electronics
                and other electronic instruments.
            </para>
            <para>The outline and pinout of the data link connector are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0814203">Figure 6.01</hotlnk>. The connector has two pins, one labeled (+) and one
                labeled (-). The signal on these wires is very different from standard truck-type electrical signals.
                Truck signals usually are on or off and either 12 volts DC or zero volts DC. The data link connector
                wires, (+) and (-), carry a pulsed signal which may or may not be detected with a voltmeter. Refer to
                the specific chapter for pin/circuit information.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0814203" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0814203" filename="../figg08/G0814203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.01- Data Link Connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A - DATA LINK CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>B - DUST CAP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>An ohmmeter can be used to check wires in the engine control circuits, but specific diagnostic
                equipment must be used to check for proper system operation and diagnostics.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08142_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08142_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08142.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
