<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3176 - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - CRUISE AND PTO
        CONTROLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRUISE AND PTO CONTROLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The cruise control switches are used as PTO controls (if vehicle is so equipped) when the vehicle road
                speed is not present (this is an owner selected parameter). Refer to the Owners Manuals furnished with
                the vehicle for operating instructions.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control ON/OFF Switch (66)</title>
            <para>The cruise ON/OFF switch circuit (97AE) is an input to the ECM through ECM connector (320) terminal
                #10. The ground side of the ON/OFF switch is connected through circuit 97-GH/97GA to ECM connector (320)
                terminal #2 (GRD). With the switch ON, the ECM sees 0 volts at ECM connector (320) terminal #10. With
                the switch OFF, the ECM sees 5 volts at ECM connector (320) terminal #10.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Set/Resume Switch (67)</title>
            <para>The Set/Resume switch "pointer" terminal is connected through common circuit (97-GD/97-GA) to ECM
                connector (320) terminal #2 (GRD). The "set" terminal is an input (circuit 97AB) to the ECM through ECM
                connector (320) input terminal #38. The "resume" terminal is an input (circuit 97AA) to the ECM through
                ECM connector (320) input terminal #3.
            </para>
            <para>With the switch in the "set" position, the ECM sees 0 volts at ECM connector (320) terminal #38 and 5
                volts at terminal #3. In "resume" the ECM sees 5 volts at ECM connector (320) terminal #38 and 0 volts
                at terminal #3. In the set/resume neutral position, the ECM sees 5 volts at both ECM connector (320)
                terminals #3 and #38.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813302">
            <title>Service Brake Switch (69)</title>
            <para>Service brake switch circuit (97AL) is an input to the ECM through ECM connector (320) terminal #30.
                The ground side of the ON/OFF switch is connected through circuit 97H/97-GB/97-GA to ECM connector (320)
                terminal #2. With the service brakes released (switch closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at ECM connector
                (320) terminal #30. Applying the brakes opens the switch, and the ECM sees 5 volts at terminal #30.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813303">
            <title>Clutch Switch</title>
            <para>Clutch pedal switch circuit (97AH) is an input to the ECM through ECM connector (320) terminal #31.
                The ground side of the clutch pedal switch is grounded through circuit 97-GE/97-GA to ECM connector
                (320) terminal #2. With the drivers foot off the clutch pedal (switch closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at
                terminal #31. When the driver depresses the clutch pedal, the ECM sees 5 volts at terminal # 31.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813306">
            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor</title>
            <para>The vehicle speed sensor is located at the rear of the transmission. The sensor contains a permanent
                magnet that creates a magnetic field interrupted by the teeth on the speedometer output gear. As the
                rotating speedometer gear teeth repeatedly interrupt the magnetic field, a variable AC voltage is
                generated and transmitted through a 2-wire lead connecting to the Caterpillar Vehicle Speed Buffer
                mounted on top of the transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Speed Buffer (308)</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Buffer is a Caterpillar component installed by International on top of the
                transmission. The Vehicle Speed Buffer connects to Engine Harness 5-pin connector (308) and also
                connects to the Vehicle Speed Sensor with a 2-pin connector (325). The speed buffer receives the
                variable AC signal from the Vehicle Speed Sensor, processes the signal, then outputs a signal to the
                ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The vehicle speed buffer sends a buffered and shaped signal from connector (308) on circuit 47D
                through ECM connector (320) terminal #33 to the ECM. The signal to the ECM is a pulsed DC signal of 0 to
                6 volts that is interpreted by the ECM as vehicle speed.
            </para>
            <para>With the key switch ON, the speed buffer receives 12 volt operating power through engine and cab
                harness circuits 97AC/97L, from 10A F33 fuse. The fuse is located on the main fuse block. The speed
                buffer ground is through engine harness circuit 11-GV/11-GS to the engine cylinder head ground bolt.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Throttle Position Sensor (309)</title>
            <para>The Throttle Position Sensor (TPS) is an electronic sensor attached to the accelerator pedal assembly.
                The TPS connects to the cab overlay harness at 3-pin connector (309). The TPS operates on 12V ignition
                voltage (circuit 97L/99E) from F33 fuse whenever the key switch is in the ON position. The TPS is
                grounded (circuit 99-G/97-GA) through the cab and engine harness to ECM connector (320) terminal #2
                (ground).
            </para>
            <para>TPS output to the ECM is a constant frequency signal with a pulse width that varies with throttle
                position. This output signal is referred to as either "Duty Cycle" or "Pulse Width Modulated" (PWM)
                signal and is expressed as a percentage of throttle between 0 and 100%. TPS output (circuit 99) goes to
                the ECM through ECM connector (320) terminal #40.
            </para>
            <para>The "pedal mounted" TPS
                <emph type="bold">automatically calibrates to the ECM and does not have an adjustment feature</emph>
                as does the previ- ously used "Can" style remote sensor. If the TPS is not properly calibrated, it must
                be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>The pedal mounted TPS should produce a "Duty Cycle" of 10 to 22% at low idle and 75 to 90% at full
                throttle. The percent duty cycle is translated in the ECM into a throttle position percentage of 3 to
                100%.
            </para>
            <para>The remote mounted TPS is not installed by International, therefore no discussion is made of that
                sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133_X0813309.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
