<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3406B -1991 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - Cruise Control System
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise Control System</title>
        <para>Refer to Operator Manual for operation instructions.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Service Brake Switch -</emph>
            The service brake switch is closed with the brake pedal released and receives a signal from the ECM
            (terminal G) on circuit 97Z. The ground (circuit 97AL) for the brake switch goes to the clutch switch.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Clutch Switch -</emph>
            The clutch switch is wired as normally open and adjusted to be closed when the clutch pedal is released. The
            clutch switch receives a signal from the ECM (terminal G) through the brake switch and is grounded (circuit
            97-GE/11-GG) at J7.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Cruise On/Off Switch (153) -</emph>
            The cruise on/off switch receives a signal from the ECM (terminal F) on circuit 97AE. When the switch is in
            the ON position the ground path is 97-GH/97-GD/11-GG to J7.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Cruise Set/Resume Switch (154) -</emph>
            The selector switch receives a signal from ECM terminals J (set position) and H (resume position) and is
            grounded at J7.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Vehicle Speed Buffer (160) -</emph>
            The vehicle speed buffer receives 12 volt battery power from the Run Relay (when activated) on circuit 97AD.
            The speed buffer also receives a signal from the ECM (terminal B) on circuit 47D. Circuit 97-GB goes to
            ground at J7. The speed buffer receives an AC signal from the vehicle speed sensor.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Vehicle Speed Sensor -</emph>
            The vehicle speed sensor is a dual coil sensor with two pair of leads. One pair connects to the speed buffer
            and the other is connected to the vehicle speedometer circuits (47E &#38; 47C). The resistance of the two
            coils in the sensor is different, but the two leads are interchangeable. The resistance of one coil must be
            900-1100 ohms. The resistance of the other coil must be 1200-1450 ohms.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Throttle Position Sensor (158) -</emph>The throttle position sensor receives a signal from
            the ECM (terminal E) on circuit 99. The throttle position sensor receives battery power from the Run Relay
            (when activated) on circuit 97R and circuit 97-GK goes to ground at J7.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
