<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0814103">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The troubleshooting charts in this section are not designed for specific symptoms, but designed to
                test those circuits and components installed by International. Use DDEC diagnostics procedures to
                identify the suspect circuit or system, then use the procedures included in this section to troubleshoot
                the specific International circuit.
            </para>
            <para>NO TESTS in this section require testing "into" the DDEC ECM.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc id="x0814106" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>BEFORE TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
            <seqlist style="alphalc">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the vehicle batteries are fully
                            charged!
                        </emph>
                        Check battery cables and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage and corrosion. Many
                        of the voltage tests included in the procedures will give mis-leading readings if the batteries
                        are not fully charged.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting a particular circuit, inspect connectors for pushed back, loose or
                        damaged (spread or bent), or corroded terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. The wires and
                        connections must be free of damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white
                        residue will be present that must be removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect the suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections free
                        of damage or corrosion.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
