<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992-1993 - TROUBLESHOOTING - INSPECTING ELECTRICAL CONNECTORS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECTING ELECTRICAL CONNECTORS</title>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814507">
            <title>Visual Inspection</title>
            <para>The troubleshooting guides require checking specific connectors. Use the following steps to determine
                if the connector is causing the problem. If a problem is found, repair the connector and continue the
                process.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check Connector Lock Mechanism Or Retaining Screw.</emph>
                    Make sure the connector is capable of properly locking the connector together.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Perform 10 Pound Pull Test On Each Terminal/Wire In Connector.</emph>
                    Each terminal/wire should easily withstand 10 pounds of pull and remain in the connector. This test
                    checks whether the wire was properly crimped in the terminal, and whether the pin was properly
                    inserted into the connector. Repair as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Visually Inspect Wiring.</emph>
                    Look for worn or damaged wires. Check for pinched or damaged harnesses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Visually Inspect Connectors.</emph>
                    Verify that pins and sockets are not corroded, damaged or dirty. Verify correct alignment and
                    location of terminals in the connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check Individual Pins And Sockets.</emph>
                    This is especially important for intermittent problems. Using a new pin (1651968C91), insert the pin
                    into each socket, one at a time, checking for a good grip on the pin by the socket. Repeat for each
                    pin on the mating side of the connector, using a new socket (1651969C91) for the test.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Performing Electrical Tests At OEM Connector To ECM</title>
            <para>International engine harness OEM connector (263) mates with Caterpillar engine harness connector J7.
                The connector is a 40-pin Deutsch connector, with the International side having sockets (female
                terminal) and the Caterpillar side having pins.
                <emph type="bold">No tests in this manual require testing "into" the Caterpillar J7 connector.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">When testing at the International side of the Deutsch connector, never insert meter
                    probes into the sockets, as they will damage the connector.
                </emph>
                Always use test leads of the type described in paragraph
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814506">Test Leads</hotlnk>
                of this manual. The test leads must fit tightly into the terminal sockets, without expanding the
                terminal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814506">
            <title>Test Leads</title>
            <para>To construct test leads, attach an insulated alligator clip to a suitable length of 16 gauge wire. On
                the other end, use Deutsch HDT-48-00 Crimping Tool to crimp a male terminal (pin), International part
                number 1651958C1.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacing International Components</title>
            <para>When replacing electrical switches, connectors (including pins or sockets), relays or other
                components, use only approved International replacement parts. Many of the switches have gold or silver
                plated contacts and some of the connectors include gold plated terminals. By using correct replacement
                parts, you maintain the design integrity of the system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
