<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - INSTRUMENTS
        (New Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - REMOVE AND INSTALL - INSTRUMENT CLUSTER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
        <title>INSTRUMENT CLUSTER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The cluster is a reliable, quick-disconnect package for the most commonly used instruments. Should the
                need arise, the cluster body can be quickly detached from the instrument panel for quick access to any
                of its components. Either the complete cluster assembly or any of its components can be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>Always place the ignition in the OFF position (not ACC) prior to working on the cluster, due to
                potential shorting between the ground and ignition pins, which will damage the circuit board and gauges.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Static electricity can cause permanent damage to the cluster. Before working on the cluster,
                        be sure you have removed all static electricity from your body by touching metal that is
                        grounded. Do not wear clothing that causes static build up (such as nylon). Do not touch any pin
                        connectors during removal and installation of gauges. Work on the cluster in a clean environment
                        to avoid dust.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0815501">
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Protect the bezel during removal by placing a soft cloth on the forward side of the
                    steering column.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two cluster mounting screws (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0815514">Item 1, Figure 14</hotlnk>) located on the lower front face of the
                    cluster.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0815514" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0815514" filename="../figg08/G0815514.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Instrument Cluster Assembly</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CLUSTER MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. INSTRUMENT CLUSTER BEZEL</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. CLUSTER</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. WIRING HARNESS CONNECTOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. DASH PANEL</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. RETAINING TABS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress the two gray retaining tabs (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0815514">Item 6, Figure 14</hotlnk>) located on the top corners of the bezel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Holding the tabs depressed, pull the cluster forward and gently release it from the dash
                    panel. If the cluster does not come loose easily, put more pressure on the tabs and continue to pull
                    gently. Do not attempt to pry the cluster from the dash panel as damage will result.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the three wiring harness connectors from the back of the cluster assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0815515">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0815515" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0815515" filename="../figg08/G0815515.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Disconnect Wiring Harness Connectors</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Whenever any component is serviced or removed from the air system, be sure to set the
                            parking brake and/or block the vehicle to prevent it from moving while the service is being
                            performed. Also drain air from the system to prevent dirt or debris from being propelled
                            into one's eyes.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>After bleeding the air system, disconnect the air lines from the fittings on the back of the air
                    gauge. A double needle air pressure gauge is used with vehicles with air brakes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0815516">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0815516" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0815516" filename="../figg08/G0815516.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Disconnect Air Lines From Fittings on Back of Air Gauge</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Note the color of the air lines being removed from the gauge. The green line is for the
                            primary system and the orange line is for the secondary system.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The instrument cluster assembly is now free to be removed from the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the air lines to the air pressure gauge. The green line is for the primary
                    system and the orange for the secondary system.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not exceed 36 in-lbs. (4.0 Nm) of torque when tightening air lines.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the three wiring harness connectors to the back of the cluster. These connectors
                    are color-coded for proper orientation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the cluster in the instrument panel frame and push the cluster gently until the
                    retaining tabs snap into place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the two cluster mounting screws on the lower front face of the cluster.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
