<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to the Owner's Manual for operating instructions.</para>
            <para>With a Series 60 equipped International vehicle, the driver controls the engine brake ON/OFF and
                Selector switches, but the engine brake system is enabled (or disabled) by the Engine Brake Relay. The
                ECM enables or disables the Engine Brake Relay in response to the engine throttle position. The ECM
                enables the relay whenever the engine speed is 150 rpm greater than idle rpm and the throttle is in the
                idle position.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle is equipped with Antilock Brakes, the ABS system will disable the engine brake if an
                impending wheel lockup condition is detected (refer to paragraph
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814105">Engine Brake Enable Relay (271)</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>Engine Brake system components include:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch (264)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Switch (295)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Brake Selector Switch (265)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Brake Enable Relay (271)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch (264)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0814102">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                for the following discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The ON/OFF switch is a two-pole, single throw switch. With the switch in the ON position, one switch
                pole sends ignition power to the Engine Brake Enable Relay control coil. The other ON/OFF switch pole
                sends ignition voltage to the Engine Brake Enable Relay, except on vehicles equipped with ABS. On ABS
                equipped vehicles, the ignition voltage to the Engine Brake Enable Relay (271) comes from the ABS Engine
                Brake Relay (286), which is discussed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0814105">Engine Brake Enable Relay</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With And Without ABS -</emph>
                Ignition power from 20A fuse F3 goes through the clutch switch and the closed contacts of the ON/OFF
                switch (terminal 3 to 2) to the control coil (terminal 85) of Engine Brake Enable Relay (271).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Without ABS -</emph>
                Ignition power from 20A fuse F3 goes through the ON/OFF switch (terminals 6 to 5) to the common terminal
                (30) of the Engine Brake Enable Relay (271).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With ABS</emph>
                - Ignition power from 20A fuse F3 goes through the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch, then goes through the
                Normally Closed contacts of the ABS Engine Brake relay (286) to the common terminal of the Engine Brake
                Enable relay (265).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0814102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0814102" filename="../figg08/g0814102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Engine Brake - Detroit Diesel Series 60 Engine</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814105">
            <title>Engine Brake Enable Relay (271)</title>
            <para>With the clutch released, the Engine Brake Enable relay (271), control coil (terminal 85) receives
                ignition power from Brake ON/OFF switch (ON position). The ground side of the control coil (terminal 86)
                is connected through ECM connector (273), location A1 to the ECM. The ECM enables the ground path
                energizing (enabling) the relay when the throttle is released and engine speed is 150 rpm greater than
                idle rpm.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Without ABS -</emph>
                With this relay energized, ignition power from the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch on circuit 24AL passes
                through the normally open contacts (30 to 87) and is delivered on circuit 24AD to the Engine Brake
                Selector Switch.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With ABS -</emph>
                With the Engine Brake Enable Relay energized, ignition power from ABS Engine Brake Relay (286) passes
                through the normally open contacts (30 to 87) and is delivered on circuit 24AD to the Engine Brake
                Selector Switch. The ABS Engine Brake Relay (286) is energized whenever the ABS system is operating and
                is not modulating the air brakes. If a wheel lockup condition is sensed by the ABS system, the ABS
                Engine Brake Relay is energized, turning off power to Engine Brake Enable Relay (271), terminal (30).
            </para>
            <para>Note the diode assembly (270) in the ground path. The ECM terminal that circuit 24AA connects to has
                two voltage states, 0 volts and 12 volts. It has ground potential (0 volts) when enabling the Engine
                Brake relay. To disable the Engine Brake relay the terminal is switched to 12 volts. The diode prevents
                feedback into the vehicle electrical system when this terminal is at 12 volts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Selector Switch (265)</title>
            <para>The engine brake selector switch is a three position switch (6-2-4 cylinder operation). The selector
                switch receives ignition power from the Engine Brake Enable Relay (271), then directs ignition power to
                energize the selected engine brake solenoids (depends upon switch position).
            </para>
            <para>With the selector switch in the 6 CYL position, ignition power is sent from the selector switch
                through International circuits 24AE and 24AF to connector (276) then on DDEC circuits 621 and 622 to the
                front, rear and center engine brake solenoids.
            </para>
            <para>With the selector switch in the 2 CYL (center position), ignition voltage is sent through
                International circuit 24AE through connector (276) and DDEC circuit 621 to the center engine brake
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the selector switch in the 4 CYL (center position), ignition voltage is sent through
                International circuit 24AF through connector (276) and DDEC circuit 622 to the front and rear engine
                brake solenoids.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
