<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992-1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - IDLE SHUTDOWN TIMER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>IDLE SHUTDOWN TIMER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title></title>
            <para>The idle shutdown timer can be programmed to shut down the engine after the engine is allowed to
                remain at idle for a specified time period (3 - 60 minutes). To activate the Idle Shutdown Timer, the
                following conditions must be met:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1"></para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The customer must have selected this feature. The default selection is OFF. The
                        customer must also choose the allowed amount of "idle time" before shutdown.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The ECM must not detect any vehicle speed (no signal from Vehicle Speed Sensor).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The Park Brake must be applied.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The throttle must be in IDLE position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The engine must be at "operating temperature."</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>After the park brake is engaged, the idle shutdown feature begins to count down the selected time
                period. The engine can be idling at low idle or at an idle rpm selected by the PTO governor. Ninety
                seconds before the programmed shutdown time is reached, the ENGINE WARNING LIGHT begins to flash
                rapidly.
            </para>
            <para>To override the idle timer shutdown feature, the service brake or clutch pedal must be moved during
                the 90 seconds when the ENGINE WARNING LIGHT is flashing. This allows the engine to be idled for
                extensive periods. Failure to move the service brake or clutch pedal while the ENGINE WARNING LIGHT is
                flashing allows the engine to shut down at the programmed time. The Idle Shutdown will only shut down
                the engine and NOT the electrical system of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Movement of the Throttle Pedal OR releasing the Park Brake
                <emph type="underscr">at any time</emph>
                automatically resets the idle shutdown timer feature.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The ECM monitors system activity and records two events: (1) when the idle shutdown timer is
                        activated and shuts down the engine, and (2) when the idle shutdown timer is activated, but is
                        overridden before actual shutdown. These events are electronically recorded for informational
                        purposes. The fault codes do not require service.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Park Brake Switch (372)</title>
            <para>The purpose of the Park Brake switch is to enable (turn on) the shutdown timer. The Park Brake Switch
                is closed with the park brake applied and open when the park brake is released.
            </para>
            <para>Park Brake Switch circuit (97E) is an input to the ECM through OEM connector (263) terminal #11. The
                ground side of the Park Brake Switch is connected through circuit 97-GR to OEM connector (263) terminal
                #2. With the park brake released (switch open), the ECM sees 5 volts at OEM connector (263) terminal
                #11. Applying the brakes closes the switch, and the ECM sees 0 volts at terminal #11.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
