<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992-1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - GENERAL SYSTEM
        COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Module (ECM)</title>
            <para>The ECM receives battery power through the 6-way, ECM power connector. Two in-line (15 AMP) fuses
                located in the power harness protect the system. The ECM and many of the control switches are grounded
                through the engine and cab harness and the 6-way power connector directly to the negative battery
                terminal. (Refer to DDEC Ground Composite located in this chapter.)
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic On/Off Momentary Switch (331)</title>
            <para>The normally open, momentarily ON diagnostic switch receives a 5V signal from the ECM connector (341),
                terminal E1. Momentarily closing the switch pulls ECM terminal LOW (to ground) causing the ECM to turn
                diagnostics ON, or OFF if already ON.
            </para>
            <para>For use of the Diagnostic Switch, refer to the Detroit Diesel Engine manual furnished with the
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The diagnostic switch must NOT be used when driving the vehicle. If this switch is used, the
                        diagnostic mode will be grounded, causing the engine to return to idle, affecting vehicle
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>International 8-Way Data Link Connector (219)</title>
            <para>Two data link connectors (219 and 368) are installed, providing the same circuits in two different
                connectors. Both data link connectors allow an Electronic Service Tool (EST) to communicate with the
                Engine Control Module (ECM). Connector (219) is the standard International 8-way connector and connector
                (368) is the standard DDEC 12-way connector (discussed in DDEC 12-Way Data Link Connector).
            </para>
            <para>The International 8-way Connector (219) has four cavities that are used.</para>
            <para>Cavity (1), circuit 98A(+), is the positive ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the J24 RED Positive data link bus to ECM connector (341), terminal C2.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (2), circuit 98C(-), is the negative ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the J6 BLUE Negative data link bus to ECM connector (341), terminal C1. The Positive and
                Negative ATA circuits are a twisted wire pair that provide the communications link between the ECM and
                the Prolink EST.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (5), circuit 11-GL, is a ground circuit. It is grounded through circuit 11-GL, at J4 ground
                stud, located at the right cowl inner panel. This provides the ground for the EST.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity (3), circuit 97DL, provides power for the EST. With the key ON, this cavity receives power from
                S18 (15 AMP) circuit breaker through 5 amp in-line fuse (324) between circuits 97DL and 97D.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DDEC 12-Way Data Link Connector (368)</title>
            <para>This data link connector provides the same system access as Data Link connector (219), except it
                provides access through a 12-way connector common to other Detroit Diesel engine models.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity H, circuit 97DA, provides power for the electronic service tools using this connector. With the
                key ON, this cavity receives power from S18 (15 AMP) circuit breaker through 5 amp in-line fuse (324)
                between circuits 97DA and 97D.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity A, circuit 97-GL, is a ground circuit. It is grounded through circuit 97-GL, at J4 ground stud,
                located at the right cowl inner panel. This provides the ground for the EST.
            </para>
            <para>Cavity K, circuit 97E(-), is the negative ATA communication link to the ECM. It is connected through
                the RED Negative (-) data bus J6 to ECM connector (341), terminal C1. The Positive and Negative ATA
                circuits are a twisted wire pair that provide the communications link between the ECM and Data Link
                connector (368).
            </para>
            <para>Cavity J, circuit 97D(+), is the positive (+) ATA communications link to the ECM. It is connected
                through the BLUE Positive (+) data bus J24 to ECM connector (341), terminal C1. The Positive and
                Negative ATA circuits are a twisted wire pair that provide the communications link between the ECM and
                Data Link connector (368).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08146.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
