<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - INTERNATIONAL 530E I6
        HEUI ENGINES - TROUBLESHOOTING - Determining Fault Codes
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Determining Fault Codes</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Refer to Engine/Vehicle Manual EGES-175 for detailed directions on reading fault
                    codes.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The EZ-Tech&#8482; or PRO-LINK 9000&#174; electronic service tools (EST) can be used to identify
                logged fault codes. Refer to the EST manual for operating instructions.
            </para>
            <para>The Serv/Check Engine and Warn Engine lights can be used to read fault codes by following the
                procedure below.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reading Flash Codes</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KEY ON - ENGINE OFF PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold in the diagnostic on/off button and turn the key to the on position. Release the
                    diagnostic button. Do not start the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH one time. This indicates the beginning of active
                    fault codes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All International flash codes are three digit numbers.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Warn Engine light will FLASH repeatedly signalling the active fault codes. The
                    number of flashes should be counted in sequence.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At the end of each digit of the code there will be a short pause.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After each active code is displayed the Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH once to
                    indicate the next code.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once all active codes have been displayed, the Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH twice
                    to indicate the beginning of the inactive codes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inactive codes will be displayed in the same manner as active codes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the inactive codes have been displayed, the Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH
                    three times to indicate that all stored codes have been displayed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Refer to the directions in Engine/Vehicle Manual EGES-175.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>If the diagnostics indicate that a circuit external to the engine is suspect, use the diagnostic
                tables included in this section for a step-by-step procedure. Refer to the appropriate circuit diagram
                for International I6 HEUI - ENGINES in CTS-5119W or CTS-5273W.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_223.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_225.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
