<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEHR POWER
        SYSTEMS/POWERLINE ALTERNATORS USED ON EMERGENCY VEHICLES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Current is produced by rotating a magnet called a rotor inside a stationary winding called a stator
            (Figure 2). The vehicle battery supplies excitation to the field coil (rotor coil) through the regulator and
            brushes, to create a magnetic field around the rotor and through the stator. When the rotor is set in
            motion, the moving magnetic field induces an alternating current (AC) in the stator windings. So alternating
            current is produced as the magnet poles of the rotor pass through the coil windings of the stator.
        </para>
        <para>The battery stores only direct current and cannot use alternating current. So AC produced in the stator is
            converted to direct current (DC) by the positive and negative rectifier assemblies. The rectifier assemblies
            are connected to the alternator output terminals to provide DC output for charging the batteries and to
            satisfy the vehicle electrical loads.
        </para>
        <para>Rectifiers consist of silicon diodes which function as electrical switches and permit current flow in only
            one direction. The rectifier diodes are mounted in aluminum castings, called heat sinks, which are finned to
            dissipate heat.
        </para>
        <para>A built-in solid state voltage regulator controls alternator output and the battery's state of charge. The
            regulator senses when the battery has received sufficient charge and then reduces the "field" (magnetizing)
            current flow to the rotor. Reducing the field current flow, in turn, reduces alternator output.
        </para>
        <para>When headlights and/or accessories place a load on the battery, the regulator increases the field current
            flow to the rotor, thereby increasing alternator output.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
