<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - CATERPILLAR
        3176B/3406E ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - 1994 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - THROTTLE POSITION SENSOR (253)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0814831" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>THROTTLE POSITION SENSOR (253)</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <emph type="bold">
                <hotlnk document="s08148_36.xml" xrefid="x0814804">CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</hotlnk>, Figure
                <hotlnk document="s08148_7.xml" xrefid="f0814804">6.05</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            <emph type="bold">or
                <hotlnk document="s08148_7.xml" xrefid="f0814805">6.08</hotlnk>
            </emph>
            , for this discussion.
        </para>
        <para>The pedal mounted Throttle Position Sensor (TPS) is used to provide a throttle signal to the ECM. Sensor
            output is a constant frequency signal with a pulse width that varies with throttle position. This output
            signal is referred to as either "Duty Cycle" or a "Pulse Width Modulated" (PWM) signal and is expressed as a
            percentage between 0 and 100%.
        </para>
        <para>The pedal mounted Throttle Position Sensor is attached directly to the throttle pedal assembly and
            requires no adjustment. This sensor can be replaced separately from the throttle pedal assembly, however an
            incorrectly calibrated pedal mounted throttle position sensor assembly cannot be calibrated- the pedal
            assembly must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>The "soda can" style remote sensor is not used by International on 1994 engines and is not discussed in
            this manual.
        </para>
        <para>The TPS connects to the cab harness at three-pin connector (253). When the ECM is powered (key switch ON),
            the TPS
            <emph type="underscr">receives operating voltage (8 volts)</emph>
            at terminal A on circuit 99E, which is connected to ECM connector (558) terminal 35. TPS terminal B is
            grounded by circuit 99-G/97-GA/97-G through ECM connector (558) terminal 29.
        </para>
        <para>TPS terminal C outputs the variable throttle position signal on circuit 99 to ECM connector (558) terminal
            37.
        </para>
        <para>The pedal mounted TPS should produce a Duty Cycle of 10 to 22 percent at low idle and 75 to 90 percent at
            full throttle. An electronic service tool can be used to monitor the signal. The percent duty cycle is
            translated in the ECM into a throttle position percentage of 3 to 100%.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
