<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - CRUISE AND PTO CONTROLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRUISE AND PTO CONTROLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The cruise control switches are used as PTO controls (if vehicle is so equipped) when the vehicle road
                speed is not present (this is an owner selected parameter). Refer to the Owners Manual furnished with
                the vehicle for operating instructions.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise ON/OFF Switch (195)</title>
            <para>The cruise ON/OFF switch circuit (97AE) is an input to the ECM through OEM connector (191) terminal
                10. The ground side of the ON/OFF switch is connected through circuit 97-GH to OEM connector (191)
                terminal 2 (GRD). With the switch ON, the ECM sees 0 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal 10. With the
                switch OFF, the ECM sees 5 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal 10.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise SET/RESUME Switch (154)</title>
            <para>The SET/RESUME switch common terminal (5) is connected through common circuit (97-GD) to OEM connector
                (191) terminal 2 (GRD). The SET/RESUME switch SET terminal (4) is an input (circuit 97AB) to the ECM
                through OEM connector (191) terminal 38. SET/RESUME switch RESUME terminal (6) is an input (circuit
                97AA) to the ECM through OEM connector (191) terminal 3.
            </para>
            <para>With the SET/RESUME switch in the SET position, the ECM sees 0 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal
                38 and 5 volts at terminal 3.
            </para>
            <para>In RESUME position, the ECM sees 5 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal 38 and 0 volts at terminal
                3.
            </para>
            <para>In the SET/RESUME neutral position, the ECM sees 5 volts at both OEM connector (191) terminals 3 and
                38.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brake Switch (141)</title>
            <para>Service brake switch circuit 97AL is an input to the ECM through OEM connector (191) terminal 30. The
                ground or common side of the Service Brake switch is connected through circuit 97-GB to OEM connector
                (191) terminal 2 (GRD). With service brakes
                <emph type="bold">released</emph>
                (switch closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at OEM connector (191) terminal 30. Applying the brakes opens the
                switch, and the ECM sees 5 volts at terminal 30.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Switch</title>
            <para>The Clutch Switch is a normally open switch, that is adjusted to be
                <emph type="bold">closed</emph>
                when the clutch pedal is RELEASED.
            </para>
            <para>Clutch Switch circuit (97AH) is an input to the ECM through OEM connector (191) terminal 31. The
                ground side of the clutch pedal switch is grounded through circuit 97-GE to OEM connector (191) terminal
                2 (GRD). With the driver's foot off the clutch pedal (switch closed), the ECM sees 0 volts at terminal
                31. When the driver depresses the clutch pedal (switch opens), the ECM sees 5 volts at terminal 31.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813809">
            <title>Vehicle Speed Sensor (197)</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Sensor is located at the rear of the transmission. The sensor contains a permanent
                magnet that creates a magnetic field interrupted by the teeth on the speedometer output gear. As the
                rotating speedometer gear teeth repeatedly interrupt the magnetic field, a variable AC voltage is
                generated and transmitted through a 2 wire lead connecting to the Caterpillar Vehicle Speed Buffer
                mounted on top of the transmission.
            </para>
            <para>The vehicle speed signal (VSS) from the speed buffer is then sent to the Speedometer/Tachometer unit
                located in the instrument panel and to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813819">
            <title>Vehicle Speed Buffer (193)</title>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Buffer is a Caterpillar component installed by International on top of the
                transmission. The Vehicle Speed Buffer connects to Engine Harness 5 pin connector (193) and also
                connects to the Vehicle Speed Sensor through connector (197). The speed buffer receives the variable AC
                signal from the Vehicle Speed Sensor, processes the signal, then outputs a signal to the ECM and a
                signal to the Speedometer/Tachometer unit in the instrument panel.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="alphalc">
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle speed buffer output from connector (193) Pin D to the OEM connector terminal 33 is
                        series of 5 volt DC pulses. The frequency of the pulses varies directly with the speed of the
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The vehicle speed buffer sends a different type signal from speed buffer connector (193)
                        through the engine harness on circuits 47J and 47K, through engine/chassis harness connector
                        (258) to the speedometer/tachometer microprocessor. The output from speed buffer terminals C and
                        E is a series of +8 volt to -8 volt pulses. The two outputs oppose one another. When Pin C is at
                        +8 volts, Pin E is at -8 volts, and vice versa.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>With the key switch ON, the speed buffer receives 12 volt operating power (terminal A) on circuit
                97AC/97L, from 10A fuse H3. With PEEC III, speed buffer terminal D is grounded through engine harness
                circuit 11-DF/97-GB through OEM connector (191) and J7 CAT connector and Caterpillar harness to the
                engine cylinder head ground bolt. With the 3176, the Speed Buffer ground is through circuits 11-DF/11-GD
                to the cylinder head ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813816">
            <title>Throttle Position Sensor (158)</title>
            <para>The Throttle Position Sensor (TPS) is an electronic sensor (acts like a potentiometer) attached to the
                accelerator pedal assembly. The TPS connects to the cab overlay harness at 3 pin connector (158). At
                terminal A, the TPS receives 12V ignition voltage (circuit 97L/99E) from 10A fuse H3 when the key switch
                is in the ON position. TPS terminal B is grounded (circuit 99-G) through the cab and engine harness to
                OEM connector (191) terminal 2 (GRD).
            </para>
            <para>TPS terminal C outputs a constant frequency signal with a pulse width that varies with throttle
                position to ECM terminal 40. This output signal is referred to as either Duty Cycle or Pulse Width
                Modulated (PWM) signal and is expressed as a percentage of throttle between 0 and 100%.
            </para>
            <para>The pedal mounted TPS
                <emph type="bold">automatically calibrates to the ECM and does not have an adjustment feature</emph>
                as does the previously used "Beer Can" style remote sensor. If the TPS is not properly calibrated, it
                must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>The pedal mounted TPS should produce a Duty Cycle of 10 to 22 percent at low idle and 75 to 90 percent
                at full throttle. The percent duty cycle is translated in the ECM into a throttle position percentage of
                3 to 100%.
            </para>
            <para>The remote mounted TPS is not being installed by International, therefore no discussion is made of
                that sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08138.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
