<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CUMMINS ISM AND AHD
        ENGINE SYSTEM - OPERATION - Coolant Level Switch
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Coolant Level Switch</title>
        <para>The coolant level switch is a fluid level actuated switch that sends two signals to the ECM, thus
            providing a warning when coolant is being lost. It is mounted in the coolant surge tank. The coolant level
            switch is an electronic switch that operates on the electrostatic or capacitance principle and cannot be
            tested with a multimeter. The probe extends into the coolant and produces a change in capacitance when
            coolant displaces air immediately surrounding the probe. This change is converted in the switch to an on/off
            solid state switch closure indicating the absence or presence of coolant. The switch is electrically
            insulated providing a slick, non-fouling surface as well as good electrical characteristics to prevent
            current flow into the coolant. The low coolant level switch connects to the engine harness at connector
            (249). Four circuits from connector (249) connect the low coolant switch to the ECM through the 31-way ECM
            connector (1093).
        </para>
        <para>The coolant level switch (249) receives a 5 volt signal on circuit 34B(5V) from the ECM (1093). When the
            coolant level is above the probe, the switch sends a high signal (3.5 volts minimum) on circuit 34A and a
            low signal (0.5 volt maximum) on circuit 34 to the ECM (1093).
        </para>
        <para>When the coolant level is below the probe, the switch sends a low signal (0.5 volt maximum) on circuit 34A
            and a high signal (3.5 volts minimum) on circuit 34 to ECM (251).
        </para>
        <para>The low coolant level switch is grounded through circuit 34-G to ECM (1093).</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The low coolant level switch cannot be tested with a multimeter in the ohmmeter mode. This is
                    because the switch is an electronic switch and not a mechanical switch.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_184.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_186.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
