<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - POWER DISTRIBUTION AND
        GROUND SYSTEM - OPERATION - COMMON SYSTEM COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>COMMON SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuses And Circuit Breakers</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never replace a fuse or circuit breaker with a higher load rated fuse or circuit breaker.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Fuses are standard (Type III circuit breakers are optional), except for headlights and windshield
                wipers, which have Type I circuit breakers.
            </para>
            <para>Most of the fuses and/or circuit breakers are located in the Power Distribution panel in the cab. The
                Power Distribution panel cover contains a listing of installed circuit protection devices, size and
                location.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Type III Circuit Breakers</para>
                <para>Type III circuit breakers open if current flow exceeds the rated capacity and can be reset by
                    depressing the reset button on the breaker after the overload condition has been removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Type I Circuit Breakers</para>
                <para>Type I circuit breakers (headlights and windshield wipers) reset automatically. However, if the
                    excessive current flow condition causing the breaker to open is not corrected, the circuit breaker
                    will reopen and remain open until the winding cools, then automatically reset. With an overload
                    condition present, the circuit breaker will cycle (open and close) until the condition is corrected.
                    The circuit breaker will become hot to the touch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Type I circuit beakers must only be replaced with approved International Type I circuit
                        breakers.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Junction Adapters And Studs</title>
            <para>In the circuit diagrams, bussed adapters and studs are most often, but not always, given a name such
                as (B2) Battery Adapter (498), etc. These junction connections can be either feeds or grounds and are
                identified as such. The bus adapters have a common feed or ground and the other terminals are connected
                internally by a bus bar.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Relays And Solenoids</title>
            <para>Relays and solenoids are switching devices. International uses only suppressed relays and solenoids to
                prevent voltage spikes from damaging electronic components in the vehicle electrical system. Once a
                transistor has been "spiked," it may not fail immediately, but its life will be shortened.
            </para>
            <para>Note that relays used inside the cab are not sealed, but relays in less protected areas, such as the
                engine compartment, are sealed for longer life.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Only replace relays and solenoids with correct International parts.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
