<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3406B -1991 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - Kysor Shutdown System
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Kysor Shutdown System</title>
        <para>The three primary components of the Kysor system are:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Control Module</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pressurestat</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Alarmstat</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Kysor Control Module -</emph>
            The Kysor control module is a time delay switch that remains closed for approximately 30 seconds after the
            engine is started and the start switch is released. When the engine starter is engaged, power from circuit
            19B activates the 30-second delay, closing the switch between contacts 1 and 3. Ignition current from F3 (20
            AMP) fuse, to J1 ignition connector, then circuit 19A goes through the control module contacts (1 to 3) and
            on circuit 19M/97A to activate the Run Relay. Normally after 30 seconds of engine operation, the oil
            pressurestat NO (normally open) contacts have closed and control of the Run Relay is through the
            pressurestat and the alarmstat; then power on circuits 19M/97A to the Run Relay keeps it activated.
        </para>
        <para>After 30 seconds the Control Module switch will open. If the pressurestat NO switch (closed with 5 psi oil
            pressure) or the NC (normally closed) switch of the alarmstat is not closed, the Run Relay will be
            deactivated, shutting down the engine.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Pressurestat -</emph>
            The pressurestat is in the circuit to monitor engine oil pressure. It consists of two sets of contacts which
            are sensitive to engine oil pressure. One set of contacts (normally open) controls the voltage to the Run
            Relay control circuit through the C (common) terminal on the alarmstat. The other set of contacts (normally
            closed) controls the ignition voltage to the alarm and engine shutdown light.
        </para>
        <para>The NC contacts of the pressurestat control the alarm system. When the vehicle is started, the normally
            closed pressurestat contacts stay closed until the oil pressure exceeds approximately 9 psi, then they open
            and the alarm is turned off. If the oil pressure drops below approximately 9 psi, the NC (normally closed)
            contacts will close, sounding the alarm and illuminating the warning light. The alarm will continue to sound
            until the key switch is turned off.
        </para>
        <para>The NO (normally open) contacts of the pressurestat control the ignition voltage needed to keep the Run
            Relay activated. With the ignition switch in the ON position, the normally open contacts will close when the
            engine oil pressure exceeds approximately 5 psi. Ignition voltage will then pass through the pressurestat to
            the alarmstat to keep the Run Relay activated. If the engine oil pressure drops below 5 psi, the NO
            (normally open) contacts will open and deactivate the Run Relay, shutting down the engine.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Alarmstat -</emph>The alarmstat also has two sets of contacts. These contacts are
            sensitive to engine coolant temperature. The NC (normally closed) contacts provide an ignition voltage path
            from the pressurestat to keep the Run Relay activated. The NO (normally open) contacts control the alarm
            system in the event operating temperatures are exceeded.
        </para>
        <para>The NC (normally closed) alarmstat contacts that control the Run Relay will remain closed unless the
            engine coolant temperature exceeds 225 degrees F. If the NC (normally closed) contacts open, the Run Relay
            will be deactivated, shutting down the engine.
        </para>
        <para>The NO (normally open) alarmstat contacts that control the alarm system will close, sounding the alarm, if
            engine coolant temperatures exceed 219 degrees F (six degrees before engine shutdown will occur). If the NO
            (normally open) contacts close, voltage is applied to the alarm and to the engine shutdown light.
        </para>
        <para>In summary, the pressurestat NC (normally closed) contacts will close if oil pressure drops to
            approximately 9 psi and activate the alarm system. If oil pressure drops to 5 psi, the NO (normally open)
            contacts will open and deactivate the Run Relay, shutting down the engine. The alarmstat NO (normally open)
            contacts will close at 219 degrees F and activate the alarm system. At 225 degrees, the NC (normally closed)
            contacts will open and deactivate the Run Relay, shutting down the engine.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08128.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
