<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - ECM DIAGNOSTICS - DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>A diagnostic check may be performed using the Diagnostic ON/OFF switch or Pro Link EST.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Using Diagnostic ON/OFF Switch</title>
            <para>Any fault codes will be flashed through the yellow Check Engine Light. If no fault codes are logged,
                the code "25" will be flashed out on the yellow Check Engine Light. Refer to the Detroit Diesel Engine
                Manual furnished with the vehicle for the exact procedure and explanation of the flash codes.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The diagnostic switch must NOT be operated when driving the vehicle. If this is done, the
                        diagnostic mode will be entered, and the engine will be forced to idle speed, affecting vehicle
                        operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>To display flash codes, use the following procedure:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin procedure with the engine OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition key switch to the RUN position (not Crank).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="italic">Hold</emph>
                    the Diagnostic Switch in the ON position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The first fault code will begin flashing on the yellow Check Engine Light.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>For example, the yellow engine warning light blinks out: FLASH, FLASH. The first digit is a 2, then a
                half-second pause: FLASH FLASH, FLASH, FLASH, FLASH. The second digit is a 5. Code 25 is
                <emph type="italic">System OK.</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All Series 60 fault codes are 2 digits.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If more than one fault code is logged, there will be a three second pause between
                    flashes. All active codes will continue to flash in sequence until the diagnostics are turned off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To stop the diagnostics, release the diagnostic switch. Remember to turn off the
                    ignition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The Detroit Diesel Operators Engine Manual furnished with the vehicle contains flash code
                descriptions. The Detroit Diesel Troubleshooting Manual contains flash code descriptions and diagnostic
                procedures.
            </para>
            <para>If the fault code(s) or symptoms indicate a need to troubleshoot a International installed circuit or
                component, procedures are included in
                <hotlnk document="s08141_14.xml" xrefid="x0814103">Troubleshooting</hotlnk>
                in this chapter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MPSI Pro Link Electronic Service Tool (EST)</title>
            <para>The Pro Link EST with a Series 60 cartridge can be used to read logged fault codes and monitor many of
                the system switches and operating parameters. Refer to the Pro Link manual for information on using the
                EST.
            </para>
            <para>International vehicles include an 8-way and 12-way (for DDEC EST) diagnostic connector used to access
                the system with an EST.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Information</title>
            <para>To obtain Detroit Diesel Engine Service information, contact your local Detroit Diesel Distributor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
