<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CAB ACCESSORIES -
        OPERATION - Electric Windshield Wipers - Intermittent Wipe And Wash
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electric Windshield Wipers - Intermittent Wipe And Wash</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wiper Operation</title>
            <para>Refer to ELECTRIC WINDSHIELD WIPER WITH INTERMITTENT WIPE AND WASH circuit diagram in CTS-5119W or
                CTS-5273W.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low Speed Wiper Operation -</emph>With the wiper switch in the low position, power
                from terminal 5 is applied internally to terminal 2, then through circuit 82E to the low speed winding
                in the wiper motor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High Speed Wiper Operation -</emph>With the wiper switch in the high position, power
                from terminal 5 is applied internally to terminal 6, then through circuit 82D to the high speed winding
                in the wiper motor. Note that power from 5 is not applied to terminals 3 and 4 in the high speed
                position, so power is not applied to the low speed winding.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Park Operation -</emph>Note that power is always present (with key on) at P terminal
                of crank motor. When the wipers are operating, the circuit between wiper motor P and S is closed. In
                this position, power at P goes through contacts and out S, through the normally closed contacts of the
                wiper relay (143) and back to the wiper switch at terminal 1. From terminal 1, the power goes through
                terminal 2 to the low speed winding and the motor continues to operate until the park switch rotates,
                opening the circuit between terminal S and P, and closing the circuit between S and X, parking the
                wipers and turning off operation. With the key on or off, battery power is always present at the common
                terminal 30 of wiper intermittent relay (142). When the key is on, the relay is energized and supplies
                power from the normally open terminal 87 for all wiper and washer operations. Power is applied to wiper
                switch (431) at terminal 5.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Intermittent Wiper And Washer Operation</title>
            <para>The intermittent wiper and washer switches are part of switch assembly (432).</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Intermittent Wiper Operation -</emph>With ignition key on, setting the intermittent
                switch applies power from switch terminal C through circuit 82J to energize the wiper motor relay. With
                the wiper motor relay energized, power from relay (142) passes through the wiper motor relay (143) and
                through the circuit 82H to the wiper motor switch at terminal 1. With the wiper switch in the off
                position, the power passes through the switch (terminal 1 to 2) and is applied through circuit 82E to
                the low speed motor winding. When the intermittent switch contacts open, wiper motor relay (143)
                de-energizes, power is turned off to the wiper switch, and the wiper motor operates until it reaches the
                park position.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Windshield Washer Operation -</emph>Depressing the washer switch, which is part of
                switch (432), energizes the windshield washer pump and energizes the wiper motor relay (143). This
                causes the wipers to operate in the intermittent mode.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
