<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - INSTRUMENTS
        (New Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - DESCRIPTION - INDICATOR AND WARNING LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INDICATOR AND WARNING LIGHTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil/Water</title>
            <para>The "OIL/WATER" warning light and red lens provide a warning, to driver of the vehicle, that the
                engine's oil pressure is running low, that its coolant temperature is running high, or the coolant level
                is low (with electronic engines). Thus the driver can take the necessary actions to protect the engine.
                This light is also used with International engines to signal that the engine is going to shut down in 30
                seconds due to either idle shutdown counter or engine protection system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure</title>
            <para>The "BRAKE PRESS" warning light and red lens provide a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that one
                of the following conditions is present: the air pressure has dropped below an acceptable level to keep
                the brakes fully released with an air brake system, or that there is an abnormal condition detected by
                the hydraulic brake monitor module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Coolant Level</title>
            <para>The "COOLANT LEVEL" warning light and red lens were used with mechanical engines to provide a warning,
                to the driver of the vehicle, that the level of the engine coolant is down to a minimum level for safe
                operation. With electronic engines, the coolant level is monitored by the engine ECM. The red Oil/Water
                warning lamp is used to warn of a low coolant condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Oil</title>
            <para>The "CHANGE OIL" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that it is time to get the vehicle in for an oil change. This feature, available on vehicles with the
                International consolidated engine controller (CEC), keeps track of mileage and engine hours by using a
                programmed service interval counter to determine that it is time to change the engine oil and turn on
                the warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Engine</title>
            <para>The "STOP ENGINE" warning light and red lens, used with non-International engines, provide a warning,
                to the driver of the vehicle, that the engine is going to shut down in 30 seconds due to either the idle
                shutdown timer or engine protection circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Warn Engine</title>
            <para>The "WARN ENGINE" warning light and yellow lens provide a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                a sensor or system of the engine is not performing as it should. This condition could be affecting
                performance and or emissions, and indicates that the driver should get the vehicle into a shop for
                servicing. This light is also used in conjunction with the (STI) Self Test Initialization switch and
                "STOP ENGINE" light to display active and inactive engine fault codes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Traction Control</title>
            <para>The "TRAC CNTL" warning light and green lens provide a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the
                optional traction control circuitry has been engaged, and that the antilock braking has been switched
                off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Check Transmission</title>
            <para>The "CHECK TRANS" warning light and yellow lens provide a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                the transmission is overheating (with Allison non-electronic transmissions), or that the transmission is
                overheating, or the ECU senses a problem (with Allison WTEC III electronic transmissions).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Left Turn Indicator</title>
            <para>The left turn arrow indicator light and green lens provide an indication, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the turn signal switch is in the left turn position by blinking in unison with the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Brake Warning Light</title>
            <para>The "ABS" indicator light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                the antilock brake system is activating and overriding the engine retarder. The light will also
                illuminate when a fault in the ABS system is detected by the ABS controller.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Retarder On</title>
            <para>The "RETARD ON" indicator light and green lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that the transmission retarder has been enabled. Thus the driver will be reminded to turn off the
                retarder when road surfaces are slippery.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Transmission Filter</title>
            <para>The "CHANGE TRANS FILTER" warning light and yellow lens provide a warning, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the transmission fluid filter has become restricted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Retarder Overheat</title>
            <para>The "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light and red lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that the transmission retarder has reached an unsafe operating temperature. At this point the driver
                should switch off the retarder and allow it to cool before turning it back on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator</title>
            <para>An "ALTERNATOR" warning light location and yellow lens is provided for possible later use.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>High Beam Indicator</title>
            <para>The high beam indicator light and blue lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                the headlights are on and switched to the bright position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Right Turn Indicator</title>
            <para>The right turn arrow indicator light and green lens provide an indication, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the turn signal switch is in the right turn position by blinking in unison with the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Water-In-Fuel</title>
            <para>The "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that there is water up to the probe in the fuel filter. Thus the driver knows that the filter must be
                drained or changed to prevent water from getting into the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Filter</title>
            <para>The "FUEL FILTER" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that the fuel filter is becoming excessively plugged or restricted. Thus the filter should be changed to
                prevent hard starting, power limiting, or stalling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power Take Off (PTO)</title>
            <para>A location for a body-builder to install a "PTO" warning light is supplied in the instrument cluster,
                and a red lens is also provided.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Brake Fluid</title>
            <para>A "LOW BRAKE FLUID" warning light and red lens is used in the 3000FE and 3000RE model to warn the
                driver of the vehicle that the brake master cylinder is low on fluid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wait-To-Start</title>
            <para>The "WAIT-TO-START" warning light and yellow lens signals the driver to hold off on cranking over the
                engine until the glow plugs have heated up.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) Low Air</title>
            <para>The "((P))"ark brake "LOW AIR" warning light and red lens warns the driver that the air park brake
                system has either not yet pumped up to a pressure that will reliably release the park brake, or that the
                system is losing pressure and the park brake is going to apply. The light is used only with SE code
                orders.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PDL</title>
            <para>The power divider lock "PDL" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the power divider lock is engaged. Thus the driver can remember to unlock the power
                divider when acceptable road surfaces are reached.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Parking Brake</title>
            <para>The "PARK BRAKE" warning light and red lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                the parking brake is applied. This light is utilized with both air and hydraulic brake systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Parking Brake</title>
            <para>The "PARK BRAKE" warning light and red lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that
                the parking brake is applied. This light is utilized with both air and hydraulic brake systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Windshield Washer Fluid</title>
            <para>The "WSHLD WASH FLUID" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the windshield washer reservoir tank is low on windshield washer fluid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Axle</title>
            <para>The "FRONT AXLE" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle,
                that the transfer case has shifted to transfer power to the front drive shaft and axle, thus indicating
                that the vehicle is in four wheel drive.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diff Lock Engaged</title>
            <para>The "DIFF LOCK ENGAGED" warning light and yellow lens provide an indication, to the driver of the
                vehicle, that the differential lock is engaged. Thus the driver can remember to unlock the differential
                when acceptable road surfaces are reached.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Suspension Low Air</title>
            <para>The "SUSP LOW AIR" warning light and red lens warn the driver that the air suspension system has not
                yet pumped up to a safe level for operation, or that a leak has developed in the system and that it is
                deflating.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08155x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
