<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEHR POWER
        SYSTEMS/POWERLINE ALTERNATORS USED ON EMERGENCY VEHICLES - TESTING AND ANALYSIS OF CHARGING SYSTEM - OPTIMIZING
        THE CHARGING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPTIMIZING THE CHARGING SYSTEM</title>
        <para>If the discharge current is 15 amps or less, you may be able to optimize the system to correct the
            problem.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Increase alternator speed by increasing engine idle speed, pulley ratio or both. Increasing
                the engine idle from 700 RPM to 750 RPM will improve the alternator output by 15 to 20 amps Decreasing
                the size of the alternator pulley by .2 inch can increase output by 5 to 15 amps at 700 RPM.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the alternator has a remote sense (direct to battery)! This will improve system
                voltage by 0.2 volts and give 10% more current at full field.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Never run the 10-120 regulator open sense on an emergency vehicle! This creates a negative
                    temperature coefficient that will drop system voltage by 1 Volt when hot.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Upgrade the battery cables if they are too small. There should be less than 0.5 volt drop
                between the alternator POS terminal and the battery POS terminal. The voltage drop between the
                alternator NEG. terminal and the NEG. battery terminal should be less than 0.2 volt during full load
                conditions. A 2 AWG cable for runs up to 5 feet, a 0 AWG cable for 5 to 10 feet runs, and a 2/0 AWG
                cable for runs from 10 to 15 feet is recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Add a separate ground cable for systems with a chassis ground.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
