<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CUMMINS M11 AND N14
        ENGINES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to the circuit diagram Cummins M11 and N14 CELECT - ENGINE CONTROLS in CTS-5119W or CTS-5273W.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM is connected to the International electrical system at three points (or four points with
                antilock brakes installed).
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>International engine harness 28-way ECM connector (252) connects to ECM port B. This connector
                        links International sensors, switches and the diagnostic connector to the ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>International 21-way connector (251) connects to the Cummins sensor harness. This connector
                        links the International installed engine brake components, low coolant switch, fan controls and
                        switched voltage to the ECM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The International ECM power connector (216) connects to the Cummins actuator harness. This
                        connector supplies the unswitched power to the ECM and provides an ECM ground circuit to the
                        engine ground stud.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Additionally, with ABS/traction control system, the International ECM connector (252) connects
                        to the Cummins sensor harness located near the front of the ECM. J1922 Data Link connector (403)
                        connects to the ABS system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ECM POWER CIRCUITS</title>
            <para>Power is supplied at all times to the ECM from the cranking motor solenoid B+ terminal. Circuits 97B
                and 97C deliver power on the International harness through the ECM power connector (225) and the Cummins
                harness to the ECM. The Cummins harness has a 10A inline fuse in each circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM is grounded through the Cummins harness, ECM power harness connector (225) and circuit 97-G to
                the engine ground stud. The engine ground stud is connected to the cranking motor ground stud, frame
                rail and negative battery terminal.
            </para>
            <para>Turning the key switch to the ignition or start position energizes the ignition relay. The relay then
                applies power to circuits 13H and 13F, I1 ignition adapter (494), circuit 13Z, 5A fuse F6-D and circuit
                13D to the 21-way ECM connector (251).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_149.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_151.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
