<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CUMMINS CELECT - 1992-1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to appropriate circuit diagrams, located in this section, for the following discussions.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard Engine Protection System</title>
            <para>CELECT engines are equipped with an engine protection system as a standard feature. This system
                monitors important engine parameters and logs diagnostic faults when an over- or under-normal operating
                range condition occurs. The engine protection also derates engine torque and engine speed when certain
                engine fluid parameters pass a limit point.
            </para>
            <para>All CELECT engines monitor the following five inputs:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Levels**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Temperature*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Pressure*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Temperature*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake Manifold Temperature*</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>* CUMMINS-installed components.</para>
            <para>** International-installed component.</para>
            <para>If any of the above sensors signals conditions outside limits pre-set by CUMMINS, the oil/water
                warning light will begin to flash and the engine will be gradually derated. If the out-of-specification
                condition returns to acceptable limits, the light will turn off, and the fault may be logged as an
                inactive fault in the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Optional Engine Shutdown Feature</title>
            <para>This feature is optional and must be selected by the customer. The engine protection shutdown is
                triggered when the engine protection lamp starts flashing for the current engine protection/warning
                derate. Once triggered, the engine will shut down after 30 seconds. During the 30 second warning period,
                the standard torque and speed derates will occur. The engine can be restarted by cycling the key switch.
                After the engine is restarted, it will be limited to the maximum torque and/or speed derate levels of
                the out-of-range parameter if the engine protection fault is still active.
            </para>
            <para>All CELECT systems have three warning lights located in the instrument panel. Each Celect system
                includes a standard engine protection system to prevent engine damage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814314">
            <title>"Yellow" Oil/Water Warning Light</title>
            <para>The yellow oil/water warning light is located in the right gauge cluster and alerts the driver of the
                following conditions:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Low engine coolant level</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">High engine coolant temperature</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Low or High engine oil pressure</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">High intake manifold temperature</para>
            </step1>
            <para>If any of previous conditions goes outside the limits pre-set by CUMMINS, the engine will be gradually
                derated to protect the engine. If the CELECT system is derating the engine, the "yellow" oil/water
                warning light will illuminate. When the condition returns to acceptable limits, the light will turn off.
            </para>
            <para>The oil/water warning light receives 12V ignition power (key on) from J18 ignition feed adapter.
                Circuit breaker M11 (15A) provides the power to J18. The oil/water warning light ground circuit, 97AZ,
                goes to ECM terminal #1. The ECM opens or closes the ground, turning the warning light off or on in
                response to engine conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814315">
            <title>"Yellow" Engine Warning Light</title>
            <para>The "yellow" engine warning light comes on each time the key switch is turned to the ON position and
                will remain on for several seconds as a system self-test, then turn off. If the warning light remains
                ON, it means that the ECM has detected a problem. A "yellow" warning light means that the vehicle can be
                driven safely, but the fault
                <emph type="bold">must be corrected</emph>
                as soon as possible.
            </para>
            <para>The "yellow" engine warning light receives 12V ignition power (key on) from J18 ignition feed adapter.
                Circuit breaker M11 (15A) provides the power to J18. The ground circuit for this light is circuit 97AT
                to the ECM at pin #25. The ECM opens or closes the ground circuit, turning the warning light off or on
                in response to engine conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814316">
            <title>"Red" Engine Stop Light</title>
            <para>The "red" engine stop light comes on each time the key switch is turned to the ON position and remains
                on for several seconds as a system self-test, then turns off. If the "red" engine stop light remains ON,
                <emph type="bold">the vehicle must be parked as long as the fault remains.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The engine stop light receives 12V ignition power (key on) from J18 ignition feed adapter. Circuit
                breaker M11 (15A) provides the power to J18. The warning light ground circuit (97AP) goes to the ECM at
                pin #16. The ECM opens and closes the ground circuit turning the warning light off or on in response to
                engine conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic Connector (219)</title>
            <para>The 8-pin diagnostic connector utilizes four circuits as follows:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pin 1, circuit 98A(+), is the positive Data Link connection through J24 (red Data Link
                    connector) to the ECM (terminal 27).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pin 2, circuit 98C(-), is the negative Data Link connection through J6 (blue Data Link
                    connector) to the ECM (terminal 8).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pin 3, circuit 97DL/97D, is 12V ignition feed from S18 (15 AMP) circuit breaker. Power
                    is available with the key switch in the ON position. Note also that in-line fuse N2 is located
                    between circuits 97DL and 97D.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pin 5, circuit 11-GL, is grounded to the right cowl inner panel at J4.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814310">
            <title>Diagnostic On/Off Switch (234)</title>
            <para>The diagnostic on/off switch receives a 5V signal (circuit 97AN(5V)) from ECM pin #10. Closing the
                switch applies 5V to the ECM at terminal 21. This tells the ECM that the diagnostic ON/OFF switch has
                been turned to the ON position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814311">
            <title>Idle/Diagnostic Inc/Dec Switch (265)</title>
            <para>The low engine idle speed (rpm) can be adjusted with a two-position momentary, increment/decrement
                switch. This function permits the operator to adjust idle speed up or down in units of 25 rpm by
                toggling the switch. Maximum idle speed is 800 rpm and minimum idle speed is 550 rpm. When the idle has
                been changed and the key turned OFF, the new setting is saved in memory. This feature is owner selected
                and can be turned OFF with a Compulink
                <supscript>TM</supscript>
                adjustment.
            </para>
            <para>A 5V signal from the ECM is present at the switch (circuit 97AX(5V)). Momentarily placing the switch
                increment position or decrement position applies the 5 volts to the ECM at terminal #14 or terminal #23.
                This causes the engine idle rpm to be increased or decreased in 25 rpm increments.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814305">
            <title>Radiator Coolant Level Sensor (307)</title>
            <para>The Coolant Level Sensor sends coolant level data to the ECM for the engine protection system. The ECM
                communicates with the coolant sensor with four circuits. The circuits connect the ECM and the low
                coolant sensor through the Cummins 9-pin connector (C308) and the International engine harness which
                connects to the sensor with a 4-pin connector, C307. The sensor contains a printed circuit board which
                should not be tested with a volt-ohm meter. The sensor receives a 5 volt signal from the ECM and returns
                a high or low signal to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08143_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08143_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08143.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
