<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - GENERAL INFORMATION - 1992 - 1993 - CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</title>
        <para>The circuit diagrams included show the circuits and components that are part of the engine systems covered
            in this section. By eliminating circuits and components not related to the systems being covered, the
            circuit diagrams are greatly simplified.
        </para>
        <para>Each circuit component is named and may show a connector number (in parentheses), if applicable. All
            circuits are identified by a circuit number, wire gauge, and abbreviated wire colors. Circuits that are not
            numbered can be identified by a wire color and/or wire gauge.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0813201">Figure 2.01</hotlnk>
            shows an example of a circuit identification code and color abbreviations used in the circuit diagrams.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0813201" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0813201" filename="../figg08/G0813201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>FIGURE 2.01 Circuit Identification Code</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Many of the circuits in the electronic engine control system are low voltage circuits (approximately 5
            volts).
        </para>
        <para>With Cummins engines, the five volt circuits will include a (5V) in the circuit number. For example,
            97AF(5V) would be a low voltage circuit. With Caterpillar and Detroit Diesel the circuits are not identified
            with the five volt (5V) addition to the circuit number. Refer to the engine OEM manuals for specific
            information on their systems.
        </para>
        <para>Connector end views (viewed from mating end) of harness connectors are shown in many cases to help with
            testing. These connector end views are shown near the component location illustrations included in this
            section. Connectors are identified in the circuit diagrams with a number beside the component. Single
            circuit connectors are not numbered.
        </para>
        <para>Components that work together are shown together. All electrical components used in any circuit are shown
            on that diagram. The circuit breaker, fuse, or power source is shown in most cases at the top of the page.
            All wires, connectors, and other components are shown so the signal flows to ground at the bottom of the
            page (or the circuit). Only that portion of the component used in the circuit is shown. A reference is added
            to the circuit explaining where the complete component is shown.
        </para>
        <para>The symbols used on the circuit diagrams are conventional symbols (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0813202">Figure 2.02</hotlnk>). The symbols such as switches and relays are always shown in
            the IGNITION KEY OFF position, unless otherwise noted on the circuit diagram.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0813202" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0813202" filename="../figg08/G0813202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>FIGURE 2.02 Electrical Symbols</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08132_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08132_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08132.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
