<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CUMMINS CELECT 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0814011" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ECM shares control of the Engine Brake System with the vehicle driver and the Antilock Brake
                System (ABS) if the vehicle is so equipped. The operator turns ON the engine brake ON/OFF switch and
                selects two-, four- or six-cylinder braking (the selection is different with the N14 than the L10) with
                the cylinder selector switch.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle is equipped with ABS, the 12-volt power supply to the Engine Brake ON/OFF is through
                the ABS Engine Brake relay (286). This allows the ABS system to turn OFF the engine brake when wheel
                lockup is detected.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM
                <emph type="bold">will not energize</emph>
                the engine brake enable relay if it senses any of the following conditions:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch pedal depressed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator pedal depressed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Excessive manifold boost pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Failed boost pressure sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise control in active mode</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>PTO in active mode</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed below 850 rpm.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake On/Off Switch (246)</title>
            <para>The engine brake on/off switch is a 2-pole, single throw switch. One pole receives ignition power from
                20A fuse F4, and with the switch in the ON position, sends 12V ignition power to the engine brake enable
                relay (248) common terminal, numbered 30 in the circuit diagram.
            </para>
            <para>With ABS, the power passes through the Normally Closed contacts of the ABS Engine Brake Relay (286).
                <emph type="bold">The Normally Closed contacts open if the ABS system detects a wheel lockup is about to
                    occur, turning the engine brake OFF.
                </emph>
                The ABS system is discussed in GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>The other pole of the Engine Brake On/Off receives a 5V signal from ECM connector (252) terminal 10 on
                circuit 24R(5V). With the engine brake switch ON (switch closed), a 5V signal is sent on circuit 24AB
                through ECM connector (252) terminal 5 to the ECM.This signal tells the ECM that the engine brake switch
                is in the ON position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Enable Relay (248)</title>
            <para>When the engine brake On/Off switch is ON, 12V power is sent on circuit 24AA to terminal 30 of the
                engine brake relay. When the engine brake relay is energized, the power at terminal 30 goes from relay
                terminal 87 on circuit 24AD to the engine brake selector switch.
            </para>
            <para>The engine brake enable relay is energized by 12 volts from the ECM 9-way connector (251) on circuit
                24AA. The relay control coil is grounded by circuit 11-CB at J7 cab ground stud. The ECM enables the
                engine brake system by energizing the relay, if all previously discussed conditions are judged to be
                correct.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Selector Switch (247)</title>
            <para>The engine brake selector switch receives power from the engine brake enable relay (248). The engine
                brake selector switch sends the 12-volt ignition power through the ECM 9-way connector (251) to selected
                engine brake solenoids. The power does not go through the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814009">
            <title>Service Brake Switch (253)</title>
            <para>The service brake switch (closed with brake pedal released) serves both the cruise control and engine
                brake system. When the
                <emph type="underscr">brakes are not applied,</emph>
                a 5V signal is applied to ECM connector (252) terminal 13. The service brake switch
                <emph type="bold">opens</emph>
                when the brakes are applied and the 5V
                <emph type="bold">is not</emph>
                applied to ECM connector (252) terminal 13.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0814010">
            <title>Clutch Switch (295)</title>
            <para>The clutch switch serves both the cruise and engine brake system. The switch is a normally open
                switch, adjusted to be closed when the clutch pedal is in the released position. With the clutch
                released, a 5V signal is applied through the clutch switch to ECM connector (252) terminal 4.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08140_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08140_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08140.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
