<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER DIAGNOSTICS AND SERVICE - OPERATION - 9600, 9700 MODELS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>9600, 9700 MODELS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>January 1989 to January 1994 - All Engines</title>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer/Tachometer Gauges</title>
            </para>
            <para>The speedometer and tachometer gauges are driven by inputs from the microprocessor which is driven by
                the vehicle speed sensor, located at the transmission, and an engine speed sensor, located at the engine
                flywheel housing.
            </para>
            <para>The sensors are magnetic pick-up devices which sense the rotation of the speedometer gear and the
                flywheel ring gear. A permanent magnet located in these sensors establishes a magnetic field at the tip
                of the sensor. The magnetic field is repeatedly interrupted by the gear teeth, creating voltage impulses
                that are transmitted to the microprocessor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>January 1994 and Later - Mechanical Engines</title>
            <para>
                <title>Speedometer/Tachometer Module</title>
            </para>
            <para>The speedometer and tachometer gauges are driven by inputs from the microprocessor which is driven by
                the vehicle speed sensor, located at the transmission, and an engine speed sensor, located at the engine
                flywheel housing.
            </para>
            <para>The sensors are magnetic pick-up devices which sense the rotation of the speedometer gear and the
                flywheel ring gear. A permanent magnet located in these sensors establishes a magnetic field at the tip
                of the sensor. The magnetic field is repeatedly interrupted by the gear teeth, creating voltage impulses
                that are transmitted to the microprocessor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>January 1994 to November 1997 - Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>The speedometer and tachometer sensor output signals originate at the engine speed sensor (Engine
                manufacturers component) and at the vehicle speed sensor located at the transmission. These signals are
                sent to the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM). The engine ECM receives the input signals, processes
                them, and sends signals in the form of serial data transmissions over data link circuits to the
                speedo/tach microprocessor. The microprocessor then outputs the information to the speedometer and
                tachometer gauges.
            </para>
            <para>The engine ECM has been factory programmed with the information for various components a vehicle is
                equipped with, such as tire size, axle ratio, and engine model.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Any changes in vehicle components such as tire size, axle ratio, etc. requires the engine ECM
                        to be reprogrammed and not the speedo/tach microprocessor. Refer to engine manufacturers service
                        manual for information on reprogramming.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08154x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
