<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CUMMINS ISM AND AHD
        ENGINE SYSTEM - OPERATION - Electronic Accelerator Pedal Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electronic Accelerator Pedal Assembly</title>
        <para>The CM570 ECM utilizes an electronic accelerator pedal assembly that includes an integrated throttle
            position sensor (TPS) and idle validation switch (IVS). The accelerator pedal assembly is serviceable, to
            the extent that the IVS switch is replaceable without replacing the whole assembly.
        </para>
        <para>The TPS is attached to the accelerator pedal and acts like a potentiometer. Movement of the pedal results
            in a variable signal being sent to the ECM that is proportional to pedal position. A 5 volt signal from the
            ECM connector (1091) is applied to circuit 99A, connector (190), circuit 99A and the TPS/IVS (267). The
            variable wiper signal (varies with pedal position) from TPS/IVS (267) is returned to the ECM over circuit
            99, connector (190), circuit 99 and ECM connector (1091). This variable signal tells the ECM the position of
            the accelerator pedal. The TPS (267) is grounded through circuit 99-G, connector (190) and circuit 99-G to
            the ECM (1091).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Any time the accelerator pedal sensor (TPS) is disconnected from the ECM with the key switch on,
                    the TPS and ECM must be recalibrated.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The IVS is used to indicate when accelerator pedal is in the low idle position and when the pedal is not
            in the low idle position. A ground path from the ECM connector (1091), circuit 97-GA, connector (190),
            circuit 99-GA is applied to the TPS/IVS (267).
        </para>
        <para>When the accelerator is in the low idle position, the IVS (267) applies a ground signal to circuit 99B,
            connector (190) and circuit 99B to the ECM (1091). When the accelerator is not in the idle position, the IVS
            (267) applies a ground signal to circuit 99C, connector (190) and circuit 99C to the ECM (1091).
        </para>
        <para>The ECM analyzes the signals received from the TPS and IVS to make certain that the signals fall within
            certain parameters. For example: if the IVS signal indicates that the accelerator pedal is in the idle
            position, the ECM expects to see a TPS signal that indicates that no throttle is applied. If it does not see
            a logical response from both, a fault code may be logged.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM and accelerator pedal must be calibrated to one another for proper engine response. Therefore, the
            ECM and accelerator pedal must be calibrated when the accelerator pedal is initially installed, when an
            accelerator pedal is replaced, when a new calibration is downloaded to the ECM, or when the accelerator
            pedal wiring is disconnected at the pedal, the cab floor, or the ECM connector. To recalibrate the ECM and
            the accelerator pedal, move the key switch to ignition position, slowly move the accelerator pedal from idle
            position to fully depressed position and then release. Repeat this cycle two more times to assure proper
            calibration.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_183.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_185.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
