<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEATING,
        VENTILATION, AND AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - HEATER AND AIR CONDITIONER (CAB) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Power is supplied to (B2) battery stud, circuit 14H, 14Z, fuse F1-C, and circuit 75A to the heater control
            relay (463)/R5. When the key switch (40) is moved to the ignition position, power flows through the key
            switch, and circuits 13 and 13A to the coil of the ignition relay (462)/R1. The ground path for the ignition
            relay is circuits 13-GA, 75-GB, 75-GC, 50-GB, and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud. This energizes the
            ignition relay (462)/R1, and allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuits 13H and 13AK to the
            coil of the heater control relay (463)/R5. The ground path for the heater control relay is circuits 13-GT,
            77-G, 58-GA, and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud. This energizes the heater control relay (463)/R5, and
            allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuit 75B to fan control switch (11).
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (11) is moved to the low position, power flows through the switch,
            circuit 75C, connector (162), circuit 75C, resistor/thermo fuse (27), circuit 75T, connector (161), circuit
            75T, high speed relay (462)/R2 N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (161), and circuit 75F to blower motor.
            This causes the blower motor to run at low speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G,
            connector (161), circuit 75-G and 11-G to the right dash panel ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (11) is moved to the medium position, power will flow through the switch
            as in the low speed setting, and power will also flow through the switch and circuit 75N to the medium speed
            relay (462)/R3. This energizes the medium speed relay (462)/R3 and allows power to flow through heater
            control relay (463)/R5 N.O. contacts, circuit 75D, medium speed relay (462)/R3 N.O. contacts, circuit 75M,
            connector (161), circuit 75M, resistor/thermo fuse (27), circuit 75T, connector (161), circuit 75T, high
            speed relay (462)/R2 N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (161), and circuit 75F to the blower motor. This
            causes the blower motor to run at medium speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G,
            connector (161), circuit 75-G and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud. The ground path for the medium speed
            relay (462)/R3 is circuit 75-GC, 50-GB, and 11-G to right dash panel ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (11) is moved to the high position, power will flow through the switch
            as in the medium speed setting, and power will flow through the switch and circuit 75H to the high speed
            relay (462)/R2. This energizes the high speed relay (462)/R2 which is grounded through circuits 75-GB,
            75-GC, 50-GB and 11-G to the right dash panel ground stud. This allows power to flow from (B2) battery stud
            through circuit 14H, 14X, fuse F1-A, circuit 75, high speed relay (462)/R2 N.O. contacts, circuit 75F,
            connector (161), and circuit 75F to the blower motor. This causes the blower to run at high speed. The
            blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G, connector (161), circuit 75-G and 11-G to right dash panel
            ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>When the blower switch (11) is in the low, medium or high position, power is supplied by the switch to
            circuit 77 and the air conditioner switch (904). When switch (904) is moved to the on position, power flows
            through its indicator light and ground circuits 77-GK and 11-GB to left cab ground (429). This causes the
            indicator to illuminate. Power also flows from switch (904) through the blocking diode, circuits 77S and 77K
            to the A/C control relay (144), thus energizing the relay that is grounded through circuits 77-GS, 82-GA,
            12-GF, 11-GQ, and 11-GF to left dash panel ground stud.
        </para>
        <para>With the relay energized, power flows from the (B2) battery stud through circuits 14H, 14Z, fuse F1-B,
            circuit 77T, A/C control relay (144) N.O. contacts, circuit 77H, connector (162), and circuit 77B to the
            manual temperature control switch.
        </para>
        <para>When the temperature control switch determines that the temperature at the evaporator is above freezing
            (34&#176;F - 38&#176;F), its contacts will close. This will cause power to flow through the control, circuit
            77F, connector (162), circuit 77F, the air conditioning relay (463)/R6 N.C. contacts, circuit 77C, connector
            (2), circuit 77C, connector (N/L), and the black wire to the A/C compressor clutch.
        </para>
        <para>The compressor will then run until the temperature control switch's contacts open up, or the low or high
            pressure safety switch's contacts close
        </para>
        <para>With the A/C system switch (904) and the blower control switch (11) turned on, voltage is also applied by
            A/C control relay (144) to circuit 77H, connector (162), circuits 77C and 77E to the low pressure safety
            switch (N/L). Voltage is also applied to circuit 77H, connector (162), circuit 77C, and 77N to the high
            pressure safety switch. If the refrigerant pressure becomes too low, the low pressure safety switch (N/L)
            contacts will close and power will flow through circuit 77P, connector (162), and circuit 77R to the air
            conditioning relay (463)/R6. If the refrigerant pressure becomes too high, the high pressure safety switch
            (N/L) contacts will close and power will flow through circuit 77J, connector (162), and circuits 77R and 77D
            to the air conditioning relay (463)/R6. The power will flow through the air conditioning relay (463)/R6 coil
            and ground circuits 77-G, 58-GA, and 11-G to the right dash panel ground stud, thus energizing the relay.
        </para>
        <para>With the air conditioning relay (463)/R6 energized, power is interrupted to the refrigerant compressor
            clutch, and power is applied to circuit 77D going to the air conditioning relay coil. Thus the compressor is
            shut down and latched (locked) out by the air conditioning relay, and will not restart until the refrigerant
            pressure is back within operating range and the A/C on/off switch or the blower control switch is moved to
            the off position.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08157_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08157_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08157.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
