<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - GENERAL INFORMATION - 1994 - CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS - ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The individual circuits are identified by circuit number, wire gauge, and abbreviated wire colors.
                Complete circuit diagram instructions are shown in
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk document="s08147_11.xml" xrefid="x0814701">CIRCUIT DIAGRAM INSTRUCTIONS</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                of this chapter.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VREF Circuits</title>
            <para>Many of the circuits in the electronic engine control system carry low voltage and low current signals
                referred to as VREF. This voltage is approximately 5 volts. With Cummins engines these circuits will
                have a (5V) suffix included in the circuit number. For example 97AF(5V) would be a VREF circuit.
            </para>
            <para>With Caterpillar and Detroit Diesel engines the circuits are not always identified with the five volt
                (5V) addition to the circuit number. Refer to the Operation Description in each chapter for a discussion
                on how each circuit operates. Caterpillar, Cummins and Detroit Diesel manuals contain complete
                information on their respective systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Data Link Circuits</title>
            <para>Data link circuits are used to transmit serial data transmissions between the ECM and other
                controllers in the system. This type of circuit carries the signals between the ECM, the ATA data link
                connector (discussed in
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk document="s08147_10.xml" xrefid="x0814702">ATA DATA LINK CONNECTOR</hotlnk>
                </emph>
                ) and also between the ECM and the vehicle speedometer and tachometer and between the ECM and the
                Antilock Brake/Traction system controller.
                <emph type="bold">The wires for these circuits will always be "twisted" together to protect the signals
                    from interference.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08147_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08147_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08147.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
