<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEHR POWER
        SYSTEMS/POWERLINE ALTERNATORS USED ON EMERGENCY VEHICLES - RATING CHARGING SYSTEMS / ALTERNATORS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>RATING CHARGING SYSTEMS / ALTERNATORS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SPECIAL CONSIDERATIONS</title>
            <para>Emergency vehicles operate in situations which may overload charging systems and cause decreased
                system voltage. An overloaded charging system may cause the engine to shut down, damage the alternator
                or reduce battery life.
            </para>
            <para>Accessories, such as lights, radios and sirens, put additional loads on the charging system. When the
                incorrect size alternator is used or the system is not optimized with fast idle devices, optimum pulley
                ratios, and sufficient sized battery cables, system overload is likely to occur.
            </para>
            <para>Engines on emergency vehicles are prone to sit at idle for extended periods of time. An alternator
                will not put out it's rated amperage during engine idle.
            </para>
            <para>To determine if the alternator installed on the vehicle will provide sufficient current, several
                factors need to be considered:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Understand all of the electrical loads of the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Understand the operating conditions of the vehicle. Will the vehicle sit running at idle
                    with full electrical loads for long periods of time?
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">What is the pulley ratio of the alternator? Measure both the engine pulley outside
                    diameter (O.D.) and the alternator pulley O.D. Divide the engine pulley measurement by the
                    alternator pulley measurement. Example: engine pulley O.D. = 6.5 inches alternator pulley O.D. = 3.0
                    inches pulley ratio = 6.5/3.0 =2.17 This means that for every revolution of the engine the
                    alternator makes 2.17 revolutions. If the engine is idling at 700 RPM, the alternator is turning at
                    2.17 X 700 RPM = 1519 RPM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">How much current will the alternator provide at idle? Using the power curves in this
                    manual, determine the output of the alternator at the operating temperature of the vehicle. Example:
                    With the engine compartment temperature at 200&#176;F (93&#176;C) and the alternator turning at 1519
                    RPM, the power curve for the 25-35 200 amp alternator shows 30 amps available to the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Any current required by the system, not supplied by the alternator, will be drawn from the battery. As
                the battery voltage decreases the alternator will work harder to compensate. This may damage the
                alternator.
            </para>
            <para>During a return trip from an emergency, engines may not be run at high speeds long enough to recharge
                the vehicle batteries. No alternator is large enough to return hundreds of amp hours to a battery in a
                few minutes. A truck that encounters an overload condition will probably not survive a run that starts
                with a weak or partially discharged battery.
            </para>
            <para>To prevent overloading the charging system, insure the alternator is rated higher than the maximum
                current that could be required by the vehicle, use fast idle devices and optimize the charging system.
                It may be necessary to use an external battery charger to charge the vehicle batteries when the vehicle
                is parked.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
