<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - HEHR POWER
        SYSTEMS/POWERLINE ALTERNATORS USED ON EMERGENCY VEHICLES - TESTING AND ANALYSIS OF CHARGING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TESTING AND ANALYSIS OF CHARGING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>You will need a clamp-on ammeter, a tape measure, a tachometer (either hand held or in the dashboard),
                and the power curve for the alternator on the vehicle. Copies of the
                <hotlnk document="s08170_17.xml" xrefid="x0817001">Power curves
                    <xref refid="x0817001"/>
                </hotlnk>
                are provided at the end of this manual and are kept current in the Powerline data book. It is a good
                idea to record all data.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TEST CHARGING SYSTEM LOADS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the vehicle as you find it. Measure the voltage directly across each battery and
                    check to see if there is any current flowing out of it (parasitic load). Then check all load
                    switches/loads to make sure they are off. Disconnect battery cables, wait 30 seconds and estimate
                    the battery's state of charge by measuring open circuit voltage. 12.6 to 12.8 volts is 100% charged,
                    12.3 to 12.6 is 75% charged, 12.1 to 12.3 is 50% and 11.8 to 12.3 is 25% charged. If the battery is
                    below 12.3 VDC, charge it before doing the test below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Document the vehicle's equipment and connections.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Record the alternator model#, S/N, and date code.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Observe the 3 #10 bolts on the brush housing (rear face of alternator). A strap
                        between the POSITIVE POST and FIELD CURRENT TERMINAL and a strap between the FIELD CURRENT
                        TERMINAL and the VOLTAGE SENSE terminal, gives a local or alternator sense. A wire directly to
                        the battery from the FIELD CURRENT TERMINAL (no strap from POSITIVE POST to FIELD CURRENT) gives
                        a remote or battery sense. Leave the VOLTAGE SENSE to FIELD CURRENT TERMINAL strap in place.
                        This mode gives the best system performance.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Measure the O.D. of the engine pulley and the alternator pulley (pulley ratio = O.D.
                        of engine pulley/O.D. of alternator pulley). If the alternator pulley is larger than 2.5 inches,
                        you are probably not getting optimum output at idle speeds.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">What size is the POS battery cable from the alternator to the battery? Is there a
                        NEG. cable from the alternator to the battery, or is a chassis ground being used to carry large
                        currents?
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Does the vehicle have a fast idle device? Is it manual or automatically engaged with
                        loads? What engine speed does it produce?
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Does the vehicle have a load management system? Is it automatic?</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For each of the conditions below, measure the voltage directly across the terminals and
                    the current flowing in or out of the alternator and each battery.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Record pulley ratio and the engine RPM during natural engine idle. Apply the loads
                        that would be used either upon arrival or during clean-up at an emergency scene. List the loads
                        and measure the voltage and currents used by each. Pay close attention to the battery current.
                        Is it flowing in (charge) or out (discharge)? If there are multiple wires to a battery, make the
                        current measurement on each one and add up the total.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Engage the fast idle device, if equipped. Measure and record the engine RPM. Apply
                        the loads which would normally be used in a worst case (full ON) scenario at the scene. List
                        them and make voltage and current readings, both initially and after 15 minutes. Pay close
                        attention to the battery current polarity. Is it flowing in (charge) or out (discharge)? Expect
                        the alternator output to drop about 20 amps during the 15 minute test (due to heating effects).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Analysis</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Is the alternator putting out the current it should? Terminal voltage should be
                        above 13.6 volts and the current should be either equal to the demand load or at least that
                        shown on the power curve for the operating rotor speed (Alt. speed = Eng. RPM X pulley ratio).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the battery is discharging in either idle mode, the system will eventually end up
                        with dead batteries. You will have to attempt to optimize the existing system or upgrade the
                        alternator.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08170.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
