<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 - 1992 - 1993 - SYSTEM COMPONENTS AND OPERATION - ENGINE PROTECTION
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE PROTECTION SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Each Series 60 engine includes a standard engine protection system to prevent engine damage. All
                International installed Series 60 engines can be programmed to one of two modes of operation. The
                <emph type="bold">DEFAULT</emph>
                (standard) setting is for warning lights only.
            </para>
            <para>The optional (customer selectable) method is the Engine Power Reduction/Shutdown feature. This feature
                includes warning lights, engine derating and engine shutdown.
            </para>
            <para>The programmable parameter sheet included in the "Driver Information Package" with the truck indicates
                which mode of engine protection that the factory programmed this vehicle for.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Protection System</title>
            <para>Series 60 equipped vehicles have a YELLOW "Check Engine Light" (CEL) and a RED "Stop Engine Light"
                (SEL), located in the right gauge cluster. As a self-test feature, each time the key switch is turned to
                the ON position, the CEL and SEL lights turn on for several seconds, then go off.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If the lights remain ON</emph>, it means the ECM has detected a problem. A diagnostic
                check may be performed using the Diagnostic ON/OFF switch. See
                <hotlnk document="s08141_14.xml" xrefid="x0814103">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>With either the standard "Warning Lights Only" system or the programmable "Engine Power
                Reduction/Shutdown" option, the system monitors the following three inputs:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Coolant Level**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Pressure*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Oil Temperature*</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>** International Circuit And Components</para>
            <para>* DDEC Circuit And Components</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">With either of the two engine protection systems</emph>: If during vehicle
                operation (or when starting the vehicle), any of the above inputs goes outside of a limit set by Detroit
                Diesel, both the yellow CEL and red SEL lights will be turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>If the Engine Power Reduction/Shutdown feature is enabled (customer selected) and one of the three
                monitored parameters goes outside the pre-set limits, the CEL and SEL lights turn ON and the engine
                power will gradually be reduced until the engine is shutdown 30 seconds later.
            </para>
            <para>There is a Engine Override switch which, when held momentarily in the ON position, provides an
                additional 30 seconds of engine operation to allow the vehicle to be brought to a safe stop.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Yellow Check Engine Light (CEL)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If the yellow CEL remains ON, it means the ECM has detected a problem.</emph>
                Take the vehicle to a service center as soon as possible. Some engine/vehicle features may be lost while
                the light is ON.
            </para>
            <para>The CEL receives ignition power from J1 Ignition Feed Connector, which powers all the lights in the
                right gauge cluster. The CEL ground circuit, 97AT, is connected to the ECM through ECM connector (273),
                location B1. The ECM "enables" or "disables" the ground turning the CEL ON or OFF by either applying 12V
                or 0V to circuit 97AT through the ECM connector. When ECM connector (273), location B1 is HIGH (12V),
                the CEL is OFF, and when B1 is LOW (0V), the CEL is ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Red Stop Engine Light (SEL)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If the RED "Stop Engine Light" (SEL) comes on while operating the vehicle, the vehicle
                    should be brought to a safe stop, and the engine SHUT DOWN.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The SEL receives ignition power from J1 Ignition Feed Connector, which powers all the lights in the
                right gauge cluster. The SEL ground circuit, 97AP, is connected to the ECM through ECM connector (273),
                location B2. The ECM "enables" or "disables" the ground turning the SEL ON or OFF by either applying 12V
                or 0V to circuit 97AP through the ECM connector. When ECM connector (273), location B2 is HIGH (12V),
                the SEL is OFF, and when B2 is LOW (0V), the SEL is ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Override Switch (260)</title>
            <para>The engine override switch (260) is a 2-pole switch normally closed (N.C.) momentary ON switch. One
                switch pole is connected to the ECM (circuit 97AU) through connector (273), location G2. This location
                has 5V present from the ECM. The other side of the switch is ground through circuit 97-GD. Closing the
                switch causes the voltage state at ECM location G2 to change from 5V to ground, indicating to the ECM
                that the engine override switch is in the ON position. When this occurs, 30 seconds of additional run
                time is provided.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DDEC Low Coolant Module (274) And Probe (278)</title>
            <para>The DDEC coolant module (installed by International) is connected to the International engine harness
                at connector (274). 12V ignition power from 20A fuse H1, through circuit 13D to 34B powers the Low
                Coolant Module at terminal (5). The Low Coolant Module is grounded from terminal (3) on circuit 34-G.
            </para>
            <para>Low Coolant Module terminal (1) sends a very low current signal on circuit 34 to the low coolant
                probe. When the coolant level is above the probe, the signal is conducted through the probe to ground on
                circuit 34-GA. If the coolant level is
                <emph type="underscr">below the probe</emph>
                (for several seconds to prevent false signals from sloshing), the probe circuit is open, which is
                detected by the Low Coolant Module and a signal is sent to the ECM from terminal (4).
            </para>
            <para>Low Coolant Module terminal (4) is connected by circuit 34A through ECM connector (273), location H3.
                The ECM can receive several different signals from the Low Coolant Module, including one when coolant is
                ABOVE the probe and one when coolant is BELOW the probe. Additionally, the ECM monitors (using signals
                on 34A) voltage levels that the ECM uses in setting diagnostic fault codes.
                <emph type="bold">This manual does not recommend bench testing the DDEC coolant module using a Fluke DOM
                    as internal circuits may be damaged.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08141.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
