<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - CATERPILLAR
        3176B/3406E ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - 1994 - DESCRIPTION - CATERPILLAR 3176B/3406E ENGINE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CATERPILLAR 3176B/3406E ENGINE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The 3176B/3406E controllers provide engine and vehicle functions including:</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">ENGINE FUNCTIONS</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Governoring*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel/Air Ratio Control*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Injection Timing Control*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Service Diagnostics**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque Rise Shaping*</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Trip Data Recording*</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>* Caterpillar System</para>
            <para>** Caterpillar/International System</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">VEHICLE FUNCTIONS</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise Control**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Data Links**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Retarder Controls**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Protection System**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle Shutdown Timer**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Progressive Shifting**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>PTO Controls**</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Speed Limiting**</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>** Caterpillar/International System</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Programmable Parameters</title>
            <para>Certain programmable parameters that affect the engine electronic control systems may be changed with
                electronic service tools (see
                <hotlnk document="s08148_5.xml" xrefid="x0814801">ELECTRONIC SERVICE TOOLS</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>The parameters are stored in the system Electronic Control Module (ECM) and are protected from
                unauthorized change by passwords. The programmable parameters are either "System Parameters" or
                "Customer Parameters."
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">System Configuration Parameters</emph>
                are set at the factory and affect emissions or horsepower ratings within a family of engines. Factory
                passwords must be obtained and used to change System Configuration Parameters.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Customer Selectable Parameters</emph>
                are variable, and are used to specify operating parameters for: cruise control, PTO operation, vehicle
                speed limits, progressive shifting, type of engine protection system, RPM and horsepower ratings within
                the engine family. Customer passwords are needed to change Customer Parameters.
            </para>
            <para>Since each 3176B/3406E control system is electronically programmable to individual owner
                specifications,
                <emph type="bold">the operating parameters will vary from vehicle to vehicle</emph>. Some of these
                parameters may cause the engine to operate in a way that the driver (or service technician) does not
                expect, if proper training has not taken place. This may lead to power or performance complaints and/or
                service time, when the engine is operating correctly.
            </para>
            <para>EXAMPLE: If the driver attempts to drive 60 mph and the vehicle speed limiting option has been
                programmed to limit vehicle speed to 55 mph, the driver may complain of low power.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passwords</title>
            <para>"System Configuration Parameters" are protected by Caterpillar factory passwords. Factory passwords
                are necessary to:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Program a new ECM. When an ECM is replaced, the System Configuration Parameters must be
                    programmed into the new ECM. These parameters are protected by "Factory Passwords".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rerate engine to another engine family. This requires changing the Personality Module
                    Code, which is protected by "Factory Passwords".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read Customer Passwords. If the owner loses the customer password, customer parameters
                    cannot be changed. Using "Factory Passwords", the customer passwords can be read, which can then be
                    used to change customer parameters.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear certain logged Diagnostic Codes. Engine Overspeed and Incorrect Engine Software
                    fault codes can only be cleared using Factory Passwords.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">Factory passwords are only available to authorized Caterpillar dealers.</emph>
                Whenever a system configuration parameter is changed, insure that all appropriate components
                (suspension, drive lines, etc.) are matched with the new change. This may adversely affect warranty
                coverage.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For complete information on passwords, refer to the Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting
                        Guide.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Self-Diagnostics</title>
            <para>Caterpillar Electronic Engine Control systems have some ability to diagnose their own circuits. The
                ECM communicates with the Driver using a Yellow Oil/Water Warning Light and Red Engine Warning Light.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Yellow Oil/Water Warning Light -</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Caterpillar service literature refers to this light as the "Check Engine Light". This light is used
                for two purposes. The light is used to notify the driver that an active code has been logged or with the
                Idle Shutdown feature, the light flashes to indicate that the shutdown timer is within 90 seconds of
                shutting the engine down.
            </para>
            <para>On power up (key on and engine off), the Yellow Oil/Water Warning light will come on for five seconds
                and turn off, indicating that the bulb circuit is working properly.
            </para>
            <para>When a problem condition is detected, an active diagnostic code is logged, which will cause the Yellow
                Oil/Water Warning light to turn ON for five seconds, then flash OFF, then back ON for five seconds. It
                will repeat this until the condition is gone.
            </para>
            <para>The code is also logged (stored) in the ECM permanent memory. This memory is not lost when turning the
                vehicle off or when disconnecting the batteries for a short period of time.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Active and Inactive Codes -</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Codes representing current conditions are called
                <emph type="bold">ACTIVE</emph>
                codes. They indicate that a problem of some type currently exists. They should always be serviced.
            </para>
            <para>If a fault condition occurred and caused a code to be logged, but is no longer present, the code is
                referred to as an
                <emph type="bold">INACTIVE</emph>
                code. This can occur with an intermittent condition or when repairs are made and the code is not
                cleared. Logged inactive codes don't always mean something requires service. Some codes record events
                and not faults.
            </para>
            <para>Codes caused by intermittent conditions are automatically cleared, if after 100 hours of ECM
                operation, the condition does not occur again. Codes that require a Factory Password to clear do not
                automatically clear.
            </para>
            <para>With Engine Protection selected, the
                <emph type="bold">Red Engine Warning light</emph>
                will be activated. Refer to paragraph
                <hotlnk document="s08148_8.xml" xrefid="x0814802">ENGINE PROTECTION</hotlnk>
                for information on this light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08148.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
