<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 9200 9300 9400 MODELS BUILT AFTER JANUARY 1, 1995 - ELECTRONIC
        ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR - 1992-1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE PROTECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE PROTECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>PEEC III and 3176 engine control systems provide the customer a choice of three programmable engine
                protection systems, or a fourth choice where the customer chooses to turn the protection system off. The
                standard engine has all of the components for any of the three protection systems. The difference is how
                the ECM is programmed. The four customer options are:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Off - Engine protection system can be turned off. If this is selected, the yellow "Engine
                        Warning" Light is not functional.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">Driver Warning Only</emph>
                        (Default) - The system alerts the driver by turning ON the yellow "Oil/Water" Warning Light when
                        one or more of the sensors (oil pressure sensor, coolant temperature sensor and low coolant
                        level sensor) detect an out-of-limit condition. A fault or event code will be registered in the
                        ECM.
                        <emph type="bold">This is the engine protection mode programmed if no other option is selected
                            when ordering the vehicle.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">Engine Derate</emph>
                        - The Driver Warning feature (option 2) is activated,
                        <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
                        engine speed (rpm) and engine power are derated while the condition is present, to protect the
                        engine.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note that if the
                        <emph type="underscr">Oil Pressure Sensor</emph>
                        or the
                        <emph type="underscr">Coolant Temperature Sensor</emph>
                        detects an out-of-specification condition, there will be a 1-second sensor delay to verify the
                        condition before the ECM derates the engine.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note also that if the
                        <emph type="underscr">Low Coolant Level Sensor</emph>
                        detects a "low coolant condition" (coolant loss signal sent to the ECM), there will be a
                        10-second sensor delay to verify the condition before the ECM derates the engine.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="underscr">Engine Shutdown</emph>
                        - The Driver Warning (option 2) and Engine Derate (option 3) features are activated,
                        <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
                        engine shutdown will occur after 30 seconds of derating the engine. Restarts by cycling the key
                        switch will give at least 30 seconds of additional run time with the engine derated accordingly.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note that if the
                        <emph type="underscr">Oil Pressure Sensor</emph>
                        or the
                        <emph type="underscr">Coolant Temperature Sensor</emph>
                        detects an out-of-specification condition, there will be a 1-second sensor delay to verify the
                        condition, then the engine is derated for 30 seconds before shutdown.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note also that if the
                        <emph type="underscr">Low Coolant Level Sensor</emph>
                        detects a "low coolant condition" (coolant loss signal sent to the ECM), there will be a
                        10-second sensor delay to verify the condition, then the engine is derated for 40 seconds before
                        engine shutdown.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Yellow "Oil/Water" Warning Light</title>
            <para>The yellow "Oil/Water" Warning Light does not turn ON for a bulb test when the key is turned ON.
                However, after starting the engine, the "Oil/Water" Warning Light comes ON for a minimum of 2 seconds
                while the engine builds oil pressure, then the light goes out.
            </para>
            <para>The International installed Yellow "Oil/Water" Light receives J2 ignition voltage with the key ON. The
                voltage comes from circuit breaker M11 (M11 supplies voltage to the entire right gauge cluster). The
                warning light ground circuit (97AZ) goes through the cab and engine harness to OEM connector (263)
                terminal #12. The ECM opens or closes a ground switch, turning the light ON and OFF in response to ECM
                programming.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Low Coolant Sensor (307)</title>
            <para>The International installed Low Coolant Sensor is located in the surge tank. The sensor contains an
                internal printed circuit board and
                <emph type="bold">should not be tested using a volt-ohmmeter (VOM), digital or analog, as the circuit
                    board may be damaged</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>The Low Coolant sensor connects to a 4-pin connector (307) on the International engine harness. All
                four Low Coolant Sensor circuits go through the engine harness to OEM connector (263).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Low Coolant Level Sensor common terminal (C) is connected by circuit 34B to the ECM
                    through OEM connector (263) terminal #18. This circuit applies operating power (5 volts) to the
                    sensor from the ECM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Low Coolant Level Sensor ground terminal (B) is connected (circuit 34-G) to OEM
                    connector (263) terminal #2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the coolant level is NORMAL (above the probe), the ECM expects to see:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A 5-volt signal (3.5V minimum) from sensor terminal D at OEM connector C263 terminal
                        #39 AND
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A 0-volt signal (0.7V maximum) from sensor terminal A at OEM connector C263 terminal
                        #19.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the coolant level is LOW (below the probe), the ECM expects to see:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A 5-volt signal (3.5V minimum) from sensor terminal A at OEM connector C263,
                        terminal #19 AND
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A 0-volt signal (0.7V maximum) from sensor terminal D at OEM connector C263,
                        terminal #39.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Oil Pressure Sensor (CAT Component)</title>
            <para>The Caterpillar installed engine oil pressure sensor is part of the transducer module, located below
                the rack actuator housing on the left side of the engine. To diagnose the operation of this sensor,
                refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor (CAT Component)</title>
            <para>The Caterpillar installed engine coolant temperature sensor is located in the water outlet housing.
                The engine sends a 5-volt signal to the sensor and a variable signal (0.5 - 5.5 volts) is returned to
                the ECM. To diagnose the operation of this sensor, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08145.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
