<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRONIC ENGINE CONTROLS - CATERPILLAR 3176 - 1992 - 1993 - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE CONTROLS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE CONTROLS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This manual discusses only the engine brake controls as they relate to International installed
                components, including the Engine Brake ON/OFF switch (170), the Engine Brake Selector switch (171) and
                the Engine Brake Enable Relay (175). The International installed Clutch Switch and Service Brake Switch
                also provide inputs to the Engine Brake Control System and are discussed in paragraphs
                <hotlnk document="s08133_9.xml" xrefid="x0813302">Service Brake Switch</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk document="s08133_9.xml" xrefid="x0813303">Clutch Switch</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>For a complete description of Engine Brake Operation, refer to the appropriate Cater- pillar Service
                Manual.
            </para>
            <para>There are two owner-selected Engine Brake operation modes, which are "Coast" and "Latch."</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"COAST" OPERATION MODE (STANDARD MODE)</title>
            <para>If the "Coast" mode was selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed is over 950 rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The driver's foot is off both the throttle and clutch pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The service brake pedal is depressed (engine brake only operates while service brake is
                        applied).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Cruise Control switch can be in the ON position, although it will be disabled by applying
                        the service brake.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813304">
            <title>"Latch" Operation Mode</title>
            <para>If the "Latch" mode was selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine speed is over 950 rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The driver's foot is off both the throttle and clutch pedals.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The cruise control switch must be OFF.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The engine brake operates when the driver applies the service brake, but the engine brake
                        continues to operate ("latches on" so to speak) after the driver takes his foot off the brake.
                        The engine brake stays engaged (latched ON) until one of the other ECM inputs changes: clutch
                        pedal depressed, throttle pedal depressed, engine speed drops below 950 rpm or the brake pedal
                        is depressed a second time.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0813305">
            <title>ECM/Driver Engine Brake Control</title>
            <para>Control of the engine brake is shared by:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The driver, who turns the engine brake ON or OFF and selects how much engine brake is
                        desired.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before the ECM "enables" the engine brake system by sending a 12-volt signal to energize the
                        Engine Brake Enable Relay (175), the ECM verifies that the following conditions are present:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphalc">
                        <item>
                            <para>Clutch switch must be closed (pedal released).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Electronic throttle pedal is in the IDLE position.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cruise control must be OFF (see COAST option in paragraph 2.5.1).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine speed must be greater than 950 rpm.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With an Antilock Brake System (ABS) installed, the ignition power to the Engine Brake Enable
                        Relay (175) is controlled by the ABS system Engine Brake Relay. This allows the ABS system to
                        "turn off" the engine brake when the ABS system detects that one or more of the vehicle wheels
                        is encountering a slippery road surface.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>To summarize the engine brake controls, the ECM sends a 12-volt signal (when conditions are correct)
                to energize the engine brake relay (175), and the driver must turn the engine brake ON to ground the
                engine brake relay and to deliver ignition voltage from the relay to the engine brake solenoids. The ABS
                system has the ability to turn the engine brake off if wheel lockup is about to occur.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Enable Relay (175) And ON/OFF Switch (170)</title>
            <para>To "enable" (turn on) the engine brake control system, the Engine Brake Enable Relay must be
                energized. To energize the relay two things must occur:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM must supply battery voltage through ECM connector C320, terminal 22, to energize the
                        Engine Brake Enable Relay control coil.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ON/OFF switch must be in the ON position to complete the Engine Brake Enable Relay control
                        coil ground path.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Turning the Engine Brake ON/OFF Switch to the ON position completes the ground path (24Y/24-G/24-GU)
                for the Engine Brake Enable Relay to the cylinder head ground. When all conditions are correct
                (paragraphs
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813304">"Latch" Operation Mode</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0813305">ECM/Driver Engine Brake Control</hotlnk>), the ECM applies 12 volts on circuit
                24Z to the Engine Brake Enable Relay energizing coil (terminal 85) causing the relay to energize.
            </para>
            <para>Energizing the Engine Brake Enable Relay causes the relay switch to toggle, complet- ing the circuit
                between the relay common terminal (30) and the normally open terminal (87). The Engine Brake Relay
                normally open terminal (87) has ignition voltage from fuse F2 present whenever the key is ON. With the
                relay energized, the ignition power is delivered (circuit 24B) through the closed contacts of the Engine
                Brake ON/OFF Switch to the Engine Brake Selector Switch (circuit 24C).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Selector Switch (171)</title>
            <para>The Engine Brake Selector Switch receives power from Engine Brake ON/OFF switch.</para>
            <para>The selector switch directs ignition power through the cab and engine harness to all three engine
                solenoids (full brake), or center solenoid only (circuit 24D), or only to front and rear solenoids
                (circuit 24F and 24H).
            </para>
            <para>International installs the harness to the solenoids, although the engine brake solenoids are installed
                by Caterpillar.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Note the diode assembly at connector (331) in the JACOBS BRAKE Circuit Diagram. The diode's
                        purpose is to prevent voltage spikes (spikes are created when the engine brake solenoid field
                        collapses) from entering the electrical system causing damage to electronic components.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08133.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
