<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000, 9100, 9200, 9400, AND 9900 MODELS - CATERPILLAR C-10, C-12
        AND 3406E ENGINES - OPERATION - ENGINE BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE BRAKE</title>
        <para>These Caterpillar engines come with an engine brake. This manual discusses only engine brake control
            circuits and components installed by International: the engine brake on/off switch (434), the engine brake
            selector switch (433) and the connecting circuits. The International installed clutch switch (294) and
            service brake switch (141) also provide inputs to the engine brake control system.
        </para>
        <para>For a complete description of engine brake operation, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Service
            Manual.
        </para>
        <para>There are two owner selected engine brake operation modes, which are COAST and LATCH.</para>
        <para>If the COAST mode (standard mode) is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Engine speed is over 800 rpm.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The driver's foot is off the throttle pedal (throttle position less than 7%).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch pedal is not depressed.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The service brake pedal is depressed (engine brake only operates while service brake is
                    applied).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The cruise control switch can be in the on position, although it will be disabled by applying the
                    service brake.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If the LATCH mode is selected, the engine brake operates when:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Engine speed is over 800 rpm.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The driver's foot is off the throttle pedal (throttle position less than 7%).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clutch pedal is not depressed.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The cruise control switch must be off.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The engine brake operates when the driver applies the service brake, but the engine brake
                    continues to operate (latches on, so to speak) after the driver takes his foot off the brake. The
                    engine brake stays engaged (latched on) until one of the other ECM inputs changes: clutch pedal
                    depressed, throttle pedal depressed, engine speed drops below 800 rpm or the brake pedal is
                    depressed a second time.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Control of the engine brake is shared by the driver and the ECM. The driver turns the engine brake on or
            off and selects how much engine brake is desired (number of cylinders). The ECM monitors certain engine
            parameters, then enables the engine brake system when all conditions are acceptable.
        </para>
        <para>An on/off switch (434) is used to enable (turn on) the engine brake control system. With the on/off switch
            closed, the circuit between ECM connector (400) terminal 5 and the engine brake selector switch terminal 2
            is complete.
        </para>
        <para>The engine brake selector switch (433) has three circuits: Low, Medium and a common or ground circuit
            connected to the engine brake on/off switch.
        </para>
        <para>Selector switch terminal 2 is connected by circuit 24A to the engine brake on/off switch (434) at terminal
            5. When the on/off switch is on, the circuit between the engine brake selector switch (433) terminal 2 and
            ECM connector (400) terminal 5 is complete.
        </para>
        <para>With the selector switch (433) in the Low position, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector (400)
            terminal 23 and a 5 volt signal at terminal 40.
        </para>
        <para>With the selector switch (433) in the Medium position, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector (400)
            terminal 40 and a 5 volt signal at terminal 23.
        </para>
        <para>With the selector switch (433) in the High position, the ECM sees a 0 volt signal at connector (400)
            terminals 40 and 23.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_103.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191_105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08191.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
