<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 ENGINE - OPERATION -
        OPTIMIZED IDLE&#8482; (OPTIONAL)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPTIMIZED IDLE&#8482; (OPTIONAL)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to Detroit Diesel manual furnished with the vehicle for additional feature information.</para>
            <para>The Detroit Optimized Idle is a system that automatically starts and stops the engine to maintain oil
                temperature and battery voltage. The system will disable all heater blowers to conserve battery voltage
                as required.
            </para>
            <para>The Optimized Idle system can also be used to automatically start and stop the engine to maintain
                sleeper temperature. A thermostat in the sleeper compartment is utilized to maintain cab temperature.
                The inside thermostat is set for a desired temperature and a range is selected. The engine is then
                started and stopped as required to maintain inside temperature. The system is controlled by the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The system is initiated when the ignition is on, the engine is idling, the transmission is in neutral,
                the cab is lowered, the idle shutdown timer in the ECM must be enabled, and the cruise control must be
                cycled from off to on. An indicator lamp on the dash will be illuminated when the Optimized Idle is
                active. An alarm in the engine compartment will sound for 5 seconds with an additional 2 second delay
                prior to engine startup.
            </para>
            <para>The Optimized Idle system utilizes three switches to prevent unwanted starts. A transmission neutral
                safety switch, park brake switch and cab tilt switch are wired in series and help prevent a driverless
                launch of the vehicle. If any of the switches are open the system will not function. If any of the
                switches are shorted to ground during normal operation a fault will be logged and the system will be
                disabled until the problem is corrected. If the switches go to ground during engine operation the speed
                and toque drop to normal idle operation.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM also senses the vehicle speed and engine speed. If the engine speed fails to reach 200 RPM
                within 2 seconds during cranking the start is aborted. If the vehicle speed sensors record two counts
                during cranking the start will be aborted. If two starts are aborted the system is disabled. While
                running in the Optimized Idle mode, if the vehicle speed sensor detects two counts or the required
                torque exceeds 25% of the available torque, the engine is shut down. This provides additional protection
                against driverless launches.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Start Circuits</title>
            <para>The Idle Timer Switch supplies a ground on circuit 97AV, to connector (262), terminal R. The ground
                continues on circuit 97BD through the Neutral Position Switch (918) to circuit 97BB and connector
                (102/338). Circuit 97BB goes to connector (920) and the Hood Closure Switch. Circuit 97BH comes from
                (920) and is split into circuit 97BF, to Idle Relay (482) and into circuit 97BA, through (102/308) to
                circuit 97AV, to ECM connector (341) terminal H2.
            </para>
            <para>The ground on circuit 97BH at Idle Relay (482) will energize the relay. 12 Volts to the relay coil
                comes from I2 Ignition adapter (607-C) on circuit 13BA, through fuse F10-A, to circuits 17C, 17E, 17F.
                12 Volts on circuit 17T will be applied through the relay contacts to circuits 17P. Circuit 17P supplies
                12 volts to the coil of Ignition Relay (483).
            </para>
            <para>Ignition Relay (483) will be energized by a ground from the ECM connector (913), terminal B through
                connector (262) on circuit 17H. The energized relay applies 12 volts to Start Feed Adapter (509-B) from
                circuit 17E. This will engage the engine starter.
            </para>
            <para>The 10K resistor (782) provides a current path to the Ignition Relay (483) to allow the ECM to monitor
                the coil for an open condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blower Disable Circuits</title>
            <para>12 volts is supplied to Heater Relay (463-R5) from Ignition Relay (462-R1) on circuits 13H and 13T
                through Heater Control Diode (783) to circuit 13TA. The relay is energized when a ground is supplied
                from ECM connector (341) terminal F3, circuit 75BB. This ground also controls Sleeper Medium Speed Relay
                (480), Sleeper High Speed Relay (481) and Bunk blower Relay (441).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostat Circuits</title>
            <para>12 volts is supplied to Thermostat (910), terminal 5 from I3 Ignition Adapter (496-G) on circuit 13BN
                through fuse F10-B to circuit 75BD, connector (911) and (909). Ground on (910) terminal 6 comes from G2
                Gnd. Adapter (455-C) on circuit 75-GE through connector (911) and (909). Thermostat (910) terminal 4 is
                the input to the ECM (913) on circuit 75BC. Thermostat (910) terminals 1 and 3 are connector to a
                thermistor which senses the sleeper temperature.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm and Indicator Light Circuits</title>
            <para>12 volts from I2 Ignition Adapter (607-C) on circuit 13BA through fuse F10-A to circuit 17C. 17C is
                split into circuit 17K, which connects to Indicator Light (912), and circuit 17M, which connects to
                Alarm (916).
            </para>
            <para>The Indicator Light is turned on by a ground supplied from ECM connector (914) terminal B on circuits
                17LA and 17L through connector (262) to the Indicator Light (912).
            </para>
            <para>The Alarm is turned on by a ground supplied from ECM connector (913) terminal A on circuit 17N through
                connector (915) to Alarm connector (916).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_162.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_164.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
