<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - ENGINES - V8-AVNT ENGINES - REMOTE ENGINE SPEED CONTROL MODULE (RESCM)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x0825755" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REMOTE ENGINE SPEED CONTROL MODULE (RESCM)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Circuit Functions</title>
            <para>The V8 engine has an optional feature code that allows the engine to be controlled a remote location
                outside of the cab. This is accomplished by using a remote engine speed control module (RESCM).
            </para>
            <para>The remote engine speed control is an interface for body builders to use for remote operation of the
                engine. The RESCM interfaces to the ESC on the Body Data Link via J1939 proprietary messages. In most
                cases the information simply needs to pass through the ESC to the ECM. But, because of the proprietary
                nature of the communication between the RESCM and the ESC, some data conversion will be necessary.
            </para>
            <para>The RESCM provides 4 switch functions, a speedometer, a tachometer, two warning lights and a remote
                accelerator. The RESCM is also capable of providing pressure governor features covered by the Pressure
                Governor ESC feature.
            </para>
            <para>More specifically the RESCM includes:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A variable PTO enable switch (digital)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A preset PTO enable switch (digital)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A Set / Coast speed switch (duplicates the in-cab control)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A Resume / Accel speed switch (duplicates the in-cab control)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>An amber warn engine lamp (digital)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A red stop engine lamp (digital)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A speedometer (data link to electronic signal output)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A tachometer (data link to electronic signal output)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A remote accelerator (analog input)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Body Builder provides the actual hardware that is connected to the RESCM unit.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If communications should happen to be lost between the RESCM and the ESC, the sensor inputs normally
                received from the RESCM will be sent to the engine as unavailable and switch inputs will be sent to the
                engine as off.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to Body Builder Manual CT-471 or the applicable engine manual for more details.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Locations</title>
            <figure id="f082571e" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G082578.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="532px"/>
                <caption>RESCM Location</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRANSMISSION HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ENGINE HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_204.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X0825713.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
