<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON 2000 SERIES&#8482; (LCT) TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - DESCRIPTION - DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>Several diagnostic features are included in the electronic control system to assist in troubleshooting
            malfunctions and/or to monitor specific operating parameters. These features include a CHECK TRANSMISSION
            light in the instrument cluster and the (9 pin) Data Link Connector for using a Diagnostic Service Tool,
            such as the EZ-Tech&#8482;, with the TransPro software. When a malfunction is detected in the control
            system, a diagnostic code is used to identify and clarify the nature of the malfunction.
        </para>
        <para>CHECK TRANSMISSION light - The CHECK TRANSMISSION light is located in the instrument cluster. A system
            check is performed when the engine is started. The CHECK TRANSMISSION light will come on when the vehicle is
            started. The light will go out after 3 seconds, unless a system fault is detected by the TCM.
        </para>
        <para>If a system fault that inhibits the transmission operation is detected by the TCM, the CHECK TRANSMISSION
            light will illuminate indicating that transmission shifts are being restricted. Vehicle operation may
            continue in order to reach service assistance. The TCM may not respond to shift selector requests, since
            operating limitations are being placed on the transmission; i.e., upshifts and downshifts may be restricted.
            <emph type="bold">Directional changes (forward to reverse for example) may not occur.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Any time the CHECK TRANSMISSION light has been illuminated, the TCM will register a diagnostic code. It
            may be identified by using the EZ-Tech service tool with the TransPro software.
        </para>
        <para>Minor conditions can occur that will cause a diagnostic code to be registered in the TCM, but will not
            illuminate the CHECK TRANSMISSION light or restrict transmission operation.
        </para>
        <para>DATA LINK CONNECTOR - The 9 pin data link connector is used to connect a service tool to the transmission
            electronic control system. The diagnostic codes and other related information will be discussed in
            <hotlnk document="s08247_32.xml" xrefid="x0824703">ALLISON 2000 SERIES DIAGNOSTIC CODE LIST
                <xref refid="x0824703"/>
            </hotlnk>
            in this service manual section.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
