<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - INTRODUCTION - ELECTRICAL TEST EQUIPMENT - VOLTMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>VOLTMETER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Voltage is an electrical pressure or force that pushes the current through a circuit. The pressure is
                measured in Volts and the symbol V (as in 12V) is used in the circuit diagrams. The letter "E" is also
                used for voltage and stands for Electromotive Force. Voltage can be compared to the pressure necessary
                to push water through a metering valve.
            </para>
            <para>Low voltage to a lamp will cause the lamp to glow dimly. This can be caused by low source voltage
                (battery discharged or low alternator output), or by high circuit resistance in the circuit due to a
                poor connection. The resistance of the poor connection or poor ground acts as an additional load in the
                circuit, causing less voltage to be available to push current through the load device. Before making any
                meter measurements, it is important to briefly review the relationship between voltage, current, and
                resistance (Ohms Law,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825010">Ohms Law Formula</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measuring Voltage</title>
            <para>In electrical diagnosis, the voltmeter is used to answer:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Is voltage present?</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">What is the voltage reading?</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">What is the voltage drop across a load device?</para>
            </step1>
            <para>When using a voltmeter to determine if voltage is present to power a device, connect the positive
                meter lead to input connection of the device (positive side) and connect the negative meter lead to good
                vehicle ground (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825012">Voltmeter Lead Connections Diagram</hotlnk>). A good ground would be any
                metallic bracket, body panel, or fastener that is free of paint, rust or corrosion, and is connected to
                the frame, engine, or body. The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825012">Voltmeter Lead Connections Diagram</hotlnk>
                shows how much of the source voltage is available to the device. Note that the meter is connected in
                parallel to the device.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825012" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="296px"/>
                <caption>Voltmeter Lead Connections Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Should we need to determine if voltage is available at a connector where we can't readily connect to
                the device, we can connect the meter in series between ground and the connector (voltage source) as
                shown in the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825013">Connecting the Meter in Series Diagram</hotlnk>. The meter's internal
                resistance is very high so little current will flow in the circuit, and the voltage can be read
                accurately.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825013" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="296px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Connecting the Meter in Series Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>To check the voltage drop across a load device (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825014">Checking Voltage Drop Across a Load Device Diagram</hotlnk>), connect the
                positive lead of the voltmeter to the positive side of the device and the negative meter lead to the
                negative side of the device. With the device operating, measure the voltage drop across the device.
                Notice in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825014">Checking Voltage Drop Across a Load Device Diagram</hotlnk>, since we only
                have one device, all of the voltage should be dropped at the device. In any circuit, the voltage applied
                will equal the voltage dropped in the circuit. If in this circuit we only dropped 9V across the load,
                that would indicate that our wires, connections, etc. were dropping the other 3V, which would indicate
                excessive circuit resistance.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825014" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="296px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Checking Voltage Drop Across a Load Device Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_HL0825002.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
