<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000FE CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Horn</title>
            <para>Power is applied from the (J2) battery feed stud to circuit 14/14A, fuse F11, and circuit 85 to the
                coil of the horn relay (R6). When the horn button is depressed, power flows through the horn relay coil,
                circuit 85A, in-line connector (14), circuit 85A, a black wire, the steering wheel slip ring, another
                black wire, the horn button switch and circuit 85-GB to the steering column ground.
            </para>
            <para>With the horn relay energized, power flows from circuit 85, through circuit 85B, the horn relay,
                circuit 85C to the low note horn and circuit 85D to the high note horn. The horns are grounded through
                the mounting bolts and through circuit 85-G to the platform ground (J1).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Dryer with Heater</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on or accessory position, power is applied to circuit 12, fuse F7,
                circuit 39A, dash connector (2), 39A, connector (40), a black wire, connector (51)/(76), and a black
                wire to the heated air dryer (94). If the air dryer thermostat senses air temperature below 50&#176;F
                (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow through the heating element. This assures that
                the accumulated moisture does not freeze during cold weather.
            </para>
            <para>Ground is through a white wire, connector (51)/(76), a white wire, connector (40), and circuit
                39-G/11-GJ to (J10) engine ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Brake System</title>
            <para>Refer to CTS-5115 ANTILOCK BRAKE SYSTEM.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Builder Connections</title>
            <para>Refer to Description, Operation and Troubleshooting sections for circuitry of any system which may
                supply power to the body builder connectors (169) or (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Automatic Drain Valve with Heater</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on position, power is fed to circuit 12, fuse F8, circuit 39, dash
                connector (2), circuit 39, in-line connector (40), and a black wire to the heated drain valve. The drain
                valve is grounded through a white wire, in-line connector (40), circuit 39-GA/11-GJ to the (J10) engine
                or starter ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature drops below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow
                through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze in the drain
                valve during cold weather.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter/Water-In-Fuel</title>
            <para>Power is applied from the (J2) battery feed stud to the fuel heater relay (R5) through circuit 14/19,
                fuse F17 and circuit 19H. When the key switch is turned to the ON or START position, power flows from
                the key switch (20), through circuit 13A, fuse F20, circuit 19D and the relay coil. Ground for the relay
                is through circuit 11-GA to the (J1) platform ground. This energizes the relay.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay energized, power is applied to the heated fuel filter (N/L) through circuit 19B,
                connector (2), circuit 19B, connector (39) and a green wire. When the temperature drops below
                approximately 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), the thermo switch contacts close and a ground path is applied
                through a blue wire, connector (39), circuit 19-GD/11-GJ to the (J10) engine ground. This causes the
                heater element to come on.
            </para>
            <para>With key switch on, power is also applied from the fuel heater relay connector through circuit 19E to
                the water-in-fuel module (16). From the module, power is applied to the fuel filter water probe through
                circuit 19A, connector (2), circuit 19A, connector (39), and a yellow wire. Whenever water builds up to
                an unacceptable level, it causes a completed circuit path from the probe to the filter housing, which is
                grounded to the frame through its mounting bracket. This causes the module to energize.
            </para>
            <para>When the water-in-fuel module becomes energized, power is supplied to circuit 19F and the
                water-in-fuel light (9). This energizes the lamp as power flows through circuit 19-G/11-G to the (J1)
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is in the start position, the water-in-fuel module is grounded through circuit
                19-GB to the key switch ground. This serves as a bulb check to assure the bulb is operational.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module (86) is fed a signal from the flow switch (N/L),
                causing the monitor to turn on a brake warning light and alarm system and to start the hydraulic reserve
                pump to provide additional braking power. The reserve pump and warning system is also activated when the
                differential pressure switch (91) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuits 13A, 90U,
                fuse F2, circuit 90T, and blocking diode assembly (80). From the blocking diode, power is supplied
                through circuit 90J, to the hydraulic pump control relay (85) coil, and also through circuit 90H to the
                brake monitor module (86). The brake monitor module is grounded through circuit 11-GD to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link 90-FL, circuit 90, and pump control relay (85). Power is also
                applied from circuit 90-FL to circuit 90, circuit 90A, fuse F1, circuit 90B, connectors (83), (87), and
                (92), and hydraulic brake switch (209).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch contacts will be
                closed (engine not running) and a ground path is provided from the switch through circuits 90L, 90K,
                connector (84), circuit 90K, connector (88) and 90K, to a splice. From the splice, a ground path is
                provided over circuit 90L to the brake monitor module alarm input (86-A). This causes the module to
                switch the alarm output (86-C) to ground, which activates the alarm and warning light. From the splice,
                a ground circuit is also provided by way of circuit 90E to the pump control relay (85), causing it to
                energize. With the relay energized, power flows through its N.C. contacts, circuit 90S and connectors
                (84) and (88) to the reserve pump motor. This causes the reserve pump motor, which is grounded through
                its case, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>A signal path, on circuit 90Q, connectors (84) and (88) to brake monitor module connector (86-F),
                provides information to the module. It continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump and
                power supplied to it. The warning system activates if the pump motor winding opens up or if the
                hydraulic brake relay (85) remains closed (provides power to circuit 90S and the reserve pump motor),
                after the engine is running. The warning system is also activated if no power is supplied to the pump
                motor when the flow switch or differential switch contacts are closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (86-C) to ground, the brake warning light
                illuminates by power flowing to the lamp feed connector (10), through the light, connector (10), and
                circuits 90N, 90M, to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, the alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the
                alarm, and circuit 90M to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>If the ignition key is in the off position and the truck brakes are applied, the contacts of the
                hydraulic brake switch (209) close. With the contacts closed, power flows through circuits 70C, 90F, 90G
                and blocking diode assembly (81), circuit 70D, connector and diode assembly (80), and circuit 90H, to
                feed the brake monitor module at connector (86-E).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, power signals are fed from the diode connector (81) to circuit 90D and the brake
                monitor module connector (86-G) and on circuit 90C to brake monitor module connector (86-H). The module
                compares these signals and if there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits, 90D or 90C, for more
                than 14&#177;5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is also applied to the stop light relay (R4) through fuse F12 and circuit 70B. When
                the brakes are applied, power flows from diode connector (80), through circuit 70E, to the relay coil,
                which energizes the relay. The relay is grounded through circuit 70-G/11-GA to (J1) platform ground.
                With the relay energized, the contacts close and allow power to flow through the relay, circuit 70A, to
                the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Hydraulic Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the cranking motor solenoid, power is applied to circuit 90-FL/90, a connector (N/L), circuit
                90A, fuse F1, circuit 90B, connectors (83), (87) and (92) to the brake switch (209). When the brake
                pedal is depressed, the contacts of switch (209) close and power is supplied to circuit 70C, connectors
                (93), (87) and (83), and circuit 90C to the brake monitor module (86).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, power is also applied to a blocking diode (81), circuit 70D, connector (80), and
                circuit 70E to the stop light relay (R4). This energizes the relay and allows power to be applied
                through fuse F12, circuit 70B, relay (R4), and circuit 70A to the body builder connector (169). From
                this point, power is applied to the tail lights through the body builder circuitry.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Air Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the battery feed stud (J2), power is applied to circuit 14/14A, fuse F12, circuit 70, stop light
                switch jumper harness connector (26), a red wire, first stop light switch (26), and a red wire to the
                second stop light switch (26).
            </para>
            <para>When the brake pedal is depressed, the stop light switch contacts close and power is supplied to the
                common brown wire and to jumper harness connector (26). From connector (26), power is applied to
                circuits 70B/70A and the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allison AT Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is placed in the start or ignition position, power is fed through circuit 92D
                to the modulator solenoid relay (R3) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>The modulator solenoid relay is energized when the ECM (379) applies a ground to circuit 92F.</para>
            <para>With the modulator solenoid relay (403) energized, power flows through circuit 92C, the connector (2),
                circuit 92C, the auto XMSN connector (389) and circuit 92C to the modulator shift solenoid connector
                (32).
            </para>
            <para>Ground path for the modulator shift solenoid is circuit 92-G/11-GJ to cranking motor ground.</para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is placed in the start or ignition position, power is also fed through
                circuits 13/13A/13K to fuse F10. From the fuse, power is fed through circuit 97P, connector (2), and
                circuit 97P to the neutral position switch. If the transmission is in neutral, power flows through the
                switch, circuit 97AU, connector (2), circuit 97AU, and circuit 97L to the crank inhibit relay (R2).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
