<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000FE BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Power</title>
            <para>The vehicle batteries are connected in parallel and provide power through the 4/0 positive battery
                cable to the cranking motor solenoid (B) stud.
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are also connected in parallel and provide a ground path through the
                3/0 negative battery cable to the cranking motor ground stud. The frame, engine block, and cab platform
                are also interconnected by ground cables to the battery ground.
            </para>
            <para>For additional information on the operating principles for batteries, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL,
                in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking System and Circuits - Front Key Start</title>
            <para>With the vehicle in neutral and the instrument panel key switch (20) in the start position, power
                flows from the battery feed stud (1F) through circuit 14D, circuit 19, fuse F16, circuit 15, and to the
                key switch (20). From the key switch, power flows through circuit 17A, the start interrupt connector
                (195), circuit 17 and dash connector (2). Power is then applied through the chassis harness on circuit
                17, the chassis harness to engine harness connector (196), and circuit 17 to the rear control box
                connector (3). From the control box connector (3), power flows through circuit 17E to the logic side of
                the crank relay (385). The relay is grounded through circuit 97H to the control box.
            </para>
            <para>Power is also available at the switch contact end of the time delay crank relay (385) through the
                start relay (387) circuitry. With the engine stop switch (187) contacts closed, power is supplied to the
                ignition relay through circuit 14B-FL/14B, control box connector (3), circuit 14B/14A, engine stop
                switch (187), and circuit 14D.
            </para>
            <para>With the ignition in the on or start position, power flows through circuit 13/13A, fuse F19, circuit
                13K, dash connector (2A) circuit 13K, chassis/engine harness connector (196), and circuit 13K to the
                rear control box connector (3). From connector (3), power flows through circuit 13K to the blocking
                diode assembly (47), and through circuit 13B to the coil of the ignition relay. The relay is grounded
                through circuit 458/11-G to the (2G) control box ground. This causes the ignition relay to energize.
            </para>
            <para>With the transmission in neutral (neutral position switch contacts closed) and the ignition relay
                (458) energized, power flows through circuit 13P to the rear fuse holder (1B), fuse B2, circuit 97R,
                control box connector (3) and circuit 97P to the neutral position switch (436 or 438). Power then flows
                through the switch contacts, circuit 97AU, circuit 97L, connector (3) and circuit 97L to the time delay
                crank relay (385).
            </para>
            <para>Voltage is provided from the front key switch (circuit 17) through the front/rear switch (618) and
                circuit 17E to the crank relay (385) coil. If cranking is enabled, a ground path is provided through
                circuit 97H, control box connector (3), and circuit 97H to pin C46 of the (ECM) Engine Control Module
                (379).
            </para>
            <para>The energized crank relay controls the start relay (387) by providing power through circuit 17A. This
                energizes the start relay which is grounded through circuit 17D, and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank
                motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is always present at the crank motor solenoid (B) terminal through the 4/0 positive
                battery cable. The 3/0 negative battery cable is attached to the crank motor ground stud which is
                grounded to the frame rail. Power is also available at the start relay (387) through the solenoid (B)
                terminal and circuit 17-FL/17B. With the starter relay energized, power flows through the closed
                contacts and circuit 17C to the (S) terminal of the crank motor solenoid which energizes the solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the crank motor solenoid energized, the solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to rotate. When
                the engine starts and the key is released, power is removed from circuit 17A which de-energizes the
                start relay (387) and disengages the crank motor.
            </para>
            <para>If the engine does not start initially, the engine will crank until the key switch is released, the
                crank motor thermal overcrank protection system is activated, or the ECM supply voltage drops below 6
                volts. This causes the ECM to remove power from the time delay crank relay which allows the starter to
                crank for only an additional 2 second time delay period.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking System and Circuits - Rear Key Start</title>
            <para>In order to start the engine from the rear, the rear control box is equipped with an additional key
                switch (20). Battery power is available from the battery feed stud (1F), through circuit 14B-FL/14B,
                control box connector (3), and circuit 14B/14 to the key switch (20). When the key switch is turned to
                the on or start position, power flows through the key switch and through circuit 17BB, front/rear switch
                (618) and circuit 17E to the crank relay (385) and through circuit 13N to the blocking diode assembly
                (47). From there, the system circuitry is the same as described for the front key start.
            </para>
            <para>For additional information on the operating principles for cranking motors, refer to GROUP 08 -
                ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking System and Circuits - Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection</title>
            <para>With crank motor thermal overcrank protection, the start relay (387) control coil ground 17D is
                connected to the normally closed thermal overcrank protection switch (N/L) located in the end of the
                cranking motor. The overcrank protection switch is grounded through circuits 17-G/11-GJ to the crank
                motor ground stud.
            </para>
            <para>If excessive cranking causes the crank motor temperature to exceed a pre-set temperature limit, the
                thermal overcrank protection switch contacts open and causes the start relay to de-energize and the
                crank motor to disengage. When the crank motor cools, the thermal switch contacts reset and the crank
                motor can be engaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Charging System</title>
            <para>With the engine running, the function of the alternator is to produce direct current (DC) in order to
                supply power to the vehicle electrical system, and to charge the batteries.
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the alternator (+) terminal,
                circuit 2, and 2-FL/2A-FL to the crank motor solenoid (B) stud. From this stud, power is supplied to the
                body builder feed stud (1F) through circuit 14-FL/14A-FL/14.
            </para>
            <para>Any current above the needs of the vehicle electrical system is used to supply the batteries. From the
                crank motor solenoid (B) stud, the alternator also charges the batteries through the 4/0 battery cable
                to the battery positive terminal.
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for the alternator is the (-) terminal and circuit 2-G to the crank motor ground
                stud.
            </para>
            <para>For additional information on the operating principles for alternators, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL
                in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
