<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINE, CUMMINS ISM - OPERATION -
        Cruise Control
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise Control</title>
        <para>The cruise control system has three modes of operation: off, standby and active. The off position of the
            on/off switch turns cruise control off. The standby mode occurs when the driver switches the cruise control
            on/off switch (66) to the on position. The driver can then achieve the active mode by toggling the
            set/resume switch (67) after reaching the desired road speed.
        </para>
        <para>Once the system is active, the driver can accelerate beyond the set speed by depressing the accelerator
            pedal. When the pedal is released, cruise control is reactivated when the vehicle speed reaches the
            previously set speed.
        </para>
        <para>Cruise is deactivated, and returns to the standby mode in several ways: the brake or clutch pedal is
            depressed, or the vehicle speed (mph) drops below 30 mph.
        </para>
        <para>The resume switch can be used to reactivate cruise at the previous set speed, or the set switch can be
            used to establish a new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the coast feature is used to decrease vehicle speed and establish a new lower
            set speed. By holding select switch in the coast position, vehicle speed decreases until the switch is
            released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the accelerate feature is used to increase the vehicle speed and establish a new
            higher speed. By holding the select switch in the ACCEL position, vehicle speed increases until the switch
            is released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control switches are used as PTO or idle adjustment controls when the vehicle road speed is not
            present (this is a customer selected parameter). The cruise set/resume switch (67) is also used during
            on-board diagnostics [when the diagnostic switch (83)] is in the on position] to move through the diagnostic
            fault code list. Refer to the operators manual furnished with the vehicle for specific cruise control
            operating instructions.
        </para>
        <para>When the vehicle is not moving and the cruise on/off switch (66) is off, the engine idle speed can be
            adjusted by the set/resume switch (67) in increments of 25 rpm by toggling the switch. Maximum idle speed is
            800 rpm and minimum idle speed is 550 rpm.
        </para>
        <para>When the vehicle is not moving and the cruise on/off switch (66) is on, the PTO speed can be adjusted with
            the set/resume switch (67).
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control on/off switch (66) receives a ground signal on circuits 97-GC and 97-GA, through
            connector (3), on circuit 97-GA from (1091). In the on position, a ground signal is sent from the switch on
            circuit 97AE, connector (3) and circuit 97AE to ECM connector (1091) terminal 23. This indicates to the ECM
            that the cruise control switch is in the on position. In the off position, circuit 97AE returns to its 12
            volt value, indicating to the ECM that the switch is off.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise set/resume switch (67) is a momentary switch. This switch receives a ground signal on circuits
            97-GB, through connector (3) on circuit 97-GA, from (1091). The cruise selector switch sends a ground signal
            from the switch on circuit 97AB, connector (3) and circuit 97AB to the ECM connector (1091) terminal 14
            while in the set/accel position. In the resume/coast position, the switch sends a ground signal by way of
            circuit 97AA, connector (3) and circuit 97AA to the ECM connector (1091) terminal 24.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_117.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_119.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
