<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - BE 200, CE 200, CE 300 Model - MULTIPLEXING (DATA LINKS)</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="s0829052" division="truck" date="12/14/2004">
        <title>MULTIPLEXING (DATA LINKS)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The electrical system on the BE 200, CE 200/300 Bus has been significantly redesigned. Unlike the
                electrical systems on previous models, which utilized point to point wiring for all input signals and
                output loads, this system uses multiplexed wiring technologies to provide control and communication
                between major functional areas of the bus. Multiplexing simply means, communicating information through
                a small number of wires (called a data link) without requiring a wire for each piece of information.
                This information could be gauge information such as engine oil pressure, or switch information that
                controls bus functions such as headlamps. The electrical system relies on a collection of electronic
                circuit modules and software to perform bus functions instead of implementing similar features using
                complex wire harness designs with electromechanical relays and switches. These electronic module
                components are connected together by electronic data links. These data links can be thought of as
                computer networks that allow the electronic components on the bus to communicate with one another.
            </para>
            <para>The concept of multiplexing is not new to IC Corporation. Data links for communicating between engine
                controllers, the instrument cluster and the diagnostic connector have been used for several years.
            </para>
            <para>The goal of multiplexing is to reduce cab harness wiring and to simplify circuits. This is
                accomplished by using low current data link circuits for communication between cab switches and the
                electrical system controller and the instrument cluster. Other data links in the bus allow other
                electrical controllers and the instrument cluster to communicate with each other.
            </para>
            <para>IC Corporation multiplexing uses two types of data links; J1708 and J1939. The J1708 data link is
                often referred to as ATA and J1939 is often referred to as CAN.
            </para>
            <para>There are three separate data links used on the BE/CE Bus.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Drivetrain 1939 data link - This J1939 data link provides a path for communication between the
                        engine controller, transmission controller, antilock brake system (ABS) controller, pyrometer
                        ammeter module (PAM), electrical system controller (ESC) and the electronic gauge cluster (EGC)
                        or instrument cluster.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Switch data link - This J1708 data link provides a path for communication between the switch
                        packs and ESC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1708 data link - This is the same J1708 data link (sometimes referred to as ATA) that has been
                        used in the past. This data link will be used almost exclusively for diagnostics and programming
                        of engines and other controllers.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The heart of the multiplexed system is the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f08290301">Electrical System Controller</hotlnk>
                (ESC). The ESC communicates with the switches on the switch data link, controllers from other features
                on the drivetrain 1939 data link and remote power modules on the body builder data link. It also
                receives input from various sensors and hard wire inputs throughout the bus. The ESC converts these
                inputs into data to be transmitted on the data links. It is also the power source for circuits that feed
                the components, controlled by the multiplexed switches, inside and outside of the cab.
            </para>
            <figure id="f08290301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08290401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Electrical System Controller (ESC)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>(1600) 36 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1601) BROWN 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1602) 36 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1603) BROWN 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1604) BLUE 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_39.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
