<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - WINDSHIELD WIPERS
        AND WASHERS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WINDSHIELD WIPERS AND WASHERS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electric W/S Wiper and Washer With Int'l Turn Signal Switch (With or Without Intermittent Control)
            </title>
            <para>When key switch (24) is moved to the ignition or accessories position, power is available through
                circuit 12, (J2) accessory feed block, and circuit 12B to circuit breaker F18. From circuit breaker F18,
                power is fed to the wipe/wash module (457) over circuit 82K. the ground path for the module is circuit
                11-GK to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Windshield Washer Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Power is supplied to the coil of wash relay (270) from F18 through circuits 82, 87B, and 87E. Circuit
                87F connects the relay coil to the wipe/wash module (457). When the module switches circuit 87F to
                ground, the wash relay (270) is activated.
            </para>
            <para>When the knob at the end of the turn signal switch lever is pushed in for a couple of seconds, it
                completes a circuit from wipe/wash module conn. (457), through circuit 87, turn signal connector (460),
                through the turn signal switch, back to conn. (460) and circuit 87H to module (457). This tells the
                module to activate the wash relay (270) as described above. With the relay activated, power flows from
                circuit breaker F18, through circuits 82, 87B, wash relay (270) contacts, and circuit 87A to windshield
                washer pump (510) activating it. [Circuit 87C, connector (2), and circuit 87B provide the circuit
                between the wash relay (270) and pump for trucks with air brakes and left side wash bottle.] The ground
                path is circuit 87-G and 11-GE to ground relay panel (11-GK to cab ground for trucks with air brakes).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Windshield Wiper Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Power is supplied to the coil of the low speed relay (272) from circuit breaker F18 through circuits
                82 and 82L. Power is supplied to the coil of the high speed relay (271) from circuit breaker F18 through
                circuits 82, 82A and 82H.
            </para>
            <para>When the wiper switch, which is on the turn signal switch lever, is in the off position, switch
                contacts are closed between the following circuits:
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Without delay wipers</emph>
                - connector (460) pin A to F, and pin B to F.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With delay wipers</emph>- connector (460) pin A to F, pin B to F, and pin C to F.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Broken wires, connector, or switch will cause the wipers to function in a mode other than
                        off.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the wiper switch is rotated to the low speed position, only the following switch contacts are
                closed:
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Without delay wipers</emph>
                - connector (460) pin B to F.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With delay wipers</emph>
                - connector (460 pin A to F.
            </para>
            <para>This causes the wipe/wash module (457) to ground circuit 82M which energizes low speed relay (272).
                With the relay energized, power flows from circuit breaker F18 through circuits 82, 82A, the normally
                closed relay contacts of the high speed relay (271), circuit 82F, the normally open contacts of the low
                speed relay (272), circuit 82D, and connector (29) to the windshield wiper motor low speed winding. The
                ground path is through the case to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the wiper switch is rotated to the high speed position, switch contacts are closed between the
                following circuits:
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Without delay wipers</emph>
                - connector (460) no closed circuits.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">With delay wipers</emph>
                - connector (460) no closed circuits
            </para>
            <para>This causes the wipe/wash module (457) to keep circuit 82M grounded, and ground circuit 82J which
                energizes both high speed relay (271) and low speed relay (272). With relay (271) energized, power flows
                from circuit breaker F18 through circuits 82, 82A, the normally open contacts of high speed relay (271),
                circuit 82C, and connector (29) to the windshield wiper motor high speed winding causing the wipers to
                run at high speed.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the high speed relay is energized, the power to the low speed relay normally open
                        contacts is removed, which cuts power to the low speed winding of the windshield wiper motor.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Moving the windshield wiper switch to the off position causes the wipe/wash module (457) to open the
                ground path to both the low speed relay (272) and the high speed relay (271). If the wipers are not in
                their park location, power will flow from circuit breaker F18, through circuits 82, 82B, connector (29),
                the park switch, connector (29), circuit 82E, the normally closed contacts of the low speed relay (272),
                circuit 82D, connector (29), the low speed windshield wiper motor winding, and the case to ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electric W/S Washer With Air Wipers and Int'l Turn Signal Switch</title>
            <para>When a vehicle is built with the International turn signal switch and air wipers, the same electronic
                module is utilized that would be used to control electric wipers and washers with International turn
                signal switch. Also with the exception of a dash mounted windshield washer switch (34), and circuits 87
                and 87H going to connector (460), all the circuitry used to control the washer with electric wipers is
                the same. Refer to Electric W/S Wiper and Washer With International Turn Signal Switch (With or Without
                Intermittent Control above.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electric W/S Wiper and Washer With Signal-Stat 910/915 Turn Signal Switch (Non-Intermittent)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Wiper Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the ignition or accessory position, power is available to flow through
                circuit 12 to the (J2) accessory feed block. When wiper switch (31) is moved to the low speed position,
                power will flow from (J2), through circuit 12B, circuit breaker F18, circuits 82, 82S, switch (31),
                circuit 82U, connector (29), the green wire, the low speed motor winding and the windshield wiper motor.
                The ground path is through the motor housing to the dash.
            </para>
            <para>When the wiper switch (31) is moved to the high speed position, power flows into the switch, then
                flows out circuit 82T, through connector (29), the red wire, and the high speed motor winding. The
                ground path is through the motor housing to the dash.
            </para>
            <para>When switch (31) is moved to the off position, power will flow through circuit 82B, connector (29),
                the black wire, the park position switch in the motor, the white wire, connector (29), circuit 82V,
                connector (203), circuit 82AB, switch (31), circuit 82U, connector (29), the green wire, and the low
                speed winding until the wipers are in the park position. The ground path is through the motor housing to
                the dash.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Windshield Washer Pump Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (24) is moved to the ignition or accessory position, power is available to flow
                through circuit 12, (J2) accessory feed block, circuit 12B, circuit breaker F18, circuit 82, and circuit
                87K to the washer switch (34).
            </para>
            <para>When switch (34) is moved to the on position, power flows through the switch, through circuits 87P,
                87N, connector (2), and circuit 87B to the windshield washer pump (510). [With Model 4000, the power
                feed from the switch to the motor is circuit 87P and 87M.] The ground path is circuit 11-GK to cab
                ground. [With Model 4000, the ground path is circuit 87-G and 11-GE to ground relay panel.]
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electric W/S Washer W/Air Wipers and Signal-Stat Turn Signal Switch</title>
            <para>When a vehicle is built with the Signal-Stat turn signal switch and air wipers, the same electric
                circuitry is utilized for the washer system that is used for the washer system with electric wipers. See
                Electric W/S Wiper and Washer With Signal-Stat 910/915 Turn Signal Switch (Non-Intermittent) above.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>W/S Wiper and Washer With Intermittent Wiper With Signal-Stat 910/915 Turn Signal Switch</title>
            <para>When the key switch (24) is moved to the ignition or accessory position, power is applied to circuit
                12, (J2) accessory feed block, circuit 12B, and circuit breaker F18.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Washer Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When washer switch (34) contacts are closed, power flows from circuit breaker F18 through circuits 82,
                87K, washer switch (34), circuit 87P, and circuit 87M to the windshield washer pump (510). This
                activates the washer pump. With tractor or truck with air brakes and left mounted washer bottle, power
                flows instead from washer switch (34) through circuit 87P, circuit 87N, connector (2), and circuit 82B
                to windshield washer pump (510).
            </para>
            <para>The ground path is circuit 87-G and 11-GE to cab ground relay bracket. With tractor or truck with air
                brakes and left mounted washer bottle, the ground path is circuit 11-GK to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the intermittent switch is moved and held in its uppermost position, power flows from circuit
                breaker F18, through circuit 87J, connector (52), the washer contacts of the intermittent switch,
                connector (52), circuit 87L and 87M to the windshield washer pump (510).
            </para>
            <para>With tractor or truck with air brakes and left mounted washer bottle, power flows from circuit 87L
                through circuit 87N, connector (2), and circuit 82B to the windshield washer pump (510). This activates
                the washer pump. The ground path is as listed previously. The ground path for the intermittent wiper
                switch is through connector (52), circuits 82-GB, 11-GA, and 11-GF to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Intermittent Wiper Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the intermittent wiper switch is moved from the off position to one of the delay positions, power
                flows from fuse F18, through circuit 87J, and connector (52) to the intermittent switch. The switch will
                then, at preset intervals, output a brief voltage through connector (52), on circuit 82X. This signal
                energizes the intermittent wiper relay (277) by flowing through its coil and the ground path circuit
                82-GA and 11-GE to cab ground relay bracket.
            </para>
            <para>This will start a single sweep of the wipers if the wiper switch (31) is in the off position. When the
                wiper relay (277) is energized, current flows from fuse F18 through circuits 82, 82AA, the intermittent
                relay, circuit 82Y, connector (203), circuit 82W, wiper switch (31), circuit 82U, and connector (29) to
                the windshield wiper motor low speed winding. The ground path is through the case to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>While the wipers are sweeping, the signal from the intermittent wiper switch will drop out, the
                intermittent wiper relay will de-energize, and the park switch contacts will be closed. With the park
                switch contacts closed, power will flow from fuse F18, through circuits 82, 82S, wiper switch (31),
                circuit 82B, connector (29), the park switch, connector (29), circuit 82V, connector (203), circuit 82Z,
                the normally closed contact of the intermittent relay (277), circuit 82Y, 82W, wiper switch (31),
                circuit 82U, and connector (29) to the low speed wiper motor winding.
            </para>
            <para>This will bring the wipers back to the parked position where the contacts of the park switch will open
                up causing the wiper motor to stop.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low and High Speed Wiper Operation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the wiper switch (31) is placed in the low speed position, power flows from fuse F18, through
                circuits 82, 82S, wiper switch (31), circuit 82U, connector (29), and the low speed wiper motor winding.
            </para>
            <para>When the wiper switch (31) is placed in the high speed position, power flows from fuse F18, through
                circuits 82, 82S, wiper switch (31), circuit 82T, connector (29), and the high speed wiper motor
                winding.
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for both settings is through the wiper motor case to cab ground.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
