<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER AND AUXILIARY GAUGE SWITCH PACK - DIAGNOSTICS - ON-LINE
        DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="s0825488" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ON-LINE DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <para>On-line Diagnostics are automatically performed by the ESC while the key is in the accessory or ignition
            position. Any faults encountered will be entered in the active fault list.
        </para>
        <para>On power up the check electrical system light will turn on then off after the gauge sweep. If there is an
            active fault the light will stay on for an extra minute. If a fault occurs during operation of the vehicle
            the light will come on for 1 minute. This will alert the driver that an active fault exists.
        </para>
        <para>If the check electrical system light comes on and stays on after the gauge sweep is completed then the EGC
            is not communicating with the engine controller and/or the ESC.
        </para>
        <para>If the EGC loses communication with the ESC or engine controller during vehicle operation, the check
            electrical system light will turn on and stay on. The light will be accompanied by 10 short beeps from the
            EGC alarm.
        </para>
        <para>Diagnostic trouble codes will be moved to the "previously active" list after the condition creating the
            fault is repaired.
        </para>
        <para>Placing the EGC in diagnostic mode will allow the EGC to display up to 40 active and previously active
            diagnostic messages from the ESC.
        </para>
        <para>To engage the diagnostic mode turn the Ignition key "ON" (or in accessory) then press the Cruise "ON"
            switch and the Cruise "RESUME" switch simultaneously. If no faults are present, the gauge cluster display
            will read "NO FAULT". If faults are present, the gauge cluster will display a message with the number of
            faults followed by the diagnostic codes. Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0825403b">Diagnostic Trouble Code Display</hotlnk>. The display will show each DTC for 10
            seconds then automatically scroll to the next entry and continue to cycle through the faults. To manually
            cycle through the fault list, press the cluster display selector button.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0825403b" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825449.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="432px"/>
            <caption>Diagnostic Trouble Code Display</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BYTE 7 FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>2. BYTE 8 FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SPN FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>4. FMI FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>5. ACTIVE/PREVIOUSLY ACTIVE STATUS INDICATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>6. COMPILED FORMAT OF DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s082503_FC.xml" xrefid="x0826300">Diagnostic Trouble Code List</hotlnk>.
            <xref refid="x0826300"/>
        </para>
        <para>While in the diagnostic mode, diagnostic trouble codes may be cleared by turning the left turn signal on
            and pressing the cruise "ON" switch and the cruise "SET" switch simultaneously. All previously active faults
            will be cleared. Active faults will reappear as the ESC updates faults once a second.
        </para>
        <para>To exit the diagnostic mode, cycle the key switch or release the parking brake.</para>
        <para>The diagnostic service tool, running the INTUNE software, can be used to view diagnostic trouble codes and
            occurrence counts. The tool can also be used to clear previous active ESC diagnostic trouble codes. Other
            diagnostic software can be used to view and clear engine controller, ABS and transmission diagnostic trouble
            codes. Refer to the appropriate software manual for details.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X0825410.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_77.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
