<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS -
        TROUBLESHOOTING - VEHICLE CHARGING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="2">
        <title>VEHICLE CHARGING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Batteries Undercharged</title>
            <para>Before beginning test procedures: check battery cables and alternator wiring (especially grounds) for
                clean, tight connections. Wires and connectors should not be damaged or corroded.
            </para>
            <para>Perform the following checks before removing the alternator from the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Accessories having been left on for an extended time.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check alternator drive belt tension (refer to GROUP 12 - ENGINE, Cooling in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual for belt tension specifications). As a general rule, if the alternator fan can
                    be rotated by pulling on the fan with one finger, the belt is too loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for defective batteries as described in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Battery Section
                    in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wiring defects. Visually check wiring, clamps, and connections for clean, tight
                    connections, free of damage and corrosion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine OFF, check voltage to ground at the BAT terminal of the alternator. A
                    zero reading indicates an open in circuit 2, between the alternator and batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A defective component or wiring defect may be causing a small current drain that is less
                    than the fuse rating for the circuit so the fuse does not open. To locate the unwanted current
                    drain:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Batteries should be fully charged for the following test.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">KEY OFF- Turn all accessories and controls off. Disconnect circuit 2 from the
                        alternator B terminal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To check the entire system for current drains, insert the DMM leads in the COM and
                        10A fused jack on the meter. Set the meter to DC Amps. Connect the meter in series with the
                        alternator (if the meter leads are not connected with correct polarity, a (-) amp reading will
                        be present.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Some current draw will be present. If the current draw is less than 0.3A move the
                        lead from the 10A jack to the 320mA jack to read the exact current flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Refer to the Battery Power Distribution circuit diagrams in CTS-5298 or S08225.
                        Remove the battery feed fuses one at a time, while monitoring the meter for any change in
                        current flow. Note that some circuits (such as clock or radio or engine computer, etc.) should
                        be drawing some current. Look for current draw in circuits that should not be active.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0821308">Alternator Wiring Test.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator Tests</title>
            <para>The alternator output must reach the batteries and accessory loads with a minimum amount of voltage
                loss. Any loss slows the rate of charge to the batteries and can cause the batteries to be undercharged.
                Discharged batteries can damage the starter and cause vehicle electrical components to operate
                improperly.
            </para>
            <para>Most alternators control the maximum system voltage using a voltage regulator. Maximum voltage output
                is available at the alternator BAT terminal, but if any voltage is lost in the wiring, something less
                than the maximum will reach the batteries and load devices. The greatest losses occur when the charging
                system is outputting at the maximum rated level (amps).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0821308">
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0821309">Alternator Wiring Test</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <para>Instead of using alternator current output this test uses the same amount of current but draws it from
                the batteries (must be fully charged). Using the carbon pile load, the current flows in reverse through
                the circuit without the engine running.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Without the engine running, connect the carbon pile to the alternator output terminal
                    and ground.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Alternator output is at battery voltage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect voltmeter between alternator output terminal and positive battery terminal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Rated output is stamped on the
                    case or on a tag.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read voltmeter and record positive circuit voltage loss. Immediately turn the carbon
                    pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the voltmeter connections to between the alternator, ground and negative battery
                    terminal. Adjust carbon pile to rated output (amps) of the alternator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read voltmeter and record negative circuit voltage loss. Immediately turn carbon pile
                    off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Positive Circuit Loss Voltage (step 4) ________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
                Negative Circuit Loss Voltage (step 6) ________
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
                System Loss ________
            </para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.7V or less</emph>, go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0821309">Alternator Replacement Test</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is greater than 0.7V</emph>, repair circuit(s) with excessive voltage loss and retest.
                Then go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0821309">Alternator Replacement Test.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0821309" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0821309.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Alternator Wiring Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0821309">
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0821310">Alternator Replacement Test</hotlnk>
                - Voltage Output Test
            </title>
            <para>If the wiring tests have been performed (circuits OK), adjust alternator belt and tighten mounting
                bolts and ground connections. Batteries must be near full charge with more than 12.4 volts no load
                voltage.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0821310">Voltage Output Test</hotlnk>
                </title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle at shop temperature, connect voltmeter between alternator "B" (+) and "G"
                    (-) terminals.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With NO electrical loads turned on, start the engine. Fast idle engine until voltage
                    stabilizes (does not increase) for 2 minutes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and record alternator output voltage _______V (should not exceed 15.5 volts).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If voltage reading is above 15.5V, replace the alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0821310" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0821310.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="502px"/>
                <caption>Alternator Replacement Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0821310">Alternator Replacement Test</hotlnk>
                - Amperage Output Test
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle at shop temperature, connect carbon pile and clamp-on ammeter as shown (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0821310">see Figure above</hotlnk>). Clamp around all wires connected to alternator
                    "B" terminal. (To use an ammeter without an induction clamp, disconnect circuits to alternator "B"
                    terminal and connect meter shunt between alternator B+ terminal and all circuits previously
                    removed.)
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not connect an ammeter without a high current shunt.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With NO electrical loads turned on, start the engine, and speed up and maintain a high
                    RPM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on and adjust carbon pile until ammeter reads its highest value and record
                    ______A.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off carbon pile and engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If reading is zero (no output), the rotor should be magnetized with the alternator
                    hooked up normally. To do this,
                    <emph type="bold">momentarily</emph>
                    connect a jumper lead from the alternator "B" terminal to the indicator "R" terminal. This will
                    restore normal residual magnetism.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 2, 3, and 4. If output is still zero, replace alternator.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator Replacement Test - Replacement</title>
            <para>Replace alternator if either of the following exists:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Output voltage exceeded 15.5V.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Output current is not within 10% of the alternator rated output stamped on the alternator.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_91.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_93.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
