<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CAB FEATURES - WINDSHIELD WIPER AND WASHER PUMP - WIPER MOTOR CIRCUITS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x082581104" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>WIPER MOTOR CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection Management</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The testing method for troubleshooting the electrical systems portrayed in this manual is a
                        basic voltage test. An alternative method of checking for voltage drops within a given circuit
                        may be a quicker method of identifying an exact problem.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>A fault in the wiper motor circuits will be apparent when the high or low speed wipers don't work. The
                ESC will log an active diagnostic trouble code when there is a short or open in the wiper power relay R1
                circuits or the wiper high-low relay circuits. Problems in the wiper circuits could be attributed to a
                failed relay, a failed motor, a tripped wiper motor circuit breaker, a short, an open or a problem in
                the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825852">wiper circuits</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825852" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08258b4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="532px"/>
                <caption>Wiper Circuits (Connectors Viewed From Mating End) - Always Refer to the Circuit Diagram Book
                    for Latest Circuit Information
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>R1 (4003) WIPER POWER RELAY
                        <callout2>LOCATED IN ENGINE POWER DISTRIBUTION CENTER</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>R2 (4003) WIPER HIGH-LOW RELAY
                        <callout2>LOCATED IN ENGINE POWER DISTRIBUTION CENTER</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>(4004) 36-WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(4008) 8-WAY BLUE SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(4006) GROUND STUD</callout1>
                    <callout1>(4015) WIPER MOTOR CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <table id="t0825838" tblwidth="pg-wide" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Wiper Motor Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.71in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.88in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.98in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.87in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="1.22in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="3" nameend="6" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Trouble Codes</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>611 14 6 3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>Wiper power, less than normal low current but more than open circuit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>611 14 6 4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>Wiper power, greater than normal high current and less than fusing current</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>611 14 6 6</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>Wiper power has current flow when output commanded off</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>611 14 6 2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>Wiper power over current</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when there is a short to ground or an
                                    excessive load in a circuit connected to the wiper power output of ESC connector
                                    (4008) pin F.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>The virtual fuse in the ESC will trip during a short. To reset the fuse, the
                                        key switch must be cycled.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Disconnecting connectors will cause new open circuit diagnostic trouble codes
                                        to be logged. Clear all diagnostic trouble codes after connections have been
                                        restored.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>Turn off wipers and disconnect wiper motor connector (4015). Cycle key switch and
                                    clear diagnostic trouble code codes. Turn on the high speed wipers. If the
                                    diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a short or an overload in the
                                    wiper motor. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a short in the
                                    circuits to the wiper relays or between the ESC and the wiper motor, or in the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Disconnect blue ESC connector (4008). Cycle key switch and clear diagnostic
                                    trouble code codes. Turn on the high speed wiper and check for diagnostic trouble
                                    codes. If the diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a short in the
                                    circuits between the ESC and the wiper motor. If the diagnostic trouble code
                                    reoccurs, there is a short inside the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Check high speed wiper voltage between harness connector (4015) pin D and C.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>611 14 6 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>Wiper power under current</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when the wipers are turned on and there is
                                    an open in circuits between the high speed wiper motor output of the ESC, through
                                    the motor, and ground.
                                </para>
                                <para>Check for open circuits or tripped wiper motor circuit breaker.</para>
                                <para>Check high speed wiper voltage between harness connector (4015) pin D and C with
                                    high speed wiper switch on.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1" align="center">
                                <para>2033 14 14 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper on relay driver overloaded. Connector 4004 pin 29 current overload. To much
                                    load attached or defective relay.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when there is an overload in the circuits
                                    between wiper power relay R1 and the ESC, an excessive load on the circuit or a high
                                    resistance in the relay coil.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Disconnecting connectors will cause new open circuit diagnostic trouble codes
                                        to be logged. Clear all diagnostic trouble codes after connections have been
                                        restored.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>Remove wiper power relay R1. Clear diagnostic trouble code codes and turn on the
                                    high speed wipers. If the diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a short
                                    or an overload in the relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a
                                    short in the circuits between the relay socket and the ESC, or in the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Disconnect ESC connector (4004), and clear diagnostic trouble codes. Turn on the
                                    high speed wiper and check for diagnostic trouble codes. If the diagnostic trouble
                                    code doesn't reoccur, there is an overload in the circuits between the ESC and the
                                    relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is an overload inside the ESC.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1" align="center">
                                <para>2033 14 14 2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper on relay driver circuit open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>Connector 4004 Pin 29 open. Open circuit or defective relay.</para>
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when wipers are turned on and there is an
                                    open in circuits between ESC connector (4004) pin 29, through the wiper power relay,
                                    and ground.
                                </para>
                                <para>Check for open circuits or open relay coil.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>2033 14 14 3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper on relay driver circuit shorted. Connector 4004 pin 29 shorted to ground.
                                    short circuit or defective relay.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when there is a short in the circuits
                                    between wiper power relay R1 and the ESC, an excessive load on the circuit or a
                                    short in the relay coil.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Disconnecting connectors will cause new open circuit diagnostic trouble codes
                                        to be logged. Clear all diagnostic trouble codes after connections have been
                                        restored.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>Remove wiper power Relay R1. Clear diagnostic trouble code codes and turn on the
                                    high speed wipers. If the diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a short
                                    or an overload in the relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a
                                    short in the circuits between the relay socket and the ESC, or in the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Disconnect ESC connector (4004), and clear diagnostic trouble codes. Turn on the
                                    high speed wiper and check for diagnostic trouble codes. If the diagnostic trouble
                                    code doesn't reoccur, there is a short in the circuits between the ESC and the
                                    relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a short inside the ESC.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>2033 14 8 1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper high-low relay driver overloaded. Connector 4004 pin 20 current overload. To
                                    much load attached or defective relay.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when there is an overload in the circuits
                                    between wiper power relay R2 and the ESC, an excessive load on the circuit or a high
                                    resistance in the relay coil.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Disconnecting connectors will cause new open circuit diagnostic trouble codes
                                        to be logged. Clear all diagnostic trouble codes after connections have been
                                        restored.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>Remove high-low relay R2. Clear diagnostic trouble code codes and turn on the high
                                    speed wipers. If the diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a short or an
                                    overload in the relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a short in
                                    the circuits between the relay socket and the ESC, or in the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Disconnect ESC connector (4004), and clear diagnostic trouble codes. Turn on the
                                    high speed wiper and check for diagnostic trouble codes. If the diagnostic trouble
                                    code doesn't reoccur, there is an overload in the circuits between the ESC and the
                                    relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is an overload inside the ESC.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>2033 14 8 2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper high-low relay driver circuit open circuit.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                                <para>Connector 4004 Pin 20 open. Open circuit or defective relay.</para>
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when high wipers are turned on and there is
                                    an open in circuits between ESC connector (4004) pin 20, through the wiper power
                                    relay, and ground.
                                </para>
                                <para>Check for open circuits or open relay coil.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>2033 14 8 3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                                <para>Wiper high-low relay driver circuit shorted. Connector 4004 pin 20 shorted to
                                    ground, short circuit or defective relay.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>This diagnostic trouble code is logged when there is a short in the circuits
                                    between wiper high-low relay R2 and the ESC, an excessive load on the circuit or a
                                    short in the relay coil.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Disconnecting connectors will cause new open circuit diagnostic trouble codes
                                        to be logged. Clear all diagnostic trouble codes after connections have been
                                        restored.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>Remove wiper high-low relay R2. Clear diagnostic trouble code codes and turn on
                                    the high speed wipers. If the diagnostic trouble code doesn't reoccur, there is a
                                    short or an overload in the relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is
                                    a short in the circuits between the relay socket and the ESC, or in the ESC.
                                </para>
                                <para>Disconnect ESC connector (4004), and clear diagnostic trouble codes. Turn on the
                                    high speed wiper and check for diagnostic trouble codes. If the diagnostic trouble
                                    code doesn't reoccur, there is a short in the circuits between the ESC and the
                                    relay. If the diagnostic trouble code reoccurs, there is a short inside the ESC.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="t08258381" tblwidth="pg-wide" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Wiper Motor Voltage Checks</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.64in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.92in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.94in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.87in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="1.26in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="3" nameend="6" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="4" nameend="6" spanname="S4T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="2" nameend="3" spanname="S2T3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" valign="bottom">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Wiper Motor Harness Connector (4015) Voltage Checks</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>Check with ignition on and (4015) disconnected.</para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Always use breakout box ZTSE 4477 to take measurements on ESC connectors.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>(4015) Harness connector, pin A to ground</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <note>
                                    <para>A load device, such as a test light, must be used in parallel with voltmeter
                                        probes to read an accurate voltage.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is missing, check for short or open in circuit J82B or J82F. If
                                    circuits check good check for voltage from ESC connector (4008) pin F.
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>A load device, such as a test light, must be used in parallel with voltmeter
                                        probes to read an accurate voltage from pin F.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <para>If voltage is missing consider replacing ESC.</para>
                                <para>
                                    <hotlnk document="s082503_X0825310A.xml" xrefid="x0825310a">Refer to ESC Replacement
                                        in this manual.
                                        <xref refid="x0825310a"/>
                                    </hotlnk>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>(4015) Harness connector, pin A to pin C.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is missing, check for open in circuits J82-G or J11-GJ to ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>With wiper switch in low selection (4015) Harness connector, pin E to ground
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>With low speed wiper switch on, 12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                                <para>With low speed wiper switch off and wipers parked, 0 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is incorrect, check for open or short in circuit J82L and perform wiper
                                    relay R1 and R2 circuit checks.
                                </para>
                                <para>If circuit and relays check good, verify voltage out of ESC.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>(4015) Harness connector, pin D to ground</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>With high speed wiper switch on, 12 &#177; 1.5 volts</para>
                                <para>With low speed wiper switch off, 0 volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is incorrect, check for open or short in circuit J82H and perform wiper
                                    relay R1 and R2 circuit checks.
                                </para>
                                <para>If circuit and relays check good, verify voltage out of ESC.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>When the key is on the ESC will supply battery voltage to blue connector (4008) pin F. This voltage is
                applied to wiper motor connector (4015) cavity A, wiper power relay R1 pins 4 and 5, and wiper high-low
                relay R2.
            </para>
            <para>When high or low wipers are selected the ESC will supply a ground from system controller connector
                (4004) terminal 29 to wiper power relay 94003) R1 terminal 2. This will energize the wiper power relay
                and apply 12 volts to the common contact of wiper high-low relay (4003) R2.
            </para>
            <para>When low speed wipers are selected the wiper high-low relay will remain de-energized and the voltage
                at the common contact will pass through the normally closed contact to the low speed wiper motor
                windings.
            </para>
            <para>When high speed wipers are selected the wiper high-low relay will energize and the voltage at the
                common contact will pass through the normally open contact to the high speed wiper motor windings.
            </para>
            <para>Ground for the wiper motor is supplied from ground stud 2 (4006) to wiper motor connector (4015)
                terminal C.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X082581103.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X082581105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
