<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - 3300 Model - INTRODUCTION - VEHICLE ELECTRICAL SYSTEM OVERVIEW
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VEHICLE ELECTRICAL SYSTEM OVERVIEW</title>
        <para>The electrical system in this vehicle provides a means to distribute electrical power and provides the
            driver with controls and indications of the vehicle performance. Unlike previous electrical system designs,
            this approach uses multiplexed wiring technologies for interfacing major functional areas of the vehicle.
            Furthermore, the system relies on software algorithms to accomplish logic functions instead of implementing
            similar features using complex wire harness designs with relays and switches.
        </para>
        <para>A natural benefit of this system is increased diagnostic capability in terms on line, off line and off
            board testing.
        </para>
        <para>On-line diagnostics are performed on the vehicle while it is in operation. If a detectable fault occurs,
            the check electrical system lamp will illuminate for 5 seconds. If a communication failure between the ESC
            and EGC occurs, the lamp will stay illuminated until communications are restored.
        </para>
        <para>Off-line diagnostics are enabled when the system is put in diagnostic mode. While the system is in the
            diagnostic mode, diagnostic trouble codes will be displayed on the odometer.
        </para>
        <para>Off-board diagnostics require the use of an electronic service tool, such as the EZ-Tech&#174;, and the
            Diamond Logic Builder&#8482; diagnostic software. The EST is connected to the vehicle diagnostic connector.
            The Diamond Logic Builder&#8482; software will allow the technician to view diagnostic trouble codes,
            monitor inputs to the ESC and activate outputs from the ESC.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_S0829850.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
