<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - HYDRAULIC (HYDRO-MAX II) BRAKE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x082597">
        <title>HYDRAULIC (HYDRO-MAX II) BRAKE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f0825972" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825961.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Hydraulic (Hydro-Max) Brake Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DIFFERENTIAL PRESSURE SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FLOW SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HYDROMAX PUMP RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HYDROMAX PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HYDROMAX BRAKE MODULE
                        <callout2>LOCATED BEHIND INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825972">Hydraulic (Hydro-Max) Brake Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The Bendix Hydromax hydraulic brake booster is standard on all vehicles with hydraulic brakes. It
                powers a split system which protects against total brake failure by using separate fluid lines to feed
                the front and rear axle brakes. The master cylinder provides fluid pressurized by the power steering
                pump and the Hydro-Max II booster to activate the brake pads against the discs. It is a dual mode system
                which will automatically provide reduced back-up brake power, from an electric/hydraulic pump, should
                there be a loss of power steering pump pressure. The electric/hydraulic pump also provides brake power
                when the engine is not running.
            </para>
            <para>The Hydromax system is a supplementary backup for hydraulic brake systems. It is meant to be active
                when there is a problem with the power steering system that normally provides the brake pressure. The
                electrical system controller provides battery voltage to the Hydromax pump relay coil when the key is
                on. It will also provide battery voltage to the relay coil when the key is off and the brake pedal is
                engaged. The relay is energized when a ground is applied to the other side of the coil when the flow
                switch closes (loss of power steering fluid flow) or the differential pressure switch closes (pressure
                difference in master cylinder). The ESC also monitors a digital signal from the Hydromax module and will
                send a request to turn on the warning light and buzzer to the electronic gauge cluster as required.
            </para>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the flow switch will close, cause the pump relay to energize, and
                start the reserve pump. The monitor module is fed a signal from the flow switch, causing the monitor to
                request the ESC to turn on the brake pressure warning light.
            </para>
            <para>The reserve pump and brake warning light are also activated when the differential pressure switch
                (4032) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>The module continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump motor and power supplied to it. A
                signal path, circuit J90HA, a minifuse, circuit J90H, pass through connector (4014) and circuit A90N to
                brake monitor module connector (1400) pin G provides information to the module. The module will request
                activation of the alarm and warning light under the following conditions:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The ignition is on and flow switch is not open. (It is normal for alarm and lamp to activate
                        when key is in ignition position and engine is not running.)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the pump motor winding opens up.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the Hydro-Max II pump relay (4033) remains closed (provides power to circuit J90F and the
                        reserve pump motor) after the engine is running, and the flow switch opens.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If no power is supplied to the pump motor when the flow switch or differential pressure switch
                        contacts are closed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When the brake monitor module has sensed the pump has been activated or a failure has occurred it will
                provide a ground from (1400) pin F to system controller connector (1600) pin 9. The ESC will communicate
                a message on the drivetrain data link to the EGC instructing it to turn on the brake pressure warning
                lamp.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_356.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_358.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
