<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER AND AUXILIARY GAUGE SWITCH PACK - TROUBLESHOOTING -
        CHECK ELECTRICAL SYSTEM WARNING LAMP
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x0825408" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CHECK ELECTRICAL SYSTEM WARNING LAMP</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Circuit Function</title>
            <figure id="f0825405a" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825409.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Check Electrical System Warning Lamp Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER (ESC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVE TRAIN 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER (EGC)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825405a">check electrical system warning lamp</hotlnk>
                will light and stay on any time the EGC loses communication with the ESC or power to ESC connector
                (4009) or (4010). The lamp will also light if communication from the engine controller is lost. The
                gauges controlled by the ESC will go to zero if communication between the EGC and ESC is lost. The
                gauges controlled by the engine controller will go to zero if communication between the EGC and engine
                controller is lost.
            </para>
            <para>The check electrical system warning lamp should light during the EGC gauge sweep, after the key is
                turned to the ignition position. If the lamp doesn't light during the gauge sweep the lamp could be
                burned out or there may be a problem in the EGC.
            </para>
            <para>The check electrical system warning lamp should come on for 1 minute when a fault is detected by the
                ESC.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection/Management</title>
            <para>If the stays on continuously and none of the gauges are working correctly after the gauge sweep, the
                EGC is not communicating on the Drivetrain 1939 Data Link or there is a problem with the data link.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s082504_X082523.xml" xrefid="x082523">Drivetrain 1939 Data Link.</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x082523"/>
            </para>
            <para>If the lamp stays on continuously when no active faults are present or doesn't come on when active
                faults are present, the problem may be in ESC/EGC programming or ESC/EGC hardware.
            </para>
            <para>The service tool (EZ-Tech) running the "INTUNE" diagnostic software can be used to turn all warning
                lamps on and off. The service tool can also be used to verify if the problem is limited to the ESC, EGC
                or the data link.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_X08254107.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_X08254091.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
