<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - BE 200, CE 200, CE 300 Model - BODY FEATURES - Windshield Wipers
        And Washer Pump - CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Circuit Functions</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f08290927">Washer and Wiper function diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f08290927" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08290927.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Washer and Wiper Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WIPER MOTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TURN SIGNAL WASHER/WIPER CONTROL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. WASHER BOTTLE (WITH WASHER PUMP MOTOR)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Windshield wiper functions Include, low wipers, high wipers, intermittent wipers, wiper park,
                windshield washer and washer fluid level.
            </para>
            <para>The wiper switches are direct inputs to the ESC (not multiplexed). The switches determine the speeds
                controlled by the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>The ESC provides battery voltage on a 20 amp circuit to the wiper motor park circuits and two wiper
                control relays.
            </para>
            <para>The wiper power relay switches control of the wiper motor from park circuit control to ESC circuit
                control.
            </para>
            <para>While the ignition is on, the windshield washer will always come on when the washer switch is
                activated. The washer pump is directly connected to the washer switch and is not controlled by the ESC.
                There is also an input from the washer switch to the ESC. If the windshield washer is requested and the
                current wiper speed is not high, the wipers shall be set to low speed and stay in low speed for a set
                amount of time after the request. If the windshield washer is requested and the current wiper speed is
                high, the wipers speed will remain high.
            </para>
            <para>The windshield wipers have eight speeds: off, high, low, and five different intermittent speeds. These
                are determined by the condition of the three wiper switches in the turn signal assembly.
            </para>
            <para>When the wipers are turned off, while the ignition is on, the wipers will automatically park. The
                wiper park circuits also control the cycle of the intermittent wiper sweep.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_X08290129.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_205.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
