<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Two Speed
        Axle Wiring With Manual or Non-Electronic Automatic Transmission
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Two Speed Axle Wiring With Manual or Non-Electronic Automatic Transmission</title>
        <para>When the key switch (24) is placed in the ignition or accessory position, power is applied to circuit 12,
            accessory feed block (J2), circuit 12A, fuse F14. From the fuse, power is applied to circuit 93, connector
            (14), and circuit M1BLUE to the two speed axle switch (55) for manual transmission or switch (75) with
            automatic transmissions.
        </para>
        <para>When the switch is in the LOW position, power is applied to circuit M1BROWN, connector (59) and circuit
            M1BROWN with manual transmission, connector (14), and circuit 93A to the engine Electronic Control Module
            (ECM). This causes the ECM to adjust the signal being sent to the speedometer and odometer in order to show
            the correct speed and mileage for the gear ratio change.
        </para>
        <para>With an electric shift motor, power at connector (14) and circuit 93B is applied to circuit 93B,
            dash/chassis connector (13), and a brown wire to the electric shift motor (703). This causes the axle to be
            in the LOW range.
        </para>
        <para>When equipped with an air shift solenoid (263), power is not available at the solenoid and the two speed
            axle will be in LOW range.
        </para>
        <para>When the switch is moved to the HIGH position, power is applied to circuit M1RED, connector (59) and
            circuit M1RED with manual transmissions, connector 14, circuit 93C, dash/chassis connector (13), and a red
            wire to the axle shift solenoid or the electric shift motor. This causes the axle to be shifted to the HIGH
            range.
        </para>
        <para>With the selector switch in the HIGH position, power is removed on circuit 93A to the engine ECM. This
            causes the ECM to adjust the signal being sent to the speedometer and odometer in order to show the correct
            speed and mileage for the gear ratio change.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_199.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_201.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
