<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS - ELECTRONIC COMPONENTS - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATA Data Link and Diagnostic/ Programming Connector</title>
            <para>The 9-pin ATA data link connector (384) supplies power for an Electronic Service Tool (EST) through
                fuse F6 and circuit 97C. Ground for the EST is through 97-GK to cab ground (2G).
            </para>
            <para>The EST is able to communicate with the engine control system through a twisted pair of wire circuits.
                The connector serial data transmission lines are through circuit 98B(+)/98E(+) and circuit 98D(-)/98F(-)
                to the instrument cluster (27). Communication with the ECM2 or IDM2 is through circuit 98B(+)/98A(+) and
                circuit 98D(-)/98C(-) to the 48-pin dash connector (3). From the dash connector (3), the communication
                circuits are 98AB(+)/98A(+) to ECM2 connector (6021) pin 20 and 98CB(-)/98C(-) to pin 21, and circuits
                are 98AB(+)/98AA(+) to IDM2 connector (6011) pin 2 and 98CB(-)/98CA(-) to pin 3.
            </para>
            <para>The communication system also includes an ATA interface connector (374) for use with aftermarket
                requirements. The communication link for the interface is through circuits 98B(+)/98H(+) and
                98D(-)/98G(-).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Device Powering</title>
            <para>Uninterrupted battery power is supplied to power stud (1DVA) through circuit 14D, 20A maxifuse (413),
                circuit 14C, engine harness connector (411) and circuit 14J to the 22-pin dash connector (2). From (2),
                power is applied to circuit 14J and the power stud.
            </para>
            <para>The ground stud (2DVA) ground path is through circuit 11-GC to the 22-pin dash connector (2). From
                (2), the path is through circuit 11-GC, engine harness connector (409) and circuit 11-GB to the battery
                ground post.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Power and Ground</title>
            <para>Power is supplied by the batteries to circuit 14A, a 50A maxifuse (408), circuit 14B, engine harness
                to positive battery cable connector (411), circuit 14B/97JA to the ECM power relay (590B) coil and
                circuit 14B/97HB, fuse (F39), circuit 97HA to contacts. Also, power is supplied through circuit 14B/97LB
                to the IDM power relay (590A) coil and circuit 97TC to contacts.
            </para>
            <para>From the ECM power relay (590B) coil, power is applied to circuit 97J and pin 5 of the ECM2 (6020).
                Also, from the IDM2 power relay (590A) coil, power is applied to circuit 97LA and pin 8 of the IDM2
                (6011).
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to the ignition position, power is supplied through fuse F12, circuit
                97CR, the 48-pin dash connector (3), and circuit 97CR and a splice. From the splice power is applied to
                pin 3 of the ECM2 (6020) on circuit 97UA . This signals the ECM2 that the ignition switch is on and
                causes the ECM2 to internally switch pin 5 to ground. This completes the circuit for the ECM power relay
                (590B) which energizes the relay. With the relay (590B) energized, power is applied through the closed
                contacts to circuit 97TA and a splice. From the splice power is applied to the ECM2 (6021) pins 1 and 2
                on circuits 97CL and 97CK respectively, and to the IDM2 (6011) pin 10 on circuit 97AL.
            </para>
            <para>Also, when key switch (63) is moved to the ignition position, power is supplied through fuse F12,
                circuit 97CR, the 48-pin dash connector (3), and circuit 97CR and a splice. From the splice power is
                applied to pin 9 of the IDM2 (6011) on circuit 97UB . This signals the IDM2 that the ignition switch is
                on and causes the IDM2 to internally switch pin 9 to ground. This completes the circuit for the IDM
                power relay (590A) which energizes the relay. With the relay (590A) energized, power is applied through
                the closed contacts to circuit 97TA and a splice. From the splice power is applied to the IDM2 (6011)
                pin 12 on circuit 97Y, and the IDM2 (6011) pin 6 on circuit 97LD, fuse (F40) and circuit 97LC.
            </para>
            <para>Grounds for the ECM2 (6020) pins 6 and 7 are through circuits 97-GW and 97-GV respectively, to a
                splice. From the splice, ground is through circuit 11-G, the engine harness to negative battery cable
                harness connector (409) and circuit 11-GA to the negative battery terminal. Also, grounds for the IDM2
                (6011) pin 1 is through circuit 97-GA to a splice. From the splice, ground is through circuit 11-G, the
                engine harness to negative battery cable harness connector (409) and circuit 11-GA to the negative
                battery terminal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>
            <para>The engine Electronic Control Module (ECM2) determines the position of the accelerator pedal by
                processing the input signals from the Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch
                (IVS).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM2 sends a regulated 5 volt signal through the ECM2 connector (6021), circuit 99C, dash
                connector (3), circuit 99C to a splice, and circuit 99J to the APS/IVS (382). The APS then returns a
                variable voltage signal (depending on pedal position) through connector (382), circuit 99B, connector
                (3), and circuit 99B to the ECM2. The APS is grounded through circuit 99A/97W, connector (3), and
                circuit 97W/97WB to the ECM2 signal ground.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM2 learns the lowest and highest pedal positions by reading and storing the minimum and the
                maximum voltage levels from the APS. In this manner the ECM2 "auto-calibrates" the system to allow
                maximum pedal sensitivity.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM2 auto-calibrates as the key is on, but when the key is turned off, these values are lost. When
                the key is turned on again, this process starts over. When the pedal is disconnected (or a new one is
                installed), the pedal does not need to be calibrated, as the calibration happens when the key is turned
                on.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the on or start position, the Idle Validation Switch (IVS) (382)
                receives 12 volt ignition voltage through circuit breaker F10, and circuit 99E. When the pedal is not in
                the idle position (throttle applied), the IVS sends this 12 volt signal to the ECM over circuit 99D,
                connector (3), and circuit 99D to the ECM2 (6021).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM2 compares the inputs it receives on circuit 99B and circuit 99D from the APS/IVS to verify
                when the pedal is in the idle position. If the APS signal from circuit 99B indicates throttle is being
                applied, then the ECM2 expects to see 12 volts at IVS circuit 99D. If the APS signal, circuit 99B,
                indicates throttle is not applied, then the ECM2 expects to see 0 volts at the IVS circuit 99D. The
                timing process is critical between the APS and the IVS sensors. For this reason, it is very difficult to
                determine if the APS/IVS assembly is working properly using a volt-ohmmeter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Barometric Air Pressure (BAP) Sensor</title>
            <para>The ECM2 (6021) sends a regulated 5 volt signal from ECM2 (6021) through circuit 99C, dash connector
                (3), circuit 99C to a splice, and circuit 97BL to BAP sensor (437). The BAP sensor returns a variable
                voltage signal (represents atmospheric pressure) on circuit 97CD, connector (3) and circuit 97CD to the
                ECM2 (6020). The BAP sensor is grounded by circuit 97Z/97W, connector (3), circuit 97W/97WB to the ECM2
                (6021) signal ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Temperature Sensor (ATS)</title>
            <para>The IDM2 (6011) sends a regulated 5 volt reference signal through circuit 97AX to the Air Temperature
                Sensor (463). As the temperature changes, the sensor changes resistance and provides the IDM2 (6011)
                with an air temperature signal voltage. The sensor is grounded through circuit 97BU/97WB to the ECM2
                (6021) signal ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control/Remote Engine Controls</title>
            <para>When key switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is supplied through circuit 13C to
                the ignition relay (4G). The relay is grounded through circuits 13-G/11-GB to cab ground. This energizes
                the relay (4G) and switches battery power from circuit breaker F31, circuits 15/15C, dash connector (2),
                circuits 15C/15D, through the closed relay contacts and circuit 13A to circuit breaker F13. From the
                circuit breaker, power is supplied through circuit 97B to the brake/cruise interface relay (1133). The
                brake/cruise interface relay (1133) is grounded through circuits 97-GJ/11-GA to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link circuit through circuits 90-FL/90/90B, dash connector (2),
                circuit 90B, circuit breaker F21 and circuit 97DK to the brake/cruise interface relay (1133) contacts.
                Power is supplied to the cruise control On/Off switch (391) through the closed relay contacts and
                circuit 97DJ. When the switch is in the On position, power flows through the closed switch contacts and
                circuit 97CF to the MSM (3041). The MSM (3041) received the On position of the cruise control On/Off
                switch and is communicated&#160;to the ECM2.
            </para>
            <para>The cruise control Set/Resume switch (392) to be operational, with the cruise control On/Off switch
                (391) in the On position and power is applied from the switch to the cruise Set/Resume switch (392)
                through circuit 97DH. Momentarily depressing the Set portion of this switch supplies a 12 volt signal to
                the MSM (3041) through circuits 97DH/97CA and is communicated&#160;to the ECM2. This engages the cruise
                control and causes the ECM2 to maintain the current engine RPM. If the cruise control speed is already
                set, depressing the switch in the Set position causes the engine RPM to decrease until the switch is
                released.
            </para>
            <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch (391) in the On position, depressing the Resume portion of the
                Set/Resume switch (392) supplies a 0 volt ground signal to the MSM (3041) through circuits 97-GE/97-GL
                to cab ground and is communicated&#160;to the ECM2. If the cruise control speed has not been engaged,
                momentarily depressing the switch causes the ECM2 to resume the last engine RPM setting.
            </para>
            <para>If the cruise control is already engaged, momentarily depressing the resume portion of the switch will
                cause the engine RPM and speed to increase in small incremental amounts until the desired speed is
                reached.
            </para>
            <para>Engine control circuits are also provided for remote, preset and variable speed switches and a remote
                accelerator pedal for completion by the body builder when remote engine controls are required. When the
                key switch is on, power is supplied through circuit breaker F11, circuit 97K, dash connector (3) and
                circuit 97DF to the body builder switch connections (N/L), located at the cowl power distribution
                center. The ECM2 (6020) signal circuits 46A, 46B, 47B, 97AR, 97CC and 97CB can also be found at this
                location.
            </para>
            <para>For information on remote engine controls for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous
                Information in CT-471 Body Builder Book.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
