<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - HEATER AND AIR CONDITIONER - OPERATION -
        Blower-Cab
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Blower-Cab</title>
        <para>Power is supplied to (B2) battery stud, circuits 14H, 14Z, fuse F1-C and circuit 75A to the main control
            relay (463-R5). When the ignition switch is on, power is applied to circuit 62P of HVAC control connector
            (1057). When the HVAC control is not in the OFF position, 12 volts is applied to the coil of main control
            relay (463-R5). The ground path for the main control relay is circuits 13-GT, 77-G, 58-GA and 11-G to right
            dash panel ground stud. This energizes the main control relay (463-R5) and allows power to flow through the
            relay contacts and circuit 75B to blower control switch (1056).
        </para>
        <para>When the blower control switch (1056) is moved to the low position, there is no input from the switch to
            resistor block (27). Power from main control relay (463-R5) will be applied through circuit 75BL, 75C,
            connector (162), 75C to resistor block (27) terminal C. Power from the resistor block will be applied
            through circuit 75T, connector (161), circuit 75T, high speed relay (462-R2) N.C. contacts, circuit 75F,
            connector (161) and circuit 75F to the blower motor. This causes the blower motor to run at low speed. The
            blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G, connector (161), circuits 75-G and 75-GL to connector
            (1057) of the HVAC control module. Power flows through these circuits when the blower switch is in any
            position other than HIGH, as long as the middle knob of the HVAC control module is not in the OFF position.
        </para>
        <para>When the blower control switch (1056) is moved to the medium low position, power will flow through the
            switch, circuit 75BH, connector (161), circuit 75M to resistor block (27) terminal A. Power from the
            resistor block, terminal B, will be applied through circuit 75T, connector (161), circuit 75T, high speed
            relay (462-R2) N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (161) and circuit 75F to the blower motor. This causes
            the blower motor to run at medium low speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G, connector
            (161), circuits 75-G and 75-GL to connector (1057) of the HVAC control module.
        </para>
        <para>When the blower control switch (1056) is moved to the medium high position, power will flow through the
            switch on circuit 75N to the coil of medium high speed relay (462-R3). This energizes the medium high speed
            relay (462-R3) which is grounded through circuits 75-GC, 50-GB and 11-G to the right dash panel ground stud.
            Power from main control relay (462-R2), on circuit 75BL and 75D, will be applied to heater box pigtail
            connector (1060) on circuit 75M. Power will be applied to the resistor block from connector (1060) on
            circuit75BH. Power from the resistor block will be applied through circuit 75T, connector (161), circuit
            75T, high speed relay (462-R2) N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (161) and circuit 75F to the blower
            motor. This causes the blower motor to run at medium high speed. The blower motor ground path is through
            circuit 75-G, connector (161), circuits 75-G and 75-GL to connector (1057) of the HVAC control module.
        </para>
        <para>When the blower control switch (1056) is moved to the high position, power will flow through the switch on
            circuit 75H to the high speed relay (462-R2). This energizes the high speed relay (462-R2) which is grounded
            through circuits 75-GB, 75-GC, 50-GB and 11-G to the right dash panel ground stud. This allows power to flow
            from (B2) battery stud through circuits 14H, 14X, fuse F1-A, circuit 75, high speed relay (462-R2) N.O.
            contacts, circuit 75F, connector (161), and circuit 75F to the blower motor. This causes the blower to run
            at high speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G, connector (161), circuits 75-G and
            75-GL to connector (1057) of the HVAC control module.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_366.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_368.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
