<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3600, 3800, 4000FBC - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Dryer (Bendix AD-9)</title>
            <para>The function of the air dryer is to collect moisture and contaminants before air reaches the first
                reservoir, thus providing moisture-free air for the air brake system. The heater in the air dryer
                prevents freeze-up in the purge drain valve during cold weather.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allison (Non Electronic) Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>With the Allison electrically controlled transmission, only the shift modulator valve is controlled by
                the engine computer. A neutral position switch is also provided to prevent the truck from being started
                in drive gear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Bendix Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake booster is offered on all hydraulic brake models. It powers a
                split system which protects against brake failure by using separate fluid lines to feed the front and
                rear axle brakes. The master cylinder provides fluid pressurized by the power steering pump and the
                Hydro-Max II booster to activate the brake pads against the disc or drums. It is a dual mode system
                which will automatically provide back-up brake power, from an electric/hydraulic pump, should there be a
                loss of power steering pump pressure.
            </para>
            <para>A warning light and alarm, which can indicate various hydraulic and electrical malfunctions, are
                standard.
            </para>
            <para>A hydraulic brake/stop light switch assembly signals the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM) and
                energizes the stop lights. The ECM uses this signal to control the PTO, cruise control, compression
                brake, vehicle retarder, cold ambient protection and idle shutdown timer systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Drain Valve</title>
            <para>The function of the automatic drain valve is to automatically expel accumulated moisture from the air
                tank. The heater in the drain valve prevents freeze-up in the purge drain valve during cold weather
                operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter With Water-in-Fuel Light, Fuel Filter Restriction Light</title>
            <para>The fuel filter heater is mounted in the fuel filter and when operating, it helps prevent fuel from
                gelling in the unfiltered side of the filter. The system consists of a fuel heater relay, the filter
                heating element, and a normally open thermoswitch. The switch contacts close at approximately 50&#176;F.
            </para>
            <para>The water-in-fuel system consists of a control module, a water probe, and a warning light in the dash
                cluster. When water is present in the fuel filter, increased current will flow from the probe to ground.
                The module senses this increase and turns on the warning light. The system also conducts a bulb check
                when the key switch is in the start position to verify the light operates.
            </para>
            <para>The fuel filter restriction light is activated when the fuel filter becomes restricted. This causes
                the fuel filter vacuum switch contacts to close and activates the light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two Speed Axle Wiring With Manual or Non-Electronic Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>A two speed rear axle is used when deep gear reduction and higher speeds are required. The axle is
                shifted with an air cylinder or electric motor depending on option. The two speed axle wiring provides a
                voltage signal to the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM), so the speedometer and odometer will
                correctly measure speed and mileage when the rear axle assembly is shifted to a different gear ratio.
            </para>
            <para>The command to change ranges is given by the driver when he moves a switch on the gear shift lever
                (manual transmission) or the switch on the instrument panel (with non-electronic Allison transmission).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
