<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION - Stop, Tail, Turn and
        Hazard Signal Lights With Flasher
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Stop, Tail, Turn and Hazard Signal Lights With Flasher</title>
        <para>When the brakes are applied, stoplight switch (640) closes and power flows from (B2) battery stud through
            circuits 14H and 14E to fuse F3-B. From the fuse, power flows through circuit 70, stoplight switch, and
            circuit 70A, to turn signal switch and circuit 70D to stoplight relay (464)/R10.
        </para>
        <para>This energizes the stoplight relay through ground path circuits 70-G, 56-G, 57-G, and 11-G to ground stud
            at right dash panel. This allows power to flow from (B1) battery stud through circuits 14K, and 14F to fuse
            F7-D. From the fuse, power flows through circuit 70E, stoplight relay (464)/R10 and circuit 70C to the
            trailer socket.
        </para>
        <para>From the turn signal switch power flows through circuit 56B to bright element of the left rear stop, tail,
            and turn light, and the four wheel trailer connection. Power also flows from the turn signal switch on
            circuit 57B to bright element of the right rear stop, tail, and turn light, and the four wheel trailer
            connection. Circuit 11-GV is the ground path for the left and right rear stop, tail, and turn light.
        </para>
        <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the left turn position, power flows from (B1) battery stud through
            circuits 14K, 14R, fuse F2-D, and circuit 55 to the flasher unit. From the flasher unit power flows through
            circuit 55A, and the turn signal switch.
        </para>
        <para>From the turn signal switch power flows through circuit 56D to the left side turn light, and 56E to the
            left turn relay (464)/R11. The left turn relay is energized through ground path circuits 56-G, 57-G, and
            11-G to ground stud at right dash panel. Power also flows from the turn signal switch through circuit 56B to
            the four wheel trailer connection and the bright element of the left rear stop, tail, and turn light.
            Circuit 11-GV is the ground path for the left rear stop, tail, and turn light.
        </para>
        <para>With the left turn relay energized, power flows from (B1) battery stud through circuits 14K, 14L, fuse
            F7-B, and circuit 56H to the left turn relay. Power then flows through circuit 56C to the trailer socket,
            and circuits 56A and 56R to the left turn indicator. The ground path is circuit 62-GD and 11-GF to ground
            stud left dash panel.
        </para>
        <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the right turn position, power flows from the turn signal switch,
            through circuit 57D to the right side turn light, and circuit 57E to the right turn relay (464)/R12. The
            right turn relay is energized through ground path circuits 57-G, and 11-G to ground stud at right dash
            panel. Power also flows from the turn signal switch through circuit 57B to the four wheel trailer connection
            and the bright element of the right rear stop, tail, and turn light. Circuits 11-GV and 11-GV make up the
            ground path for the right rear stop, tail, and turn light.
        </para>
        <para>With the right turn relay energized power flows from (B1) battery stud through circuits 14K, 14L, fuse
            F7-C, and circuit 57H to the right turn relay. Power then flows through circuit 57C to the trailer socket,
            and circuits 57A and 57R to the right turn indicator. The ground path is circuits 62-GD and 11-GF to ground
            stud left dash panel.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_302.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_304.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
