<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - 3300 Model - ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER - DIAGNOSTICS - GAUGE
        SWEEP
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x08298016" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GAUGE SWEEP</title>
        <para>After the ignition is turned on, a gauge sweep of the EGC will be performed. Each gauge must sweep from
            zero to maximum to zero in unison. All of the gauge warning lights will illuminate along with the panel
            warning lights that are applicable to features installed on the vehicle. The yellow and red "ENGINE" warning
            lamps should also illuminate (they are turned on by the engine controller not the gauge cluster test). The
            alarms associated with each gauge warning light do not sound. All of the segments of the EGC LCD should
            display while the gauges sweep. At the end of the sweep the LCD will turn off all segments for .5 seconds,
            display the firmware version number, then return to operational mode. The lights controlled by the panel
            dimmer in the EGC will also come on during the gauge sweep.
        </para>
        <para>A gauge that points between the 9 and 10 o'clock position is most likely connected to the wrong location
            on the circuit board inside the EGC.
        </para>
        <para>If the instrument cluster or any of the remote modules experience a system fault, they will transmit a
            fault message to the ESC.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_71.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_S08298003.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
