<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - CUMMINS ISM AND AHD ENGINE SYSTEM -
        TROUBLESHOOTING - Performing A Diagnostic Check With The Engine Off
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Performing A Diagnostic Check With The Engine Off</title>
        <para>A diagnostic check may be performed using the Diagnostic On/Off switch and Cruise Set/Resume. Any error
            codes will be flashed through the red Engine Stop Light and yellow Engine Warning Light. If no errors are
            found, both lights will stay on while the diagnostics switch is on. Consult the Cummins Operation and
            Maintenance Manual furnished with the vehicle for exact procedures and fault code information.
        </para>
        <para>To determine the fault codes use the following procedure:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Begin the procedure with the engine off.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the switch key in the off position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the diagnostic On/Off switch to the on position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the key switch to run position (not crank).</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Cummins CM570 engine diagnostics must be run with the engine NOT RUNNING.</para>
                <para>If BOTH
                    <emph type="boldundersc">Yellow Engine Warning</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="boldundersc">Red Engine Stop</emph>
                    lights come ON and stay ON, it is an indication that no engine faults are present.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>If BOTH the yellow Engine Warning and red Engine Stop lights come on momentarily and then go out, it is an
            indication that engine faults are present.
        </para>
        <para>If BOTH the yellow Engine Warning and red Engine Stop lights come on and stay on, it is an indication that
            no engine faults are present.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Yellow
                <emph type="bold">Engine Warning</emph>
                light will flash once.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">There will be a one to two second pause.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Red
                <emph type="bold">Engine Stop</emph>
                will flash code with one or two seconds between digits.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Yellow
                <emph type="bold">Engine Warning</emph>
                light will flash indicating the end of that fault code, and then start over and repeat the same fault
                code.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To go to the second fault code, move the Set/Resume switch to the Inc. position and then
                release it. The process will then repeat itself as indicated in steps 5 through 8.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To move back to the last or previous fault code, move the Set/Resume switch to the Dec
                position and then release it. The process will then repeat itself as indicated in steps 5 through 8.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To stop the diagnostics procedure, correct the faults or move the diagnostic On/Off switch
                to the off, and turn the vehicle key switch to the off position.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_216.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_218.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
