<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - REMOTE POWER MODULE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0825914">
        <title>REMOTE POWER MODULE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259e1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08259E1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Remote Power Module Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REMOTE POWER MODULE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BODY BUILDER DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH PACK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The Remote Power Module (RPM) is used to provide power to electrical features, outside the cab,
                without running individual wires from each switch to the feature. This module is used to distribute and
                control power to various devices on the vehicle from switches inside the cab. The RPM communicates with
                the electronic system controller over the Body Builder J1939 data link.
            </para>
            <para>RPM outputs are protected by field effect transistors (FET). If an overload occurs on the circuit the
                FET will act like a type 3 circuit breaker. To reset the FET the feature must be commanded off then back
                on again.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The virtual fuse (FET) in the RPM will trip during a short on the output circuits. Cycling the
                        assigned control switch will reset the fuse.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0825946" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825946.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Connectors</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 23-WAY SIGNAL CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 8-WAY DEVICE POWER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MODULE POWER FEED (DIRECT FROM BATTERY OR STARTER STUD)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. INPUT DATA LINK AND POWER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. OUTPUT DATA LINK AND POWER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Each module receives power from a 4 gauge cable, protected by a fusible link, connected to the battery
                stud of the starter motor. Each RPM has the ability to operate up to 6 devices of 20 amps or less not to
                exceed 80 amps for the entire module.
            </para>
            <para>A maximum of 3 RPM's may be connected to the vehicle, which allows a total of 18 devices to be
                controlled as long as the 80 amps per module is not exceeded.
            </para>
            <para>Each RPM comes with a six pack of switches that is inserted into the center section of the instrument
                panel. Each switch controls 1 output of the RPM. The switch mapping is one to one with the RPM; i.e.,
                switch one controls output channel one on the RPM. The switch pack is connected to the switch data link
                that communicates switch operation to the Electronic System Controller. The ESC communicates that
                operation to the RPM.
            </para>
            <para>Each switch pack has six or twelve rocker switches. Each momentary rocker switch is stable in the
                center position. The upper section of each switch has an indicator light to provide the status of each
                power output channel. Pressing the upper section of the switch will latch the respective power output
                channel on and illuminate the indicator. Pressing the lower section of the switch will latch the power
                output channel off and turn the indicator off.
            </para>
            <para>The RPM also has inputs on the module itself that can be wired to control the outputs. The output
                channels may be controlled remotely by using a three position momentary single pole, double throw switch
                on each remote switch input. In this case, battery volts should be connected to one pole of the switch
                and ground should be connected to the other. Applying battery volts to the remote switch input shall
                turn the output channel "ON". Applying ground to the remote switch input shall turn the output channel
                off.
            </para>
            <para>The lamp indicator on the instrument panel switch will always display the current status of the output
                channel as long as the ignition key is in the "RUN" or "ACCESSORY" position.
            </para>
            <para>The Remote Power Module is an optional feature that provides switched electrical loads on the chassis,
                up to 20 amps per load and 80 amps, maximum, per module (Several Remote Power Modules, as well as 7-pack
                air solenoids and a remote engine speed controller pack may be chained together). These loads can be
                switched using a switch pack in the cab or by using tri-state switches connected directly to the Remote
                Power Module. Virtual fuses protect the circuits of the Remote Power Module from current overload. These
                virtual fuses may be rated up to 20 amps.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The virtual fuse in the RPM will trip during a short. To reset the fuse, the switch
                        controlling the feature must be cycled off then back on.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Remote Power Module communicates with the Electrical System Controller (ESC) via the body builder
                data link. The Remote Power Module switches provided in the cab are 3-position, center stable. These
                switches are windowed to allow user to assign switch names as desired. Pressing a switch up will result
                in the corresponding Remote Power Module output to be switched on. Pressing a switch down will result in
                the corresponding Remote Power Module output to be switched off. When the switch is in the stable state
                (center), the present state of the output will be maintained. The tri-state inputs at the Remote Power
                Module may be optionally used to control the outputs of the Remote Power Module. If a conflict exists
                between the cab control and the Remote Power Module tri-state inputs, where neither switch is in the
                center stable position, the Remote Power Module output will be switched off. The indicator in the
                switch-pack will illuminate when the corresponding Remote Power Module output is switched on and no
                errors are detected. If the Remote Power Module detects an over current situation, then the switch
                indicator will flash quickly
            </para>
            <para>The normal operation of this feature is defined as follows:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the ignition is turned on, all outputs will be turned off unless a programmable
                    parameter specifies that a particular output be turned on with the ignition. These outputs will be
                    on during engine-crank.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The switch status from the panel-mounted switches and Remote Power Module tri-state
                    inputs will be polled to determine if an output should be turned on or off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The status of errors will then be considered. If a panel-mounted switch error is
                    present, the given output will be turned off. If an over current situation is detected, the output
                    request will remain on, but the indicator on the panel-mounted switches will flash quickly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The resulting command will be sent to the Remote Power Module via the body builder data
                    link.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The remote power module software feature will send an "off command" to any output of the
                    physical Remote Power Module when there is a conflict between the respective tri-state input
                    switches from the Remote Power Module and the respective panel-mounted switches of the ESC.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Likewise, the outputs of the Remote Power Module will be commanded to the off position, when a Switch
                Data Link error and body builder data link error is detected. If a Switch Data Link error occurs, the
                switches will be ignored. If a body builder data link error occurs, the tri-state inputs will be
                ignored. The outputs will also be turned off when the ignition has been turned off. If an output is
                latched on by the either switch being in the ON position, the output will immediately be turned back on.
            </para>
            <para>The remote power module software feature will attempt to turn off the outputs of the Remote Power
                Module by commanding them off if an error is detected on the Switch Data Link or body builder data link.
            </para>
            <para>In an over current state, the indicator on the panel-mounted switches will flash while the condition
                exists. A diagnostic trouble code will also be set while the over current condition exists.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X08259F.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_418.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
