<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, DT-466E, I-530E AND T-444E
        - Description - Cruise Control/PTO System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise Control/PTO System</title>
        <para>The Cruise/PTO system feature controls engine and vehicle speed using automotive style set/coast,
            resume/accel, on/off switches and is controlled by the ECM. Speed control is disabled when the off switch is
            depressed, the brake is applied, the clutch pedal is depressed or an automatic transmission is placed in
            neutral.
        </para>
        <para>The clutch pedal switch supplies the Driveline Disengaged Signal (DDS) to the ECM and the service brake
            switches supply a Brake Normally Open (BNO) and Brake Normally Closed (BNC) signal to the ECM. These signals
            indicate pedal positions and are used by the ECM in operating the Cruise/PTO control system.
        </para>
        <para>The Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) and the Camshaft Position sensor (CMP) provide vehicle speed and engine RPM
            signals to the ECM. This information is also used by the ECM to control the Cruise/PTO system.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control switches and circuitry are also used for in-cab control of preset, variable, and mobile
            PTO operation applications and require programming of the engine ECM.
        </para>
        <para>For information on remote PTO control for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous Information in
            CT-471 Body Builder Book.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_175.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_177.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
