<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - RE 200/RE 300 ELECTRONIC ENGINES -
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATA Data Link and Diagnostic/ Programming Connector</title>
            <para>A diagnostic/programming ATA data link connector allows an Electronic Service Tool (EST) to
                communicate with the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM2), the Injector Driver Module (IDM2) and the
                Multiplexed Signal Module (MSM). The data communication link carries serial data transmissions between
                the ECM2 and the electronic service tool and is used to transmit calibration, programming and diagnostic
                information. The data link provides communication capabilities for:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Engine parameter data transmission</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics and troubleshooting</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Customer programming of vehicle parameters</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Production line programming of vehicle features</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Field programming.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM2 Power and Ground</title>
            <para>The engine Electronic Control Module 2 (ECM2) monitors and controls engine performance to ensure
                maximum performance and adherence to emission standards. The ECM2 also monitors and controls vehicle
                features such as cruise control and starter engagement. The module is provided with 12 volt operating
                power through a relay when the key switch is in the ignition position. The circuitry is protected by a
                50 amp fuse that is part of the battery cable assembly. Control module ground is to the negative post of
                the batteries.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>APS/IVS</title>
            <para>The Accelerator Pedal Position Sensor (APS) is a potentiometer type sensor which, when supplied with a
                5 volt reference signal from the Electronic Control Module 2 (ECM2), provides a linear analog voltage
                signal that indicates the driver's demand for power. The APS signal is used in calculating desired fuel
                quantity and injector timing.
            </para>
            <para>The Idle Validation Switch (IVS) is a 0/12 volt switch that provides the ECM2 with a redundant signal
                to verify when the pedal is in the idle position.
            </para>
            <para>These two functions are integrated into one component mounted on the accelerator pedal. The pedal
                assembly is serviceable to the extent that the APS/IVS can be replaced without replacing the complete
                pedal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BAP</title>
            <para>The Barometric Air Pressure sensor (BAP) is a variable capacitance sensor, that when supplied with a 5
                volt reference signal from the ECM2, produces a linear analog voltage signal that varies with altitude.
                The BAP signal is used by the ECM2 to adjust timing and fuel quantity, to optimize engine operation and
                control smoke throughout all altitude conditions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATS</title>
            <para>The ambient Air Temperature Sensor (ATS) is a thermistor type sensor that has a variable resistance
                which changes when exposed to different temperatures. The ECM2 and IDM2 measures the signal from the
                sensor and uses the data to adjust timing and fuel rate to limit smoke emissions in cold weather
                starting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control/Remote Engine Controls</title>
            <para>The cruise control system controls engine and vehicle speed using automotive style on/off and
                set/resume switches. Speed control is disabled when the off switch is depressed, the brake is applied,
                the clutch pedal is depressed or an automatic transmission is placed in neutral.
            </para>
            <para>The clutch pedal switch supplies the Driveline Disengaged Signal (DDS) to the ECM2 and the brake
                switches also supply input signals to the ECM2. These signals indicate pedal positions and are used by
                the ECM2 in operating the cruise control system.
            </para>
            <para>The Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) and the Camshaft Position sensor (CMP) provide vehicle speed and engine
                RPM signals to the ECM2. This information is also used by the ECM2 to control the system.
            </para>
            <para>Circuity for remote engine speed controls are provided for use by a body builder. For information on
                remote engine controls for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous Information in CT-471 Body
                Builder Book.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_69.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_71.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
