<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - FE 300 GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS -
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Coolant Temperature Gauge</title>
            <para>The engine water temperature gauge is driven by the ECM2 through the ATA data-link circuits.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Oil Temperature Gauge</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is to circuit A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuit A28/A28A, the yellow instrument cluster
                connector (10), pin 1 to the transmission oil temperature gauge. The transmission temperature is sensed
                by the transmission temperature sending unit (38). The sending unit feeds an electrical voltage through
                pin A of connector (38), circuit K31, pin F of connector (2) and circuit A31, pin 17 of the yellow
                instrument cluster connector (10) to the transmission oil temperature gauge, which displays the
                transmission oil temperature. The transmission temperature sending unit (38) pin B is grounded through
                circuits K31-G/K11-GJ to the (J10) engine ground. The transmission oil temperature gauge is grounded
                through pin 6 of connector (10) circuits A28-GA/A11-GB/A11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Level Gauge</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is to circuit A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuit A28/A28B, the green instrument cluster
                (11), pin 10 to the fuel gauge. The level of fuel in the vehicle fuel tank is sensed by the fuel sending
                unit (37). The sending unit feeds an electrical voltage through circuit K36, pin A of connector (37),
                circuit K36, pin D of connector (2) and circuit A36, pin 3 of connector (11) to the fuel gauge, which
                displays the fuel level. The fuel sender (37) pin B is grounded through circuits K36-G/K11-GJ to the
                (J10) engine ground. The fuel gauge is grounded through pin 2 of connector (11) circuits
                A28-G/A11-GB/A11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltmeter Gauge</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is measured by the engine ECM2, converted to a data signal, and transferred over
                the data link to the instrument cluster's microprocessor. This signal is transferred over the data link
                on circuits A98E(+) and A98F(-) to pins 7 and 9 of connector (11), into the instrument cluster. The
                instrument cluster's processor then drives the voltmeter display gauge.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tachometer Gauge and Speedometer Gauge</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the Tachometer and Speedometer
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Oil Pressure/High Water Temperature/Low Coolant Level Lights and Alarm</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the warning light and alarm
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake Low Fluid and Parking Brake Warning System</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is turned to the on position, power is supplied to the low brake fluid
                warning system through circuit A28A, to a splice, circuit A90R, the low level fluid warning light (89),
                circuit A90V, to a splice, circuit A90P, connector (84), circuit A90P, connector (88), and circuit A90P
                to the normally open sensor switch (90). When a low brake fluid level is encountered, the sensor switch
                closes and the circuit is ground through the switch, circuits A11-GF and A11-GE to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is turned to the start position, a momentary ground is applied through the key
                switch, circuit A90X, diode connector assembly (82) and circuit A90W to the previously mentioned splice.
                This causes the warning light to come on as a bulb check and go off when the key is released from the
                start position.
            </para>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C
                and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8. When the parking brake is applied,
                power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17, circuits A44A and K44A, the park
                brake switch (218), and circuits K44-G and K11-GD to start motor ground. This will cause the park brake
                warning light to illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is applied. The lamp will also illuminate
                when the key switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied through circuit A44, a
                brake diode (82), and circuit A90X, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
            <para>When the key is turned to the start position, a ground is applied to the circuitry through the
                ignition switch, circuits A44B and A44, connector (2), and circuit A44 to circuit A44B at the park brake
                switch. This causes the warning light to come on as a bulb check and go off when the key is released
                from the start position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Air Pressure Warning System</title>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C
                and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8. When the parking brake is applied,
                power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17, circuits A44 to the park brake
                switch (218), and circuits A44GA to platform ground. This will cause the park brake warning light to
                illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is applied. The lamp will also illuminate when the key
                switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied through circuit A44GB, a brake diode
                (64), and circuit A44, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is turned on, power is applied to circuit A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuit
                A28/A28A, connector (10), the instrument cluster printed circuit board, the brake warning light, the
                circuit board, connector (10), circuit A40A, and to the fast mode side of alarm (211).
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle is started and the air pressure is below 60 psi, the air pressure switch (717) is
                closed and provides a ground path for the alarm and warning light through circuit A40, connector (2),
                circuit K40, and through the closed air pressure switch (717) which is grounded through its mounting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic/Programming Connector and Self-Test Switch and Warning Light System</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the Diagnostic/Programming
                Connector and Self-Test Switch and Warning Light System.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wait-to-Start Warning Light</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for a description of the warning light system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
