<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000FE POWER DISTRIBUTION AND GROUNDS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Battery Power Distribution (Key Off)</title>
            <para>Power is supplied from the vehicle batteries to the cranking motor solenoid terminal "B" over a 4/0
                red cable. From the "B" terminal, power is supplied over circuits 90-FL and 90 to the hydraulic brake
                system pump control relay (85) and over circuits 90-FL, 90A and 90B to the hydraulic brake switch (209).
            </para>
            <para>From the "B" terminal, power is also supplied on circuits 14A, and 14 to the (J2) battery feed stud.
                Splices along these circuits also supply power to the alternator on circuit 2, to the start relay switch
                (122) on circuit 17B, and to the ammeter over circuit 26A, and circuit 26 and 26A.
            </para>
            <para>From the (J2) feed stud, power is fed on circuit 14 to a splice, which directs the power to the power
                distribution center fuse panel on circuit 14A, which supplies the horn, stop lights and turn signals;
                circuit 14C, which supplies the headlights; circuit 19, which supplies the key switch and the heated
                fuel filter and water-in-fuel systems; and circuit 14B which supplies the ECM power relay and diagnostic
                connector.
            </para>
            <para>Power is also supplied from the (J2) feed stud to the daytime running light system on circuit 66F and
                to the antilock brake system on circuit 94.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Power Distribution (Key Switch - Accessory)</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the accessory position, power is supplied over circuit 12 to the power
                distribution fuse panel to supply the daytime running lights, the air dryer, the drain valve and the
                body builder connector (170) circuits.
            </para>
            <para>From the key switch, power is also supplied to the Delco 21-SI alternator "I" terminal or to the
                Leece-Neville 105 amp, slow speed alternator ignition terminal, over circuit 1.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Power Distribution (Key Switch - Ignition or Start)</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the ignition position, power is supplied over circuit 13E to the body builder
                connector (169); circuits 13 and 13A to the fuel heater relay; circuits 13 and 13F to the instrument
                panel cluster; circuits 13 and 13H to the backup light switch, warning alarm, auto transmission and
                ether start systems; and 13 and 13C to the radiator shutters. Power is also supplied to the same
                circuits as listed under the (Key Switch - Accessory) heading above.
            </para>
            <para>With the key switch in the start position, power is supplied to the same circuits as in the ignition
                position, with the exception of circuits 1 and 12. Power is also supplied to the start interrupt (N/L),
                neutral position switch (N/L) and the start relay (387).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Grounds and Junction Points</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0826901">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0826902">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0826901" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0826901.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Ground Distribution Tables</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0826902" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0826902.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Ground Distribution Tables (Cont.)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
