<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - CUMMINS ISM ENGINE - OPERATION - Cummins ISM Cruise
        Control
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cummins ISM Cruise Control</title>
        <para>The cruise control switches are used as PTO controls when the vehicle road speed is not present (this is a
            customer selected parameter). Refer to the operators manual furnished with the vehicle for specific cruise
            control operating instructions.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control system has three modes of operation: off, standby and active. The off position of the
            on/off switch turns cruise control off. The standby mode occurs when the driver switches the cruise control
            on/off switch to the on position. The driver can then achieve the active mode by toggling the set/resume
            switch after reaching the desired road speed.
        </para>
        <para>Once the system is active, the driver can accelerate beyond the set speed by depressing the accelerator
            pedal. When the pedal is released, cruise control is reactivated when the vehicle speed reaches the
            previously set speed.
        </para>
        <para>Cruise is deactivated, and returns to the standby mode in several ways: the brake or clutch pedal is
            depressed, the engine speed (rpm) drops below 1000 rpm, or the vehicle speed (mph) drops below 30 mph.
        </para>
        <para>The resume switch can be used to reactivate cruise at the previous set speed, or the set switch can be
            used to establish a new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the coast feature is used to decrease vehicle speed and establish a new lower
            set speed. By holding select switch in the coast position, vehicle speed decreases until the switch is
            released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>While in the active mode, the accelerate feature is used to increase the vehicle speed and establish a new
            higher speed. By holding the select switch in the accel position, vehicle speed increases until the switch
            is released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted cruise control on/off switch (419) receives a ground signal on circuits 97-GC and 97-GA,
            through connector (262) on circuit 97-GA from (955). In the on position, a ground signal is sent from the
            switch on circuit 97AE, connector (262), and circuit 97AE to ECM connector (955) terminal 23. This indicates
            to the ECM that the cruise control switch is in the on position. In the off position, circuit 97AE returns
            to its 12 volt value, indicating to the ECM that the switch is off.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted cruise set/resume switch (418) is a momentary switch. This switch receives a ground signal on
            circuits 97-GB, through connector (262) on circuit 97-GA from (955). The cruise selector switch sends a
            ground signal from the switch on circuit 97AB, connector (262), and circuit 97AB to the ECM connector (955)
            terminal 14 while in the set/accel position. In the resume/coast position, the switch sends a ground signal
            by way of circuit 97AA, connector (262), and circuit 97AA to the ECM connector (955) terminal 24.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise set/resume switch also adjusts the low engine idle speed, PTO settings and is used during
            on-board diagnostics (when the diagnostic switch is in the on position) to move through the diagnostic fault
            code list.
        </para>
        <para>The engine idle speed can be adjusted by the switch in increments of 25 rpm by toggling the switch.
            Maximum idle speed is 800 rpm and minimum idle speed is 550 rpm. When the idle has been changed and the key
            turned off, the new setting is saved in memory. This feature is owner selected and can be turned off with an
            electronic service tool.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_126.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_128.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
