<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Hydraulic
        Brake System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
        <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the flow
            is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module is fed a signal from the flow switch, causing the monitor
            to turn on a brake warning light and start the hydraulic reserve pump to provide additional brake power. The
            reserve pump and brake warning light are also activated when the differential pressure switch (301) is
            tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
        </para>
        <para>When key switch (24) is in the ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuit 13, fuse F3,
            circuit 90U, connector (47) and blocking diode assembly (48). From blocking diode assembly (48), power is
            supplied to circuit 90H, connector (2), circuit 90H, hydraulic brake relay (300) and to circuit 90F and the
            brake monitor module (49). The brake monitor module (49) is grounded through circuit 90-G/11-G/11-GL to cab
            ground stud (2G).
        </para>
        <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link 90-FL, circuits 90, 90A and hydraulic brake relay (300). Power is
            also supplied from 90-FL to circuit 90/90B, conn. (2), fuse F33, circuit 90C, and hydraulic brake switch
            (50).
        </para>
        <para>When the key switch (24) is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch contacts will be
            closed (engine is not running) and a ground path is provided from the switch over circuit 90L and 90K to a
            splice. From the splice, a ground path is provided over circuit 90M, connector (2), and circuit 90M to the
            brake monitor module alarm input (49-A). This causes the module to switch the alarm output (49-C) to ground
            which activates the alarm and warning light. From the splice, a ground circuit is also provided by way of
            circuit 90J to the hydraulic brake relay (300), causing it to energize. With the relay energized, power
            flows through its N.C. contacts, and circuit 90N to the reserve pump motor. This causes the reserve pump
            motor, which is grounded through its case, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
        </para>
        <para>A signal path, circuit 90P, connector (2) and circuit 90P to brake monitor module connector (49-F)
            provides information to the module. The module continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump
            motor and power supplied to it, and activates the alarm and warning light under the following conditions:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>If the pump motor winding opens up.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the hydraulic brake relay (300) remains closed (provides power to circuit 90N and the reserve
                    pump motor) after the engine is running, and the flow switch opens up.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If no power is supplied to the pump motor when the flow switch or differential pressure switch
                    contacts are closed.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (49-C) to ground, the brake warning light
            illuminates by power flowing to the lamp feed connector (28) through the light, connector (26), and circuit
            90T to the module at connector (49-C).
        </para>
        <para>The alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the alarm, and circuit 90S
            to the module at connector (49-C).
        </para>
        <para>If ignition key is in the off position and the truck brakes are applied, the contacts of hydraulic brake
            switch (50) close. With the contacts closed, power flows through circuit 90D, connector (47), blocking diode
            assembly (48), connector (47) and circuit 90F to feed the brake monitor module at connector (49-E). At the
            same time a power signal is fed from switch (50) to circuit 90D, 90E, and the brake monitor module (49-G).
            This signal is compared to a signal provided from stop light switch (51) and circuit 70C/90R to the brake
            monitor module (49-H). If there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits 90E or 90R for longer than 14
            &#177; 5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
        </para>
        <para>When the brakes are applied, the hydraulic brake switch (50) also applies voltage to circuit 97M,
            connector (3) and circuit 97M to the ECM. At the same time, the stop light switch (51) applies voltage to
            the ECM through circuit 70C/97N, connector (3) and circuit 97N as a redundant signal. This signals the ECM
            that the brakes are applied.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_200.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
