<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000RE LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the start or ignition position, power is applied to circuit
                13/13H, fuse F24, circuit 71, dash connector (2), circuit 71, chassis/engine harness connector (196),
                circuit 71, back-up light switch connector (41) and a black wire to the back-up light switch. When the
                back-up light switch contacts close, power flows through a white wire, connector (41), circuit 71A,
                chassis/engine harness connector (196), circuit 71A, connector (2), and circuit 71A to the body builder
                connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System With Tilt Column and Douglas Turn Signal</title>
            <para>Power flows from the (1F) battery feed stud through circuit 14D/14C to fuse F14 and F15. When the
                headlight switch is in the PARK or on position, power flows through fuse F14, circuit 50A, to the
                headlight switch (23). This supplies power for the parking lights through circuit 58, and body builder
                connector (169), cavity H. Power is also applied to the panel lights through circuit 62.
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight switch is in the on position, power flows through fuse F15, circuit 50, headlight
                switch (23), circuit 51, connector (4), a green wire, and to the dimmer switch.
            </para>
            <para>With the dimmer switch in the low position, power flows through the low beam switch contacts, a blue
                wire, connector (4), and circuit 53/53B to the body builder connector (170), cavity C.
            </para>
            <para>With the dimmer switch in the high position, power flows through the high beam switch contacts, a
                brown wire, connector (4), and circuit 52/52B to the body builder connector (170), cavity D. At the same
                time, power is also applied to the high beam dash indicator light through circuit 52A and the green
                cluster connector (11). Ground for the light is through circuit 28-G/11-GB/11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System With Stationary Column and International Turn Signal</title>
            <para>When the headlight dimmer switch is in the low beam position, and the headlight switch (23) is moved
                to the headlight on position, power flows from body builder feed stud (1F) through circuit 50, the
                closed headlight switch contacts, and circuit 66/51A to the lift-to-dim relay (100) contacts, and
                circuit 51F to the relay coil. Power flows through the coil of relay (100) and through circuit 51D to
                the turn signal headlight dimmer switch connector (6). Power flows through the switch contacts,
                connector (6), and circuit 51-G/11-GB/11-G to the platform ground. This energizes relay (100) and allows
                power to flow through circuit 53A/53B to the body builder connector (170).
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight dimmer switch is moved to the high beam position, the switch contacts open and the
                ground path to relay (100) is removed, which de-energizes the relay. Power then flows through circuit
                52C/52B to the body builder connector (170).
            </para>
            <para>When the high beams are energized, power also flows from the 52C/52B splice through circuit 52A,
                cluster connector (11), and the printed circuit board to the high beam indicator lamp. The indicator
                lamp is grounded through the printed circuit board, connector (11) and circuit 28-G/11- GB/11-G to the
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the headlight switch, power is also applied through circuit 50B to the flash-to-pass relay (101)
                contacts and circuit 51C to the relay coil. When the turn signal lever is pushed forward and held in the
                flash-to-pass position, power flows through the coil of relay (101), circuit 51E, connector (6), dimmer
                switch contacts, connector (6), and circuit 51-G/11-GB/ 11-G to the platform ground. This energizes
                relay (101) and allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuit 52D/52B to the body builder
                connector (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Air Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the battery feed stud (1F), power is applied to circuit 14D/14A, fuse F12, and circuit 70 to stop
                light switch (79). At the same time power is also applied through circuit 70B to stop light switch (78).
            </para>
            <para>When the brake pedal is depressed, the stop light switch contacts close and power is applied to
                circuits 70C and 70A to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is in the park or on position, power is applied through circuit 62,
                fuse F21, circuit 62A, and connector (22) to the panel light dimmer control. The dimmer control ground
                is through connector (22), and circuit 62-GD/11-G to the platform ground. The dimmer control provides an
                adjustable voltage of 0 to 12 volts to the panel light junction (8) through circuit 62H.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is applied through circuit 62C and dash cluster connector
                (11) to the center cluster lights. The lights are grounded through connector (11) and circuit 62-GB/11-G
                to the platform ground. Power is also applied through circuit 62D and dash cluster connector (12) to the
                right cluster lights. The lights are grounded through connector (12) and circuit 62-GC/11-G to the
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the transmission shift lever indicator
                light (7) through circuit 62E. The light ground is through circuit 62-GE/ 11-GB/11-G to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the cruise switch panel light (150)
                through circuit 62L. The light ground is through circuit 62-GF/11-G to the platform ground. Power is
                also provided to the body builder connector (169) through circuit 62J.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Turn Signals</title>
            <para>Power for the turn signal circuitry is supplied by the (1F) feed stud through circuit 14D/14A, fuse
                F13, and circuit 55 to the flasher unit (1). Power is then supplied through circuit 55A/60, turn signal
                jumper harness connector (13), and circuit 55A/60 to the turn signal switch (62) [turn signal switch
                (95) with tilt steering column].
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal is moved to the left turn position, the switch contacts close and power is
                applied to the jumper harness circuit 56, jumper connector (13), and circuit 56 to a splice. From the
                splice, power is supplied to the body builder connector (169) on circuit 56C. From the splice, power is
                also applied through circuit 56B, the green dash cluster connector (11), and a printed circuit board to
                the left turn indicator light. The light is grounded through the printed circuit, connector (11), and
                circuit 28-G/11-GB/11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the turn signal switch, power is also supplied to the body builder connector (170) through the
                jumper harness circuit 56A, jumper connector (13), and circuit 56A.
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal is moved to the right turn position, the switch contacts close and power is
                applied to the jumper harness circuit 57, jumper connector (13), and circuit 57 to a splice. From the
                splice, power is supplied to the body builder connector (169) on circuit 57C. From the splice, power is
                also applied through circuit 57B, the green dash cluster connector (11), and a printed circuit board to
                the right turn indicator light. The light is grounded through the printed circuit, connector (11), and
                circuit 28-G/11-GB/11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the turn signal switch, power is also supplied to the body builder connector (170) through the
                jumper harness circuit 57A, jumper connector (13), and circuit 57A.
            </para>
            <para>When the hazard button is pushed, switch contacts close and power is applied to all of the previously
                discussed feed circuits. This causes the indicator lights to flash and any lights connected to the turn
                signal circuitry in the body builder connectors (169) and (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Daytime Running Lights (DRL)</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to USA DRL module (165) from (J2) junction block, through circuit 66F fuse F5 and
                circuit 66A. The module is provided a ground path through circuit 66-GA to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When high beam/bright headlights are turned ON, a signal is sent to the USA DRL module (165) through
                circuit 66E, connector (224) and circuit 66E. Thus the module which supplies power to the fog light
                circuit 64A can switch OFF the fog lights when the high beam/bright headlights are selected.
            </para>
            <para>The USA DRL module (165) is enabled via circuit 66 when the key switch (20) is moved to the ignition
                or accessories position. The module will then apply power to circuit 66C, connector (224), circuits 66C,
                53, connector (4), circuit 53B to the low beam elements. The module will power the lights at about 60%
                of full power. When the headlight switch is moved to headlight ON position, the power from the headlight
                switch will override the module and power the lamps at 100%.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_50.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_52.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
