<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX II BRAKE MONITOR SYSTEM - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>COMMON PROBLEMS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the hydraulic brake switch (50) or the stop light switch (51) assembly is severely
                    out of adjustment, its contacts will not open up when the brake pedal is released. This will cause
                    the 14&#177;5 second time limit to be exceeded, and the brake warning light and alarm to latch on.
                    This problem is detectable by either the brake lights remaining on due to the adjustment of switch
                    (51), or the Hydro-Max motor continuing to run (when key switch is on and engine is not running) due
                    to the adjustment of switch (50). Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08268_X0826801.xml" xrefid="x0826801">SWITCH ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>, and re-adjust
                    the switch(es).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If either the hydraulic brake switch (50) or the stop light switch (51) is severely out
                    of adjustment, a movement or jarring of the brake pedal may cause one of the switch's contacts to
                    remain closed for longer than the 14&#177;5 second time limit, latching on the brake warning light
                    and alarm. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08268_X0826801.xml" xrefid="x0826801">SWITCH ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>, and re-adjust
                    switch or switches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the master cylinder is allowed to become low on fluid in one of its halves, has a
                    failure in one of its halves, or if air gets into the system, the differential pressure valve spool
                    will move and close the switch contacts. This will activate the motor, and the monitor will activate
                    the warning light and alarm. If the valve spool contains a burr, it might prevent the spool from
                    returning to its centered position when the problem is corrected. Thus the warning light and alarm
                    do not reset when the key switch is moved to the off position. Therefore the warning light and alarm
                    will re-activate when the vehicle is started. Refer to standard procedures for refilling and
                    bleeding air from hydraulic brake systems.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a poor ground is present at the taillights of the vehicle, when the headlight or
                    parking lights are turned on, power may feed through the brake light bulb and circuits 70B and 90R
                    to the brake monitor module (49) pin H. This will fool the monitor into thinking that only one brake
                    switch is functioning, thus latching on the warning light and alarm. Another indication of this
                    problem may be the shutting off of cruise control or PTO operations when the lights are switched on.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
