<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake Systems</title>
            <para>The Bendix Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake booster is offered on all hydraulic brake models. It powers a
                split system which protects against brake failure by using separate fluid lines to feed the front and
                rear axle brakes. The master cylinder provides fluid pressurized by the power steering pump and the
                Hydro-Max II booster to activate the brake pads against the disc or drums. It is a dual mode system
                which will automatically provide back-up brake power, from an electric/hydraulic pump, should there be a
                loss of power steering pump pressure.
            </para>
            <para>A warning light and alarm, which can indicate various hydraulic and electrical malfunctions, are
                standard.
            </para>
            <para>A hydraulic brake and stop light switch each signal the engine Electronic Control Module (ECM2) when
                the brakes are applied. The ECM2 uses these signals to control the cruise and engine remote controls,
                cold ambient protection and idle shutdown timer systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter With Water-in-Fuel Light</title>
            <para>The fuel filter heater is mounted in the fuel filter and when operating, it helps prevent fuel from
                gelling in the unfiltered side of the filter. The system consists of an ignition relay (R20), the filter
                heating element, and a normally open thermoswitch. The switch contacts close at approximately 45&#176;F.
            </para>
            <para>The water-in-fuel system consists of a control module, a water probe, and a warning light in the dash
                cluster. When water is present in the fuel filter, increased current will flow from the probe to ground.
                The module senses this increase and turns on the warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Suspension Low Air Pressure Warning</title>
            <para>The air suspension system permits the driver to lower the frame by releasing air from the suspension
                air bags through a cab control valve. The system includes an alarm and warning light which are activated
                when low air pressure in the system is detected. The system is also protected from inadvertently
                releasing air when the ignition key switch is on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allison 2400 (LCT) Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>Discussion of the LCT (Allison 2400 Series) transmission In this section is limited to the
                transmission control module (TCM) power circuits, data link connectivity, signals from the neutral
                safety back up (NSBU) switch and circuits to the shift selector control. For detailed information on
                transmission diagnostics, refer to the Allison service manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
