<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION - Cab Dome and
        Courtesy Lights
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cab Dome and Courtesy Lights</title>
        <para>Power is fed from the batteries to junction block (J1), circuit 14A, fuse F7 and circuit 63 to a splice.
            From this splice the dome light assembly, the power distribution panel light, the left courtesy light, and
            the right courtesy light receive power, and will illuminate if either one of the cab doors is opened. From
            the splice, power is applied to circuit 63B, connector (21), and a black wire to the power distribution
            light at the fuse panel. Its ground path is through a black wire, connector (21), and circuit 63-GC to a
            splice. If the left door is opened, the ground path is through circuit 63-GB, connector (201), and the left
            door switch to cab ground. If the right door is opened, the ground path is through circuit 63-GD, connector
            (220), circuit 63-GD, connector (119), circuit 63-GJ, connector (217) and the right door switch to cab
            ground.
        </para>
        <para>From the splice, power is also applied to circuit 63D, connector (219), and the pigtail of the left
            courtesy light. Its ground path is through its other pigtail, connector (219), and circuit 63-GE to a
            splice. If the left door is opened, the ground path is through circuit 63-GB, connector (201), and the left
            door switch to cab ground. If the right door is opened, the ground path is through circuit 63-GD, connector
            (220), circuit 63-GD, connector (119), circuit 63-GJ, connector (217) and the right door switch to cab
            ground.
        </para>
        <para>From the splice, power is also applied to circuit 63F, connector (220), circuit 63F, connector (119), and
            the pigtail of the right courtesy light. Its ground path is through its other pigtail to connector (119). If
            the left door is opened, the ground path is through circuit 63-GD, connector (220), circuit 63-GD, circuit
            63-GB, connector (201), and the left door switch to cab ground. If the right door switch is opened, the
            ground path is through circuit 63-GJ, connector (217) and the right door switch to cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>From the splice, power is also applied to circuit 63A, connector (16), a yellow wire, and connector (54)
            to the dome light assembly. If the left door is opened, the ground path is through connector (54), a brown
            wire, connector (16), circuit 63-GA, circuit 63-GB, connector (201), and the left door switch to cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>If right door is opened, the ground path is through connector (54), a brown wire, connector (16), circuit
            63-GA, circuit 63-GD, connector (220), circuit 63-GD, connector (119), circuit 63-GJ, connector (217), and
            the right door switch to cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>When the switch at the dome light is moved to the map light position, a ground path is supplied to
            illuminate the map light. When the switch is moved to the dome light position, a ground path is supplied to
            illuminate both the dome light and the map light. The ground path for both switch positions is through
            connector (54), a brown wire, connector (16), circuit 63-G, and 11-G to cab ground.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_230.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_232.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
