<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - FE 300 CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Dryer with Heater</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on or accessory position, power is applied to circuit A12, fuse F7,
                circuit A39A, dash connector (2), A39A, connector (40), a black wire, connector (51)/(76), and a black
                wire to the heated air dryer (94). If the air dryer thermostat senses air temperature below 50&#176;F
                (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow through the heating element. This assures that
                the accumulated moisture does not freeze during cold weather.
            </para>
            <para>Ground is through a white wire, connector (51)/(76), a white wire, connector (40), and circuit
                K39-G/K11-GJ to (J10) engine ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Brake System</title>
            <para>Refer to S04023 ANTILOCK BRAKE SYSTEM.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Builder Connections</title>
            <para>Refer to Description, Operation and Troubleshooting sections for circuitry of any system which may
                supply power to the body builder connectors (169) or (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Automatic Drain Valve with Heater</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on position, power is fed to circuit A12, fuse F8, circuit A39,
                dash connector (2), circuit K39, in-line connector (40), and a black wire to the heated drain valve. The
                drain valve is grounded through a white wire, in-line connector (40), circuit K39-GA/K11-GJ to the (J10)
                engine or starter ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature drops below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow
                through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze in the drain
                valve during cold weather.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter/Water-In-Fuel</title>
            <para>Power is applied from the (J2) battery feed stud to the fuel heater relay (R5) through circuit
                A14/A19, fuse F17 and circuit A19H. When the key switch is turned to the ON or START position, power
                flows from the key switch (20), through circuit A13A, fuse F20, circuit A19D and the relay coil. Ground
                for the relay is through circuit A11-GA to the (J1) platform ground. This energizes the relay.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay energized, power is applied to the heated fuel filter (N/L) through circuit A19A,
                connector (2), circuit K19A, connector (6706) and a green wire. When the temperature drops below
                approximately 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), the thermal switch contacts close and a ground path is applied
                through a blue wire, connector (6706), circuit A19-GD/A11-GJ to the (J10) engine ground. This causes the
                heater element to come on.
            </para>
            <para>With key switch on, power is also applied from the fuel heater relay connector through circuit AA19E
                to the water-in-fuel module (16). From the module, power is applied to the fuel filter water probe
                through circuit A19A, connector (2), circuit K19A, connector (6706), and a yellow wire. Whenever water
                builds up to an unacceptable level, it causes a completed circuit path from the probe to the filter
                housing, which is grounded to the frame through its mounting bracket. This causes the module to
                energize.
            </para>
            <para>When the water-in-fuel module becomes energized, power is supplied to circuit A19F and the
                water-in-fuel light (9). This energizes the lamp as power flows through circuit A19-G/A11-G to the (J1)
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is in the start position, the water-in-fuel module is grounded through circuit
                A19-GB to the key switch ground. This serves as a bulb check to assure the bulb is operational.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module (86) is fed a signal from the flow switch (N/L),
                causing the monitor to turn on a brake warning light and alarm system and to start the hydraulic reserve
                pump to provide additional braking power. The reserve pump and warning system is also activated when the
                differential pressure switch (91) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuits A13A, A90U,
                fuse F2, circuit A90T, and blocking diode assembly (80). From the blocking diode, power is supplied
                through circuit A90J, to the hydraulic pump control relay (85) coil, and also through circuit A90H to
                the brake monitor module (86). The brake monitor module is grounded through circuit A11-GD to the
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link A90-FL, circuit A90, and pump control relay (85). Power is
                also applied from circuit A90-FL to circuit A90, circuit A90A, fuse F1, circuit A90B, connectors (83),
                (87), and (92), and hydraulic brake switch (209).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch contacts will be
                closed (engine not running) and a ground path is provided from the switch through circuits A90L, A90K,
                connector (84), circuit A90K, connector (88) and A90K, to a splice. From the splice, a ground path is
                provided over circuit A90L to the brake monitor module alarm input (86-A). This causes the module to
                switch the alarm output (86-C) to ground, which activates the alarm and warning light. From the splice,
                a ground circuit is also provided by way of circuit A90E to the pump control relay (85), causing it to
                energize. With the relay energized, power flows through its N.C. contacts, circuit A90S and connectors
                (84) and (88) to the reserve pump motor. This causes the reserve pump motor, which is grounded through
                its case, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>A signal path, on circuit A90Q, connectors (84) and (88) to brake monitor module connector (86-F),
                provides information to the module. It continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump and
                power supplied to it. The warning system activates if the pump motor winding opens up or if the
                hydraulic brake relay (85) remains closed (provides power to circuit A90S and the reserve pump motor),
                after the engine is running. The warning system is also activated if no power is supplied to the pump
                motor when the flow switch or differential switch contacts are closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (86-C) to ground, the brake warning light
                illuminates by power flowing to the lamp feed connector (10), through the light, connector (10), and
                circuits A90N, A90M, to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, the alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the
                alarm, and circuit A90M to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>If the ignition key is in the off position and the truck brakes are applied, the contacts of the
                hydraulic brake switch (209) close. With the contacts closed, power flows through circuits A70C, A90F,
                A90G and blocking diode assembly (81), circuit A70D, connector and diode assembly (80), and circuit
                A90H, to feed the brake monitor module at connector (86-E).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, power signals are fed from the diode connector (81) to circuit A90D and the brake
                monitor module connector (86-G) and on circuit A90C to brake monitor module connector (86-H). The module
                compares these signals and if there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits, A90D or A90C, for more
                than 14&#177;5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is also applied to the stop light relay (R4) through fuse F12 and circuit A70B. When
                the brakes are applied, power flows from diode connector (80), through circuit A70E, to the relay coil,
                which energizes the relay. The relay is grounded through circuit A70-G/A11-GA to (J1) platform ground.
                With the relay energized, the contacts close and allow power to flow through the relay, circuit A70A, to
                the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Hydraulic Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the cranking motor solenoid, power is applied to circuit A90-FL/A90, a connector (N/L), circuit
                A90A, fuse F1, circuit A90B, connectors (83), (87) and (92) to the brake switch (209). When the brake
                pedal is depressed, the contacts of switch (209) close and power is supplied to circuit A70C, connectors
                (93), (87) and (83), and circuit A90C to the brake monitor module (86).
            </para>
            <para>At the same time, power is also applied to a blocking diode (81), circuit A70D, connector (80), and
                circuit A70E to the stop light relay (R4). This energizes the relay and allows power to be applied
                through fuse F12, circuit A70B, relay (R4), and circuit A70A to the body builder connector (169). From
                this point, power is applied to the tail lights through the body builder circuitry.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Air Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the battery feed stud (J2), power is applied to circuit A14/A14A, fuse F12, circuit A70, stop
                light switch jumper harness connector (26), a red wire, first stop light switch (26), and a red wire to
                the second stop light switch (26).
            </para>
            <para>When the brake pedal is depressed, the stop light switch contacts close and power is supplied to the
                common brown wire and to jumper harness connector (26). From connector (26), power is applied to
                circuits A70B/A70A and the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
