<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS -
        OPERATION - Charging Circuits
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Charging Circuits</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>For a complete discussion on operating principles for alternators, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in
                the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the specific alternator being serviced.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>International Engines</title>
            <para>When the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the alternator or (BAT) terminal,
                and circuit 2 to a splice. From the splice, current flows through 2 fusible links, 2-FL and 2A-FL to the
                crank motor solenoid battery stud. From this stud, current flows to the batteries through the positive
                battery cable. Power is also applied to the junction block feed stud (J1) through circuit 14-FL/14,
                connector (1CF), and circuit 14.
            </para>
            <para>The alternator also supplies power from the (I) terminal (Delco 22-SI), or connector (430) (Delco
                CS-130), through circuit 1A/1-RW, bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and circuit 1 to the accessory feed
                block (J2).
            </para>
            <para>The alternator is grounded through the (GRD) terminal and circuit 2-G to the starter motor ground stud
                (G).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cummins M11E, L10 STC and Caterpillar Engines</title>
            <para>When the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the alternator (BAT) terminal and
                circuit 2 to the magnetic switch positive stud. From this stud, the alternator supplies current to the
                batteries through circuit 14/14-FL to the positive stud on the starter solenoid and then through the
                positive battery cable. From the magnetic switch stud, the alternator also supplies power to the vehicle
                electrical components through circuit 14 to the junction block feed stud (J1).
            </para>
            <para>With the Cummins M11E and Caterpillar engines, the alternator is grounded through the (GRD) terminal
                and circuit 2-G to an engine block ground. From the engine block ground, the ground circuit to the
                starter motor ground stud (G) ) is through a 6 gauge wire with Cummins or circuit 11-GL with
                Caterpillar.
            </para>
            <para>With the Cummins L10 STC, the alternator ground is through the (GRD) terminal and circuit 11-GL to the
                starter motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cummins N14E Engine</title>
            <para>When the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the alternator (BAT) terminal and
                circuit 2 to a splice, and 2 fusible link circuits, 2-FL, to the crank motor solenoid battery stud. From
                this stud, current flows to the batteries through the positive battery cable. From the solenoid battery
                stud, power is also applied to the (J1) junction feed stud through 2 fusible link circuits, 14-FL, to a
                splice, circuit 14 to the magnetic switch, and circuit 14.
            </para>
            <para>The alternator is grounded through the (GRD) terminal and circuit 11-GL, to the starter motor ground
                stud (G).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_59.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_61.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
