<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, CUMMINS M11E AND N14E -
        OPERATION - Idle/Diagnostic Switch (348)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Idle/Diagnostic Switch (348)</title>
        <para>The low idle/diagnostic switch is a dual function switch. It is a two-position momentary switch that
            adjusts the low engine idle speed. It is also used during on-board diagnostics (when the diagnostic switch
            is turned on) to move through the diagnostic fault code list. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s08230_96.xml" xrefid="x0823501">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
            charts.
        </para>
        <para>The low engine idle speed (rpm) can be adjusted from the cab, using a two-position momentary,
            increment/decrement switch. This function permits adjusting idle speed up or down in units of 25 rpm by
            toggling the switch. Maximum idle speed is 800 rpm and minimum idle speed is 550 rpm. When the idle has been
            changed and the key turned off, the new setting is saved in memory. This feature is owner selected and can
            be turned off with a Compulink electronic service tool.
        </para>
        <para>Momentarily placing the switch in the increment (INC) position applies a ground path to the ECM connector
            (320) terminal (14). From this terminal the path is circuit 97AV, connector (3), circuit 97AV, the
            idle/diagnostics switch (348), circuit 97-GD/97-GA, connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320)
            common ground terminal 10. This causes the engine idle speed to increase 25 rpm.
        </para>
        <para>Momentarily placing the switch in the decrement (DEC) position applies a ground path to the ECM connector
            (320) terminal (23). From this terminal the path is circuit 97AU, connector (3), circuit 97AU, the
            idle/diagnostics switch (348), circuit 97-GD/97-GA, connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320)
            common ground terminal 10. This causes the engine idle speed to decrease 25 rpm.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_87.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_89.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
