<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER, GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 9800 - DESCRIPTION - GAUGES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>GAUGES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This service section refers to electronic gauges, electrical gauges, and mechanical gauges. (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0824501">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0824501" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0824501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Instrument Cluster</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LEFT TURN SIGNAL / FLASHER INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. POWER DIVIDER LOCK INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. AIR RESTRICTION GAUGE (OPTIONAL) OR AIR APPLICATION (OPTIONAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PYROMETER (OPTIONAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ENGINE OIL TEMPERATURE GAUGE (OPTIONAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ENGINE OIL PRESSURE GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. VOLTMETER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. REAR LIGHT (FIFTH WHEEL) INDICATOR LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. HI-BEAM INDICATOR LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. ODOMETER</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. LOW AIR WARNING INDICATOR LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. RIGHT TURN SIGNAL/FLASHER INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. AIR PRESSURE GAUGE (PRIMARY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. AIR PRESSURE GAUGE (SECONDARY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. FUEL GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. FORWARD REAR AXLE TEMPERATURE GAUGE (OPTIONAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. TRANSMISSION OIL PRESSURE GAUGE (OPTIONAL) OR REAR REAR AXLE TEMPERATURE GAUGE
                        (OPTIONAL)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>19. TRANSMISSION OIL TEMPERATURE GAUGE (OPTIONAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>20. "OIL/WATER" WARNING LIGHT (CUMMINS M11, N14 and ISM ENGINES ONLY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>21. AIR SUSPENSION DUMP WARNING LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>22. ENGINE WARNING LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. ENGINE STOP LIGHT</callout1>
                    <callout1>24. PANEL MOUNTING SCREWS</callout1>
                    <callout1>25. ABS WARNING LIGHT*</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. TRACTION CONTROL WARNING LIGHT*</callout1>
                    <callout1>27. TRANSMISSION SERVICE WARNING LIGHT*</callout1>
                    <callout1>* THESE WARNING LIGHTS ARE LOCATED BETWEEN THE RIGHT GAUGE CLUSTER AND THE WING PANEL.
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x08245104">
            <title>Electronic Gauges</title>
            <para>The electronic gauges are the speedometer, tachometer, and voltmeter. The speedometer and tachometer
                are 4-pin gauges and are microprocessor driven gauges. The microprocessor is factory programmed to
                operate from data link signals generated by the Electronic Control Module (ECM). The voltmeter is a
                2-pin gauge, and operates by voltage supplied by the battery and charging system.
            </para>
            <para>These gauges have pin sockets located in the rear. These sockets mate with pin connectors in the gauge
                cluster.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x08245105">
            <title>Electrical Gauges</title>
            <para>The 3-pin gauges in this group operate on 12 volts and are connected directly to the gauge sender.
                Gauges in this group include engine oil temperature, axle temperature, engine water temperature, fuel,
                and transmission temperature.
            </para>
            <para>The exhaust temperature (pyrometer) gauge, also included in this section, is an electrical gauge, but
                has its own control module (signal amplifier).
            </para>
            <para>The electrical gauges have pin sockets located in the rear. These sockets mate with pin connectors in
                the gauge cluster.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x08245106">
            <title>Mechanical Gauges</title>
            <para>The air pressure, oil pressure, transmission oil pressure, and air application gauges are all
                mechanical. The gauge movement is caused by pressure from the affected system.
            </para>
            <para>These gauges are of the quick connect type. The gauges have a straight tip with an O-ring seal. The
                hub of the gauge case in which the tip fits has bayonet grooves for locking the gauge in place. The
                gauge cluster has the quick connect socket fittings. These have Schrader valves in them which close when
                the gauge is removed and prevents the gauge lines from leaking or depressurizing.
            </para>
            <para>The air restriction gauge is also mechanical. The gauge movement is caused by the pressure drop across
                it. The vacuum inside the air cleaner housing provides this pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
