<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - TWO SPEED AXLE SWITCH (WITH MANUAL TRANSMISSION)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TWO SPEED AXLE SWITCH (WITH MANUAL TRANSMISSION)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f0825942" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825934.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Two Speed Axle Switch Function Diagram (7 Pack Air Solenoid Shown)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 2 SPEED AXLE SWITCH (ON SHIFTER)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>This system uses an electronically controlled air solenoid to supply pilot air to a larger air
                solenoid which will control the two speed axle.
            </para>
            <para>The switch on the shifter is a direct input to the ESC. The ESC will send signals to a remote air
                solenoid module containing the relay configured to operate the feature. Two different solenoid packs may
                be used to control the air pressure. The 7 solenoid version is controlled by J1939 messages and the 4
                solenoid version by discrete wire.
            </para>
            <para>The two speed axle feature allows the rear axle to shift to a much reduced gear ratio for the
                transportation of heavy loads. For manual transmissions the switch will be on the shifter with high
                range being up and low range being down. The normal operating position would be high. If the power
                divider lock (PDL) feature is installed on the vehicle, it must be off in order for a shift to occur.
            </para>
            <para>The 2-speed axle is spring loaded to the low range gear, requiring air to shift to high gear. With the
                key off, the vehicle will stay or return to low range.
            </para>
            <para>When shifting from high range to low range the shifter switch will be in the high axle (up) position.
                When the shifter switch is set to low (down) position and the vehicle speed is less than the
                programmable maximum allowed shifting speed (default 3.2 kmh/2 mph) and the PDL is not on, an air
                solenoid shifts the axle into low gear. The PDL can be engaged in either high or low speed axle, but is
                not allowed to be on during the shift. Some other countries such as Mexico may need the maximum allowed
                shifting speed set much higher as it is often used as a hi/lo splitter as the vehicle is up shifted.
            </para>
            <para>When shifting from low range to high range the shifter switch will be in the low speed axle (down)
                position. When the shifter switch is set to high (up) position and the PDL is not locked, an air
                solenoid shifts the axle into high gear. Note the PDL can be engaged in either high or low speed axle
                but is not allowed to be on during the shift. The vehicle speed restriction does not apply when shifting
                from low to high range.
            </para>
            <para>If a switch or speed error occurs, the two speed axle will remain in its current range for that
                ignition cycle. When the ignition is turned off, the solenoids turn off. Upon key on, if a switch or
                speed error is active, the two speed axle will again remain in its current range for that ignition
                cycle. In the event of an air solenoid failure due to a shorted solenoid, this feature will request the
                ESC to turn off power to the air solenoid pack (or packs) to prevent uncontrolled operation of the
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>A switch indicator lamp is currently not available, but when introduced the switch indicator will
                blink slowly for errors and quickly when the feature is inhibited. If this feature commands its driven
                solenoid to turn on and the solenoid pack power has been turned off, this feature will blink the switch
                indicator slowly to communicate an error has prevented this feature from functioning.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_345.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_347.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
