<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 5000 9100 9200 9400 9900 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 5000, 5000i, 9000, 9000i - DIAGNOSTICS - GAUGE CIRCUIT TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0820708" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GAUGE CIRCUIT TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <para>If during the power up Speedometer/Tachometer self test, one or more of the electronic gauges did not go
            through the full sweep and did not go to the 6 o'clock position:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Switch the gauge with one of the other electronic gauges that went through the full sweep.
                Rerun the power up test.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Oil Pressure, Water Temperature, Voltmeter or Fuel Gauge -</emph>
                    If the suspect gauge went through the full sweep in a different gauge location, and the known good
                    gauge in the suspect location did not make a full sweep, go to step C.
                </para>
                <para>If the
                    <emph type="bold">speedometer or tachometer</emph>
                    are switched and the suspect gauge went through the full sweep in the other location, and the known
                    good gauge in the suspect location did not make a full sweep, replace the Speedometer/Tachometer
                    module.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the suspect gauge did not go through a full sweep in a different location and the
                    known good gauge moved to the suspect location, went through a full sweep, replace the suspect
                    gauge.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Oil Pressure, Water Temperature, Voltmeter, Fuel - If the known good gauge did not go
                    through a full sweep in the suspect gauge location, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08207x_42.xml" xrefid="x0820715">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>and troubleshoot the
                    gauge circuits between the Speedometer/Tachometer module and the suspect gauge cluster pins. If the
                    gauge circuits to the cluster pins check good, replace the Speedometer/Tachometer module.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
