<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - POWER DISTRIBUTION SYSTEM - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>12 Volt Power Distribution (Battery) in IC Bus With T 444E or DT 466E</title>
            <para>Power is supplied by the vehicle batteries to the engine ECM module power relay (396) with DT 466E and
                (662) with T 444E through circuit 14A, a 40 amp in-line fuse, circuit 14B, connectors (412) and (426).
                From the batteries, power is also supplied to the cranking motor solenoid (J31) battery stud (B) by a
                4/0 red wire on the IC Bus.
            </para>
            <para>From the cranking motor solenoid (J31) battery stud (B), power is supplied to circuits 90-FL and 90
                going to the hydraulic brake booster relay (300) and hydraulic brake switch (50). Power is also supplied
                to circuits 18-FL and 18 going to the glow plug relay feed stud, and circuits 17-FL and 17B going to the
                starter relay (387). With an I-6 engine, power is also supplied to the engine/dash connector (2) through
                circuits 26 and 26D for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>Also from the cranking motor solenoid (J31) battery stud, power is applied through circuits 14-FL,
                14A-FL and 14 to the mega fuse 175 amp and a junction feed stud located on the cowl relay mounting
                bracket. The alternator also supplies power to the feed stud over circuit 2.
            </para>
            <para>With a T 444E engine, power from a splice in circuit 14, is supplied through circuits 26, 26B and 26D
                to the engine/dash connector (2) for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>From the junction feed stud, power is supplied to the engine/dash connector (2) for the ammeter gauge
                through circuits 26A and 26C. Power is also supplied through circuit 14 and the mega fuse 175 amp to the
                body battery feed stud (J1), located inside the electrical access door in the left side bus body.
            </para>
            <para>Through the (J1) feed stud, power is supplied to the fuse block power distribution center (1) on
                circuit 14A, 14AA, 14B, 14E (fuse F10), and 14C (fuse F8). Power is also supplied to the key switch (63)
                on circuit 15 (fuse F7), and the headlight switch (23) on circuits 50 and 50C.
            </para>
            <para>A ground path is supplied to the cranking motor ground junction stud (G) through a 3/0 black cable to
                the batteries which are grounded to the frame. Through the cranking motor ground stud (G), the
                alternator is grounded through circuit 2-G, the start relay is grounded through circuits 11-GJ and 17-G,
                the bus cab is grounded through circuit 11-GH, and the engine is grounded through circuit 11-GS.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to individual circuits for continuation of circuitry.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>12 Volt Power Distribution (Key Switch) In IC Bus With T 444E or DT 466E</title>
            <para>Power is fed to key switch (63) on circuits 14AA, 14C (fuse F7), 14E (fuse F10), 15 (fuse F8) from
                body battery feed stud (J1). When key switch (63) is moved to ignition position, energizes IGN relay #1
                (R2) and IGN relay #2 (R3) and power is supplied to circuits 13 and 13B going to the power distribution
                center. Power is also supplied to circuit 12 going to the power distribution center, and circuit 1 going
                to dash connector (2), circuit 1, unlabeled connector, and circuit 1A to the alternator ignition stud
                (I).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the start position, power is supplied to circuit 17C, starter
                interrupt connector (195) (see Section 7), and circuit 17 to the crank relay (R5). Power is also
                supplied to circuits 13 and 13B going to the fuse block power distribution center.
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to accessories position, power is supplied to circuit 12 going to the
                fuse block power distribution center, and circuit 1 going to dash connector (2), circuit 1, unlabeled
                in-line connector, and circuit 1A to the alternator ignition stud (I).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
