<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 5000 9100 9200 9400 9900 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 5000, 5000i, 9000, 9000i - OPERATION - SPEEDOMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0820705" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SPEEDOMETER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The vehicle speed signal is generated by the vehicle speed sensor (250) located at the rear of the
                transmission. This sensor contains a permanent magnet that creates a magnetic field. The sensor is
                mounted so that the magnetic field is repeatedly broken by a 16-tooth speedometer gear on the
                transmission. As the field is broken, an AC (alternating current) pulse is generated. With electronic
                engines, this pulse is sent on circuits 97AK and 97AJ to the ECM (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0820703">Vehicle Speed Signal from ECM</hotlnk>). With mechanical engines, the pulse is
                sent over circuits 47A and 47B to the Speedometer/Tachometer module through connector (421).
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0820703">
            <title>Vehicle Speed Signal From ECM</title>
            <para>With an electronic engine, the signal from the vehicle speed sensor is used for cruise control, engine
                brakes, and other functions. The ECM processes the signal from the vehicle speed sensor and sends a
                signal in the form of a serial data transmission, over the ATA data link circuit (a positive and
                negative pair of twisted wires) to the Speedometer/Tachometer module through connector (421). The signal
                is also present at the ATA data link connector (137) and vehicle speed can be read using an electronic
                service tool (EST). For additional information on the data link, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL,
                Electronic Engine Controls, in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedometer Gauge</title>
            <para>The Speedometer/Tachometer control module processes the input signal and drives the 4-pin electronic
                speedometer gauge that plugs into the module. The speedometer and tachometer gauges are essentially the
                same except for the gauge markings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
