<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, CUMMINS M11E AND N14E -
        OPERATION - Accelerator Pedal Assembly (309)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Accelerator Pedal Assembly (309)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>CELECT engines use an electronic accelerator pedal assembly that uses an
                <emph type="bold">integrated</emph>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)/Idle Validation Switch (IVS). The
                sensor is not serviceable and if defective, must be replaced and recalibrated to the ECM.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</title>
            <para>The APS is attached to the accelerator pedal. The APS acts like a potentiometer-movement of the pedal
                results in a variable signal being sent to the ECM that is proportional to pedal position.
            </para>
            <para>The 5V signal from ECM connector (320) terminal 18 is applied on circuit 99A(5V) to APS/IVS connector
                (309) terminal C.
            </para>
            <para>The variable wiper signal (varies with pedal position) from APS/IVS connector (309) terminal A,
                returns on circuit 99, to ECM connector (320) terminal 11. This variable signal tells the ECM the
                position of the accelerator pedal.
            </para>
            <para>The APS is grounded through APS/IVS connector (309) terminal B on circuit 99-G, to ECM connector (320)
                terminal 19.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Any time the accelerator pedal sensor (APS) is disconnected from the ECM with the key switch
                        on, the APS and ECM must be recalibrated (refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x0823504">Calibrating Accelerator To ECM</hotlnk>
                        below).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>IDLE VALIDATION SWITCH (IVS)</title>
            <para>The IVS is used to indicate when accelerator pedal
                <emph type="bold">is in</emph>
                the low idle position and when the pedal
                <emph type="bold">is not in</emph>
                the low idle position.
            </para>
            <para>With the accelerator
                <emph type="bold">in the low idle position</emph>, contacts of the IVS are closed and a ground path is
                applied to ECM connector (320) terminal 6. From this terminal the path is circuit 99B, connector (3),
                circuit 99B, connector (309), the IVS, connector (309), circuit 99-GA/97-GA, connector (3), and circuit
                97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320) common ground terminal 10. This indicates to the ECM that the accelerator
                pedal is at idle position.
            </para>
            <para>When the accelerator is
                <emph type="bold">not in the low idle position,</emph>
                the idle contacts of the IVS are open and the normally open throttle contacts of the IVS are closed.
                This applies a ground path to ECM connector (320) terminal 9. From this terminal the path is circuit
                99C, connector (3), circuit 99C, connector (309), the IVS, connector (309), circuit 99-GA/97-GA,
                connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320) common ground terminal 10. This indicates to the
                ECM that the accelerator pedal is not at idle position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>APS/IVS INTERACTION</title>
            <para>The ECM analyzes the signals received from the APS and IVS signals making certain that the signals
                fall within certain parameters. For example: if the IVS signal indicates that the accelerator pedal is
                in the IDLE position, the ECM expects to see an APS signal that indicates that no throttle is applied.
                If it does not see a logical response from both, a fault code may be logged.
                <emph type="bold">The APS/IVS timing cannot be checked using a multimeter.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0823504">
            <title>CALIBRATING ACCELERATOR TO ECM</title>
            <para>The signals between the ECM and the accelerator pedal are low voltage (5V) and very low current
                (microamps). Because of these low voltages and currents, they must be electrically calibrated to one
                another for proper engine response.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM and accelerator pedal must be calibrated:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When the accelerator pedal is initially installed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When an accelerator pedal is replaced</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When a new calibration is down-loaded to the ECM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the accelerator pedal wiring is disconnected either at the pedal or at connector (320)
                        while the key switch is on
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">To recalibrate the ECM and the accelerator pedal</emph>
                - the key must be on, then the accelerator pedal must be slowly and fully depressed from idle to full
                throttle and then released. The accelerator pedal should be depressed and released three times.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_90.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_92.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
