<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON 2000 SERIES&#8482; (LCT) TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The symptoms listed in this section relate to specific events rather than specific diagnostic codes.
                It is still a necessary first step to read (and note) any active or inactive diagnostic codes.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Will Not Crank</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the following checks. If no defects are found, proceed to Step 2.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Shift Selector not in "N."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check vehicle starting system cables and wires for clean, tight connections. Check
                        connection to B+ terminal of crank motor solenoid for clean, tight connection.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check battery state-of-charge.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check operation of the NSBU by performing the steps in
                    <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824706">Neutral Start Circuits
                        <xref refid="x0824706"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . The NSBU may not be switching properly to indicate that the shift selector is in the neutral
                    position.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If neutral start system checks good, proceed to Step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects were noted in neutral start system, correct defects and test for proper
                        engine starting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the no-start condition is still present after performing steps 1 through 3, there is
                    most likely a problem with vehicle start circuit components, not related to the transmission.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANSMISSION light will not go out 3 seconds after engine is started.</title>
            <para>The CHECK TRANSMISSION light should turn on when the key is turned to the ignition position and go out
                approximately 3 seconds after the engine is started. If the TCM sets a DTC the light should remain on
                until the condition is corrected.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the TransPro software to determine if a DTC has been set.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there is a problem with the transmission and the TCM has set a DTC, perform
                        diagnostics as indicated by the DTC.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the CHECK TRANSMISSION light remains on and there are no DTCs set, perform the
                        steps in
                        <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824708">CHECK TRANSMISSION Light Circuitry
                            <xref refid="x0824708"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Backup Lights Do Not Function.</title>
            <para>If power to the backup lights is not present, perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824707">Back-Up Light Circuits
                    <xref refid="x0824707"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANSMISSION light does not come on for a few seconds after engine is started.</title>
            <para>The CHECK TRANSMISSION light should turn on when the key is turned to the ignition position and go out
                approximately 3 seconds after the engine is started. If the check transmission lamp does not turn on at
                all, perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824708">CHECK TRANSMISSION light Circuitry
                    <xref refid="x0824708"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RANGE INHIBIT light malfunction.</title>
            <para>If the range inhibit light is on all of the time or doesn't come on when expected, perform the steps
                in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824709">Range Inhibit Light Circuitry
                    <xref refid="x0824709"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MODE SELECT light or switch malfunction.</title>
            <para>If the mode select light is on all of the time, doesn't come on when the mode select button is pushed
                in, or it appears the switch is not affecting the transmission, perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824710">Check Mode Select Circuitry
                    <xref refid="x0824710"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - Transmission Will Not Go Into "Lockup" Mode.</title>
            <para>If no diagnostic codes are present, check the ABS interface circuit by performing the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824711">Torque Convertor Lock Drop for ABS System
                    <xref refid="x0824711"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Speedometer Signal.</title>
            <para>If the speedometer signal from the TCM is not present at connector (303), pin A, when the wheels are
                spinning, perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824712">Speedometer Signal
                    <xref refid="x0824712"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WITH DIFFERENTIAL LOCK- Differential lock will not engage.</title>
            <para>If differential lock relay (226) is not open at speeds below 22 MPH (35.4 KPH) or not closing at
                speeds above 22 MPH (35.4 KPH), perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824713">Differential Lock Circuits
                    <xref refid="x0824713"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Brake Circuits</title>
            <para>If the exhaust brake doesn't engage when selected or the transmission torque convertor lock-up is not
                interacting with the exhaust brake correctly, perform the steps in
                <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824714">Exhaust Brake Circuits
                    <xref refid="x0824714"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
