<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - FANS AND SHUTTERS - OPERATION - Horton Engine
        Fan Controls With Caterpillar C-10 And C-12
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Horton Engine Fan Controls With Caterpillar C-10 And C-12</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Horton Fan/Clutch Assembly</emph>- The fan clutch is engaged by air pressure supplied by
            the fan solenoid. The fan clutch is spring loaded off and air pressure is required to overcome the spring
            and engage the clutch.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Normally Open Fan Solenoid (335)</emph>
            - The N.O. fan solenoid (335) supplies air pressure to engage the fan clutch when the solenoid is not
            energized. Energizing the solenoid turns off the air pressure to the fan clutch, causing the fan clutch to
            disengage.
        </para>
        <para>The solenoid receives ignition voltage (key on) on circuit 23 from 5A fuse F2. The solenoid ground
            circuit, 23B, is connected to the normally open contact of the fan solenoid relay (538). The relay opens and
            closes, causing the fan solenoid to turn on and off.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fan Control Relay (538)</emph>
            - The fan solenoid relay control coil is energized by a 12V signal on circuit 23A from ECM connector (400)
            terminal 28. The relay control coil ground circuit 23-GA is grounded through the engine harness to cylinder
            head ground.
        </para>
        <para>When the ECM energizes the fan solenoid relay, the N.O. contacts close, completing the circuit to ground
            for circuit 23B, causing the fan solenoid to energize. This disengages the fan clutch.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM uses inputs from the engine coolant temperature sensor, retarder solenoid status and the A/C high
            pressure switch (311) to determine when the fan should be on. To turn the fan on, the ECM applies 0V to the
            fan solenoid relay. To turn the fan off, the ECM applies 12V to the fan solenoid relay.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM turns the fan on under the following conditions:</para>
        <para>If the engine speed is less than 2250 RPM or the engine is running
            <emph type="bold">and any of the following conditions exists:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Coolant temperature sensor is greater than 96&#176;C (205&#176;F)
            <emph type="bold">or</emph>
        </para>
        <para>There is an active diagnostic code for the coolant temperature sensor
            <emph type="bold">or</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The retarder solenoid signal is active (high mode) for more than 10 seconds with coolant temperature
            sensor greater than 80&#176;C (176&#176;F)
            <emph type="bold">or</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A/C high pressure switch is open
            <emph type="bold">or</emph>
        </para>
        <para>There is an active diagnostic code for an open A/C high pressure switch circuit.</para>
        <para>The ECM turns the fan off under the following conditions:</para>
        <para>Engine speed is greater than 2300 RPM
            <emph type="bold">or all of the following conditions exists:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Coolant temperature sensor is less than 92&#176;C (198&#176;F)
            <emph type="bold">and</emph>
        </para>
        <para>No active coolant temperature sensor diagnostic code
            <emph type="bold">and</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Retarder solenoid signal is active (high mode) with coolant temperature sensor less than 75&#176;C (167&#176;F)
            <emph type="bold">and</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A/C high pressure switch is closed and the ECM is not counting (or A/C fan on time is programmed to zero
            seconds)
            <emph type="bold">and</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The engine has been running at least two seconds.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Once the ECM has turned the fan on, the fan will remain on for a minimum of 180 seconds to avoid
                    unnecessary fan clutch cycling (except at engine start-up - it will run for only two seconds after
                    the engine starts). The 180 second time interval is a programmable feature.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_73.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_75.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
