<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER, GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 9800 - CLUSTER PROGRAMMING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="program" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLUSTER PROGRAMMING</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Any changes in vehicle components such as tire size, axle ratio, etc. requires the engine ECM to
                    be reprogrammed and not the speedometer/tachometer microprocessor. Refer to engine manufacturer's
                    service manual for information on reprogramming.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The International 9800 series vehicles are only offered with electronically controlled engines. Therefore,
            the speedometer/tachometer module should be programmed to read information from the data link. The cluster
            may be programmed by using an Electronic Service Tool (EST), such as the EZ-Tech&#8482; with the Instrument
            Cluster Software, connected to the data link. The cluster DIP switches should all be set to 0.
            <emph type="bold">Refer to the appropriate Electronic Service Tool manual for instructions.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If a loss of programming is suspected, and a service tool is not available, the DIP switches may be set to
            "1" for use with an electronic engine. The odometer switch (Number ten (10) on right bank) should be set to
            "0" for miles or "1" for kilometers.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Moving any of the dip switches from the 0 position disables the speedometer/tachometer
                    programming. If a DIP switch is moved, inaccurate vehicle operation data will be displayed on the
                    speedometer, tachometer, and odometer. (Moving the switches back to the 0 position will re-enable
                    the speedometer/tachometer programming.)
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
