<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS - 1000 SERIES From 01/01/1998 to 02/07/2004 - REMOVE AND INSTALL - INSTRUMENT CLUSTER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTRUMENT CLUSTER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The cluster is attached to the instrument panel by 8 screws. The cluster body can be detached from the
                instrument panel for quick access to its components. Either the complete assembly or any of 3
                subassemblies can be replaced.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Always place the ignition in the off position (not ACC) prior to removing or installing the
                        cluster. This will prevent damage to the cluster.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Static electricity can cause permanent damage to the cluster. Before working on the cluster,
                        be sure to discharge all static from your body by touching metal that is grounded. Do not wear
                        clothing that causes static buildup (such as nylon). Do not touch any pin connectors during
                        removal and installation of gauges. Work on the cluster in a clean environment to avoid dust.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0820601">
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Protect the front bezel during removal by placing a soft cloth on any items that might
                    get in the way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the eight mounting screws located around the outer edges of the cluster.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull the cluster away from the instrument panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two wiring harness connectors from the back of the cluster.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the two wiring harness connectors to the back of the cluster. These connectors
                    are color-coded for proper orientation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the cluster in the instrument panel frame and align it with the eight mounting
                    holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the eight mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08206_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08206_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08206.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
