<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION - Spot, Bunk Fluorescent
        and Reading Lights, and Cigar Lighter (Non-Raised Roof Cab)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Spot, Bunk Fluorescent and Reading Lights, and Cigar Lighter (Non-Raised Roof Cab)</title>
        <para>Power is applied by battery stud (B2) to circuits 14H and 14AP, 25A fuse F8-D, circuit 14AE, connector
            (22) and circuit 14AE to a splice.
        </para>
        <para>From the splice, power is applied to circuit 14AY, connect (N/L), and a back wire to the left spot light.
            From the splice, power is also applied to circuit 14BA, connector (N/L), and a black wire to the right spot
            light. The spot lights are grounded through their mounting brackets, and illuminate when their switches are
            moved to the on position.
        </para>
        <para>From the splice power is applied to circuit 14AZ, connector (N/L), circuit 14AE to a second splice. From
            the second splice, power is applied to circuit 84A and the cigar lighter. The cigar lighter is grounded
            through circuits 84-GA and 11-GAH to sleeper ground (J13), and heats up when the element is pushed into the
            socket.
        </para>
        <para>From the second splice, power also flows through circuit 63P to the bunk reading light connector (564).
            The bunk reading light is grounded through circuits 63-GP and 11-GAH to sleeper ground (J13), and
            illuminates when its switch is moved to the on position.
        </para>
        <para>From the second splice, power also flows through circuit 14BA to the bunk fluorescent light (562). The
            ground circuit consists of two circuits and three switches. Thus the bunk fluorescent light will illuminate
            when the switch on the light fixture, at the bunk switch panel, or at the dash switch panel is moved to its
            other position. One ground path is through connector (562), circuit 63-GB, connector (557), circuit 63-GB,
            switch (563), circuit 63-GD, connector (557), circuit 63-GD, connector (11), circuit 63-GD, connector (19),
            circuit 63-GD, switch (589), circuit 63-GE, and 11-GLC to L3 panel ground adapter (505). The other ground
            path is through connector (562), circuit 63-GA, connector (557), circuit 63-GA, switch (563), circuit 63-GC,
            connector (557), circuit 63-GC, connector (11), circuit 63-GC, connector (19), circuit 63-GC, switch (589),
            circuit 63-GE, and 11-GLC to L3 panel ground adapter (505).
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_217.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_219.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
