<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - REMOTE AIR SOLENOID MODULE (7-PACK)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x08259131">
        <title>REMOTE AIR SOLENOID MODULE (7-PACK)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259c1" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08259C1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>7- Pack Air Solenoid Module Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SWITCH PACK ON INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The 7-Pack Remote Air Solenoid Module (RASM) is an optional feature that provides switched air valve
                solenoids on the chassis. Up to two Modules may be installed on the vehicle allowing up to 14 air driven
                features to be installed on the vehicle. The ESC must be programmed to operate these solenoids with
                inputs from the 6 switch packs in the cab.
            </para>
            <para>The RASM communicates with the Electrical System Controller (ESC) via the body builder data link. The
                air solenoid valves in the Air Solenoid Module are typically normally closed valves.
            </para>
            <para>The RASM switches provided in the cab are 2-position. The "ICAP" programming software will determine
                which available switch positions control the air solenoids on the RASM. These switches are windowed to
                allow user to assign switch names as desired. Pressing a switch up will result in the corresponding ASM
                valve being opened to let air flow. Pressing a switch down will result in the corresponding ASM air
                valve to be switched off and stopping the flow of air. The indicator in the switch-pack will illuminate
                when the corresponding ASM air valve is switched on using the panel mounted switches and no errors are
                detected. If the air valve is on when it had been commanded off, the ignition signal to the ASM will be
                turned off and the indicator in the switch will flash quickly. All air valves will be switched off when
                accessories are off.
            </para>
            <para>The normal operation of this feature is defined as follows:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>When the key is in Accessory, all outputs will be turned off.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The switch status from the panel-mounted switches will be polled to determine if an output
                        should be turned on or off.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The status of errors will then be considered. If a panel mounted switch error is present, the
                        given output will be turned off. If the Air Solenoid Module indicates that a valve is off when
                        it should be on, the indicator will remain off. However, if the Air Solenoid Module indicates
                        that a valve is on when the valve had been commanded off, the ignition signal to the Air
                        Solenoid Module will be turned off and the indicator on the panel mounted switch will flash
                        quickly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The resulting command will be sent to the Air Solenoid Module via the body builder data
                        link.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The outputs will also be turned off when the Accessory has been turned off.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>The air solenoid module software feature will attempt to shut off the air valves if it has detected
                that an air valve is on when it had been commanded off. Likewise, under this condition, the solenoid
                ignition will also be turned off to disable the function of the Air Solenoid Module solenoids.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_411.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_413.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
