<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS - BATTERY - BATTERY POWER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BATTERY POWER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>There are three main functions of the storage battery:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>To supply power to the starter and ignition system so the engine can be cranked and started.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To supply extra power required when the vehicle's load requirements exceed the supply from the
                        charging system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To act as a voltage stabilizer by smoothing out or reducing temporary high voltage within the
                        electrical system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Vehicle batteries are connected in parallel with the positive battery cable connected to the cranking
                motor solenoid (B) terminal. Depending upon battery quantity and box location, some vehicles have two
                positive cables to the cranking motor solenoid. The additional cable reduces voltage drop during
                cranking.
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are connected to the cranking motor ground stud (G).</para>
            <para>In some cases, the negative battery terminals are also connected directly to the frame rail. The
                engine block ground, the cab, and the frame are also connected by ground cables or circuits to the
                cranking motor ground.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remote Start Terminal</title>
            <para>The remote starter terminal allows an external battery power source to either charge the vehicle
                batteries or assist in cranking the engine. Connect the external source positive cable to the remote
                start terminal and the external source negative cable to vehicle frame rail.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_182.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_184.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
