<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - 3300 Model - MULTIPLEXING (DATA LINKS)</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="s0829852" division="truck" date="08/01/2003">
        <title>MULTIPLEXING (DATA LINKS)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The electrical system on the 3300 chassis has been significantly redesigned. Unlike the electrical
                systems on previous models, which utilized point to point wiring for all input signals and output loads,
                this system uses multiplexed wiring technologies to provide control and communication between major
                functional areas of the 3300 chassis. Multiplexing simply means, communicating information through a
                small number of wires (called a data link) without requiring a wire for each piece of information. This
                information could be gauge information such as engine oil pressure, or switch information that controls
                3300 chassis functions such as headlamps. The electrical system relies on a collection of electronic
                circuit modules and software to perform 3300 chassis functions instead of implementing similar features
                using complex wire harness designs with electromechanical relays and switches. These electronic module
                components are connected together by electronic data links. These data links can be thought of as
                computer networks that allow the electronic components on the 3300 chassis to communicate with one
                another.
            </para>
            <para>The concept of multiplexing is not new to International Truck and Engine. Data links for communicating
                between engine controllers, the instrument cluster and the diagnostic connector have been used for
                several years.
            </para>
            <para>The goal of multiplexing is to reduce cab harness wiring and to simplify circuits. This is
                accomplished by using low current data link circuits for communication between cab switches and the
                electrical system controller and the instrument cluster. Other data links in the 3300 chassis allow
                other electrical controllers and the instrument cluster to communicate with each other.
            </para>
            <para>International Truck and Engine multiplexing uses two types of data links; J1708 and J1939. The J1708
                data link is often referred to as ATA and J1939 is often referred to as CAN.
            </para>
            <para>There are three separate data links used on the 3300 chassis.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Drivetrain 1939 data link - This J1939 data link provides a path for communication between the
                        engine controller, transmission controller, antilock brake system (ABS) controller, pyrometer
                        ammeter module (PAM), electrical system controller (ESC) and the electronic gauge cluster (EGC)
                        or instrument cluster.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Switch data link - This J1708 data link provides a path for communication between the switch
                        packs and ESC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1708 data link - This is the same J1708 data link (sometimes referred to as ATA) that has been
                        used in the past. This data link will be used almost exclusively for diagnostics and programming
                        of engines and other controllers.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The heart of the multiplexed system is the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f08298301">electrical system controller</hotlnk>
                (ESC). The ESC communicates with the switches on the switch data link, controllers from other features
                on the drivetrain 1939 data link and remote power modules on the body builder data link. It also
                receives input from various sensors and hard wire inputs throughout the 3300 chassis. The ESC converts
                these inputs into data to be transmitted on the data links. It is also the power source for circuits
                that feed the components, controlled by the multiplexed switches, inside and outside of the cab.
            </para>
            <figure id="f08298301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08298301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Electrical System Controller (ESC)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>(1600) 36 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1601) BROWN 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1602) 36 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1603) BROWN 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>(1604) BLUE 8 WAY SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
