<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - RE 200/RE 300 LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights With WTEC Transmission Allison GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the start or ignition position, battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13H, fuse F24, circuit A71, dash connector (2-C5), circuit
                N71, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-3), circuit K71, back-up light relay connector (7505-1) and
                a black wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light relay contacts close, power flows
                through a white wire, connector (7505-4) circuit K71A, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-4),
                circuit N71A, connector (2-G5), and circuit A71A to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#115 at connector (7204), pin 31. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "TRANS OIL TEMP" warning light, connector
                (12), pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N125, connector
                (523), circuit K#115, and ECU connector (7204), pin 31 to ground. This will cause the "TRANS OIL TEMP"
                warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights With LCT Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the start or ignition position, battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13H, fuse F24, circuit A71, dash connector (2-C5), circuit
                N71, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-3), circuit K71, back-up light switch connector (7303-11)
                and a black wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light switch contacts close, power flows
                through a white wire, connector (7303-10) circuit K71A, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-4),
                circuit N71A, connector (2-G5), and circuit A71A to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System With Tilt Column and Douglas Turn Signal</title>
            <para>Power flows from the (1F) battery feed stud through circuit A14D/A14C to fuse F14 and F15. When the
                headlight switch is in the PARK or on position, power flows through fuse F14, circuit A50A, to the
                headlight switch (23). This supplies power for the parking lights through circuit A58, and body builder
                connector (169), cavity H. Power is also applied to the panel lights through circuit A62.
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight switch is in the on position, power flows through fuse F15, circuit A50, headlight
                switch (23), circuit A51, connector (4), a green wire, and to the dimmer switch.
            </para>
            <para>With the dimmer switch in the low position, power flows through the low beam switch contacts, a blue
                wire, connector (4), and circuit A53/A53B to the body builder connector (170), cavity C.
            </para>
            <para>With the dimmer switch in the high position, power flows through the high beam switch contacts, a
                brown wire, connector (4), and circuit A52/A52B to the body builder connector (170), cavity D. At the
                same time, power is also applied to the high beam dash indicator light through circuit A52A and the
                green cluster connector (11). Ground for the light is through circuit A28-G/A11-G to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System With Stationary Column and International Turn Signal</title>
            <para>When the headlight dimmer switch is in the low beam position, and the headlight switch (23) is moved
                to the headlight on position, power flows from body builder feed stud (1F) through circuit A50, the
                closed headlight switch contacts, and circuit A66/A51A to the lift-to-dim relay (100) contacts, and
                circuit A51F to the relay coil. Power flows through the coil of relay (100) and through circuit A51D to
                the turn signal headlight dimmer switch connector (6). Power flows through the switch contacts,
                connector (6), and circuit A51-G/A11-GB to the platform ground. This energizes relay (100) and allows
                power to flow through circuit A53A/A53B to the body builder connector (170).
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight dimmer switch is moved to the high beam position, the switch contacts open and the
                ground path to relay (100) is removed, which de-energizes the relay. Power then flows through circuit
                A52C/A52B to the body builder connector (170).
            </para>
            <para>When the high beams are energized, power also flows from the A52C/A52B splice through circuit A52A,
                cluster connector (11), and the printed circuit board to the high beam indicator lamp. The indicator
                lamp is grounded through the printed circuit board, connector (11) and circuit A28-G/A11-G to the
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the headlight switch, power is also applied through circuit A50B to the flash-to-pass relay (101)
                contacts and circuit A51C to the relay coil. When the turn signal lever is pushed forward and held in
                the flash-to-pass position, power flows through the coil of relay (101), circuit A51E, connector (6),
                dimmer switch contacts, connector (6), and circuit A51-G/A11-GB/A11-G to the platform ground. This
                energizes relay (101) and allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuit A52D/A52B to the
                body builder connector (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch (Air Brakes)</title>
            <para>From the battery feed stud (1F), power is applied to circuit A14D/A14A, fuse F12, and circuit A70 to
                stop light switch (79). At the same time power is also applied through circuit A70B to stop light switch
                (78).
            </para>
            <para>When the brake pedal is depressed, the stop light switch contacts close and power is applied to
                circuits A70B and A70C to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is in the park or on position, power is applied through circuit 62,
                fuse F21, circuit A62A, and connector (22) to the panel light dimmer control. The dimmer control ground
                is through connector (22), and circuit A62-GD/A11-GA to the platform ground. The dimmer control provides
                an adjustable voltage of 0 to 12 volts to the panel light junction (8) through circuit A62H.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is applied through circuit A62C and dash cluster connector
                (11) to the center cluster lights. The lights are grounded through connector (11) and circuit
                A62-GB/A11-G to the platform ground. Power is also applied through circuit A62D and dash cluster
                connector (12) to the right cluster lights. The lights are grounded through connector (12) and circuit
                A62-GC/A11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the transmission shift lever indicator
                light (7) through circuit A62E. The light ground is through circuit A62-GE/ A11-G to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the cruise/throttle set/coast resume/accel
                switch panel light (150) through circuit A62L. The light ground is through circuit A62-GF/A11-G to the
                platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the cruise/throtte on/off switch panel
                light (150) through circuit A62M. The light ground is through circuit A62-GH/A11-G to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the panel light junction (8), power is also applied to the ATC switch panel light (150) through
                circuit A62N. The light ground is through circuit A62-GJ/A62-GH/A11-G to the platform ground. Power is
                also provided to the body builder connector (169) through circuit A62J.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Daytime Running Lights (DRL)</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to USA DRL module (165) from (1F) junction block, through circuit A66F fuse F5 and
                circuit A66A. The module is provided a ground path through circuit A66-GA/A11-GB to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When high beam/bright headlights are turned ON, a signal is sent to the USA DRL module (165) through
                circuit A66E, connector (4) and circuit A66E. Thus the module which supplies power to the fog light
                circuit A64A can switch OFF the fog lights when the high beam/bright headlights are selected.
            </para>
            <para>The USA DRL module (165) is enabled via circuit A66 when the key switch (20) is moved to the ignition
                or accessories position. The module will then apply power to circuit A66C, connector (4), circuits A66C,
                A53, connector (4), circuit A53B to the low beam elements. The module will power the lights at about 60%
                of full power. When the headlight switch is moved to headlight ON position, the power from the headlight
                switch will override the module and power the lamps at 100%.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights With Fuller Manual Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the start or ignition position, battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13H, fuse F24, circuit A71, dash connector (2-C5), circuit
                N71, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-3), circuit K71, back-up light switch connector (304-A) and
                a black wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light switch contacts close, power flows
                through a white wire, connector (304-C), circuit K71A, chassis/engine harness connector (9850-4),
                circuit N71A, connector (2-G5), and circuit A71A to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_65.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_67.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
