<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000FE LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Light System</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the on or start position, power is applied to circuit 13/13H,
                fuse F24, circuit 71, dash connector (2), circuit 71, back-up light switch connector (41) and a black
                wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light switch contacts close, power flows through a
                white wire, connector (41), circuit 71A, connector (2), and circuit 71A to the body builder connector
                (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System</title>
            <para>Power flows from the (J2) battery feed stud through circuit 14/14C to fuses F14 and F15. When the
                headlight switch is in the park or on position, power flows through fuse F14, circuit 50A, to the
                headlight switch (23). This supplies power for the parking lights through circuit 58, and body builder
                connector (169), cavity H. Power is also applied to the panel lights through circuit 62.
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight switch is in the on position, power flows through fuse F15, circuit 50, headlight
                switch (23), circuit 51, connector (27), a green wire, and to the dimmer switch.
            </para>
            <para>With the headlight switch on and the dimmer switch in the low beam position, power flows through the
                low beam switch contacts, a blue wire, connector (27), and circuit 53/53A to the body builder connector
                (170), cavity C.
            </para>
            <para>With the headlight switch on and the dimmer switch in the high beam position, power flows through the
                high beam switch contacts, a brown wire, connector (27), and circuit 52/52B to the body builder
                connector (170), cavity D. At the same time, power is also applied to the high beam dash indicator light
                through circuit 52A and the green cluster connector (11). Ground for the light is through circuit
                28-G/11-GB /11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights</title>
            <para>With the headlight switch on, power is supplied to the panel light switch (22) through circuit 62,
                fuse F21 and circuit 62A. The switch is grounded through circuit 62-GD/11-G to the platform ground (J1).
            </para>
            <para>The panel light switch applies variable voltage through circuit 62H to the bussed connector (8), and
                to the body builder connector (169) on circuit 62J. Power also flows through the bussed connector (8) to
                the yellow instrument panel connector (10) on circuit 62B, to the green connector (11) on circuit 62C,
                and to the natural colored connector (12) on circuit 62D. Power is also supplied to the automatic
                transmission shift selector light (7) through circuit 62E.
            </para>
            <para>The ground for the transmission shift selector light is through 62-GE/11-GB/ 11-G to the (J1) platform
                ground. Ground for the instrument panel lights is through the printed circuit board and circuit
                62-GA/11-G for connector (10), circuit 62-GB/11-G for connector (11), and circuit 62-GC/11-G for
                connector (12). Circuit 11-G is connected to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Turn Signal System</title>
            <para>Power for the turn signal circuitry is supplied by the (J2) feed stud through circuit 14/14A, fuse
                F13, and circuit 55 to the flasher unit (1). Power is then supplied through circuit 55A/60, turn signal
                jumper harness connector (13), and circuit 55A/60 to the turn signal switch (NL).
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the left turn position, the switch contacts close and power is
                applied to jumper harness circuit 56, jumper connector (13), and circuit 56 to a splice. From the
                splice, power is supplied to the body builder connector (169) on circuit 56C.
            </para>
            <para>From the splice, power is also applied through circuit 56B, the green dash connector (11), and a
                printed circuit board to the left turn indicator light. The light is grounded through the printed
                circuit, connector (11), and circuit 28-G/11-GB/ 11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the turn signal switch, power is also supplied to the body builder connector (170) through jumper
                harness circuit 56A, jumper connector (13), and circuit 56A.
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the right turn position, the switch contacts close and power
                is applied to jumper harness circuit 57, jumper connector (13), and circuit 57 to a splice. From the
                splice, power is supplied to the body builder connector (169) on circuit 57C. From the splice, power is
                also applied through circuit 57B, the green dash connector (11), and a printed circuit board to the
                right turn indicator light. The light is grounded through the printed circuit, connector (11), and
                circuit 28-G/11-GB/ 11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>From the turn signal switch, power is also supplied to the body builder connector (170) through jumper
                harness circuit 57A, jumper connector (13), and circuit 57A.
            </para>
            <para>When the hazard button is pushed, switch contacts close and power is applied to all of the previously
                discussed feed circuits. This causes the indicator lights to flash and any lights connected to the turn
                signal circuitry in the body builder connectors (169) and (170).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Daytime Running Lights (DRL)</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to USA DRL module (165) from (J2) junction block, through circuit 66F, fuse F5 and
                circuit 66A. The module is provided a ground path through circuit 66-GA to platform ground (J1).
            </para>
            <para>When high beam/bright headlights are turned ON, a signal is sent to the USA DRL module (165) through
                circuit 66E, connector (224) and circuit 66E. Thus the module which supplies power to the fog light
                circuit 64A can switch OFF the fog lights when the high beam/bright headlights are selected.
            </para>
            <para>The USA DRL module (165) is enabled via circuit 66 when the key switch (20) is moved to the ignition
                or accessories position. The module will then apply power to circuit 66C, connector (224), circuits 66C
                and 53A to body builder connector (170), cavity C. The module will power the lights at about 60% of full
                power. When the headlight switch is moved to the headlight ON position, the power from the headlight
                switch will override the module and power the lamps at 100%.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
