<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 5000 9100 9200 9400 9900 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 5000, 5000i, 9000, 9000i - OPERATION - ENGINE WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE, LIGHT, AND
        ALARM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0820710" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE, LIGHT, AND ALARM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The input signal to the Speedometer/Tachometer module for the engine water temperature gauge (and
                warning light and alarm) comes from a gauge sender with mechanical engines or the ECM with electronic
                engines.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>The International, Caterpillar, Cummins and Detroit Diesel electronic control systems include a sensor
                to determine engine water temperature, so the information is in the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends a signal in the form of a serial data transmission, over the ATA data link circuit (a
                positive and negative pair of twisted wires) to the Speedometer/Tachometer module through connector
                (421). The signal is also present at the ATA data link connector and water temperature can be read using
                an electronic service tool (EST). For additional information on the data link, refer to GROUP 08 -
                ELECTRICAL, Electronic Engine Controls, in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mechanical Engines</title>
            <para>With mechanical engines, a 2-wire water temperature sender (231) is installed on the engine. The
                Speedometer/Tachometer module applies 4.2 volts on circuit 29 to the sender. The sender is grounded by
                circuit 29-G/11-GC at the cylinder head ground stud. As the temperature of the sender increases, the
                resistance decreases, and vice versa, which creates the signal for the Speedometer/Tachometer module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Water Temperature Gauge</title>
            <para>The Speedometer/Tachometer module processes the signal from the sender and outputs signals to drive
                the gauge through connector (422) on circuits 29S(+), 29S(-), 29C(+) and 29C(-) to the left gauge
                cluster at connector (424). The water temperature gauge is a 4-pin electronically driven gauge that
                plugs into the gauge cluster.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Warning Light</title>
            <para>The water temperature warning light should turn ON and remain on as a bulb test, while the gauges go
                through the self test process with key ON and engine OFF.
            </para>
            <para>The water temperature warning light in the left gauge cluster receives ignition voltage (key ON)
                through cluster connector (423) from 10A fuse F4-A. The warning light ground path is through cluster
                connector (423) on circuit 29L to the Speedometer/Tachometer module connector (422).
            </para>
            <para>In response to sensor or ECM inputs indicating high water temperature, the module opens and closes a
                ground switch, causing the light to turn ON or OFF. The light remains ON as long as the condition is
                present.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm</title>
            <para>In response to sensor or ECM inputs indicating high water temperature, the Speedometer/Tachometer
                module causes the alarm to sound. The alarm will sound five short beeps when the high water temperature
                light turns ON. The alarm is an internal feature of the Speedometer/Tachometer module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alarm And Warning Light Trip Points</title>
            <para>The Speedometer/Tachometer module reports high water temperature (alarm and warning light) differently
                with electronic engines than with mechanical engines. With the electronic engines, the water temperature
                signal comes from the engine ECM over the data link. The high water temperature alarm and warning lights
                are turned ON and OFF by diagnostic messages provided by the International, Caterpillar, Cummins or
                Detroit Diesel ECM (engine controller).
            </para>
            <para>With mechanical engines and standard sensors, the trip point for the high water temperature alarm and
                warning light is programmed by International.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
