<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - LIGHT SYSTEMS - ROOF CLEARANCE AND MARKER OR SUNSHADE LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x08260lts02">
        <title>ROOF CLEARANCE AND MARKER OR SUNSHADE LIGHTS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f0826008" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0826013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Roof Clearance and Marker or Sunshade Lights Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVETRAIN J1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HEADLIGHT PARK LIGHT SWITCH (MOUNTED ON ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAB ROOF CLEARANCE AND MARKER OR SUNSHADE LIGHTS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0826008">Roof Clearance and Marker or Sunshade Lights Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The clearance or sunshade lights are connected to the park lamp circuits in the ESC. If
                        clearance lights and park lamps are inoperative refer to the
                        <hotlnk document="s082504_X082603.xml" xrefid="x082603">Marker, Park and Tail lamps section
                        </hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="x082603"/>
                        of this manual. If the clearance lights are inoperative but the park lights are working, proceed
                        with this section.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The standard cab roof clearance and marker lights are part of the basic cab design. If a sunshade is
                installed, the 5 lights are located in the sunshade.
            </para>
            <para>The lights are activated when the headlight switch is in the headlight or park position. The
                electronic gauge cluster will send a message to the ESC to command the lights on.
            </para>
            <para>The marker interrupt switch will also affect operation of the marker lights, park lights and clearance
                lights. The lights will turn on while the switch is held on, if the lights were previously off. The
                lights will turn off while the switch is held on, if the lights were previously on.
            </para>
            <para>The ESC supplies battery voltage to the roof lights, marker and identification lights.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_461.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_463.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
