<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3600, 3800, 4000FBC - POWER DISTRIBUTION SYSTEM - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Power Distribution (Battery) in 3600, With T 444E or DT 466E</title>
            <para>Power is supplied by the vehicle batteries to the engine ECM module power relay through circuit 14A, a
                40 amp fuse, and circuit 14B. From the batteries, power is also supplied to the cranking motor solenoid
                battery stud (B) through a 4/0 red wire.
            </para>
            <para>From the cranking motor solenoid battery stud (B), power is supplied to circuit 90-FL/90 going to the
                hydraulic brake booster relay (300) and hydraulic brake switch (50). Power is also supplied to circuit
                18-FL/18 going to the glow plug magnetic switch (T 444E only), and circuit 17-FL/17B going to the
                starter relay (122).
            </para>
            <para>With an I-6 engine, power is also supplied to the engine/dash connector (2A) through circuit 26-FL/26
                for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>Also from the cranking motor solenoid battery stud, power is applied through circuits 14-FL/14 and
                14A-FL/14 to the body builder feed stud (J1). The feed stud is located inside the platform at the lower
                left side of the steering column support. The alternator also supplies power to the feed stud through
                circuit 2.
            </para>
            <para>With a T 444E engine, power from a splice in circuit 14 is supplied through circuit 26 to the
                engine/dash connector (2A) for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>Through the body builder feed stud (J1), power is supplied to the fuse block power distribution center
                (1) on circuit 14A, 14B, and 14C. Power is also supplied to the key switch (63) on circuit 15, and to
                the headlight switch (60) on circuit 50. From the (J1) feed stud, power is also supplied to the
                engine/dash connector (2A) for the ammeter gauge. With an I-6 engine, this circuit is 26A, and for the T
                444E, the circuit is 26B/26A.
            </para>
            <para>A ground path is supplied to the cranking motor ground junction stud (G) through a 3/0 black cable to
                the batteries, which are grounded to the frame. Through the cranking motor ground stud (G), the
                alternator is grounded through circuit 2-G, the start relay is grounded through circuit 11-GJ/17-G, the
                cab is grounded through circuit 11-GH, and the engine is grounded through circuit 11-GS.
            </para>
            <para>With the DT 466E, the cranking motor is also grounded to the frame rail by a flat braided cable.
            </para>
            <para>With the T 444E, the engine is also grounded to the frame rail at the left side of the flywheel
                bellhousing.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to individual circuits for continuation of circuitry.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Power Distribution (Battery) in 3800, 4700FBC, and 4900FBC With T 444E, DT 466E, or
                International&#174; 530E
            </title>
            <para>Power is supplied by the vehicle batteries to the engine ECM module power relay through circuit 14A, a
                40 amp fuse, and circuit 14B. From the batteries, power is also supplied to the cranking motor solenoid
                battery stud (B) by a 4/0 red wire on the 3800 model, and a 3/0 red wire on 4700FBC and 4900FBC models.
            </para>
            <para>From the cranking motor solenoid battery stud (B), power is supplied to circuit 90-FL/90 going to the
                hydraulic brake booster relay (300) and hydraulic brake switch (50). Power is also supplied to circuit
                18-FL/18 going to the glow plug magnetic switch (T 444E only), and circuit 17-FL/17B going to the
                starter relay (122). With an I-6 engine, power is also supplied to the engine/dash connector (2A)
                through circuit 26-FL/26 for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>Also from the cranking motor solenoid battery stud, power is applied through circuit 14-FL/14 and
                14A-FL/14 to a junction feed stud (N/L) located on the cowl relay mounting bracket. The alternator also
                supplies power to the feed stud over circuit 2.
            </para>
            <para>With a T 444E engine, power from a splice in circuit 14, is supplied through circuit 26 to the
                engine/dash connector (2A) for the ammeter gauge.
            </para>
            <para>From the junction feed stud (N/L), power is supplied to the engine/dash connector (2A) for the ammeter
                gauge through circuit 26A. Power is also supplied through circuit 14D to the body builder feed stud
                (J1), located inside the cab at the lower left kick panel.
            </para>
            <para>Through the (J1) feed stud, power is supplied to the fuse block power distribution center (1) on
                circuit 14A, 14B, and 14C. Power is also supplied to the key switch (63) on circuit 15, and the
                headlight switch (60) on circuit 50.
            </para>
            <para>A ground path is supplied to the cranking motor ground junction stud (G) through a 3/0 black cable
                (with 3800) or a 2/0 black cable (with 4700FBC or 4900FBC) to the batteries which are grounded to the
                frame. Through the cranking motor ground stud (G), the alternator is grounded through circuit 2-G, the
                start relay is grounded through circuit 11-GJ/17-G, the cab is grounded through circuit 11-GH, and the
                engine is grounded through circuit 11-GS.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to individual circuits for continuation of circuitry.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Twelve Volt Power Distribution (Key Switch) In 3600, 3800, 4700FBC, or 4900FBC With T 444E, DT 466E,
                or International&#174; 530E
            </title>
            <para>Power is fed to key switch (63) on circuit 15 from body builder feed stud (J1). When key switch (63)
                is moved to ignition position, power is supplied to circuit 13, 13E, and 13F going to the power
                distribution center. Power is also supplied to circuit 12 going to the power distribution center, and
                circuit 1 going to dash connector (2), circuit 1-RW, 1A, unlabeled connector (N/L), and circuit 1A to
                the alternator ignition stud (I).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the start position, power is supplied to circuit 17C (circuit 17 with
                3600), starter interrupt connector (195), and circuit 17 (circuit 17C with 3600) to the crank inhibit
                relay (661). Power is also supplied to circuit 13, 13E, and 13F going to the fuse block power
                distribution center.
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to accessories position, power is supplied to circuit 12 going to the
                fuse block power distribution center, and circuit 1 going to dash connector (2), circuit 1-RW/1A,
                unlabeled in-line connector, and circuit 1A to the alternator ignition stud (I).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
