<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 5000 9100 9200 9400 9900 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 5000, 5000i, 9000, 9000i - DIAGNOSTICS - SENSOR FAULT DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x082073a" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SENSOR FAULT DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>With electronic or mechanical engines, electronic gauge sensor faults are reported by steering the
                gauge pointer to the 6 o'clock position and the alarm sounding three long beeps.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>With Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>The related gauge will go to the 6 o'clock position and the alarm will sound three long beeps based on
                diagnostic messages from the International, Caterpillar, Cummins or Detroit Diesel ECM. The software
                capabilities of these manufacturers are not the same, so not all defects will be reported. The EZ-Tech
                or Pro-Link 9000 EST can be used to check for engine fault codes that relate to sensor defects.
            </para>
            <para>Additionally, the EZ-Tech or Pro-Link 9000 EST can be used to monitor engine oil pressure, water
                temperature, vehicle speed and engine rpm from data link connector (137). This is the same signal sent
                to the Speedometer/Tachometer module, only accessed at a different connector.
            </para>
            <para>An open fuel sender or open fuel sender circuit (ground or signal circuit) will cause three long beeps
                and the gauge will go to 6 o'clock. Note that a shorted fuel sender or sender circuit would cause the
                gauge to read empty all of the time.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>With Mechanical Engines</title>
            <para>Not all fault conditions will be reported due to sensor characteristics. The related gauge will go to
                the 6 o'clock position and the alarm will sound three long beeps for:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">An open fuel sender or open fuel sender circuit (ground or signal circuit). Note that a
                    shorted fuel sender or sender circuit would cause the gauge to read empty all of the time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">An open or short in the oil pressure sensor or any of the three circuits connecting it
                    to the Speedometer/Tachometer module.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A shorted water temperature sender or circuit. Note that an open condition would cause a
                    very low false reading.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_38.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x_40.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08207x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
