<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, DT-466E, I-530E AND T-444E
        - OPERATION - Cruise Control/PTO System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise Control/PTO System</title>
        <para>Power is supplied to the cruise control On/Off switch (391) through key switch (24), fuse F6, and circuit
            28/97B. When the On/Off switch is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 97CF, dash connector
            (3) and circuit 97CF to ECM (379). This enables the cruise control.
        </para>
        <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch in the on position, power is also applied from the switch to the
            cruise Set/Resume switch (392) through circuit 97CA. Momentarily depressing the Set portion of this switch
            supplies a 12 volt signal to the ECM through circuit 97DH, dash connector (3), and circuit 97DH/97DJ. This
            engages the cruise control and causes the ECM to maintain the current engine RPM. If the cruise control
            speed is already set, depressing the switch in the Set position causes the engine RPM to decrease until the
            switch is released.
        </para>
        <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch (391) in the on position, depressing the Resume/Accel portion of the
            Set/Resume switch (392) supplies a 12 volt signal to the ECM through circuit 97DE, dash connector (3) and
            circuit 97DE/97DK. If the cruise control speed has not been engaged, momentarily depressing the switch
            causes the ECM to resume the last engine RPM setting. If the cruise control is already engaged, momentarily
            depressing the Resume/Accel portion of the switch will cause the engine RPM and speed to increase in small
            incremental amounts until the desired speed is reached.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control switches and circuitry are also used for in-cab control of preset, variable, and mobile
            PTO operation applications and require programming of the engine ECM.
        </para>
        <para>For information on remote PTO control for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous Information in
            CT-471 Body Builder Book.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_180.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_182.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
