<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX II BRAKE MONITOR SYSTEM - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>HYDRAULIC BRAKE WARNING MONITOR</title>
            <para>The warning monitor (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0826801">Figure 1</hotlnk>) is a small plastic box, containing a circuit board, that is
                mounted inside the vehicle with two #10 screws. The monitor is connected to the brake system by way of a
                Packard 10-way PC board edge connector.
            </para>
            <para>The monitor checks the Hydro-Max electric pump motor for continuity, and the hydraulic brake switch
                and the stop light switch for closure within a few seconds of each other. The monitor will then activate
                a warning light and alarm when a fault is detected.
            </para>
            <para>The monitor also checks the position of the flow switch contacts, and activates the warning light and
                alarm until the switch contacts open. The monitor also checks the position of the pressure differential
                switch contacts and activates the warning light and alarm if a difference in pressure closes the switch
                contacts.
            </para>
            <para>The condition of the hydraulic brake relay, its feed circuit, and its output circuit are also checked
                for power output to the pump motor when the brake switches, flow switch, or pressure differential switch
                is closed. Thus the warning light and alarm will be activated if power is not present at the motor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0826801" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0826801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Hydraulic Brake Warning Monitor</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>CONNECTOR PAD REFERENCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>A. TO FLOW SWITCH, DELTA "P" SWITCH, AND PUMP RELAY COIL</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. NOT USED</callout1>
                    <callout1>C. TO BRAKE WARNING LIGHT AND BUZZER</callout1>
                    <callout1>D. GROUND</callout1>
                    <callout1>E. TO PUMP RELAY COIL AND POWER</callout1>
                    <callout1>F. TO PUMP MOTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>G. TO BRAKE POWER SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>H. TO STOP LIGHT SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>J. NOT USED</callout1>
                    <callout1>K. NOT USED</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
