<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON 2000 SERIES&#8482; (LCT) TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ALLISON 2000 SERIES TRANSMISSION DIAGNOSTIC
        CODES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ALLISON 2000 SERIES TRANSMISSION DIAGNOSTIC CODES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Illumination of the CHECK TRANSMISSION light during vehicle operation indicates that the TCM has
                registered a diagnostic code.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODES (DTCs)</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DTCs can only be read by using service tool, running TransPro diagnostic software, capable of
                        connecting to the 9-pin diagnostic connector of the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This service manual section provides a "limited" discussion of the Allison 2000 Series diagnostic
                trouble codes (DTCs). For a complete, in-depth discussion, refer to the Allison 2000 Series Transmission
                Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Illumination of CHECK TRANSMISSION light at any time other than start-up indicates that the TCM has
                identified a fault in the transmission. At this time the TCM will set an active DTC. If the fault is
                intermittent and goes away the DTC will become inactive but will remain in history.
            </para>
            <para>Depending on the fault a DTC may be set without activating the CHECK TRANSMISSION light.</para>
            <para>All active codes are cleared during TCM power down. After 40 code free warm-up cycles, all codes will
                disappear from memory if they do not re-occur.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the service tool and TransPro software are unable to communicate with the TCM on the J1939
                        datalink perform the steps in troubleshooting table
                        <hotlnk document="s08247_36.xml" xrefid="x0824705">J1939 Data Link
                            <xref refid="x0824705"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The TransPro will display all active and historical codes in chronological order. The TCM also
                captures and stores a failure record for the last five DTCs (active or inactive). The information in the
                failure record may assist the technician in identifying the cause of the DTC.
                <emph type="bold">See the documentation accompanying the TransPro software for details on its setup and
                    use.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The TransPro can be used to clear all codes in the TCM.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
