<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Heated Mirrors and
        Motorized Right Mirror
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Heated Mirrors and Motorized Right Mirror</title>
        <para>With the key switch (452) in the ignition or accessory position, the accessory feed relay (446) is
            energized. The energized relay then provides power to circuits 12AF and 12L, 15A fuse F5-A, and circuit 78
            to the heated mirror switch (415). When the switch is moved to the on position, power is applied to circuit
            78A going to the left door harness connector (437), and circuit 78B going to the right door harness
            connector (403). From connector (437) power flows through circuit 78A, connector (31), the green wire, the
            left mirror heating element, the white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground (J9), thus causing
            the left mirror to heat up. From connector (403) power flows through circuit 78A, connector (31), the green
            wire, the right mirror heating element, the white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground (J14),
            thus causing the right mirror to heat up.
        </para>
        <para>Circuit 78 also feeds power to circuit 78D going to the right motorized mirror switch (540). When the
            switch is moved in the left direction, power is applied to circuit 78F, connector (403), circuit 78F,
            connector (31), and the yellow wiring going to the mirror motor. The ground path is through the white wire,
            connector (31), circuit 78E, connector (403), circuit 78E, switch (540), circuits 78-GB, 11-GLA, 11-GD, and
            left cab ground stud (429), thus causing the mirror to rotate to the left. When the switch is moved in the
            right direction, power is applied to circuit 78E, connector (403), circuit 78E, connector (31), and the
            white wiring going to the mirror motor. The ground path is through the yellow wire, connector (31), circuit
            78F, connector (403), circuit 78F, switch (540), circuits 78-GB, 11-GLA, 11-GD, and left cab ground stud
            (429), thus causing the mirror to rotate to the right.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_35.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_37.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
