<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - REMOTE AIR SOLENOID MODULE (7-PACK) - 7-PACK AIR SOLENOID MODULE
        INSTALLATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>7-PACK AIR SOLENOID MODULE INSTALLATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installing Solenoid Module</title>
            <para>The ICAP ESC programming software must be used to configure instrument panel switches, mounted in the
                6 pack switch modules, to control air driven features. Each air driven feature is added with the ICAP
                software. The software will determine which switch will control the feature and how the remote air
                solenoid module is configured. When more than four features are to be installed the 7-pack air solenoid
                module must be used. If more than seven features are added an additional 7-pack air solenoid must be
                installed
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s082503_X08259F.xml" xrefid="x08259f">Component Locations</hotlnk>
                for 7-pack RASM mounting locations.
                <xref refid="x08259f"/>
            </para>
            <para>The primary air source is connected to the collar on the left side of the module. An air collar on the
                front of each air solenoid is used to connect the air line to the air driven device. The electrical
                circuits are connected to the connectors on the right side of the module. Overlay harnesses are
                available to complete the electrical connections.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825987" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825987.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>7-Pack Remote Air Solenoid Module (Shown With last Solenoid Location Empty)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY AIR INPUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PORT PLUG (INSTALLED ON LAST SOLENOID)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRICAL CONNECTORS (EITHER CONNECTOR MAY BE USED. THE UNUSED CONNECTOR MUST HAVE A
                        TERMINATING RESISTOR INSTALLED.)
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SOLENOID MATING CONTACTS (BENEATH FOAM STRIP)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. AIR OUTPUT FROM SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. LOCATION OF JUMPER TO CUT TO CONVERT FIRST RASM TO SECOND RASM CONFIGURATION
                        (UNDERNEATH FIRST SOLENOID ON MODULE)
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>If more than seven features are added an additional 7-pack air solenoid must be installed. The
                additional 7-pack air solenoid module. A jumper is located beneath the location of the first solenoid,
                buried under potting material. The jumper must be cut to modify the solenoid module to operate as the
                second solenoid module. The cut jumper must be covered with an RTV sealant to prevent corrosion. An
                overlay harness is available to connect the first 7-pack air solenoid module to the second. The
                terminating resistor must be removed from the first ASM and installed in the second. Then the overlay
                harness must be connected between the open connector of the first module and the open connector in the
                second.
            </para>
            <para>The 7-pack ASM communicates with the ESC on the body builder data link. The ASM must be connected to
                the data link correctly to operate. If the vehicle isn't already configured with a body builder data
                link, circuits will have to be added. This includes connecting the ESC connector, adding a "Y"
                connector, installing overlay harnesses and insuring terminating resistors are installed. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s082503_X082524.xml" xrefid="x082524">Body Builder Data Link</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x082524"/>
                and the circuit diagram book for details.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installing Additional Solenoids</title>
            <para>Individual solenoids are only installed on the module as required to support the features on the
                vehicle. If five air driven features are installed on the vehicle, only five solenoids will be installed
                on the module. If other air driven features are added, additional solenoids will need to be added.
            </para>
            <para>The last solenoid on the module will have a plug installed on the right side of the solenoid where the
                next solenoid would be installed. This plug blocks air flow out of the solenoid. When an additional
                solenoid is installed the plug must be removed from the existing solenoid and installed on the new
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>Each additional air solenoid interlocks with the previous solenoid. The contacts of the solenoid slide
                through a foam strip to connect with the contacts of the solenoid module. The solenoid is secured to the
                module body with two Torx&#174; head screws.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825995" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825994.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Air Solenoid</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>There are three types of air solenoids: normally open, normally closed and an air horn solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>The ICAP software will determine the location of the controlling switches in the switch packs and the
                order of installation for the solenoids.
            </para>
            <para>The ICAP software will determine the order of installation for the solenoids.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X08259131A.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X08259F.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
