<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The contents of this service manual section focus on International-installed components and wiring and
                how those components function as part of the transmission electronic control system. For more detailed
                information regarding the Allison WT transmission and the Allison supplied components that are part of
                the WTEC III electronic control system, refer to the appropriate Allison service manuals.
            </para>
            <para>The World Transmission (WT) is an electronically controlled transmission designed by Allison
                Transmission. The WT Electronic Controls system consists of the following components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shift Selector and MODE Selector Button</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine, Turbine and Output Speed Sensors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission Wiring Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ECU to Transmission Wiring Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Interface Relays</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cab/Platform Overlay Wiring Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostic Data Link (Part Of The International Cab/Platform Harness)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>"CHECK TRANS LIGHT" Red Instrument Panel Light (Part of International Instrument Cluster)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Spare Input/Output Package Codes (Software)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT (ECU)</title>
            <para>The Electronic Control Unit (ECU) is a microcomputer, which is the brain of the transmission control
                system (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0824601">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The ECU contains Electronically Erasable Programmable Read
                Only Memory (EEPROM), which is programmed by Allison with a shift calibration that reflects the specific
                transmission assembly, the vehicle engine, and customer selected package of "Spare Input and Output"
                options available for controlling additional vehicle components.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0824601" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0824601.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="472px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. (634) BLACK SELECTOR CONNECTOR "S"</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. (632) GRAY VEHICLE CONNECTOR "V"</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. (633) BLUE TRANS. CONNECTOR "T"</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECU communicates with the vehicle electrical system and International-installed transmission
                control components through the transmission harness and International installed relays.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>The ECU receives inputs from:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>J-1587 Communications Link (Throttle Position)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shift Selector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Antilock Brake System's ECM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Panel Light Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Other components that are part of the Allison WT electronic control system (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0824602">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f0824602" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0824602.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Electronic Control Unit (ECU) And Its Sensor And Actuator Interfacing</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECU sends information to the vehicle electrical system controlling back-up light operation,
                prevents the vehicle engine from starting in any gear other than neutral, and provides the input signal
                to drive the vehicle's electronic speedometer. The ECU also is in direct communication with the Antilock
                Brake System Electronic Control Module (ECM) so that when the antilock system senses a wheel lockup
                condition is about to occur and modulates the brake system, the Allison WT control system senses this
                and will disengage the transmission lockup clutch (and will disengage a retarder if installed).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
