<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - INTERNATIONAL 530E I6 HEUI ENGINES - OPERATION -
        Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>
        <para>The Accelerator Pedal Position Sensor (APS) is a potentiometer type sensor which, when supplied with a 5
            volt reference signal from the Electronic Control Module (CEC), provides a linear analog voltage signal that
            indicates the driver's demand for power. The APS signal is used in calculating desired fuel quantity and
            injector timing.
        </para>
        <para>The Idle Validation Switch (IVS) is a 1/12 volt switch that provides the CEC with a redundant signal to
            verify when the pedal is in the idle position.
        </para>
        <para>These two functions are integrated into one component mounted on the accelerator pedal. The pedal assembly
            is serviceable to the extent that the APS/IVS can be replaced without replacing the complete pedal. The
            engine Electronic Control Module (CEC) determines the position of the accelerator pedal by processing the
            input signals from the Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS).
        </para>
        <para>The CEC sends a regulated 5 volt signal through the black CEC module connector (379), circuit 97U, engine
            connector (190), circuit 97U to a splice, and circuit 99C to the APS/IVS (267). The APS then returns a
            variable voltage signal (depending on pedal position) from connector (267), circuit 99A, connector (190) and
            circuit 99B to CEC module connector (379). The APS is grounded through circuit 99B/97W, connector (190), and
            circuit 97W/97BW to CEC (379).
        </para>
        <para>The CEC learns the lowest and highest pedal positions by reading and storing the minimum and the maximum
            voltage levels from the APS. In this manner the CEC "auto-calibrates" the system to allow maximum pedal
            sensitivity. The CEC auto-calibrates as the key is on, but when the key is turned off, these values are
            lost. When the key is turned on again, this process starts over. When the pedal is disconnected (or a new
            one is installed), the pedal does not need to be calibrated, as the calibration happens when the key is
            turned on.
        </para>
        <para>The Idle Validation Switch (IVS) (267) receives 12 volt ignition voltage from ignition adapter (494)
            circuits 13BBB, fuse F10A, circuit 47A and circuit 99E. When the pedal is not in the idle position (throttle
            applied), the IVS sends this 12 volt signal to the CEC over circuit 99D, clutch switch (294), connector
            (190), and circuit 99D to the CEC (379).
        </para>
        <para>The CEC (379) compares the inputs it receives on circuit 99B and circuit 97A from the APS/IVS to verify
            when the pedal is in the idle position. If the APS signal from circuit 99B indicates throttle is being
            applied, then the CEC expects to see 12 volts at IVS circuit 97A. If the APS signal, circuit 99B, indicates
            throttle is not applied, then the CEC expects to see 0 volts at the IVS circuit 97A. The timing process is
            critical between the APS and the IVS sensors. For this reason, it is very difficult to determine if the
            APS/IVS assembly is working properly using a volt-ohmmeter.
        </para>
        <para></para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_233.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_235.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
