<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FUSES AND CIRCUIT BREAKERS - 1000-4000, 7000, 8000 - Description - Fuses</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Fuses</title>
        <para>Fuses are designed to pass a given amount of current. The current flow limit is indicated by the rating or
            "Size" of the fuse (10 ampere, 14 ampere, etc.). Exceeding this limit will cause the fuse to "blow" opening
            the circuit.
        </para>
        <para>After the cause of the overload is determined and corrected, a new fuse must be installed in the circuit.
            Do not replace a "blown" fuse with a fuse of higher capacity. To do so may result in damage to electrical
            components or wiring. Where fuse failure is encountered, correct the cause of the overload and install a new
            fuse of the originally specified rating.
        </para>
        <para>Fuses for most vehicle wiring circuits are grouped together in a fuse panel (
            <hotlnk document="s08287_2.xml" xrefid="f0828701">Figure 1</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0828702">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Some fuse panels have removable fuse terminals which can be
            replaced if damaged. Most fuse panels provide space to install additional fuse terminals if needed for
            installation of accessory circuits.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0828702" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0828702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Fuse Panel (Flat Back Cowl and Metro II)</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Vehicles may have additional secondary or accessory circuits not routed through the fuse or circuit
            breaker panel. Such circuits are protected by "in line" fuses or remote mounted circuit breakers in the
            current feed wiring. Refer to vehicle circuit diagrams for remote fuse locations.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08287_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08287_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08287.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
