<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module is fed a signal from the flow switch, causing the
                monitor to turn on a brake warning light and alarm and start the hydraulic reserve pump to provide
                additional braking power. The reserve pump and brake warning system are also activated when the
                differential pressure switch (301) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is supplied through circuit 13C to
                the ignition relay (4G). The relay is grounded through circuit 13-G/11-GB to cab ground. This energizes
                the relay and switches battery power from circuit 15C, through the closed relay contacts and circuit 13
                to circuit breaker F9. From the circuit breaker, power is supplied through circuit 90U, brake diode
                connector (47), and a blocking diode assembly (48). From the diode assembly, power is supplied to
                circuit 90H, dash connector (2), circuit 90H, and the hydraulic brake relay (300). From the diode
                assembly, power is also applied to circuit 90F and the brake monitor module (49). The brake monitor
                module (49) is grounded through circuits 90-G/11-GA to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link circuit through circuit 90-FL/90/90B, dash connector (2),
                circuit 90B, fuse F21, and circuit 90C to the hydraulic brake switch (50).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch (381) contacts will be
                closed (engine is not running). A ground path is provided from the crank motor ground stud through
                circuit 11-GJ/90-G, flow switch connector (381), the switch, circuit 90R/90L, differential pressure
                switch connector (301), and circuit 90K to a splice.
            </para>
            <para>From the splice, a ground path is provided through circuit 90M, dash connector (2), and circuit 90M to
                the brake monitor module alarm input (49-A). This causes the module to switch the alarm output (49-C) to
                ground which activates the warning system. From the splice, a ground circuit is also provided by way of
                circuit 90J to the hydraulic brake relay (300), causing it to energize. With the relay energized, power
                flows through the N.C. contacts and circuit 90N to the reserve pump motor. This causes the reserve pump
                motor, which is grounded through its case, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>The monitor module continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump motor and its power supply
                through circuit 90P, dash connector (2) and circuit 90P. An alarm and warning light will activate if the
                pump motor winding opens up, if the hydraulic brake relay (300) remains closed (provides power to
                circuit 90N and the reserve pump motor) after the engine is running and the flow switch opens up, or if
                no power is supplied to the pump motor when the flow switch or differential pressure switch contacts are
                closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (49-C) to ground, the brake warning light and
                alarm are activated by power flowing through cluster connector (27), the light, cluster connector (28),
                and circuit 90T to the module.
            </para>
            <para>If the ignition key is in the off position and the truck brakes are applied, the contacts of the
                hydraulic brake switch (50) close. With the contacts closed, power flows through circuit 90DD, connector
                (47), blocking diode assembly (48), connector (47) and circuit 90F to feed the brake monitor module at
                connector (49-E). From connector (47), power is also supplied to circuit 90E and the brake monitor
                module (49-G). This signal is compared to a signal provided from stop light switch (50) and circuit 90R
                to brake monitor module (49-H). If there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits, 90E or 90R, for
                longer than 14 &#177; 5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
            </para>
            <para>When the brakes are applied, the brake switch (50) also applies voltage to circuit 97M, dash connector
                (3) and circuit 97M to the IDM2 (6011). This signals the IDM2 that the brakes have been applied.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter</title>
            <para>Power is applied from the cowl junction feed stud to circuit 14K and ignition relay (R20). When key
                switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is supplied through circuit breaker F16, circuit
                13E/13F, dash connector (2), and circuit 13F to the ignition relay coil. The relay is energized through
                ground circuit 19-G/11-GJ to the crank motor ground stud.
            </para>
            <para>With the ignition relay energized, power flows through the closed contacts and circuit 13L to fuse
                F38. From the fuse, power is supplied through circuit 19D, the fuel filter heater connector (6708) and
                circuit 19A to the fuel filter heater. The ground path is through the filter housing and its mounting
                bracket. When the temperature is 45&#176;F ( 7&#176;C) or less, the fuel filter heater switch contacts
                close and cause the heater element to activate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Water-In-Fuel Light</title>
            <para>With the key on, power is supplied through circuit breaker F16, circuit 19K to the water-in-fuel
                module (470). From the module, power is applied through circuit 19C, dash connector (2), and circuit 19C
                to fuel filter connector (6708) and circuit 19C to the fuel filter water probe.
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for the water-in-fuel module (470) is not a dedicated circuit. The fuel filter housing
                is grounded through its mounting bracket and whenever water builds up to an unacceptable level in the
                filter, the water completes the circuit between the probe contacts and the housing. This energizes the
                water-in-fuel module.
            </para>
            <para>When the water-in-fuel module becomes energized, power is applied through circuit 19L and cluster
                connector (28), pin 11, to the water-in-fuel light. This energizes the lamp as power flows through the
                lamp, cluster connector (27) and circuit 28-GB/11-GA to the cab ground stud (2G).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Suspension Low Air Pressure Warning</title>
            <para>With key switch (63) in the ignition position, power is applied through circuit breaker F15, circuit
                61 to the low air alarm (474), and circuit 61A, the air dump solenoid connector (475) and to the air
                dump solenoid. The solenoid is grounded through a circuit to connector (475) and circuit 61-G/11-GB to
                cab ground (2G). This activates the solenoid and prevents air from being inadvertently released from the
                air dump control valve while the key is on.
            </para>
            <para>With the key switch on, power is also supplied through circuit breaker F13, circuit 28 and dash
                connector (27) to the suspension low air warning light. From the warning light, power is supplied
                through cluster harness connector (28), pin 13, and circuit 40A to the low air alarm (474). From the
                alarm, power is supplied through circuit 40, air dump solenoid connector (475) and a circuit to the
                suspension low air pressure switch. When the system detects low air pressure, the switch contacts close
                which completes the circuit through a ground circuit to connector (475) and circuit 61-G/11-GB to cab
                ground (2G). This activates the alarm and warning light system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allison 2400 (LCT) Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, power is fed through the energized
                ignition relay (R20), circuit 13L/13K to fuse F36. From the fuse, power is supplied through circuits
                13K, 102, and 104 to contacts 2 and 4 of the engine/transmission harness gray connector (3031).
            </para>
            <para>With the key switch in the start or ignition position, power is also applied through circuit breaker
                F9, circuit 97P, dash connector (2), circuit 97P, and the NSBU connector (3026) to the neutral position
                switch. Providing the transmission is in neutral, power flows through the switch, connector (3026),
                circuit 97AU, dash connector (2), and circuit 97AU, 97LA, 97A to the ECM2 (6020) and circuit 97L to the
                crank inhibit relay (4H) system. This allows the crank motor to be engaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
