<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - INTRODUCTION - ELECTRICAL TEST EQUIPMENT - AMMETER
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>AMMETER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>An ammeter is used to measure current flow (amperage) in a circuit. Amperes are units of electron
                flow, which indicate how many electrons are passing through the circuit. Ohms Law indicates that current
                flow in a circuit is equal to the circuit voltage divided by total circuit resistance. Since amps (I) is
                the current in the circuit, increasing voltage also increases the current level (amps). Also, any
                decrease in resistance (ohms) will increase current flow (amps).
            </para>
            <para>At normal operating voltage, most circuits have a characteristic amount of current flow, referred to
                as current draw. Current draw can be measured with an ammeter. Referring to a specified current draw
                rating for a component (electrical device), measuring the current flow in the circuit, and comparing the
                two (the rated versus the actual measured) can provide valuable diagnostic information.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measuring Amperage</title>
            <para>An ammeter is connected in series with the load, switches, resistors, etc. (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825015">Measuring Current Flow Diagram</hotlnk>). This causes all of the current to
                flow through the meter. The meter will measure current flow only when the circuit is powered and
                operating. Before measuring current flow, we need to know approximately how much current will be present
                to properly connect the meter. The DMM is fused to measure up 10 amps using the 10A connection point.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="296px"/>
                <caption>Measuring Current Flow Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DMM SET TO MEASURE DC CURRENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FUSE SHOWN REMOVED</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LIGHT BULB (2 OHMS RESISTANCE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. METER LEAD CONNECTED TO 10A METER JACK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The estimate of current flow can easily be calculated. In the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825015">Measuring Current Flow Diagram</hotlnk>, the resistance of the light bulb is 2
                ohms. Applying Ohms Law, we can calculate that current flow will be 6 amps (6A = 12V/2 ohms). If we
                remove the fuse, and install the ammeter as shown, with the switch closed we will measure 6 amperes of
                current flowing in the circuit. Notice that the ammeter is installed so that all the current in the
                circuit flows through it. The ammeter is installed in series.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never attempt a voltage measurement with the test probe lead in the current jack (10A or
                        300mA). Meter damage or personal injury may result!
                    </para>
                    <para>Always make sure the power is off before cutting, soldering or removing a circuit component to
                        insert the DMM for current measurements. Even small amounts of current can be dangerous.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Excessive current draw means that more current is flowing in a circuit than the fuse and circuit were
                designed for. Excessive current will open fuses and circuit breakers. Excessive current draw can also
                quickly discharge batteries. An ammeter is useful to help diagnose these conditions.
            </para>
            <para>On the other hand, there are times reduced current draw will cause a device (electric window motor for
                example) to operate poorly. Remember increased circuit resistance causes lower current to be available
                to the device. Loose or corroded connections can frequently cause this problem.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
