<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - TWO-SPEED AXLE (AIR OPERATED)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TWO-SPEED AXLE (AIR OPERATED)</title>
        <para>An air shifted two-speed axle is available with the Allison WTEC III transmission. The two-speed axle
            shifts from high speed (low gear reduction) to low speed (high gear reduction) when the driver moves the
            two-speed switch to low position, the WTEC III ECU determines that the accelerator pedal is at idle, and the
            transmission output speed is below a preprogrammed value. A 12 volt signal is then fed to the engine ECM to
            adjust the speedometer and odometer readings for the different axle reduction ratio.
        </para>
        <para>When the two-speed axle switch is in high speed position, a ground is not applied to the Allison ECU
            connector (632)/pin 12, nor is a 12 volt signal applied to the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM (379)/pin 28.
            However, power flows through fuse F14, circuit 93, connector (14), circuit 93, connector (495), circuits 93E
            and 93G, the normally closed contacts of relay (488), circuit 93C, connector (495), circuit 93C, connector
            (14), circuit 93C, connector (13), and a red wire, to the brown wire of the energized axle solenoid.
        </para>
        <para>When the two-speed axle switch is moved to the low speed position, a signal ground is applied to the
            Allison ECU (632)/pin 12 by way of circuit 153, connector (466), circuit 93F, connector (495), circuit 93F,
            switch and connector (75), circuit 93, connector (495), circuit 93, connector (466), and circuit 161 to ECU
            (632) signal ground pin 31. This causes the ECU (632) to switch pin 2 to ground if the output speed of the
            transmission is below the programmed minimum. This causes power that is flowing through fuse F14, circuit
            93, connector (14), circuit 93, connector (495), and circuit 93E to the two-speed relay (488)/pin 86 and
            also through circuit 93G to pin 30, to flow through the coil of the relay and its ground path. The ground
            path is through circuit 93D, connector (466), and circuit 114 to the ECU (632)/pin 2 that just switched low
            (to ground). This energizes the two-speed relay (488) which removes power to the axle solenoid causing the
            axle to shift into low speed. When relay (488) energizes, a 12 volt signal is also applied to circuit 93B,
            connector (495), circuit 93B, connector (14), circuit 93A, connector (2), and circuit 93A to the Diamond
            LogicNavpaktrade; ECM (379)/pin 28 to adjust the speedometer and tachometer readings.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
