<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS From 01/01/1998 to 02/07/2004 - MISCELLANEOUS -
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OEM Installed Heater Blower Motor Circuitry</title>
            <para>Power is supplied through circuit breaker F8 and circuit 75A to the contacts of the blower motor relay
                (4I). When key switch (63) is in the accessories or on position, power is supplied through the key
                switch and circuit 12 to fuse F18. Power is applied through the fuse and circuit 75 to the coil of the
                relay. The relay is grounded through circuit 75-G/11-GB to cab ground (2G). This causes the relay to
                energize.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay energized, power is applied through the closed contacts and circuit 75C to the body
                builder connector (589). This connector is provided for use by the body builder to supply the heater fan
                switch and motor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OEM Installed Cargo Light Circuitry</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to the body builder connector (589) through fuse F5 and circuit 63 for the body
                builder installed cargo light circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OEM Installed Wiper Control Circuitry For Dual Wiper Motors</title>
            <para>Power and ground circuits are provided in the platform harness for completion by the body builder.
                With the key switch in the accessories or on position, power is supplied to the wiper motor and washer
                pump controls through fuse F18 and circuit 82 to the body builder connector (589). Ground for the
                controls is through the body builder connector and circuit 82-G/11-GB to the cab ground (2G).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OEM Installed Freon Compressor Clutch Circuitry With 1652SC</title>
            <para>The engine harness provides for power to be supplied through dash connector (2) cavity G and circuit
                77F to the freon compressor clutch connector.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
