<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS -
        OPERATION - Cranking Motor Systems And Circuits
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cranking Motor Systems And Circuits</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cummins and Caterpillar Engines</title>
            <para>With the key switch (24) in the start position (with key start) or the key switch in the ignition
                position and push button (135) depressed (with push button start), current flows from the (J1) junction
                block through circuit 15, key switch (24), circuit 17, and the starting motor magnetic switch to ground.
                This energizes the starter magnetic switch.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power from the (J1) junction block circuit 14 is always present at the positive stud of the
                magnetic switch. With the cranking motor magnetic switch energized, battery power is applied through
                circuit 17B to energize the crank motor solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the crank motor solenoid energized, the solenoid engages the cranking motor and battery power
                causes the motor's shaft to rotate. When the starter switch is released, a spring returns the solenoid
                to the released position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>International Electronic Engines</title>
            <para>When the key switch (24) is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 13A and 13B to fuse
                F17. From the fuse, power flows through circuit 97P, the 45-pin bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and the
                circuit 97P to neutral position switch connector (438) at the transmission.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, a jumper cable is installed at this connector to connect circuit 97P with
                97AU.
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, this connector is connected to the neutral position switch and when
                the transmission is in neutral, the switch contacts are closed and power flows through the switch
                contacts.
            </para>
            <para>From connector (438), power is applied through circuit 97AU, bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and
                circuit 97AU to clutch switch connector (386).
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, a jumper is installed at this connector to connect circuit 97AU with
                circuits 97A and 97L. With the transmission in neutral, power is supplied through circuit 97A, the
                22-pin bulkhead connector (3) and (3A), and circuit 97A to the ECM. Power is also applied to the crank
                inhibit relay (661) contacts through circuit 97L. When the transmission is in gear, power is removed
                from the ECM and the relay.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, connector (386) is connected to the clutch pedal switch. When the clutch
                pedal is in the released position, power flows through the switch contacts, circuit 97A, bulkhead
                connector (3) and circuit 97A to the ECM. When the clutch pedal is depressed, power is switched from the
                ECM circuitry and is applied through circuit 97L to the crank inhibit relay (661) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (24) is turned to the start position, or push button depressed, (135) with air
                brakes or (521) with hydraulic brakes, power is applied through circuit 17 to the crank inhibit relay
                (661) coil windings.
            </para>
            <para>When the automatic transmission is in neutral, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM
                is supplied with 12 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the
                crank inhibit relay (661) by providing a ground to the relay coil through circuit 97H, bulkhead
                connector (3) and (3A), and circuit 97H.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission and clutch pedal depressed, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of
                the ECM is at 0 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the crank
                inhibit relay (661) by providing a ground through circuit 97H, bulkhead connector (3) and (3A), and
                circuit 97H to the relay.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM is programmed for the type of transmission installed and adjusts for the different
                        voltages received at the ECM driveline disengagement terminal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The energized crank inhibit relay controls the start relay (387) by providing power through circuit
                17F, bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and circuit 17F to the relay. This energizes the start relay which
                is grounded through circuit 17D, and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is always present at the crank motor solenoid (B) terminal through the positive battery
                cable. Power is also available at the start relay (387) through the solenoid (B) terminal and circuit
                17-FL/17B. With the start relay energized, power flows through the relay contacts and circuit 17C to the
                (S) terminal of the crank motor solenoid which energizes the crank motor solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the crank motor solenoid energized, the solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to rotate. When
                the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank inhibit relay (661)
                which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay (387) to be de-energized and disengages the
                crank motor.
            </para>
            <para>As long as the engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection</title>
            <para>On vehicles with thermal overcrank protection, the cranking motor magnetic switch (or start relay with
                International electronic engines) control coil ground circuit 17D is connected to the normally closed
                thermal switch (417). The thermal switch is located in the end of the cranking motor. The thermal switch
                is grounded through connector (417), circuit 17-G and 11-G (17-G/11-GJ with International electronic
                engine) to the cranking motor ground (G) stud.
            </para>
            <para>If excessive cranking causes cranking motor temperature to reach pre-set thermal overcrank limits, the
                thermal switch opens causing the starter magnetic switch [or start relay (387) with International
                electronic engine], to de-energize, turning off power to the cranking motor solenoid (S) terminal,
                disengaging the cranking motor.
            </para>
            <para>When the crank motor cools, the switch closes, permitting the crank motor to operate again.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_60.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
