<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - 3300 Model - ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER AND SWITCH PACKS -
        SWITCH PACK MODULES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x08298013">
        <title>SWITCH PACK MODULES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>FUNCTION</title>
            <figure id="f08298415" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08298415.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Switch Pack Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 12 PACK SWITCH MODULE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 6 PACK SWITCH MODULE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f08298415">switch pack modules</hotlnk>
                contain the electronics required to communicate with the ESC, on the switch data link, and the
                electronics for each switch receptacle.
            </para>
            <para>Switch packs are available in 3, 6 and 12 switch configurations. The 12 pack configuration uses 2 of
                the 6 pack circuit boards.
            </para>
            <para>The 3 switch pack module does not have serial connections to support additional modules.</para>
            <para>The mechanical assembly for each switch snaps into the switch receptacle and can be released from the
                rear of the switch pack. Different mechanical assemblies determine the actuation of the switch. Blank
                covers are used when a switch receptacle is not being used.
            </para>
            <para>The function of each switch location is programmed in the ESC as well as the output from the ESC to
                the appropriate feature controlled by the switch.
            </para>
            <para>The EZ-Tech&#174; running the "Diamond Logic Builder&#8482;" diagnostic software can be used to
                identify the programmed function of each switch and to override the switch input to the ESC. See the
                diagnostic software manual for details on using the software.
            </para>
            <para>Amber LED's are used for panel lighting of the switches. Green LED's, as required, are used to
                indicate that the switch is on. Both types of LED's are replaceable.
            </para>
            <para>Switch packs are daisy chained together. The first switch pack connected to the instrument panel
                harness is identified as switch pack #1. The next switch pack (connected to first switch pack) will be
                identified as switch pack #2. A maximum of four switch packs could be installed on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>The 3 switch pack module does not have connections to support additional modules.</para>
            <para>Switches are identified by number from left to right.</para>
            <para>When switches or switch packs are added or relocated, the ESC must be programmed before the changes
                will work. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s08298_X08298012.xml" xrefid="x08298012">ESC Programming</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If more than one switch pack is being used and the switch pack positions were swapped, the
                        switch functionality may also swap or may not work at all. Be sure not to unintentionally swap
                        positions when working on switches or switch packs.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_X08298212.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
