<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC
        CODES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0824603" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING WITH DIAGNOSTIC CODES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The tests in this section are written to be performed by reading the diagnostic codes using the shift
                selector and the Fluke 88 multimeter. In many cases an electronic service tool can be used for reading
                the codes and performing some system diagnostics if the proper software is available. Note that if
                battery power is not present at the ECU, the electronic service tool will not be able to read the codes
                or perform other diagnostics.
            </para>
            <para>When beginning the troubleshooting process, always check for ACTIVE diagnostic codes first.
                <emph type="bold">The codes listed in this service section are only those codes that are likely to be
                    involved with International-installed components and harnesses.</emph>For a full listing of
                diagnostic codes, refer to the Allison WT Service Manual and WTEC III Controls and General Information
                Manual.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Low transmission oil levels, low battery power, battery power interruptions and intermittent
                        ground connections can cause many diagnostic codes to be registered.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before diagnosing any fault codes:</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check transmission oil level.</para>
            </step1>
            <para></para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824603">ECU and Shift Selector Power and Ground
                        Circuits</hotlnk>, Table 3. Look carefully for (and correct) conditions that can cause
                    intermittent conditions such as:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loose, dirty, corroded or painted connections.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check related relays and fuses for overheating or open condition.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check for damaged, chafing wires.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 13 Sub Code 12, 13, or 23 - ECU Input Voltage</title>
            <para>This code means the ECU has detected either a high, medium low, or low battery input voltage. The ECU
                monitors battery voltage input levels to its connector (632)/pins 136 and 136A, and shift selector
                (420)/pin R. LOW voltage is considered less than 8 volts, medium low voltage is considered 10 volts, and
                HIGH voltage is considered more than 32 volts. Common causes for this code are usually vehicle wiring
                conditions, vehicle charging system and batteries, or poor ground conditions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECU turns OFF when voltage drops to approximately 7.0 volts.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Perform test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824603">ECU and Shift Selector Power and Ground
                    Circuits</hotlnk>, Table 3.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 23 Sub Code 12 or 16</title>
            <para>This code indicates a fault with the shift selector assembly or the harnesses that connect it to the
                ECU.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear active codes as explained in
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_29.xml" xrefid="x0824604">Clearing Diagnostic Code Indicator</hotlnk>. If
                    code 23 XX re-occurs, go to step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for poor connections at connectors (420) and (634).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Go to test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824605">Shift Selector Harness Circuitry</hotlnk>, Table
                    5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no problem found with circuitry have Allison dealer diagnose and replace selector if
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If condition persists, replace ECU.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 26 Sub Code 00 or 11</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the ECU has not detected either a throttle source or an engine coolant
                temperature source.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When code 26 00 is logged and the throttle signal is being supplied via the J1587
                    communications link, refer to code 66 00 for troubleshooting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When code 26 11 is logged and the engine coolant temperature is being supplied via the
                    J1587 communications link, refer to code 66 00 for troubleshooting.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 35 Sub Code 00 or 16 - Power Interruption</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the ECU detected a complete battery power loss before the ignition was turned
                off. This code cannot be displayed as an active code, but will be displayed only after power is
                restored.
            </para>
            <para>When this happens, the ECU is not able to save the current operating parameters in memory before
                turning itself off.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On vehicles equipped with a master switch, turning off the master switch before turning
                    off the ignition switch can cause this code.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If improper switch sequencing is not the cause, check ECU power and ground circuits (see
                    test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824603">ECU and Shift Selector Power and Ground
                        Circuits</hotlnk>, Table 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If all system power and ground connections are satisfactory and problem persists, have
                    Allison dealer diagnose and replace ECU if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 62 Sub Code 32 or 33</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the engine coolant temperature sensor or circuit has failed. Code 62 32
                reports that the reading is below operational values. Code 62 33 reports that the leading is above
                operations values.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If code 66 11 is present refer to test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824604">J1708 Communications Link</hotlnk>, Table 4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to engine troubleshooting guide to diagnose problem with coolant temperature
                    sensor or circuits to engine ECM if code 66 11 is not present.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Main Code 66 Sub Code 00 or 11</title>
            <para>This code indicates that the Allison ECU detects a problem getting information over the J1708 (Serial
                Communications Interface) data link.
            </para>
            <para>Code 66 00 reports that the link is not functioning.</para>
            <para>Code 66 11 reports that the Allison ECU cannot find a source for the engine coolant temperature.
            </para>
            <para>These codes can also be set if the J1939 communications link communications fail.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use an electronic service tool to check for throttle and coolant temperature signals. If
                    no data communications are present refer to test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824604">J1708 Communications Link</hotlnk>, Table 4. If
                    problem not found, go to step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the engine warning lights or electronic service tool check for engine throttle or
                    coolant temperature fault codes, If no problem found, go to step 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reprogram/replace engine ECM if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
