<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - FE 300 BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING
        SYSTEMS - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="8">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before beginning these test procedures, do the following:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Make sure the vehicle batteries are at 75% state of charge (SOC) or higher. This represents an
                        open circuit voltage (OCV) of 12.4 volts. Batteries with an OCV of 12 volts or less are either
                        completely discharged or have a dead cell.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check any light or indicator lamp filaments that are suspected of being open (burned out).
                        This is done to avoid unnecessary extensive circuit checks.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect all connectors for loose or damaged pins, wires, etc. Refer to TEST EQUIPMENT AND
                        CONNECTOR REPAIR section in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the technician determines that a fuse is blown, while checking its condition, he is
                        directed to locate the cause of the overload condition and to repair it. While no further
                        instruction on this procedure is listed in the diagnostic tables, the common procedure is as
                        follows: isolate sections of the circuit by disconnecting connectors, and measure the resistance
                        to ground to find the circuit that is shorted to ground. Then locate the damaged spot in the
                        wire or connector and repair.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics for circuits that are malfunctioning by sticking in the on position are generally
                        not covered in detail. It is assumed that the technician knows to check for a malfunctioning
                        switch, relay, or solenoid.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Batteries and Cables</title>
            <para>The standard battery system for the FE 300 consists of two 12V maintenance-free batteries.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When handling batteries, always wear face or eye protection, have water supply available,
                        assure good ventilations, and be sure no open flames are present.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829601">
            <title>Batteries and Cables - Battery Test Procedure
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829613">(Figure 13</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>Test each battery separately.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both battery terminals at each battery. Check each battery visually.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine the hydrometer eye (if no eye go to next step).</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Eye shows green - go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Eye shows dark - recharge, then go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Eye shows yellow - replace battery.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a 300A load for 15 seconds. Turn off load and wait one minute.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If 12.4V or more - go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If less than 12.4V - recharge, then repeat step 3.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a test load equal to 50% of the battery CCA rating at 0&#176;F. After 15 seconds,
                    <emph type="bold">with the load still applied,</emph>
                    measure and record terminal voltage __________. Turn the load off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Estimate the battery temperature. If measured voltage does not meet or exceed the value
                    shown in the following table, replace the battery.
                </para>
                <table id="t0829605">
                    <tgroup cols="6">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.02in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.92in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.99in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="1.02in"/>
                        <colspec colname="col6" colwidth="1.05in"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                    <para>Temp.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                    <para>21.1&#176;C</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                    <para>10&#176;C</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4" align="center">
                                    <para>-1.1&#176;C</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5" align="center">
                                    <para>-9.4&#176;C</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col6" align="center">
                                    <para>-17.8&#176;C</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                    <para>Temp.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                    <para>70&#176;F</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                    <para>50&#176;F</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4" align="center">
                                    <para>30&#176;F</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5" align="center">
                                    <para>15&#176;F</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col6" align="center">
                                    <para>0&#176;F</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                    <para>Min. Volts</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                    <para>9.6</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                    <para>9.4</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col4" align="center">
                                    <para>9.1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col5" align="center">
                                    <para>8.8</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col6" align="center">
                                    <para>8.5</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all cable ends and terminals of the battery with a wire brush.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0829613" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829608.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Battery Test Procedure</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Batteries and Cables - Battery Cable Voltage Loss Test (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829614">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </title>
            <para>Slow cranking is often caused by high resistance in the battery cables or connections, especially in
                cold weather. After all batteries check good (
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829601">Battery Test Procedure</hotlnk>) and terminals are clean and tight, check the
                battery cables. To do this, place a specific load on the batteries at the starter and measure the
                voltage drop in each cable. This load will be supplied by the adjustable carbon pile.
            </para>
            <para>The voltage drop in the positive cable plus the voltage drop in the negative cable equals the
                difference between the battery voltage and the starter voltage due to the cables. The maximum acceptable
                loss has been calculated only for the specific load specified in the test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten nuts holding battery cables to the solenoid and starter terminals.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The solenoid BAT terminal is at battery voltage when batteries are connected.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect carbon pile positive lead to starter solenoid BAT terminal and negative lead to
                    starter ground terminal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect voltmeter from the starter solenoid "B" terminal to battery positive post.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn carbon pile on and adjust load to 500A. Read and record positive cable voltage
                    drop. Turn off the load and allow carbon pile to cool.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect voltmeter from negative battery post to starter ground terminal (October 1996
                    and later) or to battery frame ground (before October 1996). Attach leads directly to ground studs
                    and not the cables.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn carbon pile on and adjust load to 500A. Read and record negative cable voltage
                    drop. Turn off the load.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>POSITIVE CABLE Voltage Loss (step 4) __________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
            </para>
            <para>NEGATIVE CABLE Voltage Loss (step 6) __________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
            </para>
            <para>TOTAL CABLE LOSS__________</para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.6V or less</emph>, go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829602">Starting Motor System Circuits and Components.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>If total cable loss
                <emph type="bold">is greater than 0.6V,</emph>
                repair or replace cable(s) with excessive voltage loss and retest.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0829614" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829609.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Battery Cable Voltage Loss Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829602">
            <title>Starting Motor System Circuits and Components</title>
            <para>This section consists of five parts:
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829606">Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829605">Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 2</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829611">Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829607">Starter Motor Replacement Test</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829603">Testing Thermal Overcrank Protection System</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829606">
            <title>Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829615">Figure 15</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>Starter shifting in and out, or not pulling in, is often caused by high resistance in the starter
                solenoid circuit. When the solenoid circuit has excessive voltage loss, the starter pinion sometimes may
                not engage the flywheel. If it does engage, it may drop out too soon when battery voltage drops. The
                solenoid circuit includes the starter relay switch (located front side of platform) and leads connected
                to the starter solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>On vehicles with
                <emph type="bold">overcrank protection</emph>, refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829603">Testing Thermal Overcrank Protection System</hotlnk>
                <emph type="bold">before performing this test.</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect starter relay circuit K17A from the starter solenoid "S" terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the carbon pile positive lead to circuit K17A and the negative lead to the
                    starter ground. Connect the positive lead of a DMM voltmeter to the solenoid "B" terminal. Connect
                    negative lead of voltmeter to switch wire lead K17A (not to carbon pile clamp). Meter will show
                    battery voltage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Have an assistant turn the key switch to the start position or push start button.
                    Voltmeter reading should be zero. You should hear the starter relay switch energize with a clicking
                    sound. If the switch doesn't "click," either the starter relay switch is defective or there is no
                    voltage from the key switch circuit (refer to diagnostic test,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0829611">Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on and adjust the carbon pile to 50 amp load (for no more than 10 seconds). Read
                    and record __________ voltage on voltmeter. Release start switch. Turn off and disconnect carbon
                    pile and voltmeter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.5 volt or less</emph>, solenoid circuitry is OK. Go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829611">Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is more than 0.5 volt</emph>, go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829605">Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 2.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0829615" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829610.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829605">
            <title>Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 2
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829616">(Figure 16</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>If voltage loss in Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1 was more than 0.5 volt, the loss is
                excessive. The loss may be from loose terminals, corrosion, or a worn out starter relay switch. To
                locate the problem:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect circuit K17A from "S" terminal at starter solenoid. Connect carbon pile to
                    circuit K17A and to starter ground terminal. Turn the carbon pile on (will show 0 amps).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect starter relay and install a jumper lead from cavity 4, circuit K17A to cavity
                    1, circuit K17B.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Test lead will be at battery voltage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Connect DMM from solenoid BAT terminal to start relay connector cavity 1, circuit K17B (will show
                    zero volts).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At relay connector, install other end of jumper lead to cavity 4, circuit K17A Turn on
                    and adjust carbon pile to 50 amp load (no more than 10 seconds). Read and record first wire voltage
                    loss. Disconnect DMM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At relay connector, connect DMM from cavity 4, K17A to circuit K17A at carbon pile.
                    Connect to terminal and not to carbon pile clamp.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on and adjust carbon pile to 50 amp load (no more than 10 seconds). Read and record
                    second wire voltage loss. Disconnect and remove jumper lead and DMM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>First Wire Loss (step 3) __________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Second Wire loss (step 5) __________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Total Wiring Loss = __________(0.4V maximum loss)</para>
            <para>If wiring loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.4 volt or less,</emph>
                replace starter relay and retest per Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1.
            </para>
            <para>If wiring loss
                <emph type="bold">is more than 0.4 volt,</emph>
                repair or replace wire(s), and retest per above mentioned test, Part 1.
            </para>
            <para>If retest results are still above 0.5 volt loss, replace starter relay and retest per above mentioned
                test, Part 1.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0829616" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829611.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 2</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829611">
            <title>Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829617">Figure 17</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>A starter relay switch that does not close or drops out too soon can be caused by high resistance or
                an open in the control circuit.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect (insulate with tape) circuit K17A from starter solenoid "S" terminal. Connect
                    voltmeter to the starter BAT and GND terminals. Turn key switch on. Read and record battery cable
                    voltage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle in neutral and key switch turned to start position, you should hear the
                    starter relay "click." If not, proceed anyway. Read and record starter relay circuit voltage.
                    Release starter switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Battery Cable Voltage (step 1) _________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                Starter Relay Circuit Voltage (step 2) _________
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
                Control Circuit Loss = _________
            </para>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.5 volt or less</emph>
                and the starter relay switch closes, end the test.
            </para>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.5 volt or less</emph>
                and the starter relay switch doesn't close, replace the switch and repeat the test.
            </para>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is more than 0.5 volt</emph>and the starter relay switch doesn't close, replace switch
                and repeat test.
            </para>
            <para>If circuit loss
                <emph type="bold">is more than 0.5 volt</emph>
                and the starter relay switch closes, refer to Engine Diagnostic Manual EGES-175 (DT 466E/530E) or
                EGES-190 (T444E) for engine cranking circuit diagnostic procedures.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0829617" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829612.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829607">
            <title>Starter Motor Replacement Test (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829618">Figure 18</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <para>A. COLD WEATHER STARTER RELAY SWITCH PROBLEMS</para>
            <para>If all tests from Battery Test Procedure through Starter Relay Switch Circuit Test have been
                performed, the vehicle batteries and starter wiring have been checked.
            </para>
            <para>The starter relay switch can fail to "hold in" during cold weather cranking due to low voltage, even
                though the switches and circuits check OK. This failure sounds as though the starter is failing to stay
                engaged to the flywheel. It is caused by low system voltage releasing the starter relay switch.
            </para>
            <para>If this condition exists, remove starter relay switch. At the connector, using suitable jumper wire,
                attach one lead to circuit K17B and the other to circuit K17A
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: Circuit K17B is at battery voltage and the engine should crank when the other
                    end of the jumper is connected to circuit K17A. Remove jumper to stop cranking.
                </emph>
                If engine cranks properly with jumper in place, replace starter relay switch and make sure starter
                mounting bolts are tight.
            </para>
            <para>B. CHECKING AVAILABLE VOLTAGE AT STARTER</para>
            <para>If all previous tests have been performed, the vehicle batteries and starter wiring have been checked.
                If the engine still cranks slowly, check available voltage at the starter.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While cranking engine, measure voltage between the starter "BAT" terminal and starter
                    ground.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is 9.0 volts or more, the problem must be in the starter (or engine).
                        Replace the starter.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the voltage is less than 9.0 volts, go to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the interconnecting cable between the batteries. While cranking, measure the
                    terminal voltage of each battery by touching voltmeter leads to the post of each battery.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the difference between any two battery readings in the same battery box is more
                        than 0.5 volt or any cable is warm to the touch, replace the interconnecting cables.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If cables check OK, the problem must be in the starter (or engine). Replace the
                        starter.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0829618" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829613.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Starter Motor Replacement Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829603">
            <title>Testing Thermal Overcrank Protection System</title>
            <table id="t0829606">
                <title>Testing Thermal Overcrank Protection System</title>
                <tgroup cols="7" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="0.57in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.58in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="1.65in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="7" colwidth="1.29in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">STEP</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">KEY</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ACTION</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">TEST POINTS</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">YES- IN SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">NO-OUT OF SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Remove connector (N/L) from thermal switch and measure resistance across switch
                                    terminals (starter motor must not be hot).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Thermal sw. across term.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60; 1 ohm.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace crank motor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Start</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>With key in start position, at connector (N/L) measure voltage to ground at
                                    circuit K17D.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(N/L), K17D to gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0829606">Starter Solenoid Circuit Test - Part 1.</hotlnk>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Start</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>With key in start position, at connector (N/L) measure voltage between circuits
                                    K17D and K17-G.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(N/L), K17D to K17-G.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Repair open in circuit K17G or K11-GJ to cranking motor ground stud.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Thermal overcrank circuits check good.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Charging System</title>
            <para>This section consists of five parts: Batteries Undercharged, Alternator Tests,
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829608">Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829609">Alternator Replacement Test</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829612">Ammeter Gauge</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Batteries Undercharged</title>
            <para>Before beginning test procedures: check battery cables and alternator wiring (especially grounds) for
                clean, tight connections. Wires and connectors should not be damaged or corroded.
            </para>
            <para>Perform the following checks before removing the alternator from the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Accessories having been left on for an extended time.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check alternator drive belt tension (refer to GROUP 12 - ENGINE, Cooling in the Master
                    Service Manual for belt tension specifications). As a general rule, if the alternator fan can be
                    rotated by pulling on the fan with one finger, the belt is too loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for defective batteries as described in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Battery Section
                    in the Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wiring defects. Visually check wiring, clamps and connections for clean, tight
                    connections, free of damage and corrosion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine off, check voltage to ground at the (+) terminal of the alternator. A
                    zero reading indicates an open in circuits K2, K14A, K14-FL, or K14A-FL between the alternator and
                    batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A defective component or wiring defect may be causing a small current drain that is less
                    than the fuse rating for the circuit so the fuse does not open. To locate the unwanted current
                    drain:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Batteries should be fully charged for the following test.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">KEY OFF - turn all accessories and controls off. Disconnect circuit 2 from the
                        alternator B terminal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To check entire system for current drains, insert DMM leads in the COM and 10A fused
                        jack on the meter. Set the meter to DC Amps. Connect meter in series with the alternator. If
                        meter leads are not connected with correct polarity, a (-) amp reading will be present.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Some current draw will be present. If the current draw is less than 0.3A move the
                        lead from the 10A jack to the 320mA jack to read the exact current flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Refer to the Battery Power Distribution circuit diagrams in CTS-5216V. Remove the
                        battery feed fuses one at a time, while monitoring the meter for any change in current flow.
                        Note that some circuits (such as clock or radio or engine computer, etc.) should be drawing some
                        current. Look for current draw in circuits that should not be active.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0829608">Perform Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator Tests</title>
            <para>The alternator output must reach the batteries and accessory loads with a minimum amount of voltage
                loss. Any loss slows the rate of charge to the batteries and can cause the batteries to be undercharged.
                Discharged batteries can damage the starter and cause vehicle electrical components to operate
                improperly.
            </para>
            <para>Most alternators control the maximum system voltage using a voltage regulator. Maximum voltage output
                is available at the alternator BAT terminal, but if any voltage is lost in the wiring, something less
                than the maximum will reach the batteries and load devices. The greatest losses occur when the charging
                system is outputting at the maximum rated level (amps).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829608">
            <title>Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829619">(Figure 19)</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <para>Instead of using alternator current output this test uses the same amount of current but draws it from
                the batteries (must be fully charged). Using the carbon pile load, the current flows in reverse through
                the circuit without the engine running.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the carbon pile to the alternator output terminal and to ground. Connect Fluke
                    88 DMM from alternator (+) terminal to positive battery terminal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on and adjust carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Read and record
                    positive circuit voltage loss. Turn carbon pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the DMM from the alternator ground to the battery negative terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on and adjust carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Read and record
                    negative circuit voltage loss. Turn carbon pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Positive Circuit Loss (step 2) ___________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">plus</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Negative Circuit Loss (step 4) __________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
            </para>
            <para>TOTAL SYSTEM LOSS __________</para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.7V or less,</emph>
                go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829609">Alternator Replacement Test.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is greater than 0.7V</emph>, repair circuit(s) with excessive voltage loss and retest.
                Then go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0829609">Alternator Replacement Test.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0829619" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829614.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Alternator Wiring Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829609">
            <title>Alternator Replacement Test
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829620">(Figure 20)</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <para>If the wiring tests have been performed (circuits OK), adjust alternator belt and tighten mounting
                bolts and ground connections. Batteries must be near full charge with more than 12.4 volts no load
                voltage.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Voltage Output Test</title>
                - Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829620">Figure 20</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle at shop temperature, connect voltmeter between alternator BAT (+) and GND
                    (-) terminals.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With NO electrical loads turned on, start the engine. Fast idle until voltage stabilizes
                    (does not increase) for 2 minutes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and record alternator output voltage ________ V (should not exceed 15.5 volts).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If voltage reading is above 15.5V, replace the alternator.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Amperage Output Test</title>
                - Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0829620">Figure 20</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>With vehicle at shop temperature, connect carbon pile and clamp-on ammeter as shown. Clamp
                        around all wires connected to alternator B+ output terminal. (To use an ammeter without an
                        induction clamp, disconnect circuits from alternator B+ terminal. Connect meter shunt between
                        alternator B+ terminal and all circuits previously removed.)
                        <emph type="bold">CAUTION - Do not connect an ammeter without a high current shunt.</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With NO electrical loads turned on, start the engine, and speed up and retain a high RPM.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn on and adjust carbon pile until ammeter reads its highest value and record _______A.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn off carbon pile and engine.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If reading is zero (no output), the rotor should be magnetized with the alternator hooked up
                        normally. To do this , momentarily connect a jumper lead from the alternator BAT (+) terminal to
                        the indicator "I" terminal. This will restore normal residual magnetism.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Repeat steps 2, 3, and 4. If output is still zero, replace alternator.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Replacement</title>
            </para>
            <para>Replace alternator if either of the following exists:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Output voltage exceeded 15.5V.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Output current is not within 10% of the alternator rated output stamped on the alternator.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0829620" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0829615.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Alternator Replacement Test</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0829612">
            <title>Ammeter Gauge</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Ammeter circuitry contains fusible links and designated wire gauge and lengths, which must not
                        be altered.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t0829607">
                <title>Ammeter Gauge</title>
                <tgroup cols="7" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="0.57in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.58in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="1.65in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="7" colwidth="1.29in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">STEP</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">KEY</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ACTION</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">TEST POINTS</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">YES- IN SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">NO-OUT OF SPEC.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Disconnect engine cab connector (15). At engine connector (15A), measure voltage
                                    of circuit K26 to ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(15A), K26 to gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Locate cause of low or no voltage in engine harness circuit K26, then repair.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>At connector (15A) measure voltage of circuit K26A to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(15A), K26A to gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Locate cause of no or low voltage in engine harness circuit K26A or K26A-FL, then
                                    repair.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Reconnect engine cab connector (15) and disconnect connector (10) from cluster
                                    panel. At (10) measure voltage of circuit A26 to ground.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(10), A26 to gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Locate cause of no or low voltage in platform harness circuit A26, then repair.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>At (10) measure voltage of circuit A26A to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>(10), A26A to gnd.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Locate cause of no or low voltage in platform harness circuit A26A, then repair.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Install test ammeter between (J2) feed stud and circuit K14. Turn headlights on
                                    and compare readings.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Visual between gauges.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gauges read moderate discharge rate.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace vehicle ammeter.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>On</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Start engine and run at fast idle with no loads on.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Visual between gauges.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gauges read moderate discharge rate.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ammeter operation OK.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace vehicle ammeter.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
