<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 ENGINE - TROUBLESHOOTING -
        INSPECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INSPECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NO TESTS in this section require testing "into" the DDEC ECM.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="x0827801">
            <title>Before Troubleshooting</title>
            <seqlist style="alphauc">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Before troubleshooting, make sure that the vehicle batteries are fully
                            charged!</emph>Check battery cables and grounds for clean, tight connections free of damage
                        and corrosion. Many of the voltage tests included in the procedures will give misleading
                        readings if the batteries are not fully charged.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting a particular circuit, inspect connectors for pushed back, loose or
                        damaged (spread or bent), or corroded terminals, or wires with cut strands, etc. The wires and
                        connections must be free of damage or corrosion. When some connectors corrode, a light white
                        residue will be present that must be removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Before troubleshooting, inspect the suspect circuit grounds for clean, tight connections free
                        of damage or corrosion.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0827808">
            <title>Testing Relays</title>
            <para>International circuits use suppressed relays for controlling power to load devices (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0827801">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The suppression feature (a resistor circuit parallel to
                the relay coil) prevents voltage spikes from damaging electronic components in the vehicle.
                <emph type="bold">These relays must be replaced with approved International parts.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0827801" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0819801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Typical Relay</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The part number and relay circuit diagram are embossed on the relay body. The terminals are numbered
                on the relay in the same manner as in the circuit diagrams.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Relay Test Procedure</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With relay removed, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87A. If resistance is
                    less than 5 ohms, go to step 2; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87. If resistance is 100K ohms or more, go
                    to step 3; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using 12V battery source and test leads, connect (+) lead to terminal 85 and (-) lead to
                    terminal 86. If relay energizes with an audible click sound, go to step 4; otherwise replace the
                    relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While relay is energized, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87. If resistance
                    is less than 5 ohms, go to step 5; otherwise replace the relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While relay is energized, measure resistance between terminals 30 and 87A. If resistance
                    is 100K ohms or more, the relay is good; otherwise replace relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_165.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_167.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
