<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - LIGHT SYSTEMS - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights</title>
            <para>The vehicle back-up lights are a set of lamps that come ON when the vehicle transmission is shifted
                into reverse. This allows the driver to see while backing at night.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fog Lights</title>
            <para>Fog lights are rectangular halogen lights mounted in the bumper opening and are available with either
                amber or clear lenses. These lights are wired so that they are not illuminated when the headlights are
                on Hi-Beam. They will only operate with the headlight switch ON and the dimmer switch in the Low-Beam
                position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System - Headlight Circuitry With Tilt Steering Column and With Daytime Running Light
                (DRL)
            </title>
            <para>A headlight system with a turn signal lever controlled Lift To Dim (LTD) switch and a daytime running
                light (DRL) module is utilized which provides illumination for daytime safety recognition and for
                nighttime driving. The parking lights are integral with the front turn signal lamp assemblies, and are
                controlled by the three position headlight switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System - Headlight Circuitry With Stationary Steering Column and With Daytime Running Light
                (DRL)
            </title>
            <para>A headlight system with a turn signal lever controlled Lift To Dim and Flash To Pass (LTD and FTP)
                switch and LTD and FTP relays and circuitry is provided. A daytime running light (DRL) module is
                utilized to provide illumination for daytime safety recognition, and for nighttime driving. The parking
                lights are integral with the front turn signal lamp assemblies, and are controlled by the three position
                headlight switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System - Headlight Circuitry With Tilt Steering Column and With Special Wire For
                Headlights, Park, Tail, and Panel Lights
            </title>
            <para>The special wiring for the headlights, tail lights, park/marker lights, and panel lights will function
                with the ignition key switch ON and headlights switch OFF, in place of daytime running lights module. A
                headlight system with a turn signal lever controlled Lift To Dim (LTD) switch, which provides
                illumination when driving. The parking lights are integral with the front turn signal lamp assemblies,
                and are controlled by the three position headlight switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System - Headlight Circuitry With Stationary Steering Column and With Special Wire For
                Headlights, Park, Tail, and Panel Lights
            </title>
            <para>The special wiring for the headlights, tail lights, park/marker lights, and panel lights will function
                with the ignition key switch ON and headlights switch OFF, in place of daytime running lights module. A
                headlight system with a turn signal lever controlled Lift To Dim and Flash To Pass (LTD and FTP) switch,
                and LTD and FTP relays and circuitry, which provides illumination when driving. The parking lights are
                integral with the front turn signal lamp assemblies, and are controlled by the three position headlight
                switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights</title>
            <para>Panel lights are low wattage bulbs that illuminate gauges and other miscellaneous items. The panel
                light switch dims/brightens panel lights for the gauge clusters, speedo/tach module, analog clock, cigar
                lighter and the heater control, etc.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch - With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The stop light switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector and is utilized by the
                body builder stop light circuits. The stop light switches also supply parallel signals to the engine ECM
                to indicate when the brakes have been applied. The ECM uses this information to control various engine
                controlled features such as cruise control and vehicle retarder.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch - With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The stop light switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector and is utilized by the
                body builder stop light circuits. In addition, the switch also provides a signal to the hydraulic brake
                monitor module. The stop light switch also supplies a signal to the engine ECM to indicate the brakes
                have been applied. The ECM uses this information to control various engine controlled features such as
                cruise control and vehicle retarder.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
