<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - TRANSMISSIONS - AUTO NEUTRAL - AUTO NEUTRAL RELAY CIRCUITS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x0826172" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>AUTO NEUTRAL RELAY CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection Management</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s082503_520.xml" xrefid="f0825948">Auto Neutral Circuits</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f0825948"/>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The testing method for troubleshooting the electrical systems portrayed in this manual is a
                        basic voltage test. An alternative method of checking for voltage drops within a given circuit
                        may be a quicker method of identifying an exact problem.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The de-energized auto neutral relay completes the circuit path for the transmission ECU neutral start
                signal to the engine controller DDS input. This signal is 12 volts when the shifter is in neutral and 0
                volts when the transmission is in drive. This inhibits engine cranking while the transmission is not in
                neutral.
            </para>
            <para>The relay is energized, by a signal from the transmission ECU, when the engine is running and the
                transmission is in neutral. The energized relay applies 12 volts to the engine controller DDS input.
                This allows engine speed to be changed when the engine is running and the transmission is in neutral
                (for PTO operations). The output is also applied to the normally closed contact of the neutral light
                relay and the neutral safety switch input to the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>A fault in the auto neutral relay circuits may be present when the engine will not crank while auto
                neutral is selected or will crank when transmission is not in neutral. A failure in relay circuits could
                also prevent the engine from increasing RPM during PTO operations. Problems in the auto neutral relay
                circuits could be attributed to open or short circuits, a blown fuse, a failure in the transmission ECU
                or a failure in the engine controller.
            </para>
            <table id="t0826126" tblwidth="pg-wide" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Auto Neutral Relay Power Checks</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.80in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.77in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.76in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.87in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="1.52in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="3" nameend="6" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="4" nameend="6" spanname="S4T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                    <spanspec namest="2" nameend="3" spanname="S2T3"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Auto Neutral Relay Socket (4002) Power Checks</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>Check with ignition on and auto neutral relay (4002) removed.</para>
                                <para>Bench check relay and replace if it has failed. Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s082503_X0825015.xml" xrefid="x0825015">Bench Checking Relays.
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    <xref refid="x0825015"/>
                                </para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Always check connectors for damage and pushed-out terminals.</para>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Test Points</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>Spec.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>Comments</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Relay socket cavity M2-C1 to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                                <para>If voltage is missing, check for open or shorts in circuit J92J or open auto
                                    neutral fuse.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Relay socket cavity M2-C2 to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>12 &#177; 1.5 volts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                                <para>If voltage is missing, check for open in circuit J92JA.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Relay socket cavity M2-C2 to M2-A1.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>With engine on and transmission in neutral, 12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is incorrect, check for open in circuit J92A114 or L92A114. Also check
                                    for missing signal from ECU.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Relay socket cavity M2-B1 to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                                <para>With shifter in neutral and transmission in neutral, 12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is incorrect, check for open in circuit J92HM5, J92C123 or L92A123.
                                    Also check for short to ground in circuits J92HM5, J92C123, L92A123, J92HM4 or
                                    J92AY. Insure signal from ECU is present.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Relay socket cavity M2-A2 to ground.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3" align="center">
                                <para>With transmission in neutral and, 12 &#177; 1.5 volts.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is incorrect, check for open in circuit J17BC. Also check for short to
                                    ground in circuits J17BC, J17BD, J17B or L17B. Insure signal from ESC is present.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                                <para>If voltage is missing from the ESC consider replacing the ESC.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extended Description</title>
            <para>Power to the auto neutral relay coil and common contact is supply from the 5 amp auto neutral fuse.
            </para>
            <para>The relay is energized by a low signal from ECU "V" gray connector (7202) pin 2. The low signal is
                generated when the engine is running and the transmission is in neutral.
            </para>
            <para>The de-energized relay provides a circuit path for the neutral start signal from the ECU. This will be
                12 volts when the transmission is in neutral or 0 volts when the transmission is in gear. The signal is
                applied to the engine controller drive line disengagement switch (DDS) input. 12 volts will signal the
                engine controller that the transmission is in neutral.
            </para>
            <para>The energized relay applies 12 volts to the engine controller DDS input when the engine is on and the
                transmission is in neutral. This will allow the engine to increase RPM when a power take off is engaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X082615.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_X0826174.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
