<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - RE 200/RE 300 GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS -
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Oil Pressure Gauge</title>
            <para>When the engine is running, the ECM2 supplies a 5 volt signal to the engine oil pressure sensor
                through circuit K97CY. The sensor then provides a variable voltage signal to the ECM2.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Level Gauge</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuit A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuit
                A28/A28B, the green instrument cluster (11), pin 10 to the fuel gauge. The level of fuel in the vehicle
                fuel tank is sensed by the fuel sending unit (37). The sending unit feeds an electrical voltage through
                circuit 36, pin A of connector (37), circuit N36, pin C6 of connector (2) and circuit A36, pin 3 of
                connector (11) to the fuel gauge, which displays the fuel level. The fuel sender (37) pin B is grounded
                through circuits N36-G/N11-GA/W11-GG to the (9000A) platform ground. The fuel gauge is grounded through
                pin 2 of connector (11) circuits A28-G/A11-GA to the (IPG) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltmeter Gauge</title>
            <para>The voltmeter gauge is powered whenever the key switch is on, through the ECM2 and the ATA data-link
                circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tachometer Gauge and Speedometer Gauge</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the Tachometer and Speedometer
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Coolant Temperature Gauge</title>
            <para>The engine water temperature gauge is driven by the ECM2 through the ATA data-link circuits.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Oil Pressure/High Water Temperature/Low Coolant Level Lights and Alarm</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the warning light and alarm
                system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure Warning Light and Alarm - With Air Brake System</title>
            <para>The brake press warning light, the battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711),
                circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28D, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin
                4. When the air pressure drops below 60 psi, the pressure switch will close, and power will flow through
                the warning light, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 9, circuits A40A and A40, connector
                (2), pin A4, circuit N40, connector (9850), pin 9, circuit K40 and the low air pressure switch (6740) to
                ground (1LA). This will cause the brake press warning light to illuminate, and the warning alarm (211)
                to sound at a fast rate. The warning alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure Warning Light and Alarm - With Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>Refer to Hydraulic Brake System in the Chassis Accessories Section of this manual.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake Low Fluid and Parking Brake Warning Lights</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is turned to the on position, power is supplied to the low brake fluid
                warning system through circuit A28, to a splice, circuit A90R, the low level fluid warning light (89),
                circuit A90V, to a splice, platform/ chassis connector (2) and (90A), and circuit N90P to the normally
                open sensor switch (90). When a low brake fluid level is encountered, the sensor switch closes and the
                circuit ground is through the switch and circuit N11-GF/N11-GB to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is turned to the start position, a momentary ground is applied through the key
                switch, circuit A31-GD, circuit A44-G, brake diode assembly (82), circuit A90W to the previously
                mentioned splice, and circuit A90V to the fluid level warning bulb. This causes the warning light to
                come on as a bulb check and goes off when the key is released from the start position.
            </para>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F,
                fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8.
                When the parking brake is applied, power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17,
                circuits A44 and A44A, the park brake switch (218), and circuits A44-GA, A11-GB, and A11-G to platform
                ground. This will cause the park brake warning light to illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is
                applied. The lamp will also illuminate when the key switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a
                ground is applied through circuit A44, a brake diode (82), and circuit A44-G, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
            <para>When the key is turned to the start position, a ground is applied to the circuitry through the
                ignition switch, circuit A31-GD, circuit A44-G, brake diode assembly (82) and circuit A44 to the park
                brake bulb. This causes the warning light to come on as a bulb check and goes off when the key is
                released from the start position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic/Programming Connector and Self-Test Switch and Warning Light System</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for operation of the Diagnostic/Programming
                Connector and Self-Test Switch and Warning Light System.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wait-to-Start Warning Light</title>
            <para>Refer to the appropriate Engine Diagnostic Manual for a description of the warning light system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transmission Oil Temperature Warning Light</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuit A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuit
                A28/A28B, the green instrument cluster connector (11), pin 10 to the transmission oil temperature gauge.
                The transmission temperature is sensed by the transmission temperature sending unit (6741). The sending
                unit feeds an electrical voltage through pin A of connector (6741), circuit K31A, pin 6 of connector
                (9850), circuit N31A, pin F4 of connector (2) and circuit A31A, pin 2 of the natural instrument cluster
                connector (12) to the transmission oil temperature gauge, which displays the transmission oil
                temperature. The transmission temperature sending unit (6741) pin B is grounded through circuits
                N31-G/11-GJ to the (7104) control box ground. The transmission oil temperature gauge is grounded through
                pin 2 of connector (11) circuits A28-G/A11-G to the (IPG) platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the transmission oil temperature reaches 305&#176;F (151.7&#176;C) or more, the switch contacts
                close and completes the ground path. This causes the warning light to come on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Transmission Filter Warning Light</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with the automatic transmission filter warning light, power is supplied to fuse
                F10, circuit A31D, and the filter warning light (94). When the key switch (20) is held in the start
                position, power will flow through the filter warning light (94), circuit A31-GA, connector (344), a blue
                wire, and the pigtail of the filter pressure differential switch. This power will flow through the
                normally closed contacts of the pressure switch and its connector, a green wire, connector (344),
                circuit A31-GB, blocking diode (64), circuits A31-GC and A31-GD, and the key switch ground, thus causing
                the warning light to illuminate for a bulb check. When the transmission filter becomes restricted, the
                pressure differential switch's normally open contacts will close and power will flow through the warning
                light to the switch as above, but the power will flow through the normally open contacts of the switch
                and its connector, a brown wire, connector (344) and circuit A11-GE to platform ground, thus
                illuminating the change trans filter warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
