<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS - DESCRIPTION
        - CHARGING CIRCUITS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CHARGING CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Standard System</title>
            <para>The Delco 22-SI, 12 volt, 100-ampere capacity alternator is standard on this family of vehicles. Other
                Delco alternators are available as options. This alternator does not require power from the battery to
                begin generating electrical power, thus it is commonly referred to as a "one-wire type Delcotron." This
                means that if you bolt it on the engine, thus grounding it, install the drive belt, and start the
                engine, it will produce electricity at the output terminal (B) and the connected wire going to the crank
                motor solenoid and batteries.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>3+1 Isolated Battery System</title>
            <para>With the 3+1 system, the Delco 22-SI, 12 volt, 100-ampere capacity alternator has an additional
                circuit connected to it at the (R) terminal (relay terminal). This circuit feeds an output voltage to
                the 7V isolated battery magnetic switch, thus reconnecting the three isolated batteries for recharging.
                These three vehicle batteries are connected in parallel and to the 7V magnetic switch, thus providing
                power for cranking and for other systems when the engine is running. The fourth battery is grounded with
                the other three but provides power through a cable to the other side of the magnetic switch and other
                circuits to the (B2) battery stud, thus providing continuous power to the sleeper, and isolating the
                other three batteries to reserve their power for engine cranking.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
