<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - FUEL TRANSFER PUMP SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0825981">
        <title>FUEL TRANSFER PUMP SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f0825981" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825981.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Transfer Pump Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LEFT FUEL TANK</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FUEL TRANSFER PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ESC</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. RIGHT FUEL TANK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. FUEL LEVEL SENSORS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0825990" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825990.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Fuel Transfer Pump (5 pin pump)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825981">Fuel Transfer Pump Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>With two fuel tanks on the same truck, there is an equalizing pump that balances the fuel between the
                two tanks. The pump can only move the fuel from the left tank to the right tank and only when the engine
                is running.
            </para>
            <para>The dual tank, fuel sensing and display feature takes data from two fuel level sensors located on the
                top of each of the fuel tanks. The data displayed on the fuel gauge is the reading from the sensor in
                the right tank only. The sensors are connected to inputs on the ESC and to the fuel transfer pump
                module. The same fuel level sensors are used, regardless of the size, number and shape of the fuel tanks
                on the vehicle, however the position of the sensors in the tanks and the lengths of the swing-arms
                change.
            </para>
            <para>There are several error conditions that can occur with the fuel sensor circuits or the sensor
                itself:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>An open condition where the resistance is infinite across the two sensor terminals.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A short condition where the resistance is zero across the two sensor terminals.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>An open in circuits N37A or J37D between the pump and the ESC.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>There are mechanical problems that can occur with the fuel sensor:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A float falls off the sensor (The sensor will read empty permanently)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The sensor arm sticks in one position.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The transfer pump pumps from the left (driver side tank) to the right tank and is mounted
                        above the right tank. A sticker with an arrow indicating flow direction will be on the pump. The
                        words "in" and "out" are also stamped on appropriate ends of the pump.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_361.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_363.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
