<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODES - Terms and Definitions</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Terms and Definitions</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>1. Switches In An Invalid State</title>
            <para>In order to understand this phrase you must understand the construction of the center panel switches
                used on NGV. There are two "fingers" that protrude out of the back of the switch actuators (an upper and
                lower finger). These fingers are used to depress microswitches located on the circuit board of the
                center panel switch modules. With two microswitches there are 4 possible states for a switch to be in:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Both microswitches not depressed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Bottom microswitch only depressed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Top microswitch only depressed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Both microswitches depressed (this is always an illegal switch state, there is no switch
                        actuator that depresses both microswitches simultaneously).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>There are 4 different switch actuation types used on NGV:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monostable 2 position-An example of this type of actuator is Marker Interrupt. For the
                    marker interrupt example, the switch is stable in the down position (upper finger depressing upper
                    microswitch) and is momentary in the up position (lower finger depressing lower microswitch). If
                    both of the microswitches are depressed simultaneously or neither is depressed this is an invalid
                    state and will cause a trouble code to be set.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monostable 3 position-An example of this type of actuator is Panel Light Dimmer. For the
                    panel dimmer example, the switch is stable in the center position (neither microswitche depressed)
                    and is momentary in the up position (lower finger depressing lower microswitch) and down position
                    (upper finger depressing upper microswitch). Both microswitches depressed simultaneously is an
                    invalid state.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tristable 3 position-An example of this type of actuator is Engine Brake. For the engine
                    brake example, the switch is stable in the up (lower finger depressing lower microswitch), middle
                    (neither microswitche depressed) and down positions (upper finger depressing upper microswitch).
                    Both microswitches depressed simultaneously is an invalid state.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bistable 2 position-An example of this type of actuator is Fog Light. For the fog light
                    example, the switch is stable in the up (lower finger depressing lower microswitch) and down
                    positions (upper finger depressing upper microswitch). If both of the microswitches are depressed
                    simultaneously or neither is depressed this is an invalid state and will cause a trouble code to be
                    set.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>2. Under Current</title>
            <para>This term is used to describe the ESC virtual fuse output faults. As the DTC list states, this
                corresponds to less than 1/2 Amp being drawn on this output. In other words, less current is being drawn
                on this output than expected by the ESC.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>3. Over current</title>
            <para>This term is used to describe the ESC virtual fuse outputs and the Remote Power Module fuse faults.
                There are two types of output devices used on the ESC, a 20 Amp and a 10 Amp device. The Remote Power
                Module only uses the 20 Amp device. The 20 Amp devices behave like a 20 Amp circuit breaker and the 10
                Amp devices behave like a 10 Amp circuit breaker. Over current means that sufficient current has been
                drawn from the output to cause the "circuit breaker" to trip.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>4. Out of range high</title>
            <para>This means that the signal is outside its normal operating range on the high side. For example, the
                input pin on the ESC which is attached to the clutch switch has a normal operating voltage range of 12%
                to 18% of ignition voltage. Out of range high would correspond to a value greater than 18% of ignition
                voltage on this pin.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>5. Out of range low</title>
            <para>This means that the signal is outside its normal operating range on the low side. For example, the
                input pin on the ESC which is attached to the clutch switch has a normal operating voltage range of 12%
                to 18% of ignition voltage. Out of range low would correspond to a value less than 12% of ignition
                voltage on this pin.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>6. Over current</title>
            <para>See Number 3 above.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>7. Under current</title>
            <para>See Number 2 above.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>8. Short to ground</title>
            <para>This means that the ESC pin that the trouble code is generated for is connected to chassis ground
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>9. Overload</title>
            <para>An overload corresponds to too much load current. For example, for the virtual fuse outputs if too
                much load (i.e. too many lamps connected to this output) are attached to this output the device will
                trip.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>10. Open circuit</title>
            <para>Open circuit means that there is no load attached to the output. For example, a broken wire (or
                disconnected connector) from the ESC to the fog lights will generate an open circuit fault.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>11. Output pin over current</title>
            <para>See Number 3 above.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289_S0826301.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
