<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 ENGINES - OPERATION -
        Electronic Accelerator Pedal Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electronic Accelerator Pedal Assembly</title>
        <para>DDEC engines use an electronic accelerator pedal assembly that includes a throttle position sensor (TPS)
            and idle validation switch (IVS) function. The TPS/IVS sensor assembly is not serviceable and if defective
            must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>The TPS acts like a potentiometer. Movement of the pedal results in a variable signal being sent to the
            ECM. This signal is proportional to the pedal position. A five volt signal from the ECM (273) is sent
            through circuit 99A, connector (190), and circuit 99A to the potentiometer of TPS/IVS (267). The variable
            potentiometer wiper signal (varies with pedal position) is returned from the TPS/IVS (267) over circuit 99,
            connector (190), and circuit 99 to the ECM (273). The TPS/IVS (267) potentiometer is grounded through
            circuit 99-R, connector (190) and circuit 99-R to the ECM (273).
        </para>
        <para>The IVS is used to verify when the accelerator pedal is in the idle position. One side of the idle
            validation switch (273) is connected to circuit 99B, connector (190), and circuit 99B to the ECM (273). The
            ECM sets this input at 5 volts and when the throttle is at idle a ground is applied to this input by the
            idle validation switch (267). This ground pulls the input voltage down to nearly zero, telling the ECM that
            the accelerator pedal is in the idle position. The ground path that is applied by the IVS (267) is through
            circuits 99-GA and 97-GA, connector (190), circuits 97-GA and 97-G, connector (N/L), circuit 97G and 11-G,
            connector (N/L), and circuit 11-G to the negative battery terminal.
        </para>
        <para>The ECM analyzes the signals received from the TPS/IVS, making certain that the signals fall within
            certain parameters. For example, if the IVS signal indicates that the pedal is in the idle position, the ECM
            expects to see a TPS signal that indicates no throttle (or very little) is being applied. If the ECM does
            not see a logical response from both, a fault code will be logged. The TPS/IVS timing cannot be checked
            using a multimeter.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_150.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_152.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
