<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3000FE, 3000RE - 3000RE CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Horn</title>
            <para>Power is applied from the (1F) battery feed stud to circuit 14D/14A, fuse F11, and circuit 85 to the
                coil of the horn relay (R6). When the horn button is depressed, power flows through the horn relay coil,
                circuit 85A, an in-line connector (14), circuit 85A, another in-line connector, and circuit 85A to the
                steering wheel slip ring. From the slip ring, power flows through circuit 85A, the horn button switch
                and circuit 85-GB to the steering column ground.
            </para>
            <para>With the horn relay energized, power flows from circuit 85, through circuit 85B, the horn relay,
                circuit 85C, dash connector (2) and circuit 85C to the high note horn and circuit 85D to the low note
                horn. The horns are grounded through the mounting bolts and through circuit 85-G/11-GB to the platform
                ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Dryer with Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on or accessory position, power is applied from the ignition relay
                (458), through circuit 13P, rear control box fuse B3, circuit 39, control box connector (3), and engine
                harness circuit 39/39B to the heated air dryer. If the air dryer thermostat senses air temperature below
                50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow through the heating element. This
                assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze during cold weather.
            </para>
            <para>Ground is through circuit 39-GA, an inline connector (74) and circuits 39-G/11-GJ to the starter motor
                ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allison AT Automatic Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is placed in the start or ignition position, power is fed from the ignition
                relay (458) to the rear control box fuse A4 through circuit 13L. From the fuse, power flows through
                circuit 92D to a splice and circuit 92B to the modulator solenoid relay (403) coil. From the splice,
                power is also fed through circuit 92D to the modulator solenoid relay (403) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>The modulator solenoid relay is energized when the ECM (379) applies a ground to circuit 97F, rear
                control box connector (3), and circuit 92F.
            </para>
            <para>With the modulator solenoid relay (403) energized, power flows through circuit 92C, the control box
                connector (3), circuit 92C, the auto XMSN connector (389) (W/I6) and circuit 92C to the modulator shift
                solenoid connector (32).
            </para>
            <para>Ground path for the modulator shift solenoid is circuit 92-G/11-GJ to cranking motor ground.</para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is placed in the start or ignition position, power is also fed from the
                ignition relay (458) to the rear control box fuse B2 through circuit 13P. From the fuse, power is fed
                through circuit 97P, control box connector (3), and circuit 97P to the neutral position switch. If the
                transmission is in neutral, power flows through the switch, circuit 97AU, circuit 97L, control box
                connector (3), and circuit 97L to the crank relay (385).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drain Valve</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the ignition position, power is fed from the ignition relay (458)
                through circuit 13L, rear control box fuse A3, circuit 39A, control box connector (3), circuit 39A, and
                the electronic engine/chassis harness connector (197). Power continues through the chassis harness
                circuit 39A to the heated drain valve jumper harness connector (43), and to the drain valve pigtail
                connector (42).
            </para>
            <para>The drain valve is grounded through pigtail connector (42), conn. (43), and circuit 39-G/11-GA/11-GB
                to platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature drops below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow
                through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze in the drain
                valve during cold weather.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter</title>
            <para>Power is applied by the body builder feed stud (1F), to circuit 14D/19, fuse F17, and circuit 19H to
                the fuel heater relay (R5). When the key switch (20) is placed in the ignition or start position, power
                is also applied to circuits 13 and 13A, fuse F20, and circuit 19D to the fuel heater relay (R5) coil.
                The relay is energized through ground circuit 11-GA to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay (R5) energized, power flows through its contacts, circuit 19A, dash connector (2),
                circuit 19A, connector (401), and circuit 19A to the fuel filter heater and thermo switch (N/L). The
                ground path is through the filter housing and its mounting bracket. When the temperature is 50&#176;F
                (10&#176;C) or less, the thermo switch contacts close and cause the heater element to activate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Water-In-Fuel Light</title>
            <para>With the key on, power is supplied from the fuel heater relay (R5) socket, through circuit 19E to the
                water-in-fuel module (16). From the module, power is applied through circuit 19C, dash connector (2),
                circuit 19C, fuel filter connector (401), and circuit 19C to the fuel filter water probe (N/L).
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for the water-in-fuel module (16) is not a dedicated circuit. The fuel filter housing
                is grounded through its mounting bracket and whenever water builds up to an unacceptable level in the
                filter, the water completes the circuit between the probe contacts and the housing. This energizes the
                water-in-fuel module.
            </para>
            <para>When the water-in-fuel module becomes energized, power is supplied to circuit 19F and the
                water-in-fuel light (9). This energizes the lamp as power flows through the lamp and circuits
                19-G/11-GB/11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is in the start position, the water-in-fuel module is grounded through circuit
                19-GB to the key switch (20) ground. This serves as a bulb check to assure the bulb is operational.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Filter Restriction Light</title>
            <para>With the key switch (20) in the ignition position, power is applied through circuit 13H, fuse F25, and
                circuit 19J to the fuel filter light (69). From the light, power is applied through circuit 19B, dash
                connector (2), circuit 19B, fuel filter connector (401), and to the fuel filter vacuum switch (N/L).
                When the fuel filter becomes restricted, the fuel filter vacuum switch contacts close and complete a
                ground path for the fuel filter light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module (86) is fed a signal from the flow switch (N/L),
                causing the monitor to turn on a brake warning light and alarm system and to start the hydraulic reserve
                pump to provide additional braking power. The reserve pump and warning system is also activated when the
                differential pressure switch (91) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuit 13A, fuse F18,
                circuit 90T, and blocking diode assembly (80). From the blocking diode, power is supplied through
                circuit 90J, to the pump control relay (R1), and also through circuit 90H to the brake monitor module
                (86-E). The brake monitor module is grounded through circuit 11-GD/11-GB/ 11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link 90-FL/90FA/90, dash connector (2), and circuit 90, to the
                pump control relay (R1). When the key switch is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch
                contacts will be closed (engine not running) and a ground path is provided from the switch through
                circuit 90L, pressure differential switch (91), circuit 90K, connector (88), dash connector (2) and
                circuit 90K, to a splice. From the splice, a ground path is provided over circuit 90L, to the brake
                monitor module (86-A). This causes the module to switch the alarm output (86-C) to ground which
                activates the alarm and warning light. From the splice, a ground circuit is also provided by way of
                circuit 90E to the brake pump control relay (R1), causing it to energize. With the relay energized,
                power flows through its N.C. contacts, circuit 90S, dash connector (2) and connector (88) to the reserve
                pump motor (1F). This causes the reserve pump motor, which is grounded through its case and to the
                platform ground, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>From the pump motor, a signal path on circuit 90Q, connector (88) and dash connector (2), to the brake
                monitor module connector (86-F), provides information to the module. It continuously monitors the
                continuity of the reserve pump and power supplied to it. The warning system activates if the pump motor
                winding opens up or if the pump control relay (R1) remains closed (provides power to circuit 90S and the
                reserve pump motor), after the engine is running. The warning system is also activated if no power is
                supplied to the pump motor when the flow switch or differential switch contacts are closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (86-C) to ground, the brake warning light
                illuminates by power flowing to the dash connector (12), through the printed circuit board and the
                light, dash connector (12), and circuits 90N and 90M, to the monitor module at connector (86-C). At the
                same time, the alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the alarm,
                circuit 90NA, blocking diode (25), and circuit 90M to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is applied from circuit 90-FL/90FA to circuit 90A, dash connector (2), circuit 90A,
                fuse F2, circuit 90B, dash connector (2) and circuit 90B to the hydraulic brake stop light switch (209).
                The stop light switch ground is through circuit 90-G/11-GB to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is also applied through fuse F2 and circuit 90U to the brake relay (R3) coil, and
                circuit 90X to the relay contacts. The relay ground is through circuit 70C, dash connector (2) and
                circuit 70C to the stop light switch (209). When the brakes are applied, the contacts of the hydraulic
                brake switch (209) close. This energizes the brake relay (R3) and power is applied through circuit 90F
                to a blocking diode (80) and circuit 90H to the brake monitor module connector (86-E). Power is also
                applied from the blocking diode connector (80), through circuit 90D, to the monitor module connector
                (86-G). If the key switch is in the off position, power is also applied to the pump control relay (R1).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is also applied through fuse F12 and circuit 70B, to the stop light relay (R4) coil, and
                circuit 70D to the relay contacts. The relay ground is through circuits 70-G, the brake relay (R3) and
                70C to the stop light switch (209). When the brake is applied, the relay is energized and applies power
                through circuit 90C to the brake monitor module connector (86-H). The module compares the signals
                received at (86-G) and (86-H) and if there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits, 90D or 90C, for
                more than 14&#177;5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
            </para>
            <para>When the brakes are applied, power also flows from the energized stop light relay (R4) through circuit
                70A and to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_45.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269_47.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08269.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
