<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Mirrors - Heated And
        Lighted
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Mirrors - Heated And Lighted</title>
        <para>With the key switch (452) in the ignition or accessory position, the accessory feed relay (446) is
            energized. The energized relay then provides power to circuits 12AF and 12L, 15A fuse F5-A, and circuit 78
            to the heated mirror switch (415). When the switch is moved to the on position, power is applied to circuit
            78A going to the left door harness connector (437), and circuit 78B going to the right door harness
            connector (403). From connector (437) power flows through circuit 78A, connector (31), the green wire, the
            left mirror heating element, the white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground (J9), thus causing
            the left mirror to heat up. From connector (403) power flows through circuit 78A, connector (31), the green
            wire, the right mirror heating element, the white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground (J14),
            thus causing the right mirror to heat up.
        </para>
        <para>When the headlight switch (410) is placed in the parking lights or headlights position, the trailer tail
            lights relay (464-R9) will be energized. With the relay energized, power will flow through circuits 68E and
            68B, 15A fuse F8-C, circuits 68C and 58F, and a connector (N/L). From the connector, power flows through
            circuit 58F to the left door harness connector (437) and through circuit 58B to the right door harness
            (403). From connector (437) power flows through circuit 58B, connector (31), a yellow wire, left mirror
            light, a white wire, another white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground (J9), thus causing the
            left mirror light to illuminate. From connector (403) power flows through circuit 58B, connector (31), a
            yellow wire, right mirror light, a white wire, another white wire, connector (31), and circuit 11A to ground
            (J14), thus causing the right mirror light to illuminate.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
