<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Power</title>
            <para>Vehicle batteries are connected in parallel with the positive battery cable connected to the cranking
                motor solenoid (B) terminal. The negative battery terminals are also connected in parallel with the
                negative cable connected to the cranking motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are connected directly to the frame rail. The engine block, the cab,
                and the frame are also connected by ground cables or circuits to the cranking motor ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Charging System and Circuits</title>
            <para>While the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the terminal (B) and circuit 2, to
                mega fuse 175 amp, to circuit 14, to the body battery (cab) feed stud (J1). From the stud, power is
                supplied to the key switch (63) and the fuse block (1) power distribution center to supply the
                electrical demands of the vehicle. In addition, the alternator also supplies and maintains battery
                voltage through circuit 14/14-FL/14A-FL (and 14B-FL with 200 amp alternator) to the cranking motor
                solenoid (J31) stud (B) and through the battery cable to the batteries.
            </para>
            <para>The alternator is grounded through the terminal (GRD) and circuit 2-G to the starter motor ground stud
                (G).
            </para>
            <para>For a complete discussion on operating principles for alternators, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in
                the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the specific alternator being serviced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the ignition position, energizes IGN relay # 2 (R3) and power is
                supplied through circuit 13 to fuse F18. From the fuse, power flows through circuit 97P, the 44-pin
                bulkhead connector (2), circuit 97P, and in-line connector to the neutral position switch connector at
                the "AT" transmission.
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, in-line connectors, circuit 97P, and circuit 97AU are connected to the
                neutral position switch and when the transmission is in neutral, the switch contacts are closed and
                power flows through the switch contacts.
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, a jumper is installed at this connector (386) to connect circuit 97AU
                with circuits 97A and 97L. With the transmission in neutral, power is supplied through circuit 97A, the
                bulkhead connector (2), and circuit 97A to the ECM (379). Power is also applied to the crank relay (R5)
                contacts through circuit 97L. When the transmission is in gear, power is removed from the ECM and the
                relay (R5).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is turned to the start position, power is applied through circuit 17, to
                connector (195) (see Section 7), to circuit 17 and the crank relay (R5) coil windings.
            </para>
            <para>When an automatic transmission is in neutral, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM
                is supplied with 12 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the
                crank relay (R5) by providing a ground to the relay coil through circuit 97H, bulkhead connector (2) and
                circuit 97H.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM is programmed for the type of transmission installed and adjusts for the different
                        voltages received at the ECM driveline disengagement terminal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The energized crank relay controls the start relay (387) by providing power through circuit 17F,
                bulkhead connector (2), and circuit 17F to the relay (387). This energizes the start relay which is
                grounded through circuit 17D, and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is always present at the crank motor solenoid (J31) terminal (B) through the positive
                battery cable. Power is also available at the start relay (387) through the solenoid (J31) terminal (B)
                and circuit 17-FL/17B. With the start relay energized, power flows through the relay contacts and
                circuit 17C to the terminal (S) of the crank motor solenoid (J31) which energizes the crank motor
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the crank motor solenoid (J31) energized, the solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to rotate.
                When the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank relay (R5)
                which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay (387) to be de-energized and disengages the
                crank motor.
            </para>
            <para>As long as engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.</para>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection</title>
            <para>With thermal overcrank protection, the start relay (387) control coil ground circuit 17D is connected
                to the normally closed thermal switch (417). The thermal switch is located in the end of the cranking
                motor. The thermal switch is grounded through connector (417), and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the cranking
                motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>If excessive cranking causes cranking motor temperature to reach pre-set thermal overcrank limits, the
                thermal switch opens causing the start relay (387) to de-energize, turning OFF power to the cranking
                motor solenoid (J31) terminal (S) and disengaging the cranking motor.
            </para>
            <para>When crank motor cools, the switch closes, permitting the crank motor to operate again.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ether Start (DT 466E)</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is available at circuit 13B, fuse
                F16, and circuit 21, connector (5) and the ether start switch. If the engine block temperature is below
                10&#176;C (50&#176;F), the thermo switch contacts will be closed. This will allow power to flow through
                the ether start switch, when it is depressed, through connector (5), circuit 21A and dash connector (2).
                From connector (2), power is applied through circuit 21A, connector (500) and circuit 21B, to the ether
                bottle control valve. Power then flows through the control valve, circuit 21BC, connector (500), circuit
                21B and connector (709) to the thermo switch. When power flows through the ether bottle control valve
                (500), a shot of ether is fed into the intake manifold of the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
