<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - FE 300 LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Light System</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is moved to the on or start position, power is applied to circuit A13/A13H,
                fuse F24, circuit A71, dash connector (2), circuit A71, back-up light switch connector (41) and a black
                wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light switch contacts close, power flows through a
                white wire, connector (41), circuit A71A, connector (2), and circuit A71A to the body builder connector
                (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System</title>
            <para>Power flows from the (J2) battery feed stud through circuit A14/A14C to fuses F14 and F15. When the
                headlight switch is in the park or on position, power flows through fuse F14, circuit A50A, to the
                headlight switch (23). This supplies power for the parking lights through circuit A58, and body builder
                connector (169), cavity H. Power is also applied to the panel lights through circuit A62.
            </para>
            <para>When the headlight switch is in the on position, power flows through fuse F15, circuit A50, headlight
                switch (23), circuit A51, connector (27), a green wire, and to the dimmer switch.
            </para>
            <para>With the headlight switch on and the dimmer switch in the low beam position, power flows through the
                low beam switch contacts, a blue wire, connector (27), and circuit A53/A53A to the body builder
                connector (170), cavity C.
            </para>
            <para>With the headlight switch on and the dimmer switch in the high beam position, power flows through the
                high beam switch contacts, a brown wire, connector (27), and circuit A52/A52B to the body builder
                connector (170), cavity D. At the same time, power is also applied to the high beam dash indicator light
                through circuit A52A and the green cluster connector (11). Ground for the light is through circuit
                A28-G/A11-GB /A11-G to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights</title>
            <para>With the headlight switch on, power is supplied to the panel light switch (22) through circuit A62,
                fuse F21 and circuit A62A. The switch is grounded through circuit A62-GD/A11-G to the platform ground
                (J1).
            </para>
            <para>The panel light switch applies variable voltage through circuit A62H to the bussed connector (8), and
                to the body builder connector (169) on circuit A62J. Power also flows through the bussed connector (8)
                to the yellow instrument panel connector (10) on circuit A62B, to the green connector (11) on circuit
                A62C, and to the natural colored connector (12) on circuit A62D. Power is also supplied to the automatic
                transmission shift selector light (7) through circuit A62E.
            </para>
            <para>The ground for the transmission shift selector light is through A62-GE/A11-GB/ A11-G to the (J1)
                platform ground. Ground for the instrument panel lights is through the printed circuit board and circuit
                A62-GA/A11-G for connector (10), circuit A62-GB/A11-G for connector (11), and circuit A62-GC/A11-G for
                connector (12). Circuit A11-G is connected to the (J1) platform ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Daytime Running Lights (DRL)</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to USA DRL module (165) from (J2) junction block, through circuit A66, fuse F5 and
                circuit A66A. The module is provided a ground path through circuit A66-GA to platform ground (J1).
            </para>
            <para>When high beam/bright headlights are turned ON, a signal is sent to the USA DRL module (165) through
                circuit A66E, connector (224) and circuit A66E. Thus the module which supplies power to the fog light
                circuit A64A can switch OFF the fog lights when the high beam/bright headlights are selected.
            </para>
            <para>The USA DRL module (165) is enabled via circuit A66 when the key switch (20) is moved to the ignition
                or accessories position. The module will then apply power to circuit A66C, connector (224), circuits
                A66C and A53A to body builder connector (170), cavity C. The module will power the lights at about 60%
                of full power. When the headlight switch is moved to the headlight ON position, the power from the
                headlight switch will override the module and power the lamps at 100%.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
