<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - TURN SIGNAL AND
        STOP LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TURN SIGNAL AND STOP LIGHTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>With International Turn Signal Switch With and Without Pedestal Mounted Turn Signal</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Tractor</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the left turn position, power flows from the batteries to the
                (J1) junction block, through circuit 14R, circuit 14D, fuse F20, circuit 55, flasher (1), circuit 55A,
                and connector (459-C) to the turn signal switch.
            </para>
            <para>After flowing through the switch contacts, power flows through connector (459-D), circuit 56, 56S, and
                56A, connector (2), and circuit 56A to the left front turn light (503). For vehicles with International
                electronic engines, an extra connector (413) is located between the light and connector (2). Its ground
                path is through circuits 11-GD, 11-GC (not with Canadian DRL), 11-GB, connector (2), circuit 11-GB and
                circuit 11-GF to cab ground or 11-GJ to starter ground with International electronic engines.
            </para>
            <para>Power also flows from the turn signal switch through connector (459-D), circuits 56, 56S, 56F and
                trailer left turn relay (R5) coil. Ground is through circuits 56-GA and 11-GF to cab ground. This
                energizes relay (R5) allowing power to flow from (J1) junction block through circuits 14S and 14G, fuse
                F27, circuit 56K, (R5) relay contacts, circuit 56E, connector (182), circuit 56H, connector (12), and
                the trailer socket connections. Power also flows from the turn signal switch through connector (459-D),
                circuits 56, 56S, 56C, connector (27) and the left turn indicator. Ground is through connector (27-2),
                circuit 28-GA and circuit 11-G to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>Power also flows from the turn signal switch through connector (459-D), circuits 56, 56S, 56B,
                connector (18), and an orange wire to the left aux. turn light (169). Its ground path is through a white
                wire, connector (18), circuit 56-G and 11-G to cab ground. Power also flows from the turn signal switch
                through connector (459-E), circuit 56D, circuit 56DS, and connector (13) to left rear turn light. The
                ground path is through a white wire to frame ground.
            </para>
            <para>When each of the above mentioned circuits is switched on, the flasher (1) will heat up after a second
                or two and begin to cycle open and closed. This will cause the turn lights to flash on and off.
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the right turn position, power flows to the turn signal switch
                and out through connector (459-F), circuit 57, 57S, 57A, connector (2), and circuit 57A to the right
                front turn light (505). For vehicles with International electronic engines, an extra connector (413) is
                located between the light and connector (2). Its ground path is through circuits 11-GF, 11-GE, 11-GB,
                connector (2), circuit 11-GB and 11-GF to cab ground. Power also flows from the turn signal switch
                through connector (459-F), circuits 57, 57S, 57F, trailer right turn relay (R6) coil, and ground
                circuits 57-GA and 11-GF to cab ground. This energizes relay (R6) allowing power to flow from (J1)
                junction block through circuit 14S, circuit 14H, fuse F28, circuit 57K, (R6) relay contacts, circuit
                57E, connector (182), circuit 57H, connector (12) and the trailer socket connections. Power also flows
                from the turn signal switch through connector (459-F), circuit 57, circuit 57S, circuit 57C, connector
                (27) and the right turn indicator. Ground is through connect (27-2), circuit 28-GA and circuit 11-G to
                cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>Power also flows from the turn signal switch through connector (459-F), circuit 57, circuit 57S,
                circuit 57B, connector (220), and an orange wire to the right aux. turn light (169). Its ground path is
                through a white wire, connector (53), circuit 57-G, connector (220), circuits 57-G, and 11-GE to ground.
                Power also flows from the turn signal switch through connector (459-A), circuit 57D, circuit 57DS, and
                connector (13) to the right rear turn light. The ground path is through a white wire to frame ground.
            </para>
            <para>When each of the above mentioned circuits is switched on, the flasher (1) will heat up after a second
                or two and begin to cycle open and closed. This will cause the turn lights to flash on and off.
            </para>
            <para>When the brakes are applied on a truck or tractor, power is fed to the turn signal switch through
                connector (459-B). Power then flows to both rear lights through connector (459-A and E), circuits 57D
                and 56D when the turn signal switch is in the neutral position, or power flows to the light that is
                opposite of the one being selected at the turn signal switch for turning.
            </para>
            <para>When the hazard switch is engaged, all of the turn signal lights and all of the combination turn and
                brake lights will be switched to the power feed containing the flasher unit. Thus all of the lamps will
                flash on and off. The combination stop and turn light elements at the rear of the vehicle will stop
                flashing if brake pedal is depressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">On vehicles with pedestal mounted turn lights,</emph>all circuits feeding up to
                connector (2) are the same as vehicles without pedestal mounted turn signals, and only the front end
                wiring is different. For the left fender pedestal lamp (511), power flows from connector (2) through
                circuit 56 and 56F to the lamp. For vehicles with International electronic engines, an extra connector
                (413) is located between the light and connector (2). The power for this flows from connector (2),
                through circuit 56A, connector (413), circuit 56, and circuit 56F to the lamp. The ground path for each
                is through circuits 11-GG, 11-GB, connector (2), circuit 11-GB and circuit 11-GF to cab ground. For
                vehicles with International electronic engines, an extra connector (425) is located between the light
                and connector (2).
            </para>
            <para>For the right fender pedestal lamp (512), power flows from connector (2) through circuit 57 and 57F to
                the lamp. For vehicles with International electronic engines, an extra connector (413) is located
                between the light and connector (2). The power for this flows from connector (2), circuit 57A, connector
                (413), circuit 57, and circuit 57F to the lamp. The ground path for each is through circuits 11-GH,
                11-GB, connector (2), circuit 11-GB and circuit 11-GF to cab ground. For vehicles with International
                electronic engines, an extra connector (425) is located between the light and connector (2).
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Truck</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The operation of turn signals on trucks is the same as on tractors. The trucks, however, do not have
                the trailer left turn relay (R5) or the trailer right turn relay (R6).
            </para>
            <para>An optional trailer junction block connector (182) is available for trucks that are to be used in
                four-wheel trailer application. With this set-up, circuit 56D and circuit 56DS, between connector (459)
                and (13), are removed and circuit 56D, connector (182), and circuit 56F are substituted for the left
                rear turn signal circuits. Also circuit 57D and 57DS, between connectors (459) and (13), are removed and
                circuit 57D and 57F are substituted for right rear turn signal circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Turn Signals (Signal-Stat 910/915 Turn Signal Switch)</title>
            <para>Truck and tractors built with the optional Signal-Stat turn signal switch are wired similar to the
                International turn signal switch vehicles (without pedestal mounted turn signal) except for one mating
                connector and four circuits. The Signal-Stat connector for the turn signal switch is (422) and the
                International connector is (459). The circuits not used with the Signal-Stat turn signal are 56S, 56DS,
                57S, and 57DS. Although the pin locations are different, the same color wires from the switches mate
                with the same corresponding circuit numbers on the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
