<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, CUMMINS M11E AND N14E -
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Use with Circuit Diagram Book CTS-5122W.</para>
            <para>This chapter covers International installed components and circuits that directly interact with the
                Cummins M11E and N14E CELECT PLUS Electronic Engine Controls. CELECT PLUS is the name of the Cummins'
                heavy duty engines with a full authority fuel control injection system.
            </para>
            <para>This chapter:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Provides operation descriptions of International installed components and circuits that work
                        with the Cummins Electronic Engine Controls.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Provides Troubleshooting Charts for those circuits and components installed by
                        International.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Provides locations for International installed circuits.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>The Cummins Electronic Troubleshooting Manuals should be used to diagnose the engine control system,
                then use the step-by-step troubleshooting charts included in the
                <hotlnk document="s08230_96.xml" xrefid="x0823501">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
            <para>Cummins publications can be ordered from local Cummins Distributors or from:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Cummins Engine Co., Inc.</line>
                <line>Publishing Services CMC 40924</line>
                <line>Box 3005</line>
                <line>Columbus, IN 47202-3005</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>Refer to the circuit diagram in CTS-5122W for the following discussions.</para>
            <para>The M11E and N14E controller provides many engine/vehicle functions including:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Cruise/PTO Controls</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tachometer/Speedometer Input To Gauges</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle Shutdown</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Adjustable Low Idle Speed (In-Cab)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Cooling Fan Control</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Self Diagnostics</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Protection System</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine Brake Control</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Refer to the Cummins Engine Manual furnished with the vehicle for additional feature information.
            </para>
            <para>Since each engine control system is electronically programmable to individual owner specifications,
                <emph type="bold">the operating parameters will vary from vehicle to vehicle.</emph>
                These parameters include: maximum cruise speed, shift schedules, governor type (automotive type or
                variable speed), idle RPM, full engine shutdown as part of the engine protection system and many others.
            </para>
            <para>The electronic control module (ECM) is the control center of the CELECT PLUS system. The ECM receives
                input from Cummins and International sensors and switches, processes the information, then uses
                electrical signals to control engine and vehicle functions.
            </para>
            <para>The ECM receives inputs from International installed components including:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Service Brake Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low Coolant Level Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ABS/Traction Control Controller</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>CELECT PLUS Cab Switches</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The ECM receives information from the sensors and switches and sends signals to the injectors, fuel
                shut off valve and engine brake relay.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_79.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_81.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
