<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - INTERNATIONAL 530E I6 HEUI ENGINES - OPERATION -
        Engine Brake
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Engine Brake</title>
        <para>On vehicles equipped with compression braking, switch (434) will turn the engine brake on or off. Switch
            (433) will determine how many cylinders are used for braking by putting resistances from the resistor
            printed circuit board (390) in parallel. The CEC senses the voltage drop, across the parallel resistance,
            through (390) and will control the engine accordingly.
        </para>
        <para>The engine brake relay (286) disables engine braking when the ABS is active.</para>
        <para>When engine brake on/off switch (434) is on and the engine brake relay is not energized, a ground is sent
            from G1 ground adapter (453) on circuit 24-GA, 24AN and 24AT to terminals 2 and 5 of engine brake on/off
            switch (434). When engine brake select switch (434) is on, ground will be available at terminals 3 and 6 of
            the switch. 5 volts from CEC connector (379) will be applied to resistor printed circuit board (390),
            terminal F. This voltage will drop across a 2.2K ohm resistor (which may be selected in parallel with other
            resistors).
        </para>
        <para>When engine brake select switch (433) is in the 1 position, only the 2.2k ohm resistor connected to
            terminal D in the printed circuit board (390) will affect the voltage drop in the circuit. This will signal
            the CEC to select compression braking on two cylinders of the engine.
        </para>
        <para>When engine brake select switch (433) is in the 2 position, ground from (434) is supplied from terminal 3,
            on circuit 24AD, to resistor printed circuit board (390) terminal C. 5 volts from CEC connector (379) will
            be applied to resistor printed circuit board (390). The voltage drop across the parallel resistance between
            the 2.2K ohm and the 680 ohm resistor of printed circuit board (390) will signal the CEC to engage
            compression braking on four cylinders of the engine.
        </para>
        <para>When engine brake select switch (433) is in the 3 position, ground from (434) is supplied from terminal 3,
            on circuit 24AD, through switch (433), contacts 6, 2 &#38; 3 to resistor printed circuit board (390)
            terminals B and C. 5 volts from CEC connector (379) will be applied to resistor printed circuit board (390).
            The voltage drop across the parallel resistance between the 2.2K ohm, the 680 ohm and the 121 ohm resistor
            of printed circuit board (390) will signal the CEC to engage compression braking on all six cylinders of the
            engine.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_244.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_246.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
