<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - LIGHT SYSTEMS - OPERATION - Work Light With
        Tractor
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Work Light With Tractor</title>
        <para>Power is fed from the batteries to junction block (J1), circuit 14D, fuse F22, and circuit 65 to the work
            light switch (199). When the switch is moved to the on position, power will flow through the switch
            indicator lamp, circuit 65-G and 11-G to cab ground causing the indicator to illuminate. Power will also
            flow through circuit 65A to connector (200).
        </para>
        <para>For tractors with a sleeper, when the work light switch is in the on position, power flows through circuit
            65A, connector (707), and circuit 65A to the black work light pigtail causing the work light to illuminate.
            The ground path is through the light pigtail to sleeper ground.
        </para>
        <para>For trucks with the optional single Truck-light work light, when the work light switch is in the on
            position, power flows through both a green and yellow wire, a black wire and the work light pigtail, causing
            the work light to illuminate. The ground path is through the white light pigtail, and a white wire to the
            rear cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>For tractors without sleepers and with the standard work light, when the work light switch is in the on
            position, power flows through a black wire and connector (127) to the orange work light pigtail causing the
            work light to illuminate. The ground path is through the white light pigtail, connector (127), and a white
            wire to rear cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>For tractors without sleepers and with the optional single Truck-light work light, when the work light
            switch is in the on position, power flows through a black wire to the black work light pigtail, causing the
            work light to illuminate. The ground path is through the white light pigtail, and a white wire to the rear
            cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>For tractors without sleepers and with the optional dual Truck-light work lights, when the work light
            switch is in the on position, power flows through a black wire to the black work light pigtails, causing the
            work lights to illuminate. The ground path is through the white light pigtails, and a white wire to the rear
            cab ground.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_231.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_233.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
