<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODES - DIAGNOSTICS - OFF- LINE DIAGNOSTICS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0826304" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OFF- LINE DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Diagnostic messages from the engine controller, antilock brake system or transmission
                    <emph type="bold">are not</emph>
                    displayed on the electronic gauge cluster (EGC) digital display.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Placing the electronic gauge cluster (EGC) in diagnostic mode will allow the EGC to display active and
            previously active diagnostic messages from the electrical system controller (ESC) or from the EGC itself.
        </para>
        <para>To engage the diagnostic mode turn the Ignition key ON (or in accessory), then press the Cruise ON switch
            and the Cruise RESUME switch simultaneously. If no faults are present, the gauge cluster display will read
            NO FAULTS. If faults are present, the gauge cluster will display a message with the number of faults,
            followed by the diagnostic codes. Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f08263">Diagnostic Trouble Code Display</hotlnk>. This procedure will also initiate the
            diagnostic flash codes for the engine controller and the hydraulic ABS controller. The display will show
            each DTC for 10 seconds, then automatically scroll to the next entry and continue to cycle through the
            faults. To manually cycle through the fault list, press the cluster SELECT/RESET button.
        </para>
        <figure id="f08263" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0825449.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption>Diagnostic Trouble Code Display</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BYTE 7 FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>2. BYTE 8 FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SPN FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>4. FMI FIELD</callout1>
                <callout1>5. ACTIVE/PREVIOUSLY ACTIVE STATUS INDICATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>6. COMPILED FORMAT OF DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Diagnostic trouble codes will end with an "A" while the code is active. The code will remain active as
            long as the feature affected is active and the fault is present. If the feature is turned off or the fault
            is removed, the trouble code will be moved to the "previously active" list and the code will end with a "P".
            For example: when the work light is turned on and there is an open an active circuit fault code (611 14 11 1
            A) will be logged. When the light is turned off the code will become previously active. The fault still
            exists, but the code will not go active until the light is turned on.
        </para>
        <para>While in the diagnostic mode, previously active diagnostic trouble codes may be cleared by turning the
            left turn signal ON and pressing the Cruise ON switch and the Cruise SET switch simultaneously.
        </para>
        <para>Diagnostic codes for the engine controller and hydraulic ABS controller will not be cleared with this
            procedure.
        </para>
        <para>To exit the diagnostic mode, cycle the key switch or release the parking brake.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08289.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
