<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - HEATER AND AIR CONDITIONER - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Heater/Air Conditioner</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to (J2) accessory feed block, circuit 12B, fuse F19 and circuit 75A to the fan
                control switch (36). When switch (36) is moved to the low speed position, power flows from the switch
                through circuit 75D, both resistors, and the thermo fuse of the resistor and thermo fuse assembly (44),
                circuit 75E, blower relay (73) N.C. contacts and circuit 75F to blower motor (210). This causes the
                blower motor to run at low speed. The ground path for the blower motor is circuit 75-G/11-GE to relay
                bracket ground and 11-GC/11-GA/11-GF to cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When switch (36) is moved to the medium speed position, power flows from the switch through circuit
                75C, one resistor and the thermo fuse of the resistor and thermo fuse assembly (44), circuit 75E, blower
                relay (73) N.C. contacts, and circuit 75F to blower motor (210). This causes the blower motor to run at
                medium speed.
            </para>
            <para>When switch (36) is moved to the high speed position, power flows from the switch, through circuit
                75B, the coil of blower relay (73), circuit 75-GA/11-GE, relay bracket ground, circuit 11-GC/11-GA/11-GF
                to cab ground. This energizes relay (73) and allows power to flow from junction block (J1) through
                circuit 14B, fuse F12, circuit 75, N.O. contacts of relay (73) and circuit 75F to blower motor (210).
                This causes the blower motor to run at high speed.
            </para>
            <para>When blower switch (36) is in low, medium or high position, power is supplied by the switch to circuit
                77 and the air conditioner switch (37). When switch (37) is moved to the on position, power flows
                through its indicator light and ground circuit 77-GA/11-GA/11-GF to cab ground. This causes the
                indicator to illuminate. Power also flows from switch (37) through circuit 77A, connector (41) and
                circuit 77A to a splice. From the splice, power flows through circuit 77H to the low pressure
                refrigerant safety switch (74), through circuit 77J to the high pressure refrigerant safety switch (80),
                and through circuit 77E to A/C temperature control switch (235).
            </para>
            <para>When the A/C temperature control (235) senses that the vehicle's interior temperature is too warm for
                its setting, its contacts close and power flows through its contacts, circuit 77B, connector (41),
                circuit 77B, N.C. contacts of A/C relay (72), circuit 77F, connector (2), circuit 77F, and unlabeled
                connector to the A/C compressor clutch. This energizes the A/C compressor clutch which will start the
                cooling cycle and lower the temperature in the vehicle. The clutch will stay engaged until switch (36)
                or (37) is moved to off, A/C temperature control switch (235) cycles open or the contacts of the
                refrigerant pressure safety switches close.
            </para>
            <para>When the system is too low on refrigerant, the contacts of low pressure safety switch (74) close and
                power flows through the switch contacts, circuit 77D, 77C, connector (41), circuit 77C and the coil of
                A/C relay (72). The ground path is circuit 77-G/11-GE to the relay bracket ground. This energizes A/C
                relay (72) and opens up its N.C. contacts, which in turn removes power from the A/C compressor clutch.
                In most cases, the vehicle's interior temperature will be high enough that the A/C switch will call for
                A/C by closing its contacts, which will supply power to the A/C relay (72) on circuit 77B, and thus feed
                power to the closed N.O. contacts of relay (72), circuit 77L and the coil of relay (72). This will latch
                the energized relay and prevent the compressor from short cycling until it is repaired or the condenser
                temperature drops.
            </para>
            <para>Relay (72) is unlatched when the refrigerant pressure switches reset and either the air conditioner
                switch (37) is turned off or the A/C temperature control switch is moved to warm, opening up its
                contacts.
            </para>
            <para>As with the low pressure safety switch (74), the high pressure safety switch (80) and circuit 77K can
                also cause A/C relay (72) to energize and latch, thus interrupting the power flow to the A/C compressor
                clutch.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_300.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_302.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
