<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - 5TH WHEEL SLIDE, AIR CONTROLLED
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0825921">
        <title>5TH WHEEL SLIDE, AIR CONTROLLED</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259u2" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08259c1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>5th Wheel Slide Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SWITCH PACK ON INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>This system uses an electronically controlled air solenoid to supply pilot air to a larger air
                solenoid which will control the feature.
            </para>
            <para>The position of the switch on the dash panel is communicated to the ESC. The ESC will send signals to
                a remote air solenoid module containing the relay configured to operate the feature. Two different
                solenoid packs may be used to control the air pressure. The 7 solenoid version is controlled by J1939
                messages and the 4 solenoid version by discrete wire.
            </para>
            <para>The 5th Wheel Slide feature provides the operator with the ability to release and lock a sliding 5th
                wheel via switches in the cab.
            </para>
            <para>This feature allows the operator to release the 5th wheel in order to adjust its position forward or
                backward in order to adjust the distribution of the trailer weight over the rear axle(s). In addition,
                this feature allows the operator to move the 5th wheel towards the tractor. This increases the maximum
                allowable length for the trailer.
            </para>
            <para>Whenever the 5th wheel is released, the 5th wheel slide switch indicator shall be illuminated.
                Adjustment of the 5th wheel slide will be prohibited and the 5th wheel slide will be locked if the
                vehicle speed exceeds the vehicle speed as specified by a programmed parameter.
            </para>
            <para>Whenever movement of the 5th wheel slide is prohibited due to excessive speed, the switch indicator
                will flash slowly. Once this feature is in the inhibited state, the 5th wheel slide shall remain locked
                until the 5th wheel slide switch is cycled, the vehicle speed is reduced to below the maximum allowable
                vehicle speed, and there are no relevant switch or data link errors present.
            </para>
            <para>Upon the occurrence of a switch error or J1939 data link error, the 5th wheel will be locked
                regardless of the physical state of the switches.
            </para>
            <para>The 5th wheel slide shall be locked when the 5th Wheel Slide switch is set to OFF.</para>
            <para>The 5th wheel slide shall be released when the following requirements have been met:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The key is in the run position.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>There is no 5th wheel slide switch error present.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The vehicle speed is below the maximum allowable speed default of 2 MPH</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>There is no 1939 data link vehicle speed error present.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The 5th wheel slide is not currently inhibited.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>While the 5th wheel is released, detection of any of the following conditions shall cause the 5th
                wheel slide to be locked and inhibited and shall remain locked and inhibited until the 5th wheel slide
                switch has been cycled. Loss of communication with the 1708 switch pack that is providing the 5th wheel
                slide switch information. Loss of communication with the Drive Train J1939 data link that carries the
                vehicle speed information. Vehicle speed exceeds the maximum allowable speed default of 2 MPH. The 5th
                wheel slide switch indicator shall be set to ON steady, while the 5th wheel slide is released. The 5th
                wheel slide switch indicator shall be set to flash slowly when the release of the 5th wheel slide has
                been requested and power to the air solenoids has been interrupted due to a solenoid error. The 5th
                wheel slide switch indicator shall be set to flash slow whenever the operator has requested the 5th
                wheel slide to be released but the use of the 5th wheel slide is prohibited. The 5th wheel slide switch
                indicator shall be set to OFF when the 5th wheel slide switch is set to OFF. The 5th wheel slide will be
                locked and the 5th wheel slide switch indicator will be off when the key is not in the run position.
            </para>
            <para>Detection of any of the following conditions shall cause the 5th wheel slide to be locked. Loss of
                communication with the 1708 switch pack that is providing the 5th wheel slide switch information. Loss
                of communication with the Drive Train J1939 data link that carries the vehicle speed information.
                Vehicle speed exceeds the maximum allowable speed as specified per a parameter. A 5th wheel slide switch
                error is detected. The key is not in the run position.
            </para>
            <para>Detection of any of the following conditions shall cause this feature to generate a request to
                interrupt the power to the air solenoid module and thus disabling all solenoids. The 5th Wheel slide
                solenoid status as reported by private J1939 data link indicates a short. This is requirement is
                applicable for the ASM 7 pack module. The 5th wheel slide solenoid status as reported by the SSC
                feedback indicates a short. This requirement is applicable when this feature is implemented using a 4
                -pack ASM module.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_438.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_440.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
