<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - ELECTRIC
        WINDSHIELD WIPERS - INTERMITTENT WIPE AND WASH
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ELECTRIC WINDSHIELD WIPERS - INTERMITTENT WIPE AND WASH</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two Speed Wiper With Intermittent Wiper And Washer Operation</title>
            <table id="t0821200" tblwidth="full-page" numbered="no">
                <title>Wiper Washer Switch Operation</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.02in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.02in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="4.48in"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">SWITCH</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">MOTION</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">FUNCTION</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="2">
                                <para>Top Toggle (ON/OFF)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>In</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If wiper is off, Turns wiper to low speed. If wiper is on in any mode, turns wiper
                                    off.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Up</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If wiper is off, turns wiper on to high speed.</para>
                                <para>If wiper is on, Increments wiper to next highest speed.</para>
                                <para>If held more than one second wiper speed increases directly to high.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Down</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If wiper is off, turns wiper on to low speed.</para>
                                <para>If wiper is on, Increments wiper to next lowest speed.</para>
                                <para>If held more than one second wiper enters it's longest delay mode.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Bottom Button (WASH)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>In</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>If pressed less than 1/2 second, wiper performs a single lowspeed dry wipe (mist
                                    function).
                                </para>
                                <para>If pressed and held more than 1/2 second, wiper continues in low speed and washes
                                    for 2 seconds or until released (whichever occurs later).
                                </para>
                                <para>After release wiper continues to cycle in low speed for 3 seconds, then wiper
                                    returns to previous state.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>The electric windshield wiper with intermittent wipe and wash switch (1171) is an electronic device
                which controls the wiper relays and the washer pump depending on how the switch and washer button are
                pressed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Ignition switched power -</emph>With the ignition switch on power from 10 amp fuse
                F10-B is applied to wiper-low speed delay relay (143) terminal 86, wiper-high speed delay relay (143)
                terminal 86, and windshield washer w/wiper delay switch (1171) terminal 1.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Battery power -</emph>Battery power from 15 amp fuse F4-D is applied to wiper-high
                speed delay relay (143) terminal 30, windshield washer pump (9) on circuit 87B, and windshield wiper
                motor connector (430) terminal A.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low Speed Wiper Operation -</emph>When the wiper switch selects low wiper speed, a
                ground from the wiper switch (1171) terminal 3 is applied to wiper- low speed relay (143) terminal 85.
                This energizes the relay applying 12 volts from the closed contacts of high - speed relay (142) terminal
                87 to the low speed winding of the wiper motor through connector (430) terminal D.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High Speed Wiper Operation -</emph>When the wiper switch selects high wiper speed, a
                ground from the wiper switch (1171) terminal 4 is applied to wiper- high speed relay (142) terminal 85.
                This energizes the relay applying 12 volts from terminal 87 to the high speed winding of the wiper motor
                through connector (430) terminal E.
            </para>
            <para>The wiper switch also energizes the low speed relay (143), with a ground on circuit 82B, to open the
                park circuits and prevent 12 volts from being applied to the low speed winding of the wiper motor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Park Operation -</emph>Note that power is always present at the P terminal of the
                crank motor. When the wipers are turned off and the wiper blades are not parked, the circuit between
                wiper motor P and S is closed. In this position, power at P goes through the contacts and out S, through
                the normally closed contacts of the wiper relay (143) and back to the low speed winding of the wiper
                motor. The motor continues to operate until the park switch rotates, opening the circuit between
                terminal S and P, and closing the circuit between S and X, parking the wipers and turning off operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Windshield Washer Operation -</emph>When the wiper switch selects the windshield
                washer, ground from switch (1171) is applied from terminal 5 to circuit 87A of the washer pump motor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Intermittent Wiper/Wash Operation -</emph>The electronic wiper switch (1171) controls
                the washer and the low and high speed wiper circuits to perform intermittent wiping and washing as
                requested.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_42.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_44.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
