<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - CAB FEATURES - FRONT DOORS WINDOWS AND LOCKS (POWER) - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x082580403" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driver Side Power Window and Lock</title>
            <para>The switch data link is connected to driver side pod signal connector (3202) terminal D and C. The
                circuit path from the ESC connector (1600) is on twisted pair A3F(-)/A3E(+), to circuits A3X(-)/A3W(+),
                through door/IP connector (3200) terminals B and A, to circuits E3X(-) and E3W(+).
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage to the driver side pod signal connector (3202) terminal G is provided from fuse block
                (1011), F15. The circuit path from the fuse block is circuit A81B, through door/IP connector (3200)
                terminal C, and E81B.
            </para>
            <para>System ground to the driver side pod signal connector (3202) terminal E is provided from negative stud
                (1858). The circuit path from the negative stud is circuit A11-GH, A81-GA, through driver door pod
                (3200) terminal D, and E81-GA.
            </para>
            <para>Control voltage to driver window motor (3100) terminals A and B is supplied from driver pod load
                connector (3201) terminals B and A on circuits E83A and E83E.
            </para>
            <para>Control voltage to driver power lock (3203) terminals A and B is supplied from driver pod load
                connector (3201) terminals C and D on circuits E81A and E81E.
            </para>
            <para>Pressing the power window button will cause the pod to apply voltage to the power window motor until
                the motor reaches its mechanical limit. Pressing the passenger side power window button on the driver
                pod will cause the pod to send a message on the switch data link commanding the passenger pod to apply
                voltage to the window motor.
            </para>
            <para>Pressing the power lock button will cause the pod to momentarily apply voltage to the power lock motor
                in the driver door. The pod will also sends a message on the switch data link commanding the pods in the
                other door(s) with power locks to apply voltage to their lock motor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Passenger side</title>
            <para>The switch data link is connected to passenger side pod signal connector (3202) terminal D and C. The
                circuit path from the ESC connector (1600) is on twisted pair A3F(-)/A3E(+), to circuits A3P(-)/A3N(+),
                through door/IP connector (3204) terminals B and A, to circuits E3X(-) and E3W(+).
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage to the passenger side pod signal connector (3202) terminal G is provided from fuse
                block (1011), F16. The circuit path from the fuse block is circuit A81A, through passenger door pod
                (3204) terminal C, and E81B.
            </para>
            <para>System ground to the passenger side pod signal connector (3202) terminal E is provided from negative
                stud (1858). The circuit path from the negative stud is circuit A11-GH, A81-G, through passenger door
                pod (3204) terminal D, and E81-GA.
            </para>
            <para>Control voltage to passenger window motor (3100) terminals A and B is supplied from passenger pod load
                connector (3201) on circuits E83A and E83E.
            </para>
            <para>Control voltage to driver power lock (3203) terminals A and B is supplied from driver pod load
                connector (3201) terminals C and D on circuits E81A and E81E.
            </para>
            <para>Pressing the power window button will cause the pod to apply voltage to the power window motor until
                the motor reaches it's mechanical limit.
            </para>
            <para>Pressing the power lock button will cause the pod to momentarily apply voltage to the power lock motor
                in the passenger door. The pod will also send a message on the switch data link, commanding the pods in
                the other door(s) to apply voltage to their lock motor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_X082580402.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_242.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
