<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60 ENGINE - OPERATION - IDLE
        TIMER/PARK BRAKE SWITCH
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>IDLE TIMER/PARK BRAKE SWITCH</title>
        <para>The customer selectable idle shutdown feature shuts down the engine [does not shut down power to the cab]
            after a customer selected [programmed] length of time between 3 and 100 minutes. The timer [an ECM function]
            begins counting when the parking brake is set [which closes the park brake switch (268)], the engine
            temperature is above 104&#176;F/40&#176;C, the engine speed is at idle rpm, and the ECM does not see any
            clutch or brake pedal operation.
        </para>
        <para>If these conditions are present, the ECM counts down the customer selected length of time until 90 seconds
            before the scheduled engine shutdown is to occur. At this time the yellow engine warning light begins to
            flash rapidly.
        </para>
        <para>The idle timer can be disabled by depressing the accelerator pedal. This will allow the idle timer to be
            overridden if longer idle time is wanted. The shutdown timing sequence can be re-started by releasing and
            re-applying the parking brake.
        </para>
        <para>If the idle timer shuts the engine down, fueling is stopped, but ignition voltage is still present to the
            ECM on circuit 13D at connector (341).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The key switch must be cycled to off and back to on before the engine will start.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The engine is shut down, but power to the cab is not turned off.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The idle timer/park brake switch (328) is an air operated normally closed (N.C.) switch. Its contacts are
            closed when the parking brakes are applied, and its contacts open up when the brakes are released. One
            terminal of the idle timer switch (328) is connected to circuit 97AV, connector (262), circuit 97AV and the
            ECM (341). The other terminal of the switch is connected to ground by way of circuits 97-GE and 97-GA,
            connector (262), circuits 97-GA and 97-G, connector (N/L), circuits 97-G and 11-G, connector (N/L), and
            circuit 11-G to the negative terminal of the batteries.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_160.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_162.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
