<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3600, 3800, 4000FBC - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, DT 466E, International&#174; 530E AND T
        444E - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECM Power and Ground</title>
            <para>Power is supplied from the batteries to circuit 14A, a 40A power relay fuse, circuit 14B, positive
                battery connector (412), circuit 14B, battery harness connector (426), and circuit 14B to the Electronic
                Control Module (ECM) power relay (396) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>Power is also supplied from the (J1) battery feed stud to circuit 14B, fuse C2, circuit 97CT, the
                22-pin bulkhead connector (3), and circuit 97CT to the ECM power relay coil. From the relay, power is
                applied to circuit 97AH and pin 25 of the ECM (379).
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to the ignition position, power is supplied to circuit 13, fuse C1,
                circuit 97CR, the 22-pin bulkhead connector (3), and circuit 97CR to pin 24 of the ECM (379). This
                signals the ECM that the ignition switch is on and causes the ECM to internally switch pin 25 to ground.
                This completes the circuit for the ECM power relay (396) and energizes the relay. With the relay
                energized, power is applied through the relay contacts to circuit 97CM and a splice. From the splice
                power is applied to the ECM pins 21, 22, and 41 on circuits 97CL, 97CK, and 97AL respectively.
            </para>
            <para>Grounds for the ECM pins 1, 2, 23, and 42 are through circuits 11-GW, 11-GX, 11-GY and 11-GZ
                respectively, to a splice. From the splice, ground is through circuit 11-G, the battery harness
                connector (426), circuit 11-G, negative battery connector (665) and circuit 11-G to the negative battery
                terminal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch (IVS)</title>
            <para>The engine Electronic Control Module (ECM) determines the position of the accelerator pedal by
                processing the input signals from the Accelerator Position Sensor (APS) and Idle Validation Switch
                (IVS).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM sends a regulated 5 volt signal through the black ECM connector (379), circuit 97U, bulkhead
                connector (3), circuit 97U to a splice, and circuit 97C to the APS/IVS (382). The APS then returns a
                variable voltage signal (depending on pedal position) from connector (382), circuit 99B, connector (3),
                and circuit 99B to ECM connector (379). The APS is grounded through circuit 99A/97W, connector (3), and
                circuit 97WB/97W to ECM (379).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM learns the lowest and highest pedal positions by reading and storing the minimum and the
                maximum voltage levels from the APS. In this manner the ECM "auto-calibrates" the system to allow
                maximum pedal sensitivity. The ECM auto-calibrates as the key is on, but when the key is turned off,
                these values are lost. When the key is turned on again, this process starts over. When the pedal is
                disconnected (or a new one is installed), the pedal does not need to be calibrated, as the calibration
                happens when the key is turned on.
            </para>
            <para>The Idle Validation Switch (IVS) (382) receives 12 volt ignition voltage from key switch (63), circuit
                13F, fuse H1, and circuit 99E. When the pedal is not in the idle position (throttle applied), the IVS
                sends this 12 volt signal to the ECM over circuit 99D, connector (3), and circuit 99D to the ECM (379).
            </para>
            <para>The ECM (379) compares the inputs it receives on circuit 99B and circuit 99D from the APS/IVS to
                verify when the pedal is in the idle position. If the APS signal from circuit 99B indicates throttle is
                being applied, then the ECM expects to see 12 volts at IVS circuit 99D. If the APS signal, circuit 99B,
                indicates throttle is not applied, then the ECM expects to see 0 volts at the IVS circuit 99D. The
                timing process is critical between the APS and the IVS sensors. For this reason, it is very difficult to
                determine if the APS/IVS assembly is working properly using a volt-ohmmeter.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Barometric Air Pressure (BAP) Sensor</title>
            <para>The ECM (379) sends a regulated 5 volt signal from ECM (379) by circuit 97U, bulkhead connector (3),
                circuit 97U to a splice, and circuit 97BL to BAP sensor (406). The BAP sensor returns a variable voltage
                signal (represents atmospheric pressure) on circuit 97CD, connector (3) and circuit 97CD to the ECM
                (379). The BAP sensor is grounded by circuit 97Z/97W, connector (3), circuit 97W/97WB to the ECM (379)
                signal ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Temperature Sensor (ATS)</title>
            <para>The ECM (379) sends a regulated 5 volt reference signal through circuit 97AX to the Air Temperature
                Sensor (463). As the temperature changes, the sensor changes resistance and provides the ECM with an air
                temperature signal voltage. The sensor is grounded through circuit 97BU/97WB to the ECM signal ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cruise Control/PTO System</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to the cruise control On/Off switch (391) through key switch (63), fuse A2 and
                circuit 28/97B. When the On/Off switch is in the On position, power is supplied through circuit 97CF,
                dash connector (3) and circuit 97CF to ECM (379). This enables the cruise control.
            </para>
            <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch in the On position, power is also applied from the switch to the
                cruise Set/Resume switch (392) through circuit 97CA. Momentarily depressing the Set portion of this
                switch supplies a 12 volt signal to the ECM through circuit 97DH, dash connector (3), and circuit
                97DH/97DJ. This engages the cruise control and causes the ECM to maintain the current engine RPM. If the
                cruise control speed is already set, depressing the switch in the Set position causes the engine RPM to
                decrease until the switch is released.
            </para>
            <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch (391) in the ON position, depressing the Resume/Accel portion of
                the Set/Resume switch (392) supplies a 12 volt signal to the ECM through circuit 97DE, dash connector
                (3) and circuit 97DE/97DK. If the cruise control speed has not been engaged, momentarily depressing the
                switch causes the ECM to resume the last engine RPM setting. If the cruise control is already engaged,
                momentarily depressing the Resume/Accel portion of the switch will cause the engine RPM and speed to
                increase in small incremental amounts until the desired speed is reached.
            </para>
            <para>The cruise control switches and circuitry are also used for in-cab control of preset, variable, and
                mobile PTO operation applications and require programming of the engine ECM.
            </para>
            <para>For information on remote PTO control for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous
                Information in CT-471 Body Builder Book.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Radiator Shutters</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is turned on, power is applied to circuit 13, fuse B1, circuit 97K, dash
                connector (3), and circuit 97K/23 to the shutter connector (337). From engine harness connector (337),
                power is supplied through circuit 23/23B, shutter solenoid connector (340), and the pigtail to the
                solenoid. [With hydraulic operated shutters, power is supplied from connector (340) to the solenoid
                through circuit 23A utilizing a jumper harness.]
            </para>
            <para>Based on limits and settings programmed into the engine ECM, the ECM determines shutter opening and
                closing requirements.
            </para>
            <para>To close the shutters, the ECM applies a ground at pin 9 of the gray ECM connector (1205). This
                completes the ground to the solenoid through the solenoid pigtail (circuit 23-GG with hydraulic
                shutters), connector (340), circuit 97ESS, engine connector (336), and circuit 97ESS to the ECM. This
                energizes the solenoid which causes the shutters to close.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM determines additional engine cooling is required, ground is removed from pin 9 which
                de-energizes the solenoid and causes the shutters to open.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
