<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - FANS AND ENGINE ACCESSORIES - FAN WIRING - INTERNATIONAL ENGINES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>FAN WIRING - INTERNATIONAL ENGINES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>FAN SOLENOID Circuit functions</title>
            <figure id="f0826002" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Fan Solenoid Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 10 AMP FUSE W/SOLENOID OR 5 AMP FUSE W/CLUTCH IN ENGINE POWER DISTRIBUTION CENTER
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FAN SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ENGINE CONTROLLER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>On vehicles with optional air activated fans (The majority of the vehicles are built with standard
                viscous drive fans that have no electrical controls). The engine controller monitors engine coolant,
                intake manifold temperature, and air conditioning head pressure. When any of these systems operate
                beyond their set parameters, the engine controller will control turning the fan off by energizing a
                solenoid to control air pressure to the fan. In the event of a solenoid circuit fault the fan will
                remain on continuously.
            </para>
            <para>The engine controller turns the fan on under the following conditions:</para>
            <para>If the engine speed is less than 2250 RPM or the engine is running
                <emph type="bold">and any of the following conditions exists:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Coolant temperature sensor is greater than 96&#176;C (205&#176;F)
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
            </para>
            <para>There is an active engine diagnostic code for the coolant temperature sensor
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The retarder solenoid signal is active (high mode) for more than 10 seconds with coolant temperature
                sensor greater than 80&#176;C (176&#176;F)
                <emph type="bold">or</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ESC sends a command, on the drivetrain 1939 data link, to the engine controller (required when
                high AC compressor pressure is sensed).
            </para>
            <para>The engine controller turns the fan off under the following conditions:</para>
            <para>Engine speed is greater than 2300 RPM
                <emph type="bold">and all of the following conditions exists:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Coolant temperature sensor is less than 92&#176;C (198&#176;F)
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
            </para>
            <para>No active coolant temperature sensor diagnostic code
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Retarder solenoid signal is active (high mode) with coolant temperature sensor less than 75&#176;C
                (167&#176;F)
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The ESC is not sending a command to the engine controller (high AC compressor pressure is not sensed)
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The engine has been running at least two seconds.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Once the engine controller has turned the fan on, the fan will remain on for a minimum of 180
                        seconds to avoid unnecessary fan clutch cycling (except at engine start-up - it will run for
                        only two seconds after the engine starts). The 180 second time interval is a programmable
                        feature in the engine controller.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_S08255.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_153.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
