<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - BE 200, CE 200, CE 300 Model - ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER -
        TROUBLESHOOTING - INSPECTING ELECTRICAL CONNECTORS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECTING ELECTRICAL CONNECTORS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Visual Inspection</title>
            <para>The troubleshooting guide requires checking specific connectors. Use the following steps to determine
                if the connector is causing the problem. If a faulty condition is found, make the necessary corrections
                and continue the process.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check the connector lock mechanism or retaining screw.</emph>
                    Make sure the connector is capable of properly locking the connector together.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Perform a 10 pound pull-test on each terminal/wire in the connector.</emph>
                    Each terminal/wire assembly should easily withstand 10 pounds of pull and remain in the connector.
                    This test determines (A) if the wire is properly in the terminal and (B) if the terminal is properly
                    inserted into the connector. Correct any faults noted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Visually inspect wiring.</emph>
                    Inspect for worn or damaged wires. Check for pinched or damaged harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Visually inspect connectors.</emph>
                    Verify that pins and sockets are free of corrosion, dirt or any other contaminants, and damage.
                    Verify correct alignment and location of terminals in the connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check individual pins and sockets.</emph>
                    This is especially important with an intermittent symptom. Using a new pin, insert the pin into each
                    socket, one at a time, checking for a good grip on the pin by the socket. Repeat for each pin on the
                    mating side of the connector, using a new female terminal for the test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Inspect Engine Ground Stud.</emph>
                    Inspect this ground and other related grounds for clean, tight connections that are free of
                    corrosion and/or other faulty conditions.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacing IC Corporation Components</title>
            <para>When replacing electrical switches, connectors (including pins and sockets), relays or other
                components, use only approved IC Corporation replacement parts. Many of the switches have gold or silver
                plated contacts and some of the connectors have gold plated terminals. By using correct replacement
                parts, you maintain the design integrity of the system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_X08290019.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_X08290020.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
