<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Two Speed
        Axle Wiring With Allison Electronic Automatic Transmission
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Two Speed Axle Wiring With Allison Electronic Automatic Transmission</title>
        <para>When the two speed axle shift switch (75) is in the High position, power is applied from fuse F14, circuit
            93, cab harness two speed axle breakout connector (14), circuit 93E, axle connector (495), and circuit 93E
            to the two speed axle relay (488). From the relay, power is applied through the coil and circuit 93D to the
            Allison Electronic Control Unit (ECU) Input/Output connector (466).
        </para>
        <para>From the relay feed, power is also supplied through circuit 93G and the relay contacts, circuit 93C,
            connector (495), circuit 93C, connector (14), and circuit 93C to the dash/chassis harness connector (13).
            Power then flows through a red wire, an in-line connector, and a brown wire to the axle solenoid. This
            activates the axle shift solenoid or electric shift motor and causes the axle to be shifted into high range.
        </para>
        <para>Power is also available at the low side of the two speed switch from the Allison ECU through the
            input/output connector (466), circuit 93F, connector (495), and circuit 93F. When the two speed axle switch
            is moved to the Low position, a ground is applied to the switch through circuit 93, connector (495) and
            circuit 93 to the input/output connector (466). This signals the ECU that the two speed axle switch is in
            the low position. If the programmed parameters of the transmission ECU have been met, it applies a ground at
            the input/output connector (466) and relay circuit 93D. This energizes the two speed axle relay (488).
        </para>
        <para>With the two speed axle relay (488) energized, power is switched from circuit 93C to circuit 93B,
            connector (495), circuit 93B, and connector (14).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">With Two Speed Axle Electric Shift Motor:</emph>When equipped with an axle shift motor,
            power at connector (14) is applied through circuit 93B, dash/chassis connector (13) and a brown wire to the
            shift motor (703) which engages the low range.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">With Two Speed Axle Air Shift Solenoid:</emph>
            When equipped with an air shift solenoid, removing power from circuit 93C causes the solenoid to de-activate
            and shift the axle into low range.
        </para>
        <para>From connector (14) and circuit 93B, power is also applied through circuit 93A to the engine Electronic
            Control Module (379). This causes the ECM to adjust the signal being sent to the speedometer and odometer in
            order to show the correct speed and mileage for the gear ratio change.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_198.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_200.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
