<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - CUMMINS M11E AND N14E ENGINES - OPERATION -
        DIAGNOSTIC SWITCH
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC SWITCH</title>
        <para>A lighted diagnostic on/off switch is provided for on-board diagnostics. The switch is connected to the
            ECM common/ground connection by way of circuits 97-GE, 97-GA, connector (262), circuits 97-GA, 97-G and ECM
            connector (263). Moving the switch to the on position closes the switch contacts and applies the ground to
            circuit 97AM, connector (262), and circuit 97AM to the Cummins engine connector (309). This tells the ECM
            that the diagnostic on/off switch has been turned on. Thus the ECM will switch modes to display fault codes
            or the absence of codes by flashing the engine warning light and the stop engine light.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted two-position momentary idle/diagnostic switch is a dual function switch. The switch adjusts
            the low engine idle speed and is also used during on-board diagnostics (when the diagnostic switch is in the
            on position) to move through the diagnostic fault code list.
        </para>
        <para>The engine idle speed can be adjusted by the switch in increments of 25 rpm by toggling the switch.
            Maximum idle speed is 800 rpm and minimum idle speed is 550 rpm. When the idle has been changed and the key
            turned off, the new setting is saved in memory. This feature is owner selected and can be turned off with an
            electronic service tool.
        </para>
        <para>The switch is connected to the ECM common/ground connection by way of circuits 97-GD, 97-GA, connector
            (262), circuits 97-GA, 97-G and ECM connector (263). Momentarily placing the switch in the increment
            position applies ground to circuit 97AV, connector (262), and circuit 97AV to the ECM (263). This causes the
            engine idle rpm to increase 25 rpm.
        </para>
        <para>Momentarily placing the switch in the decrement position applies ground to circuit 97AU, connector (262),
            and circuit 97AU to the ECM (263). This causes the engine idle rpm to decrease 25 rpm.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_93.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_95.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
