<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - INTRODUCTION - ELECTRICAL TEST EQUIPMENT - OHMS LAW REVIEW
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="hl0825002" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>OHMS LAW REVIEW</title>
        <para>Ohms Law describes the relationship of voltage, current and resistance, and provides us with a formula to
            make calculations as is shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0825010">Ohms Law Formula</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <table id="t0826620">
            <title>Ohms Law</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.43in"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="4.07in"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                            <para>Ohms Law</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825098.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                                     scalefitheight="54px"/>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>Where:</para>
                            <para>I = Current (Amperes)</para>
                            <para>E = Voltage (Volts)</para>
                            <para>R = Resistance (Ohms)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>I = E/R</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>This formula states that current flow (I) = Voltage (E) applied to a circuit divided
                                by total resistance (R) in the circuit. This shows that an increase in voltage or a
                                decrease in resistance increases current flow.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>R = E/I</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>This formula states that resistance (R) = Voltage (E) applied to a circuit divided by
                                current flow (I) in the circuit. This allows us to calculate resistance needed for a
                                specific current flow with a specific voltage applied (like 12V).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>E = IR (I multiplied by R)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>This formula provides the voltage drop across a particular load device (resistance)
                                that is part of a series of load devices.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825099.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="88px"
                                     scalefitheight="120px"/>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>Memorize the formula in the circle. You only have to cover the "letter" that you wish
                                to calculate, with your finger, and you have the formula. For example: If you cover the
                                letter "I", the formula is I = E/R.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>If any two of the values are known for a given circuit, the missing one can be found by substituting the
            values in amperes, volts, or ohms and solving for the missing value.
        </para>
        <para>In a typical circuit, battery voltage is applied to a bulb through a 10 amp fuse and a switch (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0825011">Typical Circuit</hotlnk>). Closing the switch turns on the bulb.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0825011" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Typical Circuit</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To find the current flow use the formula:</para>
        <para>I = E / R</para>
        <para>Filling in the numbers for the circuit in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0825011">Figure 11</hotlnk>, we have:
        </para>
        <para>I = 12V/2 ohms or I= 12 divided by 2 = 6 amperes of current flow.</para>
        <para>The bulb in this circuit operates at 6 amps and is rated to operate at this level. With 12 volts applied,
            the bulb will glow at the rated output level (candlepower rating). However:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the voltage applied is low (low battery), then (the value of E is lower) current flow
                will be less and the bulb will glow less brightly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Or if the connections are loose, or the switch corroded, the circuit resistance will be
                greater (value of R will be larger) and the current flow will be reduced and the bulb will glow less
                brightly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Being able to determine voltage drops is important because it provides the following information:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Too high a voltage drop indicates excessive resistance. If, for instance, a blower motor runs too
                    slowly or a light glows too dimly, one can be sure that there is excessive resistance in the
                    circuit. By taking voltage drop readings in various parts of the circuit, the problem can be
                    isolated (corroded or loose terminals for example).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Too low of a voltage drop, likewise, indicates low resistance. If for instance, a blower motor ran
                    too fast, the problem could be isolated to a low resistance in a resistor pack by taking voltage
                    drop readings.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Maximum allowable voltage drop under load is critical, especially if there is more than one high
                    resistance problem in a circuit. It is important because all voltage drops in a circuit are
                    cumulative. Corroded terminals, loose connections, damaged wires or other similar conditions create
                    undesirable voltage drops that decrease the voltage available across the key circuit components.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>Remember our earlier discussion, the increased resistance from the undesirable conditions will also
            decrease the current flow in the circuit and all the affected components will operate at less than peak
            efficiency.
        </para>
        <para>A small drop across wires (conductors), connectors, switches, etc. is normal. This is because all
            conductors have some resistance, but the total should be less than 10 percent of the total voltage drop in
            the circuit.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
