<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS From 01/01/1998 to 02/07/2004 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND
        CRANKING SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Power</title>
            <para>Vehicle batteries are connected in parallel with the positive battery cable connected to the cranking
                motor solenoid (B) terminal. The negative battery terminals are also connected in parallel with the
                negative cable connected to the cranking motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are connected directly to the frame rail. The engine block, the cab,
                and the frame are also connected by ground cables or circuits to the cranking motor ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Charging System and Circuits</title>
            <para>While the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the (BAT) terminal and circuit
                2/2-FL to the cranking motor solenoid (B) stud. From the stud, power is supplied to the cowl junction
                feed stud and power distribution center (590) through circuit 14-FL/14, to supply the electrical demands
                of the vehicle. In addition, the alternator also supplies and maintains battery voltage through the
                cranking motor solenoid (B) stud and the positive battery cable to the batteries.
            </para>
            <para>The alternator is grounded through the (GND) terminal and circuit 2-G to the crank motor ground stud
                (G).
            </para>
            <para>With 1152SC or 1552SC models, the system also includes an alternator indicator light. When the key
                switch is in the accessory or on position, power is applied to the instrument cluster indicator light
                through circuit 1 and cluster connector (28). The light is grounded through circuit 1C, dash connector
                (2) and circuit 1C to the alternator (I) terminal. When the engine starts and if the alternator is
                generating full power, the indicator light will go off.
            </para>
            <para>For a complete discussion on operating principles for alternators, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in
                the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the specific alternator being serviced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - 1652SC with Automatic Transmission</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM is programmed for the type of transmission installed and adjusts for the different
                        voltages received at the ECM driveline disengagement terminal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 13C to the ignition
                relay (4G). The relay ground is through circuit 13-G/11-GB to cab ground. This energizes the relay and
                closes the normally open contacts. Battery power is then applied through the contacts, and circuit 13 to
                circuit breaker F9. From F9, power is supplied through circuit 97P, the 22-pin dash connector (2), and
                circuit 97P to the neutral position switch connector (438M) at the transmission.
            </para>
            <para>When the transmission is in neutral, the neutral position switch contacts are closed. Power then flows
                through the contacts, switch connector (438F), circuit 97AU, dash connector (2), and circuit 97AU to the
                jumpered clutch switch connector (386).
            </para>
            <para>From this connector, power is supplied to the crank inhibit relay (4H) contacts through circuit 97L.
                At the same time, power is also supplied through circuit 97A, the 31-pin dash connector (3), and circuit
                97A to ECM (379). The driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM will be at 12 volts. Providing
                the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the crank inhibit relay by providing a
                ground to the relay coil through circuit 97H, dash connector (3), and circuit 97H. This allows power to
                flow from the key switch, through circuit 17, start interrupt connector (195) and circuit 17A to
                energize the relay.
            </para>
            <para>The energized crank inhibit relay controls the start relay (590B) by providing power through circuit
                17B, dash connector (2), and circuit 17B to the relay. This energizes the start relay which is grounded
                through circuit 17D, the thermal overcrank protection switch, and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor
                ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Power is available at the start relay normally open contacts through fuse F30 and circuit 17C. With
                the start relay energized, power flows through the closed relay contacts and circuit 17E to the (S)
                terminal of the crank motor solenoid. The energized solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to rotate.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank inhibit
                relay (4H) which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay to de-energize and disengage the
                crank motor. As long as the engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the transmission is not in neutral, the neutral position switch (438) contacts are open
                        and 0 volts are available at the ECM (379) driveline disengagement switch terminal and the crank
                        inhibit relay (4H) contacts. This prevents the vehicle from being started.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                Group 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - 1652SC with Manual Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 13C to the ignition
                relay (4G). The relay ground is through circuit 13-G/11-GB to cab ground. This energizes the relay and
                closes the normally open contacts. Battery power is then applied through the contacts, and circuit 13 to
                circuit breaker F9.
            </para>
            <para>From F9, power is supplied through circuit 97P, the 22-pin dash connector (2), and circuit 97P to the
                neutral position switch connector (438M) at the transmission. The manual transmission does not have a
                neutral position switch so connector (438M) circuit 97P, and connector (438F) circuit 97AU, are
                connected together to complete the circuit. From connector (438), power is applied through circuit 97AU,
                dash connector (2), and circuit 97AU to the clutch switch connector (386).
            </para>
            <para>When the clutch pedal is depressed, power is switched from the ECM circuitry to the crank inhibit
                relay (4H) contacts through circuit 97L. The driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM will be
                at 0 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the crank inhibit
                relay by providing a ground through circuit 97H, dash connector (3), and circuit 97H to the relay. This
                allows power to flow from the key switch, through circuit 17, start interrupt connector (195) and
                circuit 17A to energize the relay.
            </para>
            <para>The energized crank inhibit relay controls the start relay (590B) by providing power through circuit
                17B, dash connector (2), and circuit 17B to the relay. This energizes the start relay which is grounded
                through circuit 17D, the thermal overcrank protection switch and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor
                ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Power is available at the start relay normally open contacts through fuse F30 and circuit 17C. With
                the start relay energized, the contacts are closed and power flows through relay and circuit 17E to the
                (S) terminal of the crank motor solenoid. The energized solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to
                rotate.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank inhibit
                relay (4H) which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay to de-energize and disengage the
                crank motor. As long as the engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the clutch pedal is in the released position, 12 volt power is applied through the
                        normally open clutch switch (386) contacts to the ECM (379) driveline disengagement switch
                        terminal. This prevents the vehicle from being started.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                Group 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - 1152SC or 1552SC with Manual Transmission</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 13C to the ignition
                relay (4G). The relay ground is through circuit 13-G/11-GB to cab ground. This energizes the relay and
                closes the normally open contacts. Battery power is then applied through the contacts, circuit 13,
                circuit breaker F9, circuit 97P, and clutch switch connector (386) to the clutch switch.
            </para>
            <para>When the clutch pedal is depressed, power is switched from the ECM circuitry to the crank inhibit
                relay (4H) contacts through the normally closed switch contacts, connector (386), and circuit 97L. The
                driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM will be at 0 volts. Providing the engine is not
                running, this signals the ECM to energize the crank inhibit relay by providing a ground through circuit
                97H, dash connector (3), and circuit 97H to the relay. This allows power to flow from the key switch,
                through circuit 17, start interrupt connector (195) and circuit 17A to energize the relay.
            </para>
            <para>The energized crank inhibit relay controls the start relay (590B) by providing power through circuit
                17B, dash connector (2), and circuit 17B to the relay. This energizes the start relay which is grounded
                through circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>Power is available at the start relay normally open contacts through fuse F30 and circuit 17C. With
                the start relay energized, the contacts are closed and power flows through the relay and circuit 17D to
                the (S) terminal of the crank motor solenoid. The energized solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to
                rotate.
            </para>
            <para>When the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank inhibit
                relay (4H) which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay to de-energize and disengage the
                crank motor. As long as the engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the clutch pedal is in the released position, 12 volt power is applied through the
                        normally open clutch switch (386) contacts to the ECM (379) driveline disengagement switch
                        terminal. This prevents the vehicle from being started.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                Group 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection - 1652SC</title>
            <para>With thermal overcrank protection, the start relay control coil ground circuit 17D is connected to the
                normally closed thermal switch (N/L). The thermal switch is located in the end of the cranking motor.
                The thermal switch is grounded through connector (N/L), and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the cranking motor
                ground (G) stud.
            </para>
            <para>If excessive cranking causes the cranking motor temperature to reach pre-set thermal overcrank limits,
                the thermal switch opens. This causes the start relay (590B) to de-energize, turning off power to the
                cranking motor solenoid (S) terminal and disengaging the cranking motor.
            </para>
            <para>When crank motor cools, the switch closes, permitting the crank motor to operate again.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
