<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - 3300 Model - CHASSIS FEATURES - BENDIX&#8482; AIR ABS</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x08298131">
        <title>BENDIX&#8482; AIR ABS</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Discussion of the air antilock braking system in this section is limited to power circuits and data
                link connectivity. For detailed information on ABS operation and troubleshooting, refer to Bendix&#8482;
                manual SD-13-4815.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f082981004" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g082981004.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Air ABS Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BENDIX EC-30 AIR ABS ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVETRAIN 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CLUSTER 1939 DATA LINK TO ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. DIAGNOSTIC CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. 1708 DATA LINK (PRIMARILY FOR DIAGNOSTICS AND PROGRAMMING)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The ABS function of the EC-30 is designed to optimize slip on all vehicle wheels. In addition to the
                ABS function, the EC-30 can be configured to provide an automatic traction control (ATC) feature. ATC
                can improve vehicle traction during acceleration on adverse road conditions. ATC can utilize engine
                torque limiting and/or differential braking to improve vehicle traction.
            </para>
            <para>The EC-30 electronic control unit (ECU) receives input from the wheel speed sensors to activate the
                modulators required to control braking at each wheel. It also communicates, on the drive train 1939 data
                link, with controllers and other systems to limit engine torque, disable retarders and control the ABS,
                ATC and trailer ABS warning lamps.
            </para>
            <para>Effective March 1, 2001, all towing vehicles must control an in-cab trailer ABS warning lamp. Trailers
                built after this date will transmit the status of the trailer ABS unit over the power line (center pin,
                blue wire of the trailer connector) to the tractor using power line carrier (PLC) communications. For
                detailed information on trailer ABS and PLC operation, refer to Bendix&#8482; manual SD-13-4815.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_228.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298_230.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08298.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
