<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - AUXILIARY AIR SUSPENSION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>AUXILIARY AIR SUSPENSION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259g1a" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08259c1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Auxiliary Air Suspension Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SWITCH PACK ON INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The auxiliary air suspension is for use on vehicles that are occasionally not balanced from side to
                side, such as a dump truck that has a side wing plow attached during the winter. This system would have
                an appropriately sized air bag in the front corner that would adjust for the extra weight. The driver
                would then have a switch on the dash to energize (inflate) or de-energize (deflate) the system. This
                switch would be an input to the ESC that would then drive an air solenoid, on a remote air solenoid
                module, for the air bag. This feature only operates with the ignition on.
            </para>
            <para>In the event of a switch error, the resultant would be transmitted as off. In the event of an air
                solenoid failure due to shorting, this feature will request the ESC to turn off power to the air
                solenoid pack (or packs) to prevent uncontrolled operation of the solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>In the event of a switch error, the indicator in the switch will be set to a slow blink if the
                ignition is on, but due to constraints the indicator will only flash when the key is in the "run"
                position. If this feature commands its driven solenoid to turn on and the solenoid pack power has been
                turned off, this feature will blink the switch indicator slowly to communicate an error has prevented
                this feature from functioning.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_428.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_430.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
