<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, CUMMINS M11E AND N14E -
        OPERATION - Cruise/PTO Controls
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise/PTO Controls</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CRUISE OPERATION</title>
            <para>The cruise control system has three modes:
                <emph type="bold">Off, standby and active</emph>. The off position of the On/Off switch (66) turns
                cruise control off. The standby mode occurs when the driver switches the cruise control On/Off switch to
                the on position. The driver can then achieve the active mode by toggling the Set/Resume switch after
                reaching the desired road speed.
            </para>
            <para>Once the system is active, the driver can accelerate beyond the set speed by depressing the
                accelerator pedal. When the pedal is released, cruise control is reactivated when the vehicle speed
                reaches the previously set speed.
            </para>
            <para>Cruise is deactivated, returning to the standby mode in several ways: the brake or clutch pedal is
                depressed, the engine speed (rpm) drops below 1000 rpm, the vehicle speed (mph) drops below 30 miles per
                hour.
            </para>
            <para>The resume switch can be used to reactivate cruise at the previous set speed, or the set switch can be
                used to establish a new set speed.
            </para>
            <para>While in the active mode, the coast feature is used to decrease the vehicle speed and establish a new
                lower set speed. By holding the select switch in the Coast position, vehicle speed decreases until the
                switch is released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
            </para>
            <para>While in the active mode, the accelerate feature is used to increase the vehicle speed and establish a
                new higher set speed. By holding the select switch in the Accel position, vehicle speed increases until
                the switch is released; the speed at release becomes the new set speed.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s08230_93.xml" xrefid="x0823524">Service Brake Switch (69)</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk document="s08230_93.xml" xrefid="x0823525">Clutch Switch (376)</hotlnk>
                above for service brake and clutch switch operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PTO GOVERNOR</title>
            <para>The optional power takeoff (PTO) is a type of governor which controls the engine at a constant
                customer-selectable engine speed (rpm) regardless of engine load.
            </para>
            <para>The PTO governor mode is activated using the cruise control switches, but only when vehicle speed is
                less than six miles per hour.
            </para>
            <para>The PTO mode is disabled by depressing the clutch or brake pedal. In the PTO mode the throttle pedal
                does not affect PTO operation, but does not disable the PTO.
            </para>
            <para>PTO allows the operator to set and control the engine speed in the same way cruise control sets and
                controls vehicle speed.
            </para>
            <para>To activate the PTO, position the cruise On/Off switch in the on position, then toggling the
                Set/Resume switch will move the PTO into the active mode.
            </para>
            <para>Toggling the Set switch will cause the engine to idle at a Cummins preprogrammed 850 rpm. This engine
                speed can be reprogrammed using an Electronic Service Tool (EST).
            </para>
            <para>Toggling the Resume switch will cause the engine to idle at a second preprogrammed,
                customer-selectable speed.
            </para>
            <para>The Accel and Coast positions can be used to increase or decrease the engine speed, but not higher
                than the preprogrammed customer selectable maximum PTO operation speed (must be less than 2500 rpm).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CRUISE ON/OFF SWITCH (66)</title>
            <para>When the cruise control On/Off switch (66) is moved to the on position, the normally open contacts
                close and a ground path is applied to ECM connector (320) terminal 2. From this terminal the path is
                circuit 97AE, connector (3), circuit 97AE, the cruise control switch (66), circuit 97-GC/97-GA,
                connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320) common ground terminal 10.
            </para>
            <para>This indicates to the ECM that the cruise control switch is in the on position.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CRUISE SET/RESUME SWITCH (67)</title>
            <para>The cruise Set/Resume switch (67) is a momentary switch. With the cruise control On/Off switch (66) in
                the on position, and the momentary switch in the Set/Accel position, a ground path is applied to ECM
                connector (320) terminal 22. From this terminal the path is circuit 97AA, connector (3), circuit 97AA,
                the cruise Set/Resume switch (67), circuit 97-GB/97-GA, connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM
                (320) common ground terminal 10.
            </para>
            <para>This indicates to the ECM that the current road speed is to be maintained.</para>
            <para>With the cruise control On/Off switch (66) in the on position, and the momentary switch in the
                Resume/Coast position, a ground path is applied to ECM connector (320) terminal 12. From this terminal
                the path is circuit 97AB, connector (3), circuit 97AB, the cruise Set/Resume switch (67), circuit
                97-GB/97-GA, connector (3), and circuit 97-GA/97-G to the ECM (320) common ground terminal 10.
            </para>
            <para>This indicates to the ECM that the previous road speed setting is to be reactivated.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_93.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_95.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
