<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - INTERNATIONAL 530E I6 HEUI ENGINES - OPERATION -
        Cruise Control/PTO System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cruise Control/PTO System</title>
        <para>The Cruise/PTO system feature controls engine and vehicle speed using automotive style set/coast,
            resume/accel., on/off switches and is controlled by the CEC. Speed control is disabled when the off switch
            is depressed, the brake is applied, the clutch pedal is depressed or an automatic transmission is placed in
            neutral.
        </para>
        <para>The cruise control switches and circuitry are also used for in-cab control of preset, variable, and mobile
            PTO operation applications and required programming of the engine CEC.
        </para>
        <para>Power is supplied to the lighted cruise control on/off switch (391) through I1 ignition adapter, circuit
            13AA, fuse F-10C, circuit 97DS and circuit 97AD. When the on/off switch is in the on position, power is
            supplied through circuit 97CF, circuit 97CF, dash connector (190) and circuit 97CF to CEC (379). This
            enables the cruise control.
        </para>
        <para>The lighted cruise set/resume (436) is a momentary switch. This switch receives 12 volts on circuits 97CA
            and 97CF from the cruise on/off switch (435) when it is in the on position. The cruise selector switch sends
            12 volts from the switch on circuit 97DJ, connector (190), and circuit 97DJ to CEC module connector (379)
            terminal 32 while in the set position. In the resume position, the switch sends 12 volts by way of circuit
            97DK, connector (190), and circuit 97DK to the ECM CEC module connector (379) terminal 22. If the cruise
            control speed has not been engaged, momentarily depressing the switch causes the CEC to resume the last
            engine RPM setting. If the cruise control is already engaged, momentarily depressing the resume/accel
            portion of the switch will cause the engine RPM and speed to increase in small incremental amounts until the
            desired speed is reached.
        </para>
        <para>For information on remote PTO control for body builder applications, refer to Miscellaneous Information in
            CT-471 Body Builder Book.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_238.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_240.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
