<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 1000 MODELS From 01/01/1998 to 02/07/2004 - LIGHT SYSTEMS -
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exterior Lights</title>
            <para>All exterior light circuits are protected by fuses or circuit breakers in the cab fuse/relay panel.
                The lighting circuits are provided with power from a fused circuit located in the cowl power
                distribution center.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights</title>
            <para>The vehicle back-up lights are a set of lamps that come on when the vehicle transmission is shifted
                into reverse. This allows the driver to see while backing at night.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Headlight System - Headlight Circuitry With or Without Daytime Running Lights</title>
            <para>The standard headlight system includes a headlight switch, turn signal lever controlled dimmer switch
                and a relay. If equipped with Daytime Running Lights (DRL), a control module is also used to provide
                illumination for daytime safety recognition and for nighttime driving.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights and Switch Illumination</title>
            <para>Panel lights are low wattage bulbs that illuminate instrument cluster gauges and the headlight switch.
                Depending on vehicle options, the system also illuminates the cruise control switches, transmission
                temperature gauge and the automatic transmission shifter back lighting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Parking and Tail Lights</title>
            <para>The headlight switch controls the parking lights and tail lights. Circuitry is provided to the body
                builder connections which supply power to these lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Light Switch - With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The stop light switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector and is utilized by the
                body builder stop light circuits. In addition, the switch also provides a signal to the hydraulic brake
                monitor module. The stop light switch also supplies a signal to the engine ECM to indicate the brakes
                have been applied. The ECM uses this information to control various engine controlled features such as
                cruise control and vehicle retarder.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08249.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
