<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - CAB FEATURES - FRONT DOORS WINDOWS AND LOCKS (POWER) - SERVICE PROCEDURE RKE
        TRANSMITTERS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x082580404" svcproctype="Service" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE RKE TRANSMITTERS</title>
        <para>Replacement Key Fobs/Transmitters can be obtained from Service Parts by ordering part number 3544938C2.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Transmitter Learning And Erasing</title>
        </para>
        <para>Before the transmitter can be used for the first time, it has to be "learned" by the receiver. Up to 6
            transmitters with different identification codes can be learned by a single RKE Pod.
        </para>
        <para>These procedures are designed for manual learning/erasing operations on a complete vehicle. They can be
            used for learning replacement transmitters, for using up to six transmitters for accessing the same vehicle,
            or for accessing any number of vehicles using the same transmitter. If RKE is being added to the vehicle,
            additional programming of the Electrical System Controller is required to operate the horn, panic, and dome
            light functions with RKE.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure For Erasing All Learned Transmitters</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cycle the Ignition from Off to On. Step 2. must be initiated (all four buttons pressed)
                within 10 seconds of this Ignition event.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the Driver Door Pod do the following:</para>
            <para>While holding down the Driver Window-Up, Driver Window-Down, and Unlock Switches depress and hold the
                Lock switch. All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is recommended. After
                the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will erase all learned transmitters and the RKE will be disabled. At
                this point the erase procedure is finished and a new Ignition cycle must be initiated to perform any
                transmitter learning.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure For Learning A Transmitter</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This learning procedure cannot be performed during the same Ignition cycle as the "erase all
                    learned transmitters" procedure. If necessary, the erase procedure should be completed before this
                    procedure is started.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cycle the Ignition from Off to On (leaving the Ignition on will not work, it must be
                cycled). Step 4. must be initiated (all four buttons pressed) within 10 seconds of this Ignition event.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the Passenger Door Pod do the following:</para>
            <para>While holding down the Window-Up, Window-Down, and Unlock switches, depress and hold the Lock switch.
                All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will enter "Learn Mode" and stay there for 10
                seconds (or until a transmitter is learned). Once the RKE enters the "Learn Mode", the four buttons can
                be released. During the ten second "Learn Mode" any function on the new FOB/transmitter must be keyed at
                least twice (See Note 1).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>1. After the transmitter is learned the next keying of the new transmitter will perform the
                        indicated function. It is recommended that the transmitter be successively keyed until the
                        selected key's function is actually performed; i.e., pressing the Lock Button on the transmitter
                        two times should learn its code, on the third push it should lock the door and momentarily beep
                        the city horn. This is a good way to quickly confirm the success of the learning.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>2. Steps 1. through 5. of the learning process must be repeated for each transmitter to be
                        learned.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_238.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_X082580402.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
