<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Dryer</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is placed in the ignition or accessory position, power is applied to circuits
                13, 13D, fuse F22, circuit 13A, connector (3), circuits 13A, 13K, in-line connector (1141), circuit 13K
                and energized the coil of air dryer/drain valve relay (1145). The ground path is through circuit 13-G,
                connector (1142), circuits 13-G, 11-GJ and to starter ground. Power from the body battery (cab) feed
                stud (J1), circuit 14, mega fuse 175 amp, circuit 14L, relay (1145), circiut 13L, in-line fuse (1146),
                circuit 39, connector (1142), circuit 39A, connector (1143), circuit 39A, and a black wire to the air
                dryer (78). The ground path is through circuit 39-G, connector (1143), circuits 39-G, 11-GJ and a white
                wire to starter ground.
            </para>
            <para>If the air dryer (78) thermostat senses air temperature below 10&#176;C (50&#176;F), its contacts will
                close allowing current to flow through the heating element. When the thermostat senses a temperature of
                29.4&#176;C (85&#176;F), the contacts will open, interrupting the current flow.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drain Valve</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is placed in the start or ignition position, power is fed to circuits 13,
                13D, fuse F22, circuit 13A, connector (3), circuits 13A, 13K, in-line connector (1141), circuit 13K and
                energized the coil of air dryer/drain valve relay (1145). The ground path is through circuit 13-G,
                connector (1142), circuits 13-G, 11-GJ and to starter ground. Power from the body battery (cab) feed
                stud (J1), circuit 14, mega fuse 175 amp, circuit 14L, relay (1145), circuit 13L, in-line fuse (1146),
                circuit 39, connector (1142), circuits 39, 39B, connector (1144), circuit 39B and a black wire to the
                heated drain valve (42). The ground path (white wire) is through circuit 39A-G, connector (1144),
                circuits 39A-G, 11-GJ and to starter ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Filter Wiring System</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Heated Fuel Filter</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Power is applied from the battery feed stud (J1) to circuit 14, mega fuse 175 amp, circuit 14K, to the
                fuel heater/"AT" XMSN relay (1136). When the key switch (63) is placed in the ignition or start
                position, power is also applied to circuits 13, 13D, fuse F22, circuit 13A, connector (3) and circuit
                13E, connector (1139), circuit 13A to the fuel heater relay (1136) coil. The relay is energized through
                ground circuit 13A-G, connector (1139), circuits 13A-G and 11-GJ to the starter ground.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay (1136) energized, power flows through its contacts, circuits 13F and 13J, in-line fuse
                (1138), circuit 19, connector (1139), circuit 19, fuel filter connector (401) and circuit 19A to the
                fuel filter heater and thermoswitch. The ground path is through the filter housing and its mounting
                bracket. When the temperature is 10&#176;C (50&#176;F) or less, the thermoswitch contacts close and
                cause the heater element to activate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Water-In-Fuel Light</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With the key ON, power is also supplied through circuit 19A to the water-in-fuel module (470). From
                the module, power is applied through circuit 19E, fuel filter connector (401), and circuit 19C to fuel
                filter water probe.
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for the water-in-fuel module (470) is not a dedicated circuit. The fuel filter housing
                is grounded through its mounting bracket and whenever water builds up to an unacceptable level in the
                filter, the water completes the circuit between the probe contacts and the housing. This energizes the
                water-in-fuel module.
            </para>
            <para>When the water-in-fuel module becomes energized, power is supplied to circuit 19B, dash connector (2),
                circuit 19B, connector (1150), circuit 19B and the water-in-fuel light (433). This energizes the lamp as
                power flows through the lamp and circuit 19-G to the bus cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch is in the start position, the water-in-fuel module is grounded through circuit
                19C, connector (2), connector (1150) and circuit 19A to the key switch (63) ground. This serves as a
                bulb check to assure the bulb is operational.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Fuel Filter Restriction Light</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With the key switch (63) in the ignition position, energizes IGN relay # 2 (R3) and power is also
                supplied from bus cab feed (J1), circuits 14AA, 14E, fuse F10, circuit 14F, relay (R3), circuits 13,
                13C, fuse F24, circuit 28 to the fuel filter light (434). The light ground path is through circuit 19D,
                connector (1150), circuit 19D, dash connector (2) circuit 19D, fuel filter connector (401), and circuit
                19B to the fuel filter vacuum switch. When the fuel filter becomes restricted, the fuel filter vacuum
                switch contacts close, completing a ground path and causing the fuel filter light to come ON.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Automatic Transmission Shift Solenoid System (Allison "AT")</title>
            <para>When key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, power energized relay (1136), to
                circuits 13F, 92, in-line fuse (1137), circuits 92A, 92D to the modulator solenoid relay (403) coil.
                Power is also fed from a splice in circuit 92D/92A through circuit 92B to the modulator solenoid relay
                (403) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>The modulator solenoid relay (403) is energized when ECM (379) applies a ground to circuit 92E,
                connector (1140), and circuit 92E.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECM commands a transmission shift, the relay coil ground is removed by the ECM which
                de-energizes the relay. With the modulator solenoid relay de-energized, power flows through circuit 92B,
                relay connector (403), connector (1140), circuit 92C, connector (389), and circuit 92C to the modulator
                shift solenoid (404). This causes the shift to occur.
            </para>
            <para>The ground path for the modulator shift solenoid is circuit 92-G, connector (389), circuit 92-G/11-GJ
                to bus cab ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Automatic Transmission Neutral Position Wiring (Allison "AT")</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, power is also applied to circuit
                13, fuse F18, circuit 97P, connector (2), circuit 97P, and in-line connector to the neutral position
                switch. If the transmission is in neutral, power flows through the switch, in-line connector, circuit
                97AU, connector (2), and circuit 97AU to the ECM (379) and the crank relay (R5) system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module is fed a signal from the flow switch, causing the
                monitor to turn ON a brake warning light and start the hydraulic reserve pump to provide additional
                braking power. The reserve pump and brake warning light are also activated when the differential
                pressure switch (301) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When key switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuit 13, fuse F19,
                circuits 13E and 90U, connector (47), and a blocking diode assembly. From the blocking diode assembly,
                power is supplied to circuit 90H, connector (3), circuit 90H, and the hydraulic brake relay (300). From
                the diode, power is also applied to circuit 90F and the brake monitor module (49). The brake monitor
                module (49) is grounded through circuits 90-G/11-G to bus cab ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link circuit 90-FL/90/90A and hydraulic brake booster relay (300).
                Power is also supplied through circuit 90-FL/90/90B, dash connector (3), circuit 90B, fuse F26, and
                circuit 90C to the hydraulic brake switch (50).
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch contacts will be
                closed (engine is not running) and a ground path is provided from the cranking motor circuit 11-GJ/90-G,
                flow switch connector, the switch, over circuit 90R/90L, differential pressure switch connector (301),
                and circuit 90K to a splice. From the splice, a ground path is provided over circuit 90M, connector (3),
                and circuit 90M to the brake monitor module (49) alarm input (49-A). This causes the module to switch
                the alarm output (49-C) to ground which activates the warning light. From the splice, a ground circuit
                is also provided by way of circuit 90J to the hydraulic brake relay (300), causing it to energize. With
                relay (300) energized, power flows through the N.C. contacts and circuit 90N to the reserve pump motor.
                This causes the reserve pump motor, which is grounded through its case, to run and provide additional
                brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>A signal path, circuit 90P, connector (3) and circuit 90P to brake monitor module connector (49-F)
                provides information to the module. The module continuously monitors the continuity of the reserve pump
                motor and its power supply. This triggers the alarm and warning light if the pump motor winding opens
                up, if the hydraulic brake relay (300) remains closed (provides power to circuit 90N and the reserve
                pump motor) after the engine is running and the flow switch opens up, or if no power is supplied to the
                pump motor when the flow switch or differential pressure switch contacts are closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (49-C) to ground, the brake warning light
                illuminates by power flowing to the lamp feed connector (26), and circuit 90T to the module at connector
                (49-C).
            </para>
            <para>The alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the alarm, and circuit
                90S to the module at connector (49-C).
            </para>
            <para>If the ignition key is in the OFF position and the bus brakes are applied, the contacts of the
                hydraulic brake switch (50) close. With the contacts closed, power flows through circuits 90DD, 90D,
                connector (47), blocking diode assembly, connector (47) and circuit 90F to feed the brake monitor module
                at connector (49-E). At the same time a power signal is fed from switch (50) to circuits 90DD, 90D, 90E,
                and the brake monitor module (49-G). This signal is compared to a signal provided from stop light switch
                (51) and circuit 70C/90R to brake monitor module (49-H). If there is a voltage on just one of the two
                circuits 90E or 90R for longer than 14&#177;5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned ON.
            </para>
            <para>When the brakes are applied, the brake switch (50) also applies voltage to circuits 90DD, 97M, dash
                connector (2) and circuits 97M to the ECM (379). This signals the ECM that the brakes have been applied.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
