<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - ELECTRONIC ENGINES, CATERPILLAR C-10 AND C-12
        ENGINES - TROUBLESHOOTING - Determining Fault Codes
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Determining Fault Codes</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The EZ-Tech&#8482;, PRO-LINK 9000&#174;, or Caterpillar electronic service tools (EST) can be used to
                identify logged fault codes. Refer to the EST manual for operating instructions.
            </para>
            <para>The yellow Serv/Check Engine light can be used to read fault codes by following the procedure in the
                following paragraph.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reading Flash Codes</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">KEY ON - ENGINE OFF PROCEDURE</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All Caterpillar flash codes are two digit numbers.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the key to the on position. The yellow Serv/Check Engine light will turn on for
                    approximately five seconds, then turn off for several more seconds, then begins to FLASH any logged
                    codes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH the first digit. At the end of first digit
                    there is a one or two second pause.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH the second digit. At the end of the second
                    digit there will be a two or three second pause before the next fault code number is FLASHED.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The second and all successive fault codes will FLASH until all codes have been FLASHED.
                    It will stop FLASHING after the last code has been flashed. To see the fault codes again, repeat the
                    process.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flash code 55 indicates that there are no logged diagnostic codes. For a listing of
                    Caterpillar Flash codes, refer to the Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting manual. Codes are also
                    listed in the EZ- Tech or PRO-LINK 9000 manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reading Flash Codes:
                <emph type="bold">ENGINE RUNNING PROCEDURE</emph>
            </title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>All Caterpillar flash codes are two digit numbers.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin procedure with engine off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start engine and allow to run at low idle for about 30 seconds.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn cruise on/off switch to off position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold cruise set/resume switch in either position until codes begin to FLASH, then
                    release.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH the first digit. At the end of the first
                    digit there is a one or two second pause.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow Serv/Check Engine light will FLASH the second digit. At the end of the second
                    digit there will be a two or three second pause before the next fault code number is FLASHED.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The second and all successive fault codes will FLASH until all codes have been FLASHED.
                    It will stop FLASHING after the last code has been flashed. To see the fault codes again, repeat
                    steps 4 through 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flash code 55 indicates that there are no logged diagnostic codes. For a listing of
                    Caterpillar flash codes, refer to the Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting manual. Codes are also
                    listed in the EZ-Tech or PRO-LINK 9000 manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>This section includes diagnostic tables for International installed circuits and components that are
                part of the Caterpillar electronic engine control system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">To begin the process, refer to the appropriate Caterpillar Electronic Troubleshooting
                    Manual and follow their directions.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If the Caterpillar diagnostics indicate that a International circuit is suspect, use the diagnostic
                tables included in this section for a step-by-step procedure. Refer to the appropriate circuit diagram
                for CATERPILLAR C-10 or C-12 ENGINES IN CTS-5122W.
            </para>
            <para>The EZ-Tech or PRO-LINK 9000 EST's with the Caterpillar programs can be used to read fault codes,
                customer and engine parameters and monitor various switches and sensors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_156.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_158.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
