<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - TROUBLESHOOTING - GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The symptoms listed in this section relate to specific events rather than specific diagnostic codes.
                It is still a necessary first step to read (and note) any active or inactive diagnostic codes.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Will Not Crank</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the following checks. If no defects are found, proceed to Step 2.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Shift Selector not in "N."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check vehicle starting system cables and wires for clean, tight connections. Check
                        connection at B+ terminal of crank motor solenoid for clean, tight connection.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check state-of-charge of all batteries.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check ECU battery and ignition voltages and ECU grounds by performing test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824603">ECU and Shift Selector Power and Ground
                        Circuits</hotlnk>, Table 3.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery and ignition voltage to ECU are to specifications and the ground circuits
                        check good, proceed to Step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects were noted in battery, ignition or ground circuits to ECU, correct
                        defects and retest start system.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824606">Neutral Start System,</hotlnk>Table 6.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If neutral start system checks good, proceed to Step 4.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects were noted in neutral start system, correct defects and test for proper
                        engine starting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the Shift Selector harness circuitry by performing test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824605">Selector Harness Circuitry,</hotlnk>
                    Table 5. (The shift selector may not be communicating properly to the ECU that the shift selector is
                    in the neutral position.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If shift selector circuits check good, go to Step 5.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects are noted in shift circuits, correct condition and test for proper engine
                        starting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the Shift Selector operation using an electronic service tool. If an electronic
                    service tool is not available, and the shift selector circuits checked good (Step 4), replace the
                    shift selector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the no-start condition is still present after performing steps 1 through 5, have an
                    Allison dealer continue the diagnosis.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS Light Will Not Go Out at Startup</title>
            <para>The "Check Trans" light should be illuminated when the key is turned to the on position and then go
                out when the vehicle is started. If a diagnostic code is registered because of a condition detected by
                the ECU that will "inhibit" transmission operation, the Check Trans light should illuminate (refer to
                diagnostic code chart for those codes that cause the Check Trans light to illuminate).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine if transmission operation is inhibited.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If transmission operation is inhibited and diagnostic code is present, perform
                        diagnostics as indicated by the code.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If transmission is not inhibited, refer to test,
                        <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824607">Check Trans Light and Circuits,</hotlnk>Table
                        7.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS Warning Light Does Not Illuminate During Startup</title>
            <para>Refer to test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824607">Check Trans Light and Circuits,</hotlnk>Table 7.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Light Dimmer Does Not Control Electronic Shifter Backlight Intensity</title>
            <para>Refer to test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824608">Panel Light Feed and Backlight Circuits</hotlnk>,
                Table 8.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Backup Lights or Reverse Warning Does Not Function</title>
            <para>If power to the backup lights is not present at connector (13)/pin J4 refer to test ,
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824609">Backup Light Relay and Circuits,</hotlnk>
                Table 9.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Speedometer Fails To Operate</title>
            <para>If the speedometer fails to operate (tachometer operates normally) and the input signal is suspected,
                check for diagnostic codes from the ECU first.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no codes are present, refer to test
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824604">J1708 Communications Link,</hotlnk>
                    Table 4, speedometer signal ECU to ECM.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If codes are present refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08246_34.xml" xrefid="x0824603">Troubleshooting With Diagnostic Codes.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>If Transmission Will Not Go Into "Lockup" Mode Or Transmission Retarder Will Not Engage On Vehicles
                Equipped With ABS Brake System
            </title>
            <para>If no diagnostic codes are present, check the ABS interface circuit by performing test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824610">Torque Converter Lock Drop Circuitry for ABS Brake
                    System,
                </hotlnk>
                Table 10.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two-Speed Axle Will Not Shift (Air Operated)</title>
            <para>The two-speed axle range is controlled the WTEC III electronic control system by applying (or
                removing) voltage to the axle solenoid, which is a normally closed solenoid. Without voltage applied,
                the axle solenoid is closed (no air applied to axle) and the axle will operate in low range. When
                voltage is applied to the solenoid, the solenoid energizes and air pressure through the solenoid causes
                the axle to shift to the high range.
            </para>
            <para>If the two-speed axle fails to cycle between ranges when commanded and the transmission output speed
                is within the programmed range, refer to test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824611">Two-Speed Axle (Air Operated)</hotlnk>, Table 11.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Two-Speed Axle Will Not Shift (Electric Operated)</title>
            <para>The two-speed axle range is controlled by the WTEC III electronic control system applying and removing
                voltage to the axle shift motor high and low speed motor windings. When low range is selected, power
                will be applied to the low speed winding provided the transmission output speed is within the programmed
                range.
            </para>
            <para>If the two-speed axle fails to cycle between ranges when commanded and the transmission output speed
                is within the programmed range, refer to test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824612">Two-Speed Axle (Electric Operated),</hotlnk>
                Table 12.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Brake Will Not Function</title>
            <para>Exhaust brake application is controlled by the WTEC III electronic control system which applies (or
                removes) voltage to the engine brake relay which signal the ECM that it is OK to apply or remove voltage
                to the exhaust brake relay which then controls the exhaust brake air solenoid. This solenoid is a
                normally closed solenoid, and without voltage applied, the exhaust brake air solenoid is closed (exhaust
                brake not applied). When voltage is applied to the solenoid, the solenoid energizes and air pressure
                through the solenoid causes the exhaust brake to operate.
            </para>
            <para>If the exhaust brake does not activate with the exhaust brake switch in the on position, perform test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824613">Exhaust Brake,</hotlnk>
                Table 13.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Retarder Will Not Function</title>
            <para>Hydraulic Retarder application is controlled by the WTEC III electronic control system. This is done
                by energizing the accumulator solenoid valve and modulating the H solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>If the hydraulic retarder will not function when the request switch is "on" and the transmission
                output speed is above 350 rpm, perform test
                <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml" xrefid="t0824614">Hydraulic Retarder,</hotlnk>Table 14.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
