<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - BODY ELECTRICAL SYSTEMS - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Electrical Power Distribution System</title>
            <para>The bus body electrical power distribution system provides 12 vdc through the mega fuse (175 amp) and
                the body battery power feed (J1) to the fuse panel on the flasher plate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flasher Plate and Harness</title>
            <para>The flasher plate and harness are located in the electrical access door compartment. The Weldon 7000
                electronic school bus 4/8-lamp flasher or the ELS 4/8 lamp flasher is mounted on the flasher plate.
                Also, the chassis fuse block with body power feed (J1), the chassis terminal strip or body builder
                connector (194), the body fuse panel with two shunts, master disconnect solenoid or noise kill
                disconnect solenoid, and the starter interrupt/interlock solenoid, buzzer, terminals and relays are on
                the flasher plate. The flasher plate harness is connected to the engine area harness (R1, R2, R3), the
                dash harness (S1, S2, S3, S4), the accessory panel (P70 and two singles), the left hand switch panel
                (P7, P8, P9, P10, P11, P12, P54 and P81), and the left hand body harness (S6, S15, S16, S51 and eight
                wires).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuse Panel</title>
            <para>The fuse panel has three input terminals, (P1), (P2) and (P3), and seven output connectors, (A, B, C,
                D, E, F and G), for control of forty fused circuits. The fuse panel contains 40 bus body fuses in four
                columns of ten fuses each. The fuse panel four columns of ten fuses outputs are used in three different
                setups options. There are options when the fuse can be manual-resetting type and one auto-reset circuit
                breaker for w/s wipers (gold body).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weldon 7000 Electronic School Bus 4/8-Lamp Flasher</title>
            <para>The Weldon 7000 electronic school bus 4/8-lamp flasher contains circuits that are tied electronically
                to the stop arm and crossing arm system of the school bus.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ELS B-1 School Bus 4/8-Lamp Flasher</title>
            <para>The ELS B-1 electronic school bus 4/8-lamp flasher contains circuits that are tied electronically to
                the stop arm and crossing arm system of the school bus. This model flasher is shipped from ELS
                programmed for non-sequential operation of the red lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Builder Connector (194)</title>
            <para>The body builder connector (194) provides power and control to switch panel lights, ignition feed,
                accessory feed, back-up lights, stop lights, left turn lights, right turn lights and park/tail lights.
                This provides power to control the vehicle functions and options.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed</title>
            <para>The accessory feed circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized by the
                body builder emergency exit indicator light, noise kill switch, RR emergency exit door, emergency
                kick-out windows, roof hatch, 3" red light over emergency exits, master disconnect, right side door and
                driver buzzer.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights and Alarm</title>
            <para>The back-up light switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized
                by the body builder back-up lights and back-up alarm horn.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ignition Feed</title>
            <para>The ignition feed circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized by the
                body builder air compressor, air door control (two position or three door position switch) and dump
                valve circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights and Switch Illumination</title>
            <para>The panel light switch circuit dims/brightens the voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is
                utilized by the instrument cluster lights and switch illumination circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Lights</title>
            <para>The stop light switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized by
                the body builder stop light circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Park/Tail Lights</title>
            <para>The headlight switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized by
                the body builder tail light circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Left Turn Lights and Right Turn Lights</title>
            <para>The turn signal switch circuit controls voltage to the body builder connector (194) and is utilized by
                the body builder turn signal circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Starter Interrupt/Interlock</title>
            <para>The starter interrupt circuit controls voltage to the starter interrupt connectors (195F) and (195M)
                are utilized by the starter interlock vandalock device circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Electrical Harness</title>
            <para>The bus body electrical harness provide 12 vdc through the switch panels and the lights. This allows
                the driver to control the vehicle functions and options.
            </para>
            <para>The console harness interfaces with seven harnesses: the chassis adapter, the sealed engine
                compartment, the dash, the left hand switch panel, the accessory panel, the left hand body, the
                auxiliary heater. Also, the left hand body harness interfaces with two harnesses: the front cap and the
                rear cap. The right hand body harness interfaces with the rear cap.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clearance/Cluster Lights</title>
            <para>The clearance lights switch panel controls voltage to the body electrical harness and is utilized by
                the body clearance, cluster, corner marker and midship intermediate marker light circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Arm</title>
            <para>The stop arm opens to 90 degrees on the left side of the bus body and indicates to the traffic in
                front and rear of the bus to stop. The air or electric motor control circuit is tied electronically to
                the 8-way flasher system of the school bus. The motor circuit is controlled by the motor control
                circuit, from which it is insulated. For this reason, the base of the unit must be properly grounded to
                the bus body. For proper operation, the system voltage must be between 10 to 14V. While it may seem
                complicated, you can easily troubleshoot using a test light or DC voltmeter. Refer to the wiring diagram
                for the reference points listed. Note that the components which are determined to be "at fault" are not
                necessarily those which are most often encountered in the field. If further help is needed, contact the
                engineering department at Specialty Manufacturing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crossing Gate</title>
            <para>The crossing gate opens to 90 degrees on the right hand end of the front bumper. This will keep the
                children from walking in the blind spot in the front of the bus. The motor control circuit and magnet
                are tied electronically to the 8-way flasher system of the school bus.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater Fans</title>
            <para>The heater electrical harness provide 12 vdc through the left hand switch panel to the heater blower
                motors. This allows the driver to control the driver heater fans, defroster fan, stepwell heater fans,
                midship auxiliary heater fans, rear auxiliary heater fans and booster pump.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Windshield Wiper</title>
            <para>The windshield wiper electrical harness provides 12 vdc through the wiper switch panel to the w/s
                wiper motors. This allows the driver single, dual or intermittent control of the windshield wipers. The
                w/s wipers are protected by the 30 amp auto-reset circuit breaker (gold body). The wiper switch panel is
                the control for the defog fans.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_33.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
