<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX II BRAKE MONITOR SYSTEM - SWITCH ADJUSTMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0826801">
        <title>SWITCH ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>2026921C1</title>
            <para>To adjust the 2026921C1 dual switch assembly, push down on the brake pedal and hold the pedal down.
                With the pedal down, pull the plunger out of the switch about 1 inch toward the brake pedal. Slowly
                release the brake pedal and the switch will self adjust. Make sure the switch cannot rotate and is held
                in place by the tab on the switch bracket. If the switch rotates, bend the tab as required to lock the
                switch in position. With the key off, moderate to light foot pressure applied to the brake pedal should
                cause pump motor to start. If foot pressure is too hard to start pump motor, lightly pull up on the
                pedal to re-adjust the switch. Refer to TSI-96-08-08.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use excessive force when pulling up on the brake pedal. Doing so could misadjust the
                        switch and cause damage to the master cylinder.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Also check to make sure that the brake pedal does not move down slightly when the engine is started.
                If it does, there is a problem with the power steering/brake booster system. Refer to the appropriate
                power steering manual for diagnostic information. If this condition exists, the stop switch cannot be
                properly adjusted until the power steering system is repaired.
            </para>
            <para>When adjusting the stop light switch by pulling out the plunger, the plunger should take 7 to 20
                pounds of force to pull out. If the force to pull out the plunger is below 7 pounds, replace the switch.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08268.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
