<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - AUTO NEUTRAL OPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>AUTO NEUTRAL OPTION</title>
        <para>When the transmission is in drive mode, the auto neutral switch (958) is moved to the on position, and the
            parking brake is applied, the contacts of the pressure switch (3010) will close and a ground signal will be
            applied to the Allison ECU (632) pin 12. This signal is provided by circuit 153, connector (466), circuit
            153 switch and connector (3010), circuit 153A, switch and connector (958), circuit 143B and 143A to dash
            panel cab ground (2G). The contacts of the pressure switch (1001) will also close and a ground signal will
            be applied to the Allison ECU (632) pin 30. This signal is provided by circuit 117, connector (466), circuit
            117, switch and connector (1001), circuit 161C, connector (466), circuit 161C and 161 to the ECU signal
            ground at (632) pin 31. When the ECU sees that both of these inputs are switched low, it will switch the
            output at its connector (632) pin 2 low. This will allow power to flow from the key switch (24) through
            circuit 13J, connector (377), circuit 13M, fuse (301), circuit 146, connector (418), circuit 146 and 146E,
            connector (1), circuit 146E, the coil of the neutral indicator relay (962), circuit 114, connector (466),
            and circuit 114 to the ECU (632) pin 2. This will energize the relay and allow power to flow from the feed
            side, electrically hot side of the relay (962), through circuit 146F, the normally open contacts of the
            relay, circuit 114NO, the neutral indicator light (961), circuit 143D, the closed contacts of pressure
            switch (960-A) and circuit 143C to the dash panel cab ground (2G). This will cause the neutral indicator to
            illuminate, thus indicating that the ECU has recognized the request to shift the transmission into neutral
            and the parking brakes are applied.
        </para>
        <para>When the driver of the vehicle releases the parking brakes, switches (3010), (1001), and (960-A) will open
            causing the neutral indicator to go off and the transmission to return to drive mode. The transmission will
            return to drive because switches (3010) and (1001) remove the ground to the ECU connector (632) at pin 12
            and 30 respectively. The neutral indicator light will turn off because the contacts of switch (960-A) open
            and because the ECU switches connector (632) pin 2 high, which de-energizes relay (962).
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
