<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        SPEEDOMETER/TACHOMETER, GAUGES AND WARNING LIGHTS - 9800 - OPERATION - WARNING LIGHTS, INDICATOR LIGHTS AND
        ALARMS (Figure 1)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WARNING LIGHTS, INDICATOR LIGHTS AND ALARMS (
            <hotlnk document="s08245x_3.xml" xrefid="f0824501">Figure 1</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824514">
            <title>Oil/Water Warning Light</title>
            <para>This yellow light is located in the right gauge cluster and is only used when the Cummins M11, N14 or
                ISM engine is installed in the 9800. The light is part of the engine protection system. It warns when
                the following systems are out of preset levels:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake Manifold Temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Radiator Coolant Level</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The light will come on at the occurrence and then begin blinking to warn that the condition has been
                active for a period of time or the condition has become worse.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824515">
            <title>"Engine Warn" Warning Light</title>
            <para>This yellow light is located in the right gauge cluster and is part of the engine protection system.
            </para>
            <para>When a Cummins M11, N14 or ISM engine is installed in the 9800, this light indicates an active
                component or system failure. This light indicates a failure has happened, and the vehicle can still be
                operated safely.
            </para>
            <para>When a Detroit Diesel Series 60 DDEC III engine is installed in the 9800, the light warns when the
                following systems are out of preset levels:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Level</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant Temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil Temperature</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824516">
            <title>"Engine Stop" Warning Light</title>
            <para>This red light is located in the right gauge cluster and is part of the engine protection system. This
                light indicates a major system problem and the vehicle
                <emph type="bold">should be stopped and engine shut down as soon as is safely possible.</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Failure to follow the "engine warn" and "engine stop" lights could cause serious damage or
                        catastrophic failure of the engine.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824517">
            <title>Low Air Pressure Warning Light and Alarm</title>
            <para>When the vehicle air system pressure is below 76 psi, the low air pressure warning system activates,
                turning ON the warning light and causing the alarm to sound continuously. This system includes the
                warning light located in the right gauge cluster, two low air pressure switches (one in the primary
                system and one in the secondary system), and the alarm that is located in the power distribution center.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824518">
            <title>Power Divider Lock (PDL) Warning Light and Buzzer</title>
            <para>When the power divider lockout switch is engaged, the normally open switch is closed. This completes
                the ground path and turns the warning light and warning buzzer on. The light is located on the left
                gauge cluster.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824519">
            <title>Air Suspension Release Warning Light</title>
            <para>This warning light is located in the right gauge cluster. It illuminates when the tractor air
                suspension is being dumped to the atmosphere. It will stay lit until the suspension is charged to its
                operating pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824520">
            <title>ABS Warning Light</title>
            <para>This yellow light is located between the right gauge cluster and the wing panel. It indicates when the
                antilock brake system is activated.
            </para>
            <para>On
                <emph type="bold">Bendix</emph>
                systems the ABS warning light will be illuminated at engine start-up for approximately two seconds and
                then extinguish after a successful self test of the electrical system. If an error is detected at any
                time, the dash light will stay illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>On
                <emph type="bold">Wabco</emph>
                systems, when the controller is initially put into service, or each time the controller is serviced
                (fault codes cleared using an electronic service tool or the blink light switch), the vehicle must be
                driven above 4 mph to extinguish the ABS dash warning light. Once the ABS dash warning light is
                extinguished, the ABS dash warning light will function in the same manner as the Bendix ABS dash warning
                light previously mentioned.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an antilock fault develops, standard air brake system operation is maintained. The brake
                        system is still operational, but the antilock system will not operate to prevent wheel lockup if
                        the driver over-applies the brakes for existing conditions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824521">
            <title>Traction Control Warning Light</title>
            <para>This yellow light is located between the right gauge cluster and the wing panel. It indicates when the
                traction control system is activated. If wheel spin occurs during operation, the light will blink.
            </para>
            <para>At start-up the light will flash and then go out. If the light does not come on, does not flash, or
                fails to go out, the traction control system is inoperative.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824522">
            <title>Transmission Service Warning Light</title>
            <para>This yellow light is located between the right gauge cluster and the wing panel. It indicates when an
                error has been detected by the transmission computer.
            </para>
            <para>At start-up the light will come on and then go out. This indicates that the self-diagnostic test was
                successful and the lamp is working. If the light comes on at any other time, there is a problem with the
                transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824523">
            <title>Hi-Beam, Turn Signals and Flashers</title>
            <para>The Hi-beam, turn signal and flasher lights alert the driver when these systems are activated.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0824524">
            <title>Rear Light Warning Light</title>
            <para>The rear light warning light illuminates when the fifth wheel work light is on.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08245x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
