<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS -
        DESCRIPTION - Cranking Motor System And Circuits
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cranking Motor System And Circuits</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The cranking motor provides the rotation of the engine crankshaft, through the flywheel, that is
                needed to start the engine.
            </para>
            <para>The cranking motor circuits provide power to the cranking motor to turn over the crankshaft of the
                engine. If all other systems are operational, the engine will start.
            </para>
            <para>Components of the system without International engines consist of the crank motor and solenoid, the
                key start switch (or push button), and a magnetic switch.
            </para>
            <para>Components of the system with International engines consist of the crank motor and solenoid, the key
                start switch (Or push button), crank inhibit relay, start relay, the Electronic Control Module (ECM),
                and a clutch switch with a manual transmission, or a neutral position switch with an automatic
                transmission.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Cranking motors ending in a type 50, like 350 or 450, contain thermal overcrank protection.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>On vehicles with thermal overcrank protection, excessive cranking will cause cranking motor
                temperature to reach a pre-set thermal overcrank limit., The thermal switch will then open causing the
                motor to disengage. When the crank motor cools, the switch closes, permitting the crank motor to operate
                again. The thermal switch interrupts the current to the cranking system mag switch, or the start relay
                with International electronic engines.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_55.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_57.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
