<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - INTRODUCTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsection id="s08250" division="truck" date="07/26/2001">
        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>MANUAL INTRODUCTION</title>
            <para>This manual only covers the electrical system of the truck.</para>
            <para>Detailed information on engines, transmissions, and antilock brake systems may be found in vendor
                manuals and other International Truck and Engine Corporation manuals. These systems are addressed in
                this manual only to cover circuits unique to our trucks, which are not addressed in other manuals.
            </para>
            <para>This manual is intended to be used in conjunction with the electrical circuit diagram book that
                applies to the specific vehicle requiring repair. There are variations between specific models and
                periods of manufacture that may only be addressed in the circuit diagram book.
            </para>
            <para>The circuit diagram book has valuable information that can be very helpful to a technician. Beyond
                circuit diagrams, the book provides information on connector composites and parts, circuit
                identification and location information, a schematic symbol chart, a relay function and wiring guide,
                and a lamp bulb chart.
            </para>
            <para>The strategy used in this manual focuses on starting with general information and progressing toward
                more specific information to guide a technician to the cause of an electrical failure. The manual is
                grouped into major areas. These major areas are divided into sections covering each feature. Each
                feature section is further divided into the following areas:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Circuit Functions</emph>
                        include a figure representing the major components associated with the feature and a general
                        description of how the feature works.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostics</emph>
                        provides a systematic means of identifying where to start looking for component or circuit
                        failures. Example: Is there a problem with an input circuit to the ESC from a switch or output
                        circuits from the ESC to a load device. Diagnostic trouble code explanations are provided in
                        this area if applicable.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Fault Detection Management</emph>
                        provides more detail on circuit operation, a figure identifying typical circuits and connectors
                        (always refer to the circuit diagram book for the latest circuit information) and a chart with
                        the voltages or resistances at key connectors, expected during normal operation. Procedures for
                        checking specific circuits for open or shorted circuits are not provided. It is assumed a
                        technician has received training on circuit fault identification and repair.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Extended Description</emph>
                        provides more detail on power and ground circuits for the feature.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Component Locations</emph>
                        provides drawings showing locations of important components.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Other areas such as
                        <emph type="bold">Removal</emph>,
                        <emph type="bold">Installation</emph>
                        and
                        <emph type="bold">Programming</emph>
                        may also be included as required.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Operator observation and warning lights may be used to determine when there is a problem with the
                vehicle electrical system.
            </para>
            <para>Technicians must still rely on observation of failed components or malfunctioning features. Once the
                technician has identified a failure he may go to the table of contents and refer to the applicable
                section for troubleshooting information.
            </para>
            <para>Another way a feature failure may become evident is through the vehicle "on line" diagnostic system of
                the electrical system controller (ESC).
            </para>
            <para>The check electrical system warning lamp will illuminate when a detectable fault has occurred. The
                lamp may illuminate either continuously or for 5 seconds depending on the fault. When a fault occurs and
                the ESC is able to communicate with the electronic gauge cluster (EGC), the lamp will illuminate for 5
                seconds. Each time the ignition is cycled and the EGC completes a gauge sweep, the lamp will illuminate
                for 5 seconds if an active fault is present. If the light remains on consistently, there is a
                communication problem between the ESC and EGC. The technician may retrieve diagnostic trouble codes
                through the EGC odometer display. The technician may then look up the diagnostic trouble codes to locate
                the applicable troubleshooting information.
            </para>
            <para>ESC diagnostics are not capable of identifying all possible system faults. This is why problem
                identification through observation is still important.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnostic trouble code retrieval procedures for engines, transmissions, and antilock brake systems
                vary from the procedure for retrieving diagnostic trouble codes produced by the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>An electronic service tool (EST), such as the EZ-Tech, running the INTUNE software can be used to list
                vehicle diagnostic trouble codes, monitor inputs to the ESC and exercise outputs from the ESC.
            </para>
            <para>This manual is written to attempt troubleshooting without the service tool, as much as possible. The
                EZ-Tech, running the appropriate software, can also be used to troubleshoot the engine, transmission and
                ABS electrical systems.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
