<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 5000i and 9000i - HEATER AND AIR CONDITIONER - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to Truck Service Manual S16023 AIR CONDITIONER - HEATER SYSTEM: 9100
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>, 9200
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>, 9400
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>, 9900
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                MODELS for information on removal and installation of components.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>HVAC Control-Cab</title>
            <para>The HVAC control module, on the instrument panel, provides three knobs and two buttons (only one
                button is used on models without the sleeper thermostat temperature control) which can be set to
                activate the AC compressor, control cab temperature, select cab blower speed and select the desired air
                distribution.
            </para>
            <para>The blower control knob on the left side of the control allows the operator to select one of four
                blower speeds.
            </para>
            <para>The temperature control knob in the center of the HVAC control module controls a stepper motor in the
                heater box allowing the operator to determine the mixture of hot and cold air available at the air ducts
                in the cab.
            </para>
            <para>The mode control knob on the right side allows the operator to control air distribution. This is
                performed by a stepper motor in the air ducts. The operator may select air flow to the defrost duct
                (when defrost is selected the AC compressor will be activated), mixed lower duct and defrost duct, lower
                heat duct, mixed lower and upper duct, and upper duct. The MAX position controls a recirculation stepper
                motor which will recirculate air to speed up cooling of the cab. Air flow may be turned off by selecting
                OFF.
            </para>
            <para>The AC button will enable or disable the AC compressor.</para>
            <para>The BUNK button will shut off the bunk blower and all sleeper HVAC controls.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_362.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210_364.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08210.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
