<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - CAB ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Electric Windshield
        Wiper With Intermittent Wipe and Wash
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electric Windshield Wiper With Intermittent Wipe and Wash</title>
        <para>When key switch (452) is moved to the ignition or accessories position, power is applied to circuits 12
            and 12F, and the wiper intermittent relay (444). The ground path for the relay is circuits 12-GF, 82-GA,
            12-GH, 82-GD, 11-GD, and left cab ground stud (429). Thus the wiper intermittent relay (444) is energized
            and power is applied by (B1) battery stud to circuits 14K and 14AL, 15A resetting fuse F6-B, circuit 82K,
            N.O. contacts of relay (444), and circuit 82 to the intermittent switch (408). Power is also applied by the
            N.O. contacts to circuits 82A and 82B, and wiper switch (407).
        </para>
        <para>With the key switch in ignition or accessories position, and the wiper switch in the low speed position,
            power flows from switch (407) through circuit 82E, connector (507), and the green wire to the windshield
            wiper motor low speed winding. The ground path for the motor is the brown wire, connector (507), circuits
            82-GD and 11-GD, and left cab ground stud (429), thus causing the wiper motor to run at low speed.
        </para>
        <para>With the key switch in ignition or accessories position, and the wiper switch in the high speed position,
            power flows from switch (407) through circuit 82D, connector (507), and the red wire to the windshield wiper
            motor high speed winding. The ground path for the motor is the brown wire, connector (507), circuits 82-GD
            and 11-GD, and left cab ground stud (429), thus causing the wiper motor to run at high speed.
        </para>
        <para>With the key switch in ignition or accessories position, and the wiper switch in the off position, power
            flows from switch (407) through circuit 82C, connector (507), the black wire to the windshield wiper motor
            park switch, the blue wire, connector (507), circuit 82F, N.C. contacts of relay (445), circuit 82H, switch
            (407), circuit 82E, connector (507), and the green wire to the windshield wiper motor low speed winding. The
            ground path for the motor is the brown wire, connector (507), circuits 82-GD and 11-GD, and left cab ground
            stud (429), thus causing the wiper motor to run at low speed to the park position where it will stop when
            the park switch contacts open up.
        </para>
        <para>When the wiper intermittent switch (408) is set and the end of the delay cycle is reached, the circuit
            will be completed and power will flow through switch (408) and circuit 82J to the wiper relay (445),
            energizing the relay. Thus power will flow through relay (445), circuit 82H, wiper switch (407), circuit
            82E, connector (507), the green wire, and the wiper motor low speed winding.
        </para>
        <para>The ground path for the motor is the brown wire, connector (507), circuits 82-GD and 11-GD, and left cab
            ground stud (429), thus causing the wiper motor to start running at low speed and shortly thereafter the
            intermittent switch (408) will open the circuit, and de-energize relay (445). Thus the self parking
            circuitry (described in a previous paragraph) will take over and return the wipers to park position. Then
            the cycle will start over.
        </para>
        <para>When the wiper intermittent switch (408) is moved to the wash position, the circuit is completed and power
            will flow through switch (408), circuit 87A, connector (24), and the red wire to the windshield washer pump.
            The ground path for the washer motor is the brown wire, connector (24), circuits 87-G and 11-GD to left cab
            ground stud (429). Thus the washer pump will supply washer fluid to the windshield while the switch is held
            in the wash position.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_40.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_42.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
