<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - IC BUS - BODY ELECTRICAL SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Electrical Power Distribution System</title>
            <para>The bus body electrical power distribution system provides 12 vdc through the mega fuse (175 amp) and
                the body battery power feed (J1) to the fuse panel on the flasher plate.
            </para>
            <para>Power is supplied by the vehicle batteries to the cranking motor solenoid (J31) battery stud (B) by a
                4/0 red wire on the IC Bus. From the cranking motor solenoid (J31) battery stud, power is applied
                through circuits 14-FL, 14A-FL and 14, the mega fuse 175 amp to the body battery feed stud (J1), located
                inside the electrical access door on the left side bus body. From the body battery feed stud (J1), power
                is supplied through circuit 6BLK18 to terminal (P1) on the fuse panel.
            </para>
            <para>A ground path is supplied to the cranking motor ground junction stud (G) through a 3/0 black cable to
                the batteries which are grounded to the frame. Through the cranking motor ground stud (G) and the engine
                block 2/0 to the left frame ground on the engine cowl (dash &#38; toe). The circuit 6WHT45 wire connects
                through the engine cowl (dash &#38; toe) to the rear side of the flasher-plate ground stud. The body
                ground paths are through the contracts of each electrical ground to the body frame.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to individual circuits for continuation of circuitry.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flasher Plate and Harness</title>
            <para>The three methods used to control the fuse panel outputs are either using two shunts, master
                disconnect solenoid or noise kill disconnect solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>The body fuse panel fuse outputs, controlled by the two shunts connecting terminals (P1) to (P2) and
                (P3), are hot all the time.
            </para>
            <para>The body fuse panel fuse outputs, controlled by the master disconnect solenoid, fuse 21 thru fuse 30
                are hot all the time. Power from fuses 1 thru 20 and 31 thru 40 are controlled by the master disconnect
                solenoid. From fuse panel terminal (P1), power is circuit 6BLK18, the master disconnect solenoid,
                circuit 6BLK15, to fuse panel terminal (P2) and power jumper circuit 6BLK3 to fuse panel terminal (P3).
                The control of the solenoid is circuit 16BLK40 from driver buzzer or chassis terminal strip.
            </para>
            <para>The body fuse panel fuse outputs, controlled by the noise kill and master disconnect solenoid, fuse 21
                thru fuse 30 are hot all the time. Power from fuses 1 thru 20 are controlled by the master disconnect
                solenoid. From fuse panel terminal (P1), power is circuit 6BLK18, the master disconnect solenoid,
                circuit 6BLK15, to fuse panel terminal (P2). The control of the solenoid is circuit 16BLK40 from driver
                buzzer or chassis terminal strip. Power from fuses 31 thru 40 are controlled by the noise kill
                disconnect solenoid. From master disconnect solenoid, side connected to fuse panel terminal (P2), power
                is circuit 6BLK7, the noise kill disconnect solenoid, circuit 6BLK18 to fuse panel terminal (P3). The
                control of the solenoid is circuit 16BLU69 from noise kill switch in left hand switch panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuse Panel</title>
            <para>Main power from terminal (P1) is wired to fuse 21 thru fuse 30 and connects the fuses to the output
                connector (C), pins (C1 thru C10). Power from terminal (P2) is wired to fuse 11 thru fuse 16 and
                connects the fuses to the output connector (D), pins (D1 thru D6). Power from terminal (P2) is wired to
                fuse 17 thru fuse 20 and connects the fuses to the output connector (E), pins (E1 thru E4). Power from
                terminal (P2) is wired to fuse 1 and fuse 2 and connects the fuses to the output connector (F), pins (F1
                and F2). Power from terminal (P2) is wired to fuse 3 thru fuse 10 and connects the fuses to the output
                connector (G), pins (G1 thru G8). Power from terminal (P3) is wired to fuse 31 thru fuse 38 and connects
                the fuses to the output connector (A), pins (A1 thru A8). Power from terminal (P3) is wired to fuse 39
                and fuse 40 and connects the fuses to the output connector (B), pins (B1 and B2).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Weldon 7000 Electronic School Bus 4/8-Lamp Flasher</title>
            <para>The Weldon 7000 electronic school bus 4/8-lamp flasher module contains circuits. The flasher module
                outputs are connected to terminal strip (TB1). The (TB1) interfaces the flasher module to the warning
                lights, stop arm and crossing arm system of the school bus. Power from terminal (P2) is to fuse panel
                fuse 1, connector (F2), circuit 12BLK1, connector (J8), connector (C14), master flasher switch on left
                hand switch panel, connector (C14), circuit 12RED30, connector (J8), circuit 12RED30 to master switch on
                the flasher. Power from terminal (P2) is to fuse panel fuse 1, connector (F2), circuit 12BLK1, connector
                (J8), connector (C14), master flasher switch, connector (C14), circuit 12BLK1, to flasher module start
                switch on the left hand switch panel, circuit 12RED39, connector (J8), circuit 12RED39 to flasher module
                start switch on the flasher.
            </para>
            <para>When door switch is connected to terminal on flasher marked "To Flash Red Lts. ONLY after Amber
                Lts."
            </para>
            <para>1. Turn ON "MASTER SWITCH" to apply power to flasher.</para>
            <para>2. Push the momentary "START SWITCH" to start amber lights flashing.</para>
            <para>3. When door is opened (actuating the "DOOR SWITCH") the amber lights will stop flashing and the red
                lights will begin flashing. If the stop arm and/or crossing gate are installed, they will extend and the
                lights located on them will also flash.
            </para>
            <para>4. After the door is closed, all lamps will stop flashing and the stop arm and/or crossing gate will
                retract.
            </para>
            <para>5. If the door is opened without the "START SWITCH" being actuated, no lights will flash. Pushing the
                "START SWITCH" while the door is open will start the red lights flashing and extend the stop arm and/or
                crossing gate.
            </para>
            <para>When the door switch is connected to terminal on flasher marked "To flash Red Lts. Whenever door is
                open"
            </para>
            <para>1. Turn ON "MASTER SWITCH" to apply power to flasher.</para>
            <para>2. Push the momentary "START SWITCH" to start amber lights flashing.</para>
            <para>3. When door is opened (actuating the "DOOR SWITCH") the amber lights will stop flashing and the red
                lights will begin flashing. If the stop arm and/or crossing gate are installed, they will extend and the
                lights located on them will also flash.
            </para>
            <para>4. After the door is closed, all lamps will stop flashing and the stop arm and/or crossing gate will
                retract.
            </para>
            <para>5. Whenever door is opened, the red lights will begin flashing. If the stop arm and/or crossing gate
                are installed, they will extend and the lights located on them will also flash.
            </para>
            <para>The override switch on the Weldon 7000 flasher should be a double pole, single throw switch. This is
                essentially two switches combined into one housing with a single control. When you activate the override
                switch, it simultaneously supplies a separate source of power (in case there is something wrong with the
                master switch or wiring) and also supplies a separate ground signal to the flasher's door switch
                terminal (in case there is something wrong with the door switch or its wiring), causing the red lights
                to flash as long as this switch is turned on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ELS B-1 School Bus 4/8-Lamp Flasher</title>
            <para>The ELS B-1 electronic school bus 4/8-lamp flasher module contains circuits. The flasher module
                outputs are connected to terminal strip (TB1). The (TB1) interfaces the flasher module to the warning
                lights, stop arm and crossing arm system of the school bus. Power from terminal (P2) is to fuse panel
                fuse 1, connector (F2), circuit 12BLK1, connector (J8), connector (C14), master flasher switch on left
                hand switch panel, connector (C14), circuit 12RED30, connector (J8), circuit 12RED30 to master switch on
                the flasher. Power from terminal (P2) is to fuse panel fuse 1, connector (F2), circuit 12BLK1, connector
                (J8), connector (C14), master flasher switch, connector (C14), circuit 12BLK1, to flasher module start
                switch on the left hand switch panel, circuit 12RED39, connector (J8), circuit 12RED39 to flasher module
                start switch on the flasher.
            </para>
            <para>The ELS model B-1 flasher is shipped from ELS programmed for non-sequential operation of the red
                lights. For sequential operation, merely remove and discard the jumper plug marked "NS Jumper". To do
                this, grasp the little black (or red) plastic plug with fingers or long nosed pliers and pull out and
                away from the flasher. Non-sequential means the red lights come ON every time the service door is opened
                (with the master switch "ON"). Sequential means the red lights only come ON after the start switch has
                been actuated. For all applications except Florida, leave the manual button in place.
            </para>
            <para>The heavy-duty replaceable relays are oriented from left to right in the following order: selector,
                latching, amber flasher and red flasher (s-l-a-r).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Builder Connector (194)</title>
            <para>The body builder connector (194) is the circuit interface to the switch panel lights circuit 62F to
                16BLU6, ignition feed circuit 13F to 16BLK6, accessory feed circuit 12B to 16BLU6, back-up lights
                circuit 71A to 16BLU6, stop lights circuit 70C to 14RED6, left turn lights circuit 56D to 14PNK6, right
                turn lights circuit 57D to 14YEL6 and park/tail lights circuit 58E to 14BRN6. The body electrical
                circuits are continued in the following circuits.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-Master Disconnect Switch</title>
            <para>The accessory feed circuit 12B to circuit 16LTBL6 controls voltage to the body builder connector
                (194), master disconnect, rear emergency exit door, right side door, emergency kick-out windows, roof
                hatch, 3" red light over emergency exits, emergency exit indicator light, driver buzzer and noise kill
                solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>Power is fed to key switch (63) on circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F7, circuit 15 from body battery
                feed stud (J1). When the key switch is moved to the accessory, ignition, or start positions, power is
                supplied to circuit 12, fuseblock fuse F11, circuit 12B to the body builder connector (194), circuit
                16LTBL6, connector (J26), circuit 16LTBL6, master disconnect solenoid control stud. Also, from connector
                (J26), power circuit 16BLK40, connector (J54), master disconnect ON/OFF switch, connector (J54), circuit
                16BLK40A to control terminal on master disconnect solenoid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-Rear, Left and Right Emergency Exit Door Switches</title>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40 to driver buzzer and
                grounded by circuit 16PNK5, connector (J6), left hand body circuit 16PNK5, connector (J10), circuit
                16PNK5, open rear emergency exit door closed switch to ground.
            </para>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40 to driver buzzer and
                grounded by circuit 16PNK5, connector (J6), left hand body circuit 16PNK5 with splice to left hand side
                door closed switch to ground, circuit 16PNK5 to open rear exit door closed switch to ground, and
                connector (J10), rear cap circuit 16PNK5 with splice to right side door closed switch to ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-Kick-Out Emergency Window and Roof Hatch Switches</title>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40 to driver buzzer and
                grounded by circuit 16PNK14, connector (J6), left hand body circuit 16PNK14 with splice to two left hand
                kickout windows closed switch to ground, connector (J9), rear cap circuit 16PNK14, splice to right hand
                body circuit 16PNK14, with splice to two right side kickout windows closed switch to ground.
            </para>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40 to driver buzzer and
                grounded by circuit 16PNK57, connector (J6), circuit 16PNK57 to two open roof hatch closed switches to
                ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-3" Red Light Over Left, Rear and Right Emergency Doors</title>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40 to connector (J15), left
                hand body circuit 16BLK40 with splice to 3" red light over left emergency exit door, connector (J10),
                rear cap circuit 16BLK40 with splice to 3" red light over rear emergency exit door, connector (J11),
                right hand body circuit 16BLK40 to right hand side 3" red light over right hand emergency exit door.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-Emergency Exit Indicator Light</title>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40, connector (J3), 16BLK40
                to emergency exit indicator light on right hand switch panel, circuit 16PNK57, connector (J3), circuit
                16PNK57 to driver buzzer.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accessory Feed-Noise Kill Switch</title>
            <para>Power from fuse F11, circuit 16BLK40 to terminal board (TB3), circuit 16BLK40, connector (J83),
                circuit 16BLK40, connector (C38), noise kill ON/OFF switch, connector (C38), circuit 16BLU69, connector
                (J83), circuit 16BLU69, to noise kill solenoid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Back-Up Lights and Alarm</title>
            <para>The back-up light switch circuit 71A to circuit 16BLU6 controls voltage to the body builder connector
                (194), back-up lights and alarm horn.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, energizes IGN relay # 1 (R2) and
                power is also supplied from bus cab feed (J1), circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F8, circuit 14D, relay
                (R2), circuit 13B, fuseblock fuse F16, circuit 71, connector (3), circuit 71, connector (304), and a
                black wire to the back-up light switch. When the back-up light switch contacts close, power flows
                through a white wire, connector (304), circuit 71A, connector (3), and circuit 71A to the body builder
                connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power continues with circuit 71A at connector (194), circuit 16BLU83, connector (J26), flasher
                console circuit 16BLU83, connector (J15), left hand body circuit 16BLU83, connector (J10), circuit
                16BLU83, left back-up light and rear cap circuit 16BLU83, right back-up light. Also, power at connector
                (J26), sealed engine harness circuit 16BLU83A, connector (R3), chassis frame circuit 16BLU83, connector
                (SS14), chassis frame circuit 16BLU83, connector (SS15), red wire to back-up alarm horn on rear most
                crossmember, and black wire ground path connector (SS15), chassis frame circuit 16WHT83, connector
                (SS14), to ground stud on engine cowl (dash &#38; toe).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ignition Feed-Air Door Dump Valve</title>
            <para>The ignition feed circuit 13F to circuit 16BLK6 controls voltage to the body builder connector (194)
                and dump valve. When the key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, energizes IGN relay
                # 1 (R2) and power is also supplied from bus cab feed (J1), circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F8,
                circuit 14D, relay (R2), circuit 13B, fuseblock fuse F14, circuit 13F to the body builder connector
                (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power for the dump valve is circuit 16BLK83, connector (J26), flasher console circuit 16BLK83A,
                connector (J1), circuit 16BLK83 to air door switch ON the right hand dash, circuit 16BLK19, connector
                (J1), circuit 16BLK19, left hand body connector, circuit 16BLK19, connector (J71), front cap circuit
                16BLK19, connector (J72) to operate the dump valve. Or, the power for the dump valve is circuit 16BLK83,
                connector (J26), flasher console circuit 16BLK83A, connector (J1), circuit 16BLK83 to jumper across the
                air door switch on the right hand dash, circuit 16BLK19, connector (J1), circuit 16BLK19, left hand body
                connector, circuit 16BLK19, connector (J71), front cap circuit 16BLK19, connector (J72) to dump valve
                switch over entrance door to operate the dump valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ignition Feed-Air Door Control</title>
            <para>The ignition feed circuit 13F to circuit 16BLK6 controls voltage to the body builder connector (194)
                and air door control (two position or three position door switch). When the key switch (63) is moved to
                the start or ignition position, energizes IGN relay # 1 (R2) and power is also supplied from bus cab
                feed (J1), circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F8, circuit 14D, relay (R2), circuit 13B, fuseblock fuse
                F14, circuit 13F to the body builder connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power for the air door control (two position or three position door switch) is circuit 16BLK83,
                connector (J26), flasher console circuit 16BLK83, connector (J70), circuit 16BLK83 to close air door
                switch ON the left hand accessory panel, circuit 16BLK83A to open air door switch, circuit 16BLK83B from
                close door switch to connector (J70), flasher console circuit 16BLK83, connector (J15), left hand body
                connector circuit 16BLK83, connector (J71), front cap circuit 16BLK83, connector (J72) over door to the
                red wire on air close door solenoid and black wire to ground circuit 16WHT. And circuit 16BLK83A to open
                air door switch on the left hand accessory panel, circuit 16BLK20 from open air door switch to connector
                (J70), flasher console circuit 16BLK20, connector (in-line), left hand body connector circuit 16BLK20,
                connector (J71), front cap circuit 16BLK20, connector (J72) over door to the red wire on air open door
                solenoid and black wire to ground circuit 16WHT.
            </para>
            <para>The flasher start switch ground circuit 16WHT-, connector (J70), circuit 16WHT- flasher plate ground
                stud and to circuit 16WHT70, connector (J70), circuit 16WHT70, to the flasher module (Weldon) pin 9 or
                10, "flash red" or (ELS) pin 3 "door sw".
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ignition Feed-Air Compressor</title>
            <para>The ignition feed circuit 13F to circuit 16BLK6 controls voltage to the body builder connector (194)
                and air compressor. When the key switch (63) is moved to the start or ignition position, energizes IGN
                relay # 1 (R2) and power is also supplied from bus cab feed (J1), circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F8,
                circuit 14D, relay (R2), circuit 13B, fuseblock fuse F14, circuit 13F to the body builder connector
                (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power for the air compressor is circuit 16BLK83, connector (J26), flasher console circuit
                16BLK83A, connector (J1), circuit 16BLK83 to air compressor relay, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-
                to flasher plate ground stud, the power from fuse (F20), connector (E3), circuit 12BLU65, relay closed
                contacts, circuit 12BLU65, connector (R2), circuit 12BLU65, connector (E53), to blue wire of the air
                compressor and black wire to connector (E53), circuit 12WHT- to ground stud on engine cowl (dash &#38;
                toe).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Panel Lights and Switch Illumination</title>
            <para>The panel light switch circuit 62F to circuit 16DKBL dims/brightens the voltage to the body builder
                connector (194), panel lights and switch illumination.
            </para>
            <para>From body battery feed stud (J1), power is applied to circuits 14A, 14AA, fuseblock fuse F1, circuit
                50A, and headlight switch (23). When the headlight switch (23) is in the park lights or headlights ON
                position, power is fed to circuit 62, fuse 28, circuit 62A and the panel lights dimmer control (22).
                From the dimmer control (22), an adjustable voltage is applied to circuit 62B and feed block (8). From
                the feed block, power is supplied through circuit 62F to the body builder connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37A, connector (J8), circuit 16VIO37 to clearance lights
                switch, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J8), to flasher plate ground stud. Through
                connector (J8), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the destination sign, master flasher,
                flasher light and override switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37B, connector (J7), circuit 16VIO37 to dome light switch,
                with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J7), to flasher plate ground stud. Through connector
                (J7), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the driver dome, activity light, rear row, front
                dome and rear dome switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37C, connector (J9), circuit 16VIO37 to left midship heater
                switch, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J9), to flasher plate ground stud. Through
                connector (J9), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the right midship heater, driver
                heater, defrost fan and stepwell heater switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37, connector (J10), circuit 16VIO37 to booster pump switch,
                with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J10), to flasher plate ground stud. Through connector
                (J10), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the left rear heater, right rear heater, strobe
                light, master disconnect, vandalock (air door) and alternate entrance door switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37, connector (J11), circuit 16VIO37 to front power vent
                switch, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J11), to flasher plate ground stud. Through
                connector (J11), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the rear power vent, heated mirror,
                heated wiper blade and camera switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37, connector (J12), circuit 16VIO37 to flasher mom cancel
                switch, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J12), to flasher plate ground stud. Through
                connector (J12), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are the stop arm cancel, crossing gate
                cancel, luggage box lights, lift and bottom step heater switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37D, connector (J1), circuit 16VIO37 to windshield wiper
                switch, with the ground path circuit 16WHT-, connector (J1), to flasher plate ground stud.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37D, connector (J1), circuit 16VIO37, connector (C4) to
                flasher light switch, with the ground path connector (C4), circuit 16WHT-, connector (J1), to flasher
                plate ground stud. Through connector (C4), connector (J1), paralleled switch illumination power circuits
                are the override and Virginia warning light switches.
            </para>
            <para>The power for the panel lights and switch illumination is circuit 16DKBL, connector (J26), terminal
                board (TB2), flasher console circuit 16VIO37D, connector (J1), circuit 16VIO37, connector (C1) to left
                hand defog switch, with the ground path connector (C1), circuit 16WHT-, connector (J1), to flasher plate
                ground stud. Through connector (C1), connector (J1), paralleled switch illumination power circuits are
                the right defog and sander switches.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Lights</title>
            <para>The stop light switch circuit 70C to circuit 14RED6 controls voltage to the body builder connector
                (194), stop lights.
            </para>
            <para>Using air brakes, the body battery feed stud (J1), power is applied to circuits 14AA, 14A, fuseblock
                fuse F3, and circuit 70, to slice, circuit 70A, to air stop light switch connector (80). When the brake
                pedal is applied, the air stoplight switches (79) and (80) supplies power to the body builder connector
                (194) from splice to circuit 70C.
            </para>
            <para>Using hyd brakes, the body battery feed stud (J1), power is applied to circuits 14AA, 14A, fuseblock
                fuse F3, and circuit 70A to stop light switch connector (50). When the brake pedal is applied, the
                closed contacts of the stoplight switch (50) supply power to the body builder connector (194) through
                circuits 70C.
            </para>
            <para>The power continues with circuit 70C at connector (194), circuit 14RED83, connector (J26), flasher
                console circuit 14RED83, connector (J15), left hand body circuit 16RED83, connector (J9), circuit
                16RED83, 4" (or 7") left stop &#38; tail lights w/license lens and rear cap circuit 16RED84, 4" (or 7")
                right stop &#38; tail lights w/license lens.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Park/Tail Lights</title>
            <para>The park/tail lights switch circuit 58E to circuit 14BRN6 controls voltage to the body builder
                connector (194), park/tail lights.
            </para>
            <para>From body battery feed stud (J1), power is applied to circuits 14AA, 14A, fuseblock fuse F1, circuit
                50A (splice and circuit 50D with special wire), and headlight switch (23). When the headlight switch
                (23) is in the parking lights or headlights ON position, power is to circuit 58D, fuseblock fuse F27,
                circuit 58E and body builder connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power continues with circuit 58E at connector (194), circuit 14BRN83, connector (J26), flasher
                console circuit 16BRN83, connector (J15), left hand body circuit 16BRN83, connector (J9), circuit
                16BRN83, 4" (or 7") left tail lights w/license lens and rear cap circuit 16BRN84, 4" (or 7") right tail
                lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Left Turn Lights and Right Turn Lights</title>
            <para>The left turn lights circuit 56D to circuit 14PNK6 and right turn lights circuit 57D to circuit 14YEL6
                controls voltage to the body builder connector (194), turn signal lights.
            </para>
            <para>Power is applied by body battery feed stud (J1) to circuits 14AA and 14B, fuseblock fuse F6, circuit
                55, flasher (F35), and circuit 55A/60, to circuits 55A and 60 (with tilt steering column) or to circuit
                60 (with stationary column) of turn signal switch (193).
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the left turn position, the switch contacts close and power is
                also applied to connector (193) and circuit 56D to the body builder connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power continues with circuit 56D at connector (194), circuit 14YEL83, connector (J26), flasher
                console circuit 16YEL83, connector (J15), left hand body circuit 16YEL83, left side directional light,
                circuit 16YEL83, connector (J9), circuit 16YEL83, 7" left rear directional light, and connector (J26)
                circuit 16YEL83A, connector (J2), circuit 16YEL83, 7" left front cowl directional light.
            </para>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is moved to the right turn position, the switch contacts close and power
                is also applied to connector (193), and circuit 57D to the body builder connector (194).
            </para>
            <para>The power continues with circuit 57D at connector (194), circuit 14GRN84, connector (J26), flasher
                console circuit 16GRN84, connector (J15), left hand body circuit 16GRN84, connector (J9), and rear cap
                circuit 16GRN84, 7" right rear directional light, connector (J11), circuit 16GRN84, right side
                directional light, and connector (J26) circuit 16GRN84A, connector (J2), circuit 16GRN84, 7" right front
                cowl directional light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Starter Interrupt/Interlock</title>
            <para>Power is fed to key switch (63) on circuits 14AA, 14C, fuseblock fuse F7, 15 from body battery feed
                stud (J1). When the key switch is moved to the start position, power is supplied to circuit 17C, starter
                interrupt connector (195), circuit 16PNK14, connector (S47), 16PNK58, interlock solenoid closed contacts
                through circuit 16PNK58 to connector (S16) grounded switch, from solenoid circuit 16PNK58 to connector
                (S47), circuit 16PNK14, connector (195), and circuit 17 to the crank relay (R5).
            </para>
            <para>When an automatic transmission is in neutral, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM
                is supplied with 12 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the
                crank relay (R5) by providing a ground to the relay coil through circuit 97H, bulkhead connector (2) and
                circuit 97H. The starter relay (387) will energize and the starter will crank when the vandalock or
                other door switch devices do not open the ground path.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Electrical Harness</title>
            <para>The bus body electrical harness connects power from the console harness is routed through connector
                (P26) to chassis adapter connector (S26) for the left brake light, accessory feed, panels lights,
                back-up lights, ignition feed, left directional, right directional, and marker lights, and connector
                (P47) to chassis adapter connector (S47) for the starter interlock. Also, power from the console harness
                is routed through connector (RS1) to sealed engine compartment connector (SP1) for the sander, bottom
                step heater, booster pump, and connector (RS2) to sealed engine compartment connector (SP2) for the air
                compressor, and connector (RS3) to sealed engine compartment connector (SP3) for the step lights,
                back-up alarm, windshield washer, heated mirror, luggage box lights, sander fill, pa horn, crossing
                gate, crossing gate magnet, fog lights and lift solenoid. Also, power from the console harness is routed
                through connector (S1) to dash connector (P1) for the left fan, right fan and strobe lights, and
                connector (S2) to dash connector (P2) for the fog lights, vandalock, step heater and windshield washer,
                and connector (S3) to dash connector (P3) for the tell-tail lights and right hand switch panel, and
                connector (S4) to dash connector (P4) for the sanders, and connector (S5) to dash connector (P5) for the
                windshield washer switch panel. Also, power from the console harness is routed through connector (S7) to
                left hand switch panel connector (P7) for the dome lights and activity lights, and connector (S8) to
                left hand switch panel connector (P8) for the flasher start switch, override, flasher light, master
                flasher, designation sign and clearance lights, and connector (S9) to left hand switch panel connector
                (P9) for the stepwell heater, defroster fan, driver fan, left mid heater and right heater, and connector
                (S10) to left hand switch panel connector (P10) for the alt. ent door, vandalock, right rear heater,
                left rear heater and booster pump, and connector (S11) to left hand switch panel connector (P11) for the
                camera, heated wiper blade, heated mirror, rear power vent and front power vent, and connector (S12) to
                left hand switch panel connector (P12) for the bottom step heater, lift, luggage box, crossing gate,
                stop alarm cancel and flasher mon cancel, and connector (S54) to left hand switch panel connector (P54)
                for the master disconnect and strobe lights. Also, power from the console harness is routed through
                connector (S70) to accessory panel connector (P70) for the air doors. Also, power from the console
                harness is routed through connector (S6) to left body connector (P6) for the emergency buzzer, kick out
                windows, roof hatch, inval lift and spare, and connector (S15) to left body connector (P15) for the
                brake lights, directional lights, spare and cluster lights, and connector (S16) to left body connector
                (P16) for the clearance lights, cluster lights, dome lights, strobe lights, heater mirror up, act
                lights, rear door vanalock, driver lights, lift solenoid, left fan and right fan, and connector (S51) to
                left body connector (P51) for the destination sign, driver fan, power vent and mid heater. Also, power
                from the console harness is routed through connector (UM1410THX4) to auxiliary connector (UF1612PDX4)
                for the heaters and connector (UM1410THX2) to auxiliary connector (UF1612PDX2) for the heaters.
            </para>
            <para>The bus body electrical harness connects power from the left body harness is routed through connector
                (P6) to B1 front cap connector (S6) for the emergency door buzzer, kick out window, roof hatch and TT
                light, and connector (P15) to B1 front cap connector (S15) for the left brake light, ignition, sander
                feed, left back-up light, left direction light, left tail light and radio power, and connector (P16) to
                B1 front cap connector (S16) for the cluster light, clearance lights, left dome, right dome, rear dome,
                strobe light, heated mirror, activity light, rear door vanalock, driver light, TT light, left fan low,
                left fan high, right fan low and right fan high, and connector (P51) to B1 front cap connector (S51) for
                the left brake light, ignition accessory, sander feed, left back-up light, ignition feed, left direction
                light, right direction light and radio power. Also, power from the left body harness is routed through
                connector (P9) to B2 rear cap connector (S9) for the clearance lights, brakes, left tail light, right
                direction light, left direction light, red TT light, amber warning light and kick out window, and
                connector (P10) to B2 rear cap connector (S10) for the left back-up light, ignition accessory, emergency
                door buzzer, red warning light, amber warning light, right dome, destination sign, right speaker, rear
                dome and activity light, and connector (P12) to B2 rear cap connector (S12) for the TT light, step
                light, rear door vanalock and air door solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>The bus body electrical harness connects power from the right body harness is routed through connector
                (P11) to rear cap connector (S11) for the right speaker, ignition accessory, right dome light, clearance
                lights, right direction light and TT light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clearance/Cluster Lights</title>
            <para>The clearance/cluster lights switch panel voltage to the body electrical harness and is utilized by
                the body clearance, cluster, corner marker and midship intermediate marker light circuits. Power from
                terminal (P2) is to fuse panel fuse 2, connector (F1), circuit 16BLK2, connector (J8), circuit 16BLK2,
                connector (C12), clearance/cluster lights switch on left hand switch panel, connector (C12), circuit
                16YEL2, connector (J8), circuit 16YEL2, connector (J16), circuit 16YEL51, connector (J7), front cap,
                circuit 16YEL51 to cluster light, circuit 16YEL51A to cluster light and circuit 16YEL51B to cluster
                light, and circuit 16YEL2, connector (J7), front cap, circuit 16YEL2 to corner marker and circuit
                16YEL2A to corner marker light, and left body, circuit 16YEL2A to left midship intermediate marker
                light, circuit 16YEL2B, connector (J9), rear cap, circuit 16YEL2B to corner marker, cluster and corner
                marker lights, connector (J11), right body, circuit 16YEL2B to right midship intermediate marker light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stop Arm</title>
            <para>The stop arm motor circuit is controlled by the motor control circuit, from which it is insulated. For
                this reason, the base of the unit must be properly grounded to the bus body. Power from terminal (P1) is
                to fuse panel fuse 22, connector (C6), circuit 16BLK63, terminal board (TB1), red wire to (electric)
                stop arm, solid yellow to flasher module (right and left), circuit 16BLU63 from flasher "stop arm" and
                yellow wire to stop arm, and green wire to ground. Power from terminal (P1) is to fuse panel fuse 22,
                connector (C6), circuit 16BLK63, terminal board (TB1), red wire to (air) stop arm, solid red to flasher
                module (right and left), circuit 16BLU63 from flasher "stop arm" and black wire to air solenoid, and
                white wire to ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crossing Gate</title>
            <para>The crossing gate motor circuit is controlled by the motor control circuit, from which it is
                insulated. For this reason, the base of the unit must be properly grounded to the bus body. Power from
                terminal (P1) is to fuse panel fuse 22, connector (C6), circuit 16BLK63A, connector (RS3), sealed engine
                harness circuit 16BLK63, connector (SS1), red wire to gate connector and motor, from gate connector red
                wire from optional magnet, connector (SS1), to circuit 16RED64, connector (RS3), circuit 16RED64 to
                terminal board (TB1), to flasher "accy", and blue wire to connector (SS1) and blue wire from optional
                magnet to circuit 16BLU63, connector (RS3), circuit 16BLU63 to terminal board (TB1), to flasher "stop
                arm" extend, and from gate connector, white wire to connector (SS1) and white wire from optional magnet
                to circuit 16WHT- to ground on engine cowl (dash &#38; toe).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater Fans</title>
            <para>The heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater blower motors. Power from
                terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 31, connector (A6), circuit 12BLK9, connector (J9), circuit 12BLK9,
                connector (C19), driver heater control switch, from high position, connector (C19), circuit 12RED43,
                connector (J53), to orange wire of driver heater motor, and driver heater control switch, from low
                position, connector (C19), circuit 12BLU42, connector (J53), to red wire of driver heater motor, and
                from black wire of driver heater motor, connector (J53), circuit 12WHTA, connector (J81), circuit
                12WHTA, to ground stud on flasher plate.
            </para>
            <para>The defroster control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the defroster blower motors. Power
                from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 36, connector (A4), circuit 12BLK7, connector (J9), circuit
                12BLK7, connector (C20), defroster control switch, from high position, connector (C20), circuit 12RED50,
                connector (J53), to orange wire of defroster motor, and defroster control switch, from low position,
                connector (C120), circuit 12BLU49, connector (J53), to red wire of defroster motor, and from black wire
                of defroster motor, connector (J53), circuit 12WHTB, connector (J81), circuit 12WHTB, to ground stud on
                flasher plate.
            </para>
            <para>The stepwell heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater blower motors.
                Power from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 37, connector (A8), circuit 12BLK8, connector (J9),
                circuit 12BLK8, connector (C21), stepwell heater control switch, from high position, connector (C21),
                circuit 12RED17, connector (J9), circuit 12RED17, connector (J2), circuit 12RED17, connector (J7), to
                orange wire of stepwell heater motor, and stepwell heater control switch, from low position, connector
                (C21), circuit 12RED17, connector (J9), circuit 12RED17, connector (J2), circuit 12RED17, connector
                (J7), to red wire of stepwell heater motor, and from black wire of stepwell heater motor, connector
                (J7), circuit 12WHT8, to ground screw cross car.
            </para>
            <para>The left midship auxiliary heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater
                blower motors. Power from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 33, connector (A1), circuit 12BLK10,
                connector (J81), circuit 12BLK10, connector (C17), left midship auxiliary heater control switch, from
                high position, connector (C17), circuit 12RED23, connector (J81), to heater motor, and left midship
                auxiliary heater control switch, from low position, connector (C17), circuit 12BLU22, connector (J81),
                to heater motor.
            </para>
            <para>The right midship auxiliary heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater
                blower motors. Power from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 35, connector (A3), circuit 12BLK60,
                connector (J81), circuit 12BLK60, connector (C18), right midship auxiliary heater control switch, from
                high position, connector (C18), circuit 12RED25, connector (J81), to heater motor, and right midship
                auxiliary heater control switch, from low position, connector (C18), circuit 12BLU24, connector (J81),
                to heater motor.
            </para>
            <para>The left rear auxiliary heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater blower
                motors. Power from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 34, connector (A2), circuit 12BLK11, connector
                (J10), circuit 12BLK11, connector (C23), left rear auxiliary heater control switch, from high position,
                connector (C23), circuit 12RED34, connector (J10), circuit 12RED34, in-line connector, circuit 12RED34,
                in-line connector to heater motor, and left rear auxiliary heater control switch, from low position,
                connector (C23), circuit 12BLU33, connector (J10), circuit 12BLU33, in-line connector, circuit 12BLU33,
                in-line connector to heater motor.
            </para>
            <para>The right rear auxiliary heater control switches uses high, low, and OFF control of the heater blower
                motors. Power from terminal (P3) is to fuse panel fuse 40, connector (B2), circuit 12BLK61, connector
                (J54), circuit 12BLK61, connector (C24), right rear auxiliary heater control switch, from high position,
                connector (C24), circuit 12RED38, connector (J54), circuit 12RED38, in-line connector, circuit 12RED38,
                in-line connector to heater motor, and right rear auxiliary heater control switch, from low position,
                connector (C24), circuit 12BLU37, connector (J54), circuit 12BLU37, in-line connector, circuit 12BLU37,
                in-line connector to heater motor.
            </para>
            <para>The booster pump control switches uses ON/OFF control of the booster pump motor. Power from terminal
                (P2) is to fuse panel fuse 6, connector (G3), circuit 12BLK14, connector (S10), circuit 12BLK14,
                connector (C22), booster pump control switch, from ON position, connector (C22), circuit 12BLU44,
                connector (S10), circuit 12BLU44, connector (RP1), circuit 12BLU44, connector (ES2), to orange wire of
                booster pump motor, and from black wire of booster pump motor, connector (ES2), circuit 12WHT-, to
                ground stud on engine cowl (dash &#38; doe).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>W/S Wiper</title>
            <para>The wiper switch uses either single, dual or intermittent control of the windshield wipers. Power from
                terminal (P2) is to fuse panel fuse 5, connector (G4), circuit 12BLK12, connector (J3), circuit 12BLK12,
                connector (J5), circuit 12BLK12, splice, circuit 12BLK12A, connector (J9), circuit 12RED, dual control
                w/s wiper switch with intermittent function, and circuit 12BLK, connector (J9), circuit 12WHT-,
                connector (J5), circuit 12WHT-, connector (J3), circuit 12WHT12 to ground. And from splice, circuit
                12BLK12A, connector (J5), circuit 12BLK12A, connector (J45) to black wire of the w/s wiper motor assy,
                and brown wire, connector (J45) and circuit 12WHT- to ground. And from splice, circuit 12BLK13,
                connector (J5), circuit 12BLK13, connector (J46) to black wire of the w/s wiper motor assy, and brown
                wire, connector (J46) and circuit 12WHT- to ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_32.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08266.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
