<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - LIGHT SYSTEMS - HEADLIGHT SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x08260220">
        <title>HEADLIGHT SYSTEM</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f0826025" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0826065.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Headlights Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEADLIGHTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DRIVETRAIN 1939 DATA LINK (FROM ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIRECT HEADLIGHT ENABLE CIRCUIT FROM EGC</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HEADLIGHT SWITCH (IN ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. DIMMER SWITCH (PART OF TURN SIGNAL ASSEMBLY)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0826025">Headlights Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The headlight system consists of the headlights, headlight switch, dimmer switch, flash to pass, day
                time running lights (mandatory for Canada, optional for USA) and the optional "lights on with wipers
                feature".
            </para>
            <para>The fender mounted headlights are a one lamp system and share a molded cavity with the turn signals.
                The headlight switch is a 3-position (off/parking lights/headlights) rocker type located below the EGC.
                When the key is in the ignition position and the headlight switch is on the EGC will communicate with
                the ESC on the drivetrain 1939 data link. The ESC supplies voltage to the headlights as requested.
            </para>
            <para>While the key is not in the ignition position, the headlights will only operate in the low beam mode.
                This is enabled by a direct circuit from the EGC to the ESC, which is not dependant on the data link.
                This also acts as a fail-safe to activate the low beam headlights when communication on the drivetrain
                1939 data link is interrupted.
            </para>
            <para>The dimmer and flash to pass switches are located in the turn signal assembly. Pulling the turn signal
                lever toward the driver as far as it will go, while the headlights are on, will switch the headlights
                between hi-beam and low-beam operation.
            </para>
            <para>When the key is on and the headlights are off, pulling the turn signal slightly toward the driver and
                releasing the turn signal lever will flash the headlights.
            </para>
            <para>When the key is on and the headlights are on, pulling the turn signal slightly toward the driver and
                releasing the turn signal lever will momentarily switch the headlights between hi-beam and low-beam
                operation.
            </para>
            <para>The programmable day time running light feature allows the vehicle to operate in a "lights on"
                condition at all times without driver input. This system operates the headlights at partial
                illumination, but still helps to increase visibility even in bright sunshine. The daytime running lights
                will go off when the park brake is set or the ignition is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>When the programmable "lights on with wipers feature" is enabled the low beam headlights and park
                lights will be turned on by the ESC anytime the windshield wipers are activated, except during momentary
                wash/wipe. The lights will remain on after the wipers are turned off until the headlight switch is
                turned on and off or the key is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle is equipped with a remote keyless entry, the ESC will also turn the headlights on or
                off as required.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_476.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_478.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
