<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON 2000 SERIES&#8482; (LCT) TRANSMISSION ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This manual should be used to supplement the Allison troubleshooting manual TS3192EN.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before welding on any vehicle with an electronic control module for the transmission, engine,
                        antilock brake system or other electronically controlled components, it is mandatory to remove
                        all connectors going to the Electronic Control Module(s), including grounds. It is also
                        mandatory to disconnect the positive (+) and negative (- ) battery cables before connecting the
                        welder. Always attach welder ground cables as close as possible to the part being welded. Never
                        connect the welder ground cable to an ECM or ECM mounting bracket.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The contents of this service manual section focus on International-installed components and wiring and
                how those components function as part of the transmission electronic control system. For more detailed
                information regarding the Allison 2000 Series transmission and the Allison supplied components that are
                part of the electronic control system, refer to the appropriate Allison service manuals.
            </para>
            <para>The Allison 2000 Series transmission is an electronically controlled transmission designed by Allison
                Transmission Division of General Motors Corporation.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The majority of the troubleshooting procedures in this manual require using the EZ-Tech&#8482;
                        service tool with the TransPro&#174; diagnostic software, connected to the (9-pin) diagnostic
                        connector. TransPro software is available through Kent-Moore Heavy-Duty Division. A facility
                        that does not have the TransPro software will be limited to checking for system power to the
                        TCM, malfunctioning relays and poor connections.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Transmission Control Module (TCM)</title>
            <para>The Transmission Control Module (TCM) is a microprocessor, which is the brain of the transmission
                control system (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0824701">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The TCM contains Electronically Erasable Programmable Read
                Only Memory (EEPROM), which is programmed by Allison with a shift calibration that reflects the specific
                transmission.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0824701" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0824701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="200"/>
                <caption>Transmission Control Module (TCM)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRANSMISSION CONTROL MODULE (TCM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. GRAY CONNECTOR (3030)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RED CONNECTOR (3084)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0824702" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0824702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px" resolution="200"/>
                <caption>Transmission Control Module (TCM) Functions And Controls</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The TCM communicates with the vehicle electrical system and International-installed transmission
                control components through the transmission harness.
            </para>
            <para>The TCM receives inputs from:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>J1939 Data Link (Throttle Position)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Shift Selector</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Neutral Start/Reverse Signal Switch (Commonly called the NSBU)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The Antilock Brake System's ECM</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The TCM also receives inputs from other components that are part of the Allison electronic
                        control system (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0824702">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08247.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
