<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - CHASSIS ACCESSORIES - OPERATION - Transfer Case
        Shift Switch and Front Axle Engagement Switch and Indicator Lamp
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Transfer Case Shift Switch and Front Axle Engagement Switch and Indicator Lamp</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Transfer Case Shift Switch</title>
            <para>When the key switch (24) is in the ignition or accessories position, power is fed to accessories feed
                block (J2), circuit 12A, fuse F14, circuit 93, and connector (14) to transfer case shift switch (174).
                When the switch is moved to the on position, power flows through its indicator and ground circuit 93-G
                to cab ground indicating that it is in the on position. Power also flows through circuit 93C, connector
                (14), circuit 93C, connector (13) and a brown wire to the transfer case shift solenoid which is grounded
                through its mounting bracket and a blue wire to cab ground. This shifts the transfer case into low
                range.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Axle Engagement Switch and Indicator Lamp</title>
            <para>Power is fed to the front axle engagement switch, from the transfer case switch, by way of circuit 42.
                When the switch is moved to the on position, power flows through its indicator, and ground circuit 42-G
                and 93-G to cab ground, indicating that it is in the on position.
            </para>
            <para>Power also flows through circuit 93C, connector (14), circuit 93B, connector (13), and a brown wire to
                the front axle engagement solenoid which is grounded through its mounting bracket and a blue wire to cab
                ground. This engages the front axle drive gears, which are located in the transfer case, to power the
                front drive axle.
            </para>
            <para>Power is provided to the front axle engaged indicator lamp by way of circuit 42C and connector (28).
            </para>
            <para>When the front axle is engaged, switch (708) contacts close, and a ground path is provided to the
                front axle engaged indicator lamp through connector (28), circuit 42-GA, connector (13), a red wire, the
                switch, and a brown wire to cab ground. This provides confirmation that the front axle is fully engaged.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_203.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_205.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
