<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 MODEL - HEATER AND AIR CONDITIONER (CAB) - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Power is supplied to (B2) battery stud, circuit 14W, 14Z, fuse F1-C, and circuit 75A to the heater control
            relay (463)/R5. When the key switch (452) is moved to the ignition position, power flows through the key
            switch, and circuits 13 and 13A to the coil of the ignition relay (462)/R1. The ground path for the ignition
            relay is circuits 11-GN and 11-GB to right cab ground stud (404). This energizes the ignition relay
            (462)/R1, and allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuits 13H and 13T to the coil of the
            heater control relay (463)/R5. The ground path for the heater control relay is circuits 13-GT, 50-GB, 75-GC,
            75-GB, 11-GN, and 11-GB to right cab ground stud (404). This energizes the heater control relay (463)/R5,
            and allows power to flow through the N.O. contacts and circuit 75B to fan control switch (83).
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (83) is moved to the low position, power flows through the switch,
            circuit 75C, connector (45), circuit 75C, resistor/thermofuse (27), circuit 75T, connector (44), circuit
            75T, high speed relay (462)/R2 N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (44), and circuit 75F to blower motor
            (39). This causes the blower motor to run at low speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuit
            75-G, connector (44), circuits 75-G and 11-G to right cab ground stud (404).
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (83) is moved to the medium position, power will flow through the switch
            as in the low speed setting, and power will also flow through the switch and circuit 75N to the medium speed
            relay (462)/R3. This energizes the medium speed relay (462)/R3 and allows power to flow through heater
            control relay (463)/R5 N.O. contacts, circuit 75D, medium speed relay (462)/R3 N.O. contacts, circuit 75M,
            connector (44), circuit 75M, resistor/thermofuse (27), circuit 75T, connector (44), circuit 75T, high speed
            relay (462)/R2 N.C. contacts, circuit 75F, connector (44), and circuit 75F to blower motor (39). This causes
            the blower motor to run at medium speed. The blower motor ground path is through circuits 75-G, connector
            (44), circuits 75-G and 11-G to right cab ground stud (404). The ground path for the medium speed relay
            (462)/R3 is circuits 75-GC, 75-GB, 11-GN and 11-GB to right cab ground stud (404).
        </para>
        <para>When the heater-A/C blower switch (83) is moved to the high position, power will flow through the switch
            as in the medium speed setting, and power will also flow through the switch and circuit 75H to the high
            speed relay (462)/R2. This energizes the high speed relay (462)/R2 which is grounded through circuits 75-GB,
            11-GN, and 11-GB to the right cab ground stud (404). This allows power to flow from (B2) battery stud
            through circuit 14W, 14X, fuse F1-A, circuit 75, high speed relay (462)/R2 N.O. contacts, circuit 75F,
            connector (44), and circuit 75F to blower motor (39). This causes the blower to run at high speed. The
            blower motor ground path is through circuit 75-G, connector (44), circuits 75-G and 11-G to right cab ground
            stud (404).
        </para>
        <para>When the blower switch (83) is in the low, medium or high position, power is supplied by the switch to
            circuit 77 and the air conditioner switch (30). When switch (30) is moved to the on position, power flows
            through its indicator light and ground circuits 77-GK and 11-GI to cab ground (429). This causes the
            indicator to illuminate. Power also flows from switch (30) through the blocking diode, circuits 77S and 77K
            to the A/C control relay (447)/R16, thus energizing the relay that is grounded through circuits 77-GS,
            12-GF, 82-GA, 12-GH, 82-GD and 11-GD to left cab ground stud (429).
        </para>
        <para>With the relay energized, power flows from the (B2) battery stud through circuits 14W and 14Z, fuse F1-B,
            circuit 77T, A/C control relay (447)/R16 N.O. contacts, circuit 77H, connector (45), and circuit 77B to the
            manual temperature control switch.
        </para>
        <para>When the temperature control switch determines that the temperature at the evaporator is above freezing
            [34&#176;F - 38&#176;F (1&#176;C - 3&#176;C)] , its contacts will close. This will cause power to flow
            through the control, circuit 77F, connector (45), circuit 77F, the air conditioning relay (463)/R6 N.C.
            contacts, circuit 77A, connector (102), circuit 77A, connector (N/L), and the black wire to the A/C
            compressor clutch.
        </para>
        <para>The compressor will then run until the temperature control switch's contacts open up, or the low or high
            pressure safety switch's contacts close.
        </para>
        <para>With the A/C system switch (30) and the blower control switch (83) turned on, voltage is also applied by
            A/C control relay (447)/R16 to circuit 77H, connector (45), and circuits 77C and 77E to the low pressure
            safety switch (N/L). Voltage is also applied to circuit 77H, connector (45), circuit 77C, and curcuit 77N to
            the high pressure safety switch. If the refrigerant pressure becomes too low, the low pressure safety switch
            (N/L) contacts will close and power will flow through circuits 77P and 77R, connector (45), circuits 77R and
            77D to the air conditioning relay (463)/R6. If the refrigerant pressure becomes too high, the high pressure
            safety switch (N/L) contacts will close and power will flow through circuits 77J and 77R, connector (45),
            circuits 77R and 77D to the air conditioning relay (463)/R6. The power will flow through the air
            conditioning relay (463)/R6 coil and ground circuits 77-G, 13-GT, 50-GB, 75-GC, 75-GB, 11-GN, and 11-GB to
            the right cab ground stud (404), thus energizing the relay.
        </para>
        <para>With the air conditioning relay (463)/R6 energized, power is interrupted to the refrigerant compressor
            clutch, and power is applied to circuit 77D going to the air conditioning relay coil. Thus the compressor is
            shut down and latched (locked) out by the air conditioning relay, and will not restart until the refrigerant
            pressure is back within operating range and the A/C on/off switch or the blower control switch is moved to
            the off position.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_249.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270_251.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08270.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
