<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ELECTRICAL
        SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3600, 3800, 4000FBC - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Power</title>
            <para>Vehicle batteries are connected in parallel with the positive battery cable connected to the cranking
                motor solenoid (B) terminal. The negative battery terminals are also connected in parallel with the
                negative cable connected to the cranking motor ground stud (G).
            </para>
            <para>The negative battery terminals are connected directly to the frame rail. The engine block, the cab,
                and the frame are also connected by ground cables or circuits to the cranking motor ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Power - Remote Start Terminal</title>
            <para>The remote start terminal allows an external battery power source to either charge the vehicle
                batteries or assist in cranking the engine. Connect the external battery positive cable to the remote
                start terminal and the external negative cable to vehicle frame rail.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Charging System and Circuits</title>
            <para>While the vehicle is running, the alternator supplies power through the (B) terminal and circuit 2 to
                the body builder feed stud (J1). From the stud, power is supplied to the key switch and the fuse block
                (1) power distribution center to supply the electrical demands of the vehicle. In addition, the
                alternator also supplies and maintains battery voltage through circuit 14/14-FL/14A-FL to the cranking
                motor solenoid (B) stud and through the battery cable to the batteries.
            </para>
            <para>The alternator is grounded through the (GRD) terminal and circuit 2-G to the starter motor ground stud
                (G).
            </para>
            <para>For a complete discussion on operating principles for alternators, refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in
                the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the specific alternator being serviced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the on position, power is supplied through circuit 13F to fuse H1. From
                the fuse, power flows through circuit 97P, the 45-pin bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and circuit 97P
                to the neutral position switch connector (438M) at the transmission.
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, connectors (438M) circuit 97P, and (438F) circuit 97AU are connected
                to the neutral position switch and when the transmission is in neutral, the switch contacts are closed
                and power flows through the switch contacts.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, circuits 97P and 97AU are connected together to complete the circuit.
            </para>
            <para>From connector (438), power is applied through circuit 97AU, bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and
                circuit 97AU to clutch switch connector (386).
            </para>
            <para>With an automatic transmission, a jumper is installed at this connector to connect circuit 97AU with
                circuits 97A and 97L. With the transmission in neutral, power is supplied through circuit 97A, the
                22-pin bulkhead connector (3) and (3A), and circuit 97A to the ECM. Power is also applied to the crank
                inhibit relay (661) contacts through circuit 97L. When the transmission is in gear, power is removed
                from the ECM and the relay.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission, connector (386) is connected to the clutch pedal switch. When the clutch
                pedal is in the released position, power flows through the switch contacts, circuit 97A, 22-pin bulkhead
                connector (3) and circuit 97A to the ECM. When the clutch pedal is depressed, power is switched from the
                ECM circuitry and is applied through circuit 97L to the crank inhibit relay (661) contacts.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is turned to the start position, power is applied through circuits 17 and 17C
                to the crank inhibit relay (661) coil windings.
            </para>
            <para>When an automatic transmission is in neutral, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of the ECM
                is supplied with 12 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the
                crank inhibit relay (661) by providing a ground to the relay coil through circuit 97H, bulkhead
                connector (3) and (3A), and circuit 97H.
            </para>
            <para>With a manual transmission and clutch pedal depressed, the driveline disengagement switch terminal of
                the ECM is a 0 volts. Providing the engine is not running, this signals the ECM to energize the crank
                inhibit relay (661) by providing a ground through circuit 97H, bulkhead connector (3) and (3A), and
                circuit 97H to the relay.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECM is programmed for the type of transmission installed and adjusts for the different
                        voltages received at the ECM driveline disengagement terminal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The energized crank inhibit relay controls the start relay (387) by providing power through circuit
                17F (17A with 3600), bulkhead connector (2) and (2A), and circuit 17F to the relay. This energizes the
                start relay which is grounded through circuit 17D, and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the crank motor ground stud
                (G).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is always present at the crank motor solenoid (B) terminal through the positive battery
                cable. Power is also available at the start relay (387) through the solenoid (B) terminal and circuit
                17-FL/17B. With the start relay energized, power flows through the relay contacts and circuit 17C to the
                (S) terminal of the crank motor solenoid which energizes the crank motor solenoid.
            </para>
            <para>With the crank motor solenoid energized, the solenoid engages the crank motor's shaft to rotate. When
                the engine starts and the key is released, the ECM removes the ground from the crank inhibit relay (661)
                which de-energizes the relay. This causes the start relay (387) to be de-energized and disengages the
                crank motor.
            </para>
            <para>As long as engine is running, the ECM will not allow the cranking motor to be engaged.</para>
            <para>For complete information on operation and servicing cranking motors used on these vehicles, refer to
                GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cranking Motor System and Circuits - Cranking Motor Thermal Overcrank Protection</title>
            <para>With thermal overcrank protection, the start relay control coil ground circuit 17D is connected to the
                normally closed thermal switch (417). The thermal switch is located in the end of the cranking motor.
                The thermal switch is grounded through connector (417), and circuit 17-G/11-GJ to the cranking motor
                ground (G) stud.
            </para>
            <para>If excessive cranking causes cranking motor temperature to reach pre-set thermal overcrank limits, the
                thermal switch opens causing the start relay (387) to de-energize, turning off power to the cranking
                motor solenoid (S) terminal and disengaging the cranking motor.
            </para>
            <para>When crank motor cools, the switch closes, permitting the crank motor to operate again.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ether Start</title>
            <para>When the key switch (63) is in the ignition or start position, power is available at circuit 12, fuse
                D1, and circuit 39/21, and the ether start switch. If the engine block temperature is below 50&#176; F,
                the thermo switch contacts will be closed. This will allow power to flow through the ether start switch,
                when it is depressed, through circuit 21A, and dash connector (2). From connector (2), power is applied
                through circuit 21A, connector (413) and circuit 21A (hood harness w/3800, 4000FBC), control valve
                connector (500) and circuit 21C, to the ether bottle control valve. Power then flows through the control
                valve, circuit 21B, control valve connector (500), and circuit 21B to the thermo switch. When power
                flows through the ether bottle control valve (500), a shot of ether is fed into the intake manifold of
                the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08267.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
