<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - INTRODUCTION - ELECTRICAL TEST EQUIPMENT - JUMPER WIRES AND TEST LEADS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>JUMPER WIRES AND TEST LEADS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Jumper Wires</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When using jumpers and test leads, always take care not to cause damage by forcing probe tips
                        into cavities. Use the appropriate tip adapters to prevent damage. Expanded cavities will cause
                        increased circuit resistance.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Jumper wires allow "jumping" across a suspected open or break in a circuit.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the circuit (Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0825009">Jumpers in Circuits</hotlnk>) works properly with the jumper wire in
                    place, but does not work when the jumper wire is removed, the circuit has an open spot.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0825009" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                             scalefitheight="432px"/>
                    <caption>Jumpers in Circuits</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A circuit without any opens or breaks has continuity (is continuous) and a DMM can be
                    used to measure the continuity (resistance of a few ohms) of the circuit with the battery removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Jumper wires are fitted with several types of tips or ends. It will be helpful to have several jumper
                wires available with different tips.
            </para>
            <para>If bypassing the switch with a jumper wire causes the light to illuminate, but closing the switch does
                not, it indicates the switch has failed.
            </para>
            <para>If, when the switch is closed, the light does not illuminate, and "jumpering" the switch doesn't cause
                the light to operate, but "jumpering" the light to ground causes the light to operate, then there is an
                open in the ground circuit.
            </para>
            <para>The jumper wire can be used to check for open relay contacts, wire breaks, poor ground connections,
                etc.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Test Leads</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When probing connectors, always take care not to damage them by forcing probe tips into
                        cavities. Use the appropriate tip adapters to prevent damage. Expanded cavities will cause
                        increased circuit resistance.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>NEVER insert the test meter probe tip into connectors where the probe tip will expand the terminal.
                Expanded terminals will cause increased circuit resistance.
            </para>
            <para>Construct test leads using a mating terminal, a short lead and an alligator clip. Insert the mating
                terminal into the connector and attach the alligator clip to the meter lead.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_HL0825002.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
