<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 2000, 4000, 8000 - BATTERY, CHARGING AND CRANKING SYSTEMS -
        TROUBLESHOOTING - Vehicle Charging System
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="3">
        <title>Vehicle Charging System</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Batteries Undercharged</title>
            <para>Before beginning test procedures: check battery cables and alternator wiring (especially grounds) for
                clean, tight connections. Wires and connectors should not be damaged or corroded.
            </para>
            <para>Perform the following checks before removing the alternator from the vehicle.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Accessories having been left on for an extended time.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check alternator drive belt tension (refer to GROUP 12 - ENGINE, Cooling in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual for belt tension specifications). As a general rule, if the alternator fan can
                    be rotated by pulling on the fan with one finger, the belt is too loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for defective batteries as described in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Battery Section
                    in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wiring defects. Visually check wiring, clamps, and connections for clean, tight
                    connections, free of damage and corrosion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine off, check voltage to ground at the BAT terminal of the alternator. A
                    zero reading indicates an open in circuit 2, between the alternator and batteries.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A defective component or wiring defect may be causing a small current drain that is less
                    than the fuse rating for the circuit so the fuse does not open. To locate the unwanted current
                    drain:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Batteries should be fully charged for the following test.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">KEY OFF- Turn all accessories and controls off. Disconnect circuit 2 from the
                        alternator B terminal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To check the entire system for current drains, insert the DMM leads in the COM and
                        10A fused jack on the meter. Set the meter to DC amps. Connect the meter in series with the
                        alternator. If the meter leads are not connected with correct polarity, a (-) amp reading will
                        be present.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Some current draw will be present. If the current draw is less than 0.3A move the
                        lead from the 10A jack to the 320mA jack to read the exact current flow.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Refer to the Battery Power Distribution circuit diagrams in CTS-5122W. Remove the
                        battery feed fuses one at a time, while monitoring the meter for any change in current flow.
                        Note that some circuits (such as clock or radio or engine computer, etc.) should be drawing some
                        current. Look for current draw in circuits that should not be active.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0823308">Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1</hotlnk>
                    below.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Alternator Tests</title>
            <para>The alternator output must reach the batteries and accessory loads with a minimum amount of voltage
                loss. Any loss slows the rate of charge to the batteries and can cause the batteries to be undercharged.
                Discharged batteries can damage the starter and cause vehicle electrical components to operate
                improperly.
            </para>
            <para>Most alternators control the maximum system voltage using a voltage regulator. Maximum voltage output
                is available at the alternator BAT terminal, but if any voltage is lost in the wiring, something less
                than the maximum will reach the batteries and load devices. The greatest losses occur when the charging
                system is outputting at the maximum rated level (amps).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0823308">
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0823310">Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <para>Instead of using alternator current output this test (and Alternator Wiring Test - Part 2 below) uses
                the same amount of current but draws it from the batteries (must be fully charged). Using the carbon
                pile load, the current flows in reverse through the circuit without the engine running.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Without the engine running, connect the carbon pile to the alternator output terminal
                    and ground.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Alternator output is at battery voltage.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect voltmeter across battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Rated output is stamped on the
                    case or on a tag.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure and record BATTERY VOLTAGE. Turn the carbon pile off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the voltmeter to the alternator, but do not connect to carbon pile clamps. Adjust
                    carbon pile to rated output (amps) of the alternator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure and record ALTERNATOR VOLTAGE. Turn carbon pile off.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>BATTERY Voltage (step 4) ________</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                ALTERNATOR Voltage (step 6) __________
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
                System Loss ________
            </para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is 0.7V or less</emph>, go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0823309">Alternator Replacement Test</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>If system loss
                <emph type="bold">is greater than 0.7V</emph>
                go to
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0823310">Alternator Wiring Test - Part 2.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0823310" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0823310.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0823310">
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0823311">Alternator Wiring Test - Part 2 (12V System Only)</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <para>If system voltage is MORE than 0.7V in Alternator Wiring Test - Part 1, above, perform this test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the carbon pile still connected, connect Fluke 88 meter to alternator BAT terminal
                    and to the positive battery terminal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Measure and record POSITIVE
                    CIRCUIT LOSS. Turn carbon pile off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the meter to the alternator ground and to the battery negative terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the carbon pile to alternator rated output (amps). Measure and record NEGATIVE
                    CIRCUIT LOSS. Turn carbon pile off.
                </para>
                <para>POSITIVE CIRCUIT LOSS (step 2) __________</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">plus</emph>NEGATIVE CIRCUIT LOSS (step 4) __________
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">equals</emph>
                    TOTAL SYSTEM LOSS __________
                </para>
                <para>If system loss
                    <emph type="bold">is 0.7V or less,</emph>
                    go to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0823309">Alternator Replacement Test,</hotlnk>
                    below.
                </para>
                <para>If system loss
                    <emph type="bold">is greater than 0.7V</emph>, repair circuit(s) defects, then go to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x0823309">Alternator Replacement Test,</hotlnk>
                    below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0823311" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0823311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Alternator Wiring Test - Part 2 (12V System Only)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0823309">
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0823312">Alternator Replacement Test (12 V System Only)</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the wiring tests have been performed (circuits OK), adjust alternator belt and
                    tighten mounting bolts and ground connections.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With vehicle at shop temperature, connect the carbon pile and the ammeter as shown. To
                    use an ammeter without induction clamp, connect meter leads to same terminals as the carbon pile.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With NO electrical loads turned on, start the engine. Fast idle until voltage stabilizes
                    (does not increase for 2 minutes). Voltage then should not exceed 15V.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Speed up the engine and turn on the carbon pile until the ammeter shows output has
                    reached the highest value. Record the value ______A. Turn off carbon pile and the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rated output is stamped on the alternator case or on a tag. If current output measured
                    is not within 10% of rated output or the voltage exceeds 15V, replace the alternator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0823312" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G0823312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Alternator Replacement Test (12V System Only)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_65.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230_67.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08230.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
