<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CAB FEATURES - FRONT DOORS WINDOWS AND LOCKS (POWER)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec id="x0825804">
        <title>FRONT DOORS WINDOWS AND LOCKS (POWER)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0825813">Front Doors Power Windows And Locks Function Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0825813" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0825841.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="532px"/>
                <caption>Front Doors Power Windows and Locks Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DRIVERS SIDE DOOR POD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. POWER LOCK MOTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PASSENGER SIDE DOOR POD</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. REMOTE KEYLESS ENTRY (RKE) TRANSMITTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. POWER WINDOW MOTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER (ESC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. POWER WINDOW MOTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>A door pod on each door houses the switches and contains the electronics required to control the power
                windows and locks.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A malfunctioning pod must be replaced. Individual parts of the pod are not replaceable.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The door pods communicate with each other and the ESC on the switch data link. This allows the driver
                side pod to control all windows in the vehicle. It also allows all pods to control all locks.
            </para>
            <para>The door pods will not operate the power windows when the ignition is off.</para>
            <para>The ESC also sends commands to the pods to control the pod backlighting.</para>
            <para>If the remote keyless entry (RKE) option is installed on the vehicle, the key FOB transmitter
                communicates with the passenger front door pod to unlock or lock the doors. The door pod also
                communicates with the ESC, on the switch data link, to request the other remote keyless entry functions.
            </para>
            <para>The International Keyless Entry System uses electronic door pods in the driver and passenger side
                doors which also operate the power door locks and the power windows. If equipped with RKE, the memory in
                the receiver (front passenger door pod) learns the transmitter codes from the key FOBS (transmitters)
                and only recognizes those which it has learned in the programming process. Each vehicle's passenger side
                door pod has the ability to learn up to six transmitter codes allowing the vehicle to be accessed by six
                different key FOBS. Each key FOB has a unique code which can be learned by any number of RKE equipped
                vehicles.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_236.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_238.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
