<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - FE 300, RE 200, RE 300 - RE 200/RE 300 CHASSIS ACCESSORIES -
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AIR DRYER WITH AIR BRAKES: RE 200 (V8 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on or accessory position, power is applied from the ignition relay
                (6309), through circuit V13P, rear control box fuse B3, circuit V39, control box connector (6000), pin
                F2, and engine harness circuit K39/K39B to the heated air dryer (6705), pin A. If the air dryer
                thermostat senses air temperature below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to
                flow through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze during cold
                weather.
            </para>
            <para>Ground is through circuit K39-GA, an inline connector (6705), pin B and circuits K39-G/K11-GH to the
                starter motor ground (7104).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>AIR DRYER WITH AIR BRAKES: RE 300 (I6 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in the on or accessory position, power is applied from the ignition relay
                (6309), through circuit V13P, rear control box fuse B3, circuit V39, control box connector (6000), pin
                F2, and engine harness circuit K39/K39B to the heated air dryer (6705), pin A. If the air dryer
                thermostat senses air temperature below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to
                flow through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze during cold
                weather.
            </para>
            <para>Ground is through circuit K39-GA, an inline connector (6705), pin B and circuits K39-GA to the starter
                motor ground (7104).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drain Valve</title>
            <para>When the key switch (6305) is in the ignition position, power is fed from the ignition relay (6309)
                through circuit V13L, rear control box fuse A3, circuit K39A, control box connector (6000), circuit
                K39A, and the electronic engine/chassis harness connector (9850). Power continues through the chassis
                harness circuit N39A to the heated drain valve jumper harness connector (43), and to the drain valve
                pigtail connector (42).
            </para>
            <para>The drain valve is grounded through pigtail connector (42), conn. (43), and circuit
                N39-G/N11-GA/N11-GB to platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature drops below 50&#176;F (10&#176;C), its contacts close and allow current to flow
                through the heating element. This assures that the accumulated moisture does not freeze in the drain
                valve during cold weather.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heated Fuel Filter</title>
            <para>Power is applied by the body builder feed stud (1F), to circuit A14D/A19, fuse F17, and circuit A19H
                to the fuel heater relay (R5). When the key switch (20) is placed in the ignition or start position,
                power is also applied to circuits A13 and A13A, fuse F20, and circuit A19D to the fuel heater relay (R5)
                coil. The relay is energized through ground circuit A11-GM/A11-GB to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>With the relay (R5) energized, power flows through its contacts, circuit A19A, dash connector (2),
                circuit A19A, connector (6704 or 6708), and circuit K19A to the fuel filter heater and thermo switch
                (N/L). The ground path is through the filter housing and its mounting bracket. When the temperature is
                50&#176;F (10&#176;C) or less, the thermo switch contacts close and cause the heater element to
                activate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: RE 200 (V8 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13A, fuse F20, circuits
                A19D, to the fuel heater relay (R5). With the key switch (20) in the on or start position, the
                water-in-fuel module (16) receives power at WIF connector (3116), pin A, from fuel heater relay (R5) and
                circuit A19E. When the key switch is moved to the start position, the key switch (20) ground is applied
                to circuit A19-GB going to the water-in-fuel module (16), pin C, to the WIF connector (3116), pin E.
                This initiates a bulb check by causing the module to apply power to connector (16), pin B, circuit A19F,
                to the WIF connector (3116), pin B, and the water-in-fuel module warning light (9). This causes the
                warning light, grounded through connector (9), circuit A19-G, to the WIF connector (3116), pin C,
                circuit A19-G, to the WIF connector (3116), pin D, circuits A19-GC/A11-G, to platform ground (1PG), to
                illuminate. When water is detected in the fuel filter by the water probe, a ground path is completed to
                the water-in-fuel module (16), pin D, circuit A19C, to the WIF connector (3116), pin F, circuit A19C, to
                connector (2), pin H6, circuit N19C, connector (9851), pin F, circuit K19C, fuel filter connector
                (6704), pin 2, and water probe (1WP), thus causing the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: RE 300 (I6 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>The I6 engine ECM2 will turn on the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light. The battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13A, fuse F20, circuits A97AC/A97AB, to the MSM1 connector
                (3114) pin 7 and to the WIF connector (3116), pin G, circuit A19K, to the WIF connector (3116), pin C,
                circuit A19-G, to the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light (9), pin B. The "WATER-IN-FUEL" indicator is
                controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred
                over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the
                MSM1 connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM2 connector (3115) through pin 3,
                circuit A19-GD, to the WIF connector (3116), pin H, circuit A19F, to the WIF connector (3116), pin B, to
                the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light (9), pin A, thus causing the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fuel Filter Restriction Light</title>
            <para>With the key switch (20) in the ignition position, power is applied through circuit A13H, fuse F25,
                and circuit A19J to the fuel filter light (69). From the light, power is applied through circuit A19B,
                dash connector (2), circuit A19B, fuel filter connector (6704 or 6708), and to the fuel filter vacuum
                switch (N/L). When the fuel filter becomes restricted, the fuel filter vacuum switch contacts close and
                complete a ground path for the fuel filter light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Brake System</title>
            <para>The Hydro-Max II hydraulic brake system uses hydraulic pressure from the power steering pump. If the
                flow is inadequate or interrupted, the monitor module (86) is fed a signal from the flow switch (N/L),
                causing the monitor to turn on a brake warning light and alarm system and to start the hydraulic reserve
                pump to provide additional braking power. The reserve pump and warning system is also activated when the
                differential pressure switch (91) is tripped due to a pressure loss in one half of the brake system.
            </para>
            <para>When the key switch (20) is in ignition or start position, power is supplied to circuit A13A, fuse
                F18, circuit A90T, and blocking diode assembly (80). From the blocking diode, power is supplied through
                circuit A90J, to the pump control relay (R1), and also through circuit A90H to the brake monitor module
                (86-E). The brake monitor module is grounded through circuit 11-GD/11-GB/ 11-G to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is applied to fusible link N90-FL/N90FA/A90, dash connector (2), and circuit A90, to the
                pump control relay (R1). When the key switch is moved to the start or ignition position, the flow switch
                contacts will be closed (engine not running) and a ground path is provided from the switch through
                circuit A90L, pressure differential switch (91), circuit A90K, connector (88), dash connector (2) and
                circuit A90K, to a splice. From the splice, a ground path is provided over circuit A90L, to the brake
                monitor module (86-A). This causes the module to switch the alarm output (86-C) to ground which
                activates the alarm and warning light. From the splice, a ground circuit is also provided by way of
                circuit A90E to the brake pump control relay (R1), causing it to energize. With the relay energized,
                power flows through its N.C. contacts, circuit A90S, dash connector (2) and connector (88) to the
                reserve pump motor (1F). This causes the reserve pump motor, which is grounded through its case and to
                the platform ground, to run and provide additional brake power (fluid flow).
            </para>
            <para>From the pump motor, a signal path on circuit N90Q, connector (88) and dash connector (2), to the
                brake monitor module connector (86-F), provides information to the module. It continuously monitors the
                continuity of the reserve pump and power supplied to it. The warning system activates if the pump motor
                winding opens up or if the pump control relay (R1) remains closed (provides power to circuit N90S and
                the reserve pump motor), after the engine is running. The warning system is also activated if no power
                is supplied to the pump motor when the flow switch or differential switch contacts are closed.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake monitor module switches its alarm output (86-C) to ground, the brake warning light
                illuminates by power flowing to the dash connector (12), through the printed circuit board and the
                light, dash connector (12), and circuits A90N and A90M, to the monitor module at connector (86-C). At
                the same time, the alarm also sounds by power flowing to the B+ terminal of the alarm, through the
                alarm, circuit A90NA, blocking diode (25), and circuit A90M to the module at connector (86-C).
            </para>
            <para>When the hydraulic brake pressure system monitor module (86) detects a problem with the brake system,
                it applies a ground to circuit A90M, connector and blocking diode (25), and circuit A90NA to the alarm
                (211). Power will then flow from fuse F24 through circuit A13B and alarm connector (211), causing the
                alarm to sound at a fast rate. When a problem is detected, a ground is also applied by circuit A90M,
                connector (25), circuit A90N, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 9 to the brake warning
                light, causing it to illuminate. The brake warning light, the battery voltage is through the ignition
                switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C, and natural instrument cluster
                connector (12), pin 8.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is applied from circuit N90-FL/N90FA to circuit A90A, dash connector (2), circuit
                A90A, fuse F2, circuit A90B, dash connector (2) and circuit N90B to the hydraulic brake stop light
                switch (209). The stop light switch ground is through circuit N90-G/N11-GB to the platform ground.
            </para>
            <para>Battery voltage is also applied through fuse F2 and circuit A90U to the brake relay (R3) coil, and
                circuit A90X to the relay contacts. The relay ground is through circuit A70C, dash connector (2) and
                circuit N70C to the stop light switch (209). When the brakes are applied, the contacts of the hydraulic
                brake switch (209) close. This energizes the brake relay (R3) and power is applied through circuit A90F
                to a blocking diode (80) and circuit A90H to the brake monitor module connector (86-E). Power is also
                applied from the blocking diode connector (80), through circuit A90D, to the monitor module connector
                (86-G). If the key switch is in the off position, power is also applied to the pump control relay (R1).
            </para>
            <para>Battery power is also applied through fuse F12 and circuit A70B, to the stop light relay (R4) coil,
                and circuit A70D to the relay contacts. The relay ground is through circuits A70-G, the brake relay (R3)
                and A70C to the stop light switch (209). When the brake is applied, the relay is energized and applies
                power through circuit A90C to the brake monitor module connector (86-H). The module compares the signals
                received at (86-G) and (86-H) and if there is a voltage on just one of the two circuits, A90D or A90C,
                for more than 14&#177;5 seconds, the warning light and alarm will be turned on.
            </para>
            <para>When the brakes are applied, power also flows from the energized stop light relay (R4) through circuit
                A70A and to the body builder connector (169).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_60.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08296.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
