<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Electrical System Troubleshooting Guide - BE 200, CE 200, CE 300 Model - ELECTRONIC GAUGE CLUSTER -
        DESCRIPTION - DIGITAL DISPLAY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DIGITAL DISPLAY</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f08290504">digital display</hotlnk>
                is an LCD located in the bottom-center of the EGC.
            </para>
            <para>The three lines of the digital display provide a transmission shift display, a numeric display, and an
                alphanumeric line.
            </para>
            <para>The display will dim to match the back lights when the park lights are switched on. The brightness of
                the display is adjusted with the panel light dimmer switch.
            </para>
            <figure id="f08290504" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08290504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="448px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Electronic Gauge Cluster Display</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>EGC DISPLAY WITH ALLISON TRANSMISSIONS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Select/Reset Switch</title>
            <para>The EGC includes a Select/Reset switch used to control the digital display. The switch interfaces
                directly with the EGC and is located on the lower right of the EGC lens. The switch allows the user to
                select modes within each major functional area of the display, as listed below, and perform reset
                functions. Each time the switch is momentarily depressed it will progress to the next mode. Depressing
                the switch for period of three seconds, while in the odometer mode, will switch the display between
                miles and kilometers. Depressing the switch for period of three seconds or more in other modes will
                clear the display or toggle between options depending upon the current mode. The reset function has no
                effect if the parameter cannot be reset.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Total Vehicle Distance</title>
            <para>The EGC displays the total distance the vehicle has traveled. This value may be toggled between miles
                and kilometers by depressing the select/reset switch and holding it for 3 seconds while in this mode.
                The digital display visually indicates whether the current reading is in miles or kilometers. The
                display indicates the elapsed mileage from 0 to 1,999,999 miles in 1 mile/kilometer increments.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Trip Distance</title>
            <para>The display function also includes trip distance. Trip distance is calculated as the total vehicle
                distance minus total vehicle distance when the trip distance was last cleared. Depressing the
                select/reset switch for at least three seconds while in this mode will clear the trip distance function
                and store the total vehicle distance. The digital display visually indicates whether the current reading
                is trip miles or trip kilometers based upon the current odometer mode. The display indicates the elapsed
                mileage from 0 to 199,999.9 miles in 0.1 mile/kilometer increments.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Default Odometer Turn On Mode</title>
            <para>The display remembers, after the power-on, the last miles or kilometers mode that it was set to before
                power-off. It will return to this mode upon the next start-up.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hours Functions</title>
            <para>The EGC display provides several engine hours modes.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Total Engine Hours</title>
            <para>The hours display is based on engine hours extracted from the engine controller. The digital display
                visually indicates that the current reading is hours.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Trip Hours</title>
            <para>The hours functions also includes trip hours. Trip hours are totaled as accumulated engine hours minus
                accumulated engine hours when the trip hours function was last cleared. By depressing the select/reset
                switch for at least three seconds while in this mode, trip hours function will be cleared.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Oil</title>
            <para>Vehicles with International engines will display a "CHG OIL" message when a programmed engine hours or
                engine miles interval has been exceeded. Refer to the appropriate engine manual for information on
                programming the interval and clearing the message.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic Message</title>
            <para>The LCD is capable of displaying a diagnostic trouble code (DTC) message when requested by the ESC or
                service tool (EZ-Tech&#174;). Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s08290_S08290003.xml" xrefid="s08290003">On-Line Diagnostics</hotlnk>.
                <xref refid="s08290003"/>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Diagnostic messages from the engine controller, antilock brake system or transmission
                        <emph type="bold">are not</emph>
                        displayed on the electronic gauge cluster (EGC) digital display.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Digital Display Lighting</title>
            <para>The display will dim to match the back lights when the park lights are switched on. The brightness of
                the display is adjusted with the panel light dimmer switch.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_73.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290_75.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08290.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
