<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - ENGINE/EXHAUST BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ENGINE/EXHAUST BRAKE</title>
        <para>An exhaust brake is available with the Allison WTEC III transmissions and the International DT engines.
            The exhaust brake control system is activated by moving the On/Off switch (447) to the on position which
            closes its contacts. This allows power to flow from fuse (301) through circuit 146A, the closed contacts of
            switch (447), circuit 119, connector (418), circuit 119 and Allison ECU pin 11.
        </para>
        <para>When the transmission output speed is above a certain value and the ABS control module is not detecting
            wheel slip, the torque converter will be in lock-up mode and the Allison ECU (632) will switch the output of
            pin 3 to high (not switched to ground).
        </para>
        <para>This leaves the engine brake relay (667), which is grounded through circuit 132 going to the ECU (632)/pin
            3 de-energized. Thus a ground path for the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM (379) is provided through pin 15,
            circuit 24, connector (3), circuit 24, connector (377), circuit 24, connector (418), circuit 24 and the
            normally closed contacts of relay (667). From the relay, the ground path continues through circuit 94-GE,
            connector (418), circuits 94-GE, 94-GC, and 11-G to cab ground.
        </para>
        <para>With pin 15 of the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM (379) grounded, if the accelerator pedal is allowed to
            return to idle position, the ECM will de-energize exhaust brake relay (449) by removing the ground
            (switching low) to pin 47, circuit 24A, connector (372), and circuit 24A. The coil of the exhaust brake
            relay (449) receives power from fuse F4 by way of circuit 97K, connector (3), circuits 97K and 24B,
            connector (372), and circuits 24B and 24D. Circuit 24B, that feeds circuit 240 and the relay coil, also
            supplies power by way of circuit 24C to common contact pin 30 of the relay. Power then flows through the
            normally closed relay contacts and circuit 24E to the exhaust brake solenoid causing it to energize and
            apply air to the exhaust brake actuator, which activates the exhaust brake.
        </para>
        <para>The exhaust brake will remain active until one of the following occurs:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The ABS controller senses an impending wheel lock-up.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The torque converter comes out of lock-up mode.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The accelerator pedal is moved beyond the idle position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The exhaust brake On/Off switch is turned off.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>FIRST CONDITION - The ABS controller communicates to the Allison ECU, over the data link, that wheel slip
            may be occurring. Then the Allison ECU will switch its output to the engine brake relay low. Thus, causing
            the relay to energize and signal the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM to energize the exhaust brake relay. This
            will de-energize the exhaust brake solenoid, which will stop supplying air pressure to the engine brake
            actuator, and thus turn off the exhaust brake.
        </para>
        <para>SECOND CONDITION - The Allison ECU will detect the loss of torque converter lock-up due to decreased
            vehicle speed, thus decreased transmission output speed, and it will switch its output to the engine brake
            relay low. Thus causing the relay to energize and signal the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM to energize the
            exhaust brake relay. This will de-energize the exhaust brake solenoid, which will stop supplying air
            pressure to the engine brake actuator, and thus turn off the exhaust brake.
        </para>
        <para>THIRD CONDITION - The Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM will sense that the accelerator pedal has been moved
            beyond the idle position, it will energize the exhaust brake relay. This will de-energize the exhaust brake
            solenoid, which will stop supplying air pressure to the engine brake actuator, and thus turn off the exhaust
            brake.
        </para>
        <para>FOURTH CONDITION - The Allison ECU will detect that the On/Off switch has been moved to the off position
            (opened), and it will switch its output to the engine brake relay low. Thus causing the relay to energize
            and signal the Diamond LogicNavpaktrade; ECM to energize the exhaust brake relay. This will de-energize the
            exhaust brake solenoid, which will stop supplying air pressure to the engine brake actuator, and thus turn
            off the exhaust brake.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
