<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600 Models
        Built Before 05/20/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - POWER DIVIDER LOCK
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>POWER DIVIDER LOCK</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259c8" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g08259c1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Power Divider Lock Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SWITCH PACK ON INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>This system uses an electronically controlled air solenoid to supply pilot air to a larger air
                solenoid which will control the feature.
            </para>
            <para>The position of the switch on the dash panel is communicated to the ESC. The ESC will send signals to
                a remote air solenoid module containing the relay configured to operate the feature. Two different
                solenoid packs may be used to control the air pressure. The 7 solenoid version is controlled by J1939
                messages and the 4 solenoid version by discrete wire.
            </para>
            <para>Driver controlled Power Divider Lock (PDL) when engaged, can lock the front axle and the rear axle of
                a tandem axle. This helps prevent one axle from taking the majority of the power while slipping. Some
                drivers may desire (as an option) a visual warning when the vehicle has exceeded a set speed. This is
                referred to as the PDL warning speed (default set at 160kph/100mph ).
            </para>
            <para>When the PDL Lock switch is turned on (flipped up) the ESC will command the air solenoid to engage the
                PDL.
            </para>
            <para>Power Divider Lock disengaged (Off) is the default and fail-safe range. If the PDL switch fails (error
                condition exists) PDL will disengage or not engage.
            </para>
            <para>If the switch is set on but the vehicle is speed is greater than PDL warning speed the switch ON light
                will continuously fast flash and 5 beeps will occur until the speed is reduced 3 kph below PDL warning
                speed or the PDL switch is turned off. If the dash switch is malfunctioning or the vehicle speed message
                is not received, the switch ON light will continuously slow flash.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_434.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503_436.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082503.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
