<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500, 8600
        Models Built After 05/19/2003 - CHASSIS FEATURES - SUSPENSION DUMP
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SUSPENSION DUMP</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f08259h2" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08259C1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Suspension Dump Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 7 PACK AIR SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SOLENOID POWER CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BODY BUILDER 1939 DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SWITCH DATA LINK</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SWITCH PACK ON INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>This feature allows the back of the vehicle to lower several inches by dumping the air from the
                suspension bags. This is used mainly for trailer pickup and drop off as well as loading and unloading
                equipment on and off the back of straight trucks.
            </para>
            <para>When the suspension dump switch, mounted in the switch pack, is turned on the switch pack will
                communicate with the ESC to request the ESC to command the air solenoid, located in a 4 solenoid pack or
                a 7 solenoid pack, to energize. When the solenoid energizes it will supply pilot air to the Hadley valve
                of the air suspension system. This will cause the system to deflate.
            </para>
            <para>The suspension dump operations will occur only when the key switch is in the ignition position or
                accessory feed is on. The dump suspension indicator (solid light) and the dump suspension solenoid shall
                be on when the dump suspension switch is set to on, the vehicle is moving at the less than maximum
                allowed dump speed, and any related errors are not present. If the suspension is dumped and the ignition
                is turned off, the normally closed SV1 valve prevents inflating the suspension system. If the suspension
                is not dumped, the ignition is off and the switch is turned to the on position, upon turning the key to
                ignition or accessory the suspension will deflate.
            </para>
            <para>If there are any related errors the dump suspension solenoid shall be set to off. If vehicle speed is
                greater than maximum allowable dump speed the suspension dump solenoid will be set to off. If the
                suspension is deflated and the vehicle accelerates beyond the maximum dump speed the suspension will
                re-inflate even with the suspension dump switch in the dump position. If the vehicle then slows to
                maximum dump speed or less the suspension will not dump until the dump switch is re-initialized (turned
                off then back on).
            </para>
            <para>If there are any related errors and the accessory power is on, the suspension dump indicator will
                continuously flash slowly. If suspension dump is requested and vehicle speed is greater that maximum
                allowable dump speed (default 5 mph), the suspension dump indicator will continuously flash at a fast
                rate and five short beeps will occur. Even when the vehicle speed decreases below the maximum dump speed
                the suspension dump indicator will continue to flash fast.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>AIR SUSPENSION DUMP OPERATION WITH DUAL SOLENOID CONTROL VALVES</title>
            </para>
            <para>Feature Code: 0595273.</para>
            <para>Models: 4200, 4300, 4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 and 8600.</para>
            <para>The effective dates for the models listed above are:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Springfield Production September 5, 2003 through present</line>
                <line>Garland Production September 7, 2003 through present</line>
                <line>Escobedo Production September 7, 2003 through present</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>After the above referenced dates the HPV Air Suspension Control System was revised to be controlled by
                the ESC using two air solenoids and a shuttle valve. The revision was accompanied by the changing of the
                0595042 code to 0595273. The suspension input is provided by a two position, bi-stable switch that has
                an indicator light in the upper (Dump) position. When the Air Suspension Dump (ASD) switch is in the
                "DUMP" position, the operator is requesting the ESC to release air from the air suspension. When the ASD
                is in the "SUSP" position, the operator is requesting the air suspension to be, or remain, supplied with
                air pressure. When requesting suspension dump, the system is applying air pressure to the Dump Control
                Line port of the Hadley Height Control Valve mounted above the rear axle. The following will provide
                additional information to help the technician better understand the system function to aid in the
                troubleshooting process.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Procedure</title>
            </para>
            <para>The two air solenoids mentioned above in the system description control a two position shuttle valve
                that either feeds air pressure (dump) or vents (suspension active) the control line that is connected to
                the dump port of the Hadley Control Valve. The two normally open (when no power is applied) air
                solenoids will be set to opposite states under normal key on conditions. The suspension dump operation
                will only change state when the key switch is in the run, crank, or acc position. When the key is off,
                or there is an error, both air solenoids will be de-energized. See the next figure for system layout and
                function.
            </para>
            <para>NORMAL OPERATION (Key On)</para>
            <para>When the ESC commands the "DUMP" operation:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The ASD solenoid A will be de-energized (open)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD solenoid B will be energized (closed)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shuttle valve passes air pressure from solenoid A to Dump Control Line</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>When the ESC commands the "SUSP" operation:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The ASD solenoid A will be energized (closed)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD solenoid B will be de-energized (open)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shuttle closes air pressure feed to Dump Control Line and vents it</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>When switching from "SUSP" to "DUMP" the suspension will dump if:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The vehicle is moving less than the maximum allowable dump speed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD switch is in the "DUMP" position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the key is in the RUN or ACC position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the key state signal must report a good status</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the Wheel Based Vehicle Speed signal must report a good status</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And there is not a Traction Control or ABS event.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f08259h3" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/G08259C3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="562px"/>
                <caption>Air Suspension Dump Operation With Dual Solenoid Control Valves</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_X082599A.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504_424.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s082504.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
