<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE / 2000 4000 and 8000 MODELS BUILT OCTOBER 1, 1998 AND AFTER -
        ALLISON WT TRANSMISSION WITH WTEC III ELECTRONIC CONTROLS - ELECTRICAL OPERATION - PANEL LIGHT SWITCH
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PANEL LIGHT SWITCH</title>
        <para>The vehicle panel light dimmer switch sends variable voltage (when the driver sets brightness level) to
            the shift selector. The shift selector reacts to the changes in voltage from the panel light dimmer control
            in the following manner.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When vehicle lights are OFF or the panel light dimmer is turned completely off, no panel
                light voltage is delivered to the ECU. When this occurs, the ECU will cause the shift selector display
                to be at full intensity and the pushbuttons to not be backlit.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the vehicle lights are on, and the panel light dimmer is set to display the panel lights
                at less than the brightest intensity, the ECU sees a reduced voltage (compares the voltage to ignition
                voltage from key switch) and displays the shift selector at something less than full lighting intensity.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the panel light control set to display panel lights at full intensity, the ECU sees
                full ignition voltage and will display the shift selector lights at full intensity.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08246.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
