<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - General Electrical - J1939 HIGH
        SPEED DATA LINK CABLE (SAE J1939/15)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>J1939 HIGH SPEED DATA LINK CABLE (SAE J1939/15)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The information in this section applies to all 3200, 4000, 7000, and 8000 models.</para>
            <para>Performing the proper repairs or modifications of the cable is critical to the integrity and
                performance of the vehicle systems. (For repair procedure see Electrical Troubleshooting Guide - S08250
                or Data Link Repair in this manual.) This information based on SAE J1939/15 and TMC RP 142.
            </para>
            <para>These instructions are intended for modifications that meet the SAE spec; i.e., no internal resistor.
                When extending the backbone the proper materials must be used. The data link cable consists of a twisted
                pair of insulated wires and are covered by an insulating jacket. The data link cable must meet the SAE -
                specified characteristic impedance of 120 ohms. Never splice regular automotive type wire such as GXL,
                SXL, TXL into the data link cable. Use data link cable furnished by Raychem, part number 2021D0309.
            </para>
            <para>The backbone is the main part of the cable. This is terminated at each end with a 120 ohm resistor.
                When adding a device the backbone must be extended. This is done by removing the resistor, inserting the
                backbone extension, then plugging the resistor and the device into the extension.
            </para>
            <para>The International&#174; high performance vehicle will always have a power train J1939 system. This is
                for key operations that come from the factory direct. A second J1939 system is put in place for body
                builders and will be referred to as body builder J1939. Circuit diagrams are shown in Chapter 9 of the
                Circuit Diagram Book (S08322) under Remote Power Units, Solenoid Packs, Remote Engine Speed Controller.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939</title>
            <para>J1939 is a high speed serial communications data link. The system requires two resistor caps. The
                first resistor cap for Body Builder J1939 currently starts in the engine compartment. The second
                resistor cap ends where the last module is placed. The wire between these two resistors is called the
                backbone. The backbone cannot be longer than 131.2 feet (40m). A module can tap into the backbone. This
                point is called the Node. The distance between two nodes can not be less than 3.9 inches (0.1m). The
                cable length from the node to the module cannot be longer than 9.8 feet (3m).
            </para>
            <para>With the research of the robustness of the J1939-15 lite (unshielded) International removed the shield
                from their high performance vehicle in January 2002. Mixing of the shielded (J1939-11) and unshielded
                (J1939-15) is not recommended.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ADDING Body Builder J1939, Power and Grounds</title>
            <para>Without any Body Builder J1939: Ask Service Parts for "the components needed to add the Body Builder
                J1939 datalink to the vehicle. Service part kits are available to add the datalink, RPMs and switch
                packs."
            </para>
            <para>Most of the software information is processed in the BC. Therefore, the J1939 wires must be connected
                to the BC. Refer to Circuit Diagram Manual S08322, Chapter 10, Remote Power Units, Solenoid Packs,
                Remote Engine Speed Controller for proper circuit installation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
