<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Engine Speed Control Features -
        12VXV - THROTTLE, HAND CONTROL, Mobile, Variable Speed
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB12VXV" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>12VXV - THROTTLE, HAND CONTROL, Mobile, Variable Speed</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>12VXV - THROTTLE, HAND CONTROL Engine Speed Control for PTO; Electronic, Mobile, Variable Speed; (Range 2
            to 20 MPH) Mounted on Steering Wheel
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Mobile Variable Speed feature 12VXV allows the equipment operator to feather engine speed up or down to
            make fine adjustments to engine speed to achieve the desired functionality. The vehicle is moving; however,
            the accelerator and brake pedals are inoperative. Speed is controlled through the steering wheel controls.
            Application examples are Concrete Mixer, Asphalt Spreader, Dump (dumping gravel, etc.), and other
            applications that require fine control of engine speed while the vehicle is moving.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: No software in the BC is required.</para>
        <para>Software feature codes that must be removed: NONE</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>No additional wiring is associated with this feature.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This feature is added by programming the Engine Control Module (ECM) for mobile, variable speed control.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to the Body Builder Book CT-471 (PBB-71000A) for engine ECM programming functionality.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB12VXU.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB12VZA.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
