<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - International&#174;
        Diamond Logic&#8482; Electrical System Overview - Data Links
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Data Links</title>
        <para>International's multiplexing uses two types of data links, J1708 and J1939. The J1708 data link is often
            referred to as ATA and J1939 is often referred to as CAN. These two types are utilized in four separate data
            links on the vehicle.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Power Train data link - J1939</emph>
                </para>
                <para>This data link provides a path for communication between the engine controller, transmission
                    controller, antilock brake system (ABS) controller, pyrometer ammeter module (PAM), Electrical
                    System Controller (ESC), auxiliary gauge switch pack (AGSP) and the electronic gauge cluster (EGC).
                    It also provides for programming and diagnostic functions.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Body Builder data link - J1939</emph>
                </para>
                <para>This data link provides a path for communication between the remote power module(s), remote PTO,
                    air solenoid 7 pack(s) and the ESC.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Switch data link - J1708</emph>
                </para>
                <para>This J1708 data link provides a path for communication between the center panel switch packs, door
                    pods and ESC.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">ATA data link - J1708</emph>
                </para>
                <para>This is the same J1708 data link (sometimes referred to as ATA) that has been used in the past.
                    This data link is used almost exclusively for communicating with the engine diagnostic and
                    programming tool to identify engine electrical system problems or program desired settings
                    controlled by the engine ECM.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_SBB7300002.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
