<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - FE 300 and IC Bus - REMOVE AND INSTALL - INSTRUMENT
        CLUSTER COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INSTRUMENT CLUSTER COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the cluster released from the dash panel (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s08313_28.xml" xrefid="hl0831301">INSTRUMENT CLUSTER, Remove</hotlnk>), remove the
                    three (3) bezel screws that fasten the bezel to the cluster housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0831317">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Place the instrument cluster face up on a clean,
                    horizontal surface to prevent loss of unused gauge covers, gauges, etc.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0831317" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0831317" filename="../figg08/G0831317.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Remove Bezel Screws Fastening Bezel to Cluster Housing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bezel lens assembly from the housing and put it in a safe place to prevent
                    scratching. Take care not to damage the gauge pointers with the bezel.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Individual gauge dials are not protected by a lens. When removing or installing gauges,
                            handle them by the edge of the dial face only. Do not touch the gauge pointer.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All gauges, with the exception of the air pressure, hourmeter and odometer, are plug-in
                    gauges. To remove, locate the hole in the back of the cluster behind the gauge and using a small,
                    blunt tool such as a small screwdriver handle, push the gauge out of the housing. Once the gauge has
                    cleared the housing, it may be removed from the front.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>After a gauge is removed from the cluster, it is important that the exposed terminals
                            attached to the circuit board are not touched or shorted across. Static electricity or
                            shorting between power and ground terminals can damage the cluster.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove the hourmeter and/or odometer, disconnect the wiring plugs from the circuit
                    board at the back of the cluster. At the front of the cluster, remove the adhesive-backed mask
                    covering the gauge, then retract the two fingers that hold the gauges in the cluster and lift the
                    gauge out of the cluster.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When removing or installing the hourmeter or odometer, do not touch the metal portion of
                            the leads that fasten to the circuit board. A static discharge could damage the cluster.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The mechanical type air gauge is front serviceable after the air line fittings and the
                    retaining nuts have been removed from the rear of the gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The panel lamp bulbs are the push-in type and are mounted in a twist lock receptacle.
                    They are serviceable from the rear of the instrument cluster by twisting to remove (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0831318">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0831318" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0831318" filename="../figg08/G0831318.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Twist Panel Lamp Bulbs to Remove</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The gauge back lights are #936 bulbs and the turn signals, high beam and warning lights are #37.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
