<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        Power Windows / Locks, Remote Keyless Entry - 16WJU, 16WJV and 16WKZ - Electric Windows, Remote Lock and Unlock,
        and Use of the Aux Feature
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB16WJU" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>16WJU, 16WJV and 16WKZ - Electric Windows, Remote Lock and Unlock, and Use of the Aux Feature</title>
        <para>Refer to the Circuit Diagram in
            <exhotlnk document="../S08/S082853_CD16WJU.xml" bookname="S082853">S08285, Chapter 3, page 4</exhotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
            16WKZ - KEYLESS ENTRY SYSTEM REMOTE With Panic and Auxiliary Buttons, Includes One Key Fob (Transmitter)
        </para>
        <para>16WJU - WINDOW, POWER (2) And Power Locks, Left and Right Doors</para>
        <para>16WJV - WINDOW, POWER (4) And Power Door Locks, Front and Rear Doors, Left and Right</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Driver and passenger power windows and door locks are available. The driver switches are located on the
            driver door trim and can control all door windows and locks. The passenger switches are located on the
            passenger door trim and can control the passenger door window and all locks. Window express down is
            available for all window switches by momentarily depressing the window down switch. The driver can "lockout"
            all non-driver controllable window switches by momentarily depressing the lower left switch on the driver
            door control.
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300087" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G73000AS.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Driver's Side Door Pod</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f7300088" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G73000AT.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Passenger's Side Door Pod</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The International Keyless Entry System uses electronic door pods in the driver and passenger side doors
            which also operate the power door locks and the power windows. If equipped with Remote Keyless Entry
            (optional code), the memory in the receiver (front passenger door pod) learns the transmitter codes from the
            key fobs (transmitters) and only recognizes those which it has learned in the programming process. Each
            vehicle's passenger side door pod has the ability to learn up to six transmitter codes allowing the vehicle
            to be accessed by six different key fobs. Each key fob has a unique code which can be learned by any number
            of RKE equipped vehicles.
        </para>
        <para>The Key FOB controls the following functions:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Chirp of the horn and doors lock if the lock button is pressed on the key fob</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Autolock function, which automatically locks the doors at a vehicle speed of 15 MPH see details
                    below.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Panic function, button with horn symbol, which chirps the horn on/off in unison with the
                    headlights and park lights for three minutes when the Panic button on the key fob is pressed and the
                    ignition switch is off. If the button is pressed prior to the time out period, the lights etc., will
                    go off
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pressing the "AUX" button will toggle the work light circuit on. Pressing the button will turn the
                    work light off. Vehicle must be ordered with work light or work light accommodation package
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>With the ignition on, if Wheel Based Vehicle Speed is above the AutoLock speed, the park brake was release
            below the auto lock speed and is still released, and the doors were closed below the auto lock speed and are
            still closed, all doors will lock.
        </para>
        <para>The autolock feature will only lock the doors once regardless of the number of times the truck stops and
            starts. Cycling the key and/or opening the door, while below the Auto Lock speed, will allow the autolock
            feature to lock the doors again when the speed conditions are met.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Horn chirp, autolock are programmable parameters.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f7300089" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G73000AU.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Keyless Entry Controller</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Transmitter Learning And Erasing</title>
        </para>
        <para>Before the transmitter can be used for the first time, it has to be "learned" by the receiver. Up to 6
            transmitters with different identification codes can be learned by a single RKE Pod.
        </para>
        <para>These procedures are designed for manual learning/erasing operations on a complete vehicle. They can be
            used for learning replacement transmitters, for using up to six transmitters for accessing the same vehicle,
            or for accessing any number of vehicles using the same transmitter. If RKE is being added to the vehicle,
            additional programming of the Electrical System Controller is required to operate the horn, panic, and dome
            light functions with RKE.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure For Erasing All Learned Transmitters</title>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Cycle the Ignition from Off to On. Step 2. must be initiated (all four buttons pressed) within 10
                    seconds of this Ignition event.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>On the
                    <emph type="bold">Driver</emph>
                    Door Pod do the following:
                </para>
                <para>While holding down the Driver Window-Up, Driver Window-Down, and Unlock Switches depress and hold
                    the Lock switch. All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is
                    recommended. After the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will erase all learned transmitters and the
                    RKE will be disabled. At this point the erase procedure is finished and a new Ignition cycle must be
                    initiated to perform any transmitter learning.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <title>Procedure For Learning A Transmitter</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This learning procedure cannot be performed during the same Ignition cycle as the "erase all
                    learned transmitters" procedure. If necessary, the erase procedure should be completed before this
                    procedure is started.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cycle the Ignition from Off to On (leaving the Ignition on will not work, it must be
                cycled). Step 2. must be initiated (all four buttons pressed) within 10 seconds of this Ignition event.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the
                <emph type="bold">Passenger</emph>
                Door Pod do the following:
            </para>
            <para>While holding down the Window-Up, Window-Down, and Unlock switches, depress and hold the Lock switch.
                All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will enter "Learn Mode" and stay there for 10
                seconds (or until a transmitter is learned). Once the RKE enters the "Learn Mode", the four buttons can
                be released. During the ten second "Learn Mode" any function on the new fob/transmitter must be keyed at
                least twice (See Note 1).
            </para>
            <para>Note 1. After the transmitter is learned the next keying of the new transmitter will perform the
                indicated function. It is recommended that the transmitter be successively keyed until the selected
                key's function is actually performed; i.e., pressing the Lock Button on the transmitter two times should
                learn its code, on the third push it should lock the door and momentarily beep the city horn. This is a
                good way to quickly confirm the success of the learning.
            </para>
            <para>Note 2. Steps 1. through 5. of the learning process must be repeated for each transmitter to be
                learned.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">PARTS INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Replacement Key Fobs/Transmitters can be obtained from Service Parts by ordering part number 3544938C2.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Required Software feature code for sales code 16WKZ: 595129</para>
        <para>Turning the
            <emph type="bold">Panic_Enable</emph>
            parameter ON enables the Panic Mode feature of the keyless remote. The panic function chirps the horn on/off
            in unison with the headlights and park lights for three minutes when the Panic button on the key fob is
            pressed and the ignition switch is off. If the button is pressed prior to the time out period, the lights
            and horn will go off.
        </para>
        <para>Turning the
            <emph type="bold">Chirp_Enable</emph>
            parameter ON enables the Chirp feature for the keyless remote. The chirp feature results in a "chirping"
            sound with the truck is locked and unlocked.
        </para>
        <table id="t73000f3">
            <title></title>
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.41*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.71*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.88*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Panic_ Enable</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>644</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Enable/ disable the Panic Mode for the Keyless Remote. A value of 1 enables and a
                                value of 0 disables the feature.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>On</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>No_ Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Chirp_ Enable</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>647</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Enable/ disable the remote lock "chirp" for Keyless Remote. A value of 1 enables and a
                                value of 0 disables the feature.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>On</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>No_ Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>Required Software feature code for sales code</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>16WJU: 595107</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>16WJV: 595108</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">AutoLock_Speed</emph>
            parameter sets the vehicle speed at which the vehicle doors will lock automatically.
        </para>
        <table id="t73000f4">
            <title></title>
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.41*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.71*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.88*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.80*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.69*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>AutoLock_ Speed</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>652</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Autolock speed. The speed at which the vehicle doors will lock automatically (requires
                                power locks); Setting this parameter to zero will disable Auto Door Locks.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>15</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>mph</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>155</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>When using the "Aux" feature, the work light circuit can be used for other features other than a work
            light - see "Work Light Feature for additional information.
        </para>
        <para>If truck was built with power locks but not the keyless entry, see "How Do I Add Work Light Feature."
        </para>
        <para>With the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software, some other systems can be activated but, only one. For
            example, the Aux button could turn on headlights or hazard lamps, not both.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The Remote Keyless Entry (RKE) feature can be added if Power Windows/Power Locks (16WJU / 16WJV) are
            already installed on the vehicle by replacing the standard front passenger side door pod with an RKE
            compatible door pod.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Software feature code 595129 must be enabled on the vehicle using ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482;
                    Builder software (see local dealer).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Remove the existing passenger side door pod and replace it with the RKE compatible pod, part
                    number 3544937C5 as described below. The desired quantity of Remote Key Fobs, part number 3544938C2,
                    must also be ordered.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Set the applicable programmable parameters, chirp enable, panic enable - see above, using ICAP or
                    the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software (see local dealer). The auto lock with vehicle speed
                    option should already be set since power locks are installed.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>As noted above, additional wiring may be required if the Aux button on the Key Fob will be
                    utilized for turning on a work light or other functions.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Program the RKE receiver to recognize the desired Key Fobs as described above.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>REMOVAL/REPLACEMENT OF PASSENGER SIDE DOOR POD:</title>
        </para>
        <para>To remove the door pod use the DIN Radio Removal Tool part number 2504954C1.</para>
        <figure id="f7300090" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G73000AV.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Insert the extraction tools (2) into the two holes on either side of the pod housing until the locking
            tabs are fully depressed. The pod can then be removed from the door panel and the extraction tools removed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300091" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G73000AW.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To install the new replacement pod connect the appropriate connectors and push the pod in until the
            locking tabs are fully engaged.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_65.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_67.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
