<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S08323" division="truck" date="05/08/2008">
        <title>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Foreword</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Contents</emph>
                - In this manual, International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation provides information about its
                different products to assist those who wish to modify these products for individual applications.
                International does not recommend or approve any firm nor make any judgements on the quality of the work
                performed by a particular firm. Individuals who use the services of a Body Builder must satisfy
                themselves as to the quality of the work.
            </para>
            <para>The party installing a body, a fifth wheel, any other equipment, or making any modifications to
                complete the vehicle for delivery and make it road-ready is responsible to see that the completed
                vehicle complies with all applicable certification procedures and safety standards, as may be set forth
                in Federal, State, and local statutes, rules and regulations.
            </para>
            <para>Specifications, descriptions and illustrative material in this literature are as accurate as known at
                time of publication but are subject to change without notice. Illustrations are not always to scale and
                may include optional equipment and accessories but may not include all standard equipment.
            </para>
            <para>In addition to this Body Builder Electrical Data Book, publication CT-471, Body Builder Data, may be
                required. The CT-471 - Body Builder Data is a set of booklets which includes a General Information Body
                Builder Data booklet for information about the International&#174; Truck and Engine product line; model
                series Body Builder Data booklets which contain information related to the features and specifications
                for each of their respective models; Component Body Builder Data booklet containing information for
                components which have common application in two or more truck series and any supplemental Body Builder
                Data booklets containing information for components which have common application in two or more truck
                series.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
