<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - RE 200 and RE 300 - OPERATION - INDICATOR AND WARNING
        LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INDICATOR AND WARNING LIGHTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN: RE 200/RE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the left turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and violet wire, connector (13)/pin D, circuits A56 and A56B to the left turn indicator connector
                (11)/pin 6. This will cause the left turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits
                A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN: RE 200/RE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the left turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and yellow wire, connector (13)/pin E, circuits A56 and A56B to the left turn indicator connector
                (11)/pin 6. This will cause the left turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits
                A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: RE 200/RE 300 With WTEC or Allison 2000 ICT Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the air anti-lock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will set
                connector (288)/pin E3, low (to ground). The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay
                (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A13N, the coil of the warning light relay (284),
                circuit A94H, connector (2), circuit N94H, and a gray wire to the ABS module (288)/pin E3. This
                energizes the warning light relay (284), and allows power to flow through fuse (F22), circuits A28,
                A94B, the anti-lock brake warning light (297), circuit A94E, the warning light relay (284). This will
                cause the warning light (297), which is grounded through circuit A94E, normally open contacts of the
                warning light relay (284), circuits A94-GA and A11-GB to platform ground (4PG), to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the hydraulic anti-lock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will
                set connector (279)/pin 1, low (to ground). The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay
                (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A13N, the coil of the warning light relay (R2),
                circuit A94K, connector (2), circuit N94K, and a gray wire to the ABS module (279)/pin 1. This energizes
                the warning light relay (R2), and allows power to flow through fuse (F22), circuits A28, A94B, the
                anti-lock brake warning light (297), circuit A94E, the warning light relay (R2), circuit A94K, connector
                (2), circuit N94K, to the hydraulic ABS module (279)/pin 1. This will cause the warning light (297),
                which is grounded through circuit A94E, normally open contacts of the warning light relay (R2), circuits
                A94-GA and A11-GB to platform ground (4PG), to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HI BEAM: RE 200/RE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is moved to the on position and the dimmer switch (4) is placed in the
                high beam position, power will flow through circuit A51, dimmer switch connector (4), a green wire, the
                switch contacts, a brown wire, connector (4), circuits A52 and A52A, and the high beam indicator lamp
                and connector (11)/pin 4. Thus the lamp, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits A28-G and
                A11-G to platform ground (1PG), will illuminate, indicating that the headlights are on and the dimmer
                switch is in the high beam position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HI BEAM: RE 200/RE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is moved to the on position and the dimmer switch (6) is placed in the
                high beam position, power will flow through circuit A51, circuit A51A, the normally closed contacts of
                lift-to-dim headlight relay (100), circuits A52C and A52A, and the high beam indicator lamp and
                connector (11)/pin 4. Thus the lamp, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits A28-G and A11-G
                to platform ground (1PG), will illuminate, indicating that the headlights are on and the dimmer switch
                is in the high beam position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN: RE 200/RE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the right turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and orange/red wire, connector (13)/pin F, circuits A57 and A57B to the right turn indicator
                connector (11)/pin 12. This will cause the right turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2
                and circuits A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks
                the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN: RE 200/RE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the right turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and light blue wire, connector (13)/pin F, circuits A57 and A57B to the right turn indicator
                connector (11)/pin 12. This will cause the right turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2
                and circuits A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks
                the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WAIT-TO-START: RE 200/RE 300</title>
            <para>When the key switch is initially moved to the ignition position, the engine controller ECM2 (6020)
                will activate the glow plugs and the "WAIT-TO-START" indicator. The battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28B, green instrument cluster
                connector (11), pin 10 to the "WAIT-TO-START" indicator. The "WAIT-TO-START" indicator is controlled by
                the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data
                link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the MSM1 connector
                (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM1 connector (3114) through pin 10, circuit A18-G, to
                pin 5 of the natural instrument cluster connector (12). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BRAKE PRESS: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the hydraulic brake pressure system monitor module (86) detects a problem with the brake system,
                it applies a ground to circuit A90M, connector and blocking diode (25), and circuit A90NA to the alarm
                (211). Power will then flow from fuse F24 through circuit A13B and alarm connector (211), causing the
                alarm to sound at a fast rate. When a problem is detected, a ground is also applied by circuit A90M,
                connector (25), circuit A90N, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 9 to the brake warning
                light, causing it to illuminate. The brake warning light, the battery voltage is through the ignition
                switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C, and natural instrument cluster
                connector (12), pin 8.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BRAKE PRESS: RE 200/RE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The brake press warning light, the battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711),
                circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28D, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin
                4. When the air pressure drops below 60 psi, the pressure switch will close, and power will flow through
                the warning light, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 9, circuits A40A and A40, connector
                (2), pin A4, circuit N40, connector (9850), pin 9, circuit K40 and the low air pressure switch (6740) to
                ground (1LA). This will cause the brake press warning light to illuminate, and the warning alarm (211)
                to sound at a fast rate. The warning alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) LOW AIR: RE 200/RE 300 With Low Air Suspension</title>
            <para>The "((P)) LOW AIR" suspension warning light, the battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay
                (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28D, and natural instrument cluster connector
                (12), pin 4. When the air pressure drops below 60 psi, the pressure switch will close, and power will
                flow through the warning light, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 9, circuits A40A and A40,
                connector (2), pin A4, circuit N40, connector (9850), pin 9, circuit K40 and the low air pressure switch
                (6740) to ground (1LA).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SERVICE: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the green instrument cluster connector (11), pin 17 to the "SERVICE"
                indicator. The "SERVICE" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). When the coolant level is low in
                the coolant surge tank, the coolant level probe (400) closes its contacts to the start motor ground,
                circuit 34-G/K11-GJ, through circuit K34A, to ECM2 connector (6020), pin 4. This causes the "SERVICE"
                indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SERVICE: RE 200/RE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the green instrument cluster connector (11), pin 17 to the "SERVICE"
                indicator. The "SERVICE" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). When the coolant level is low in
                the coolant surge tank, the coolant level probe (6400) closes its contacts to the control box ground
                (7104), circuit K34-G/K11-GG, through circuit K34A, to ECM2 connector (6020), pin 4. This causes the
                "SERVICE" indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F,
                fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8.
                When the parking brake is applied, power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17,
                circuits A44 and A44A, the park brake switch (218), and circuits A44-GA, A11-GB, and A11-G to platform
                ground. This will cause the park brake warning light to illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is
                applied. The lamp will also illuminate when the key switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a
                ground is applied through circuit A44, a brake diode (82), and circuit A44-G, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE: RE 200/RE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>Power is applied by fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C and the park brake warning light and connector
                (12), pin 8. When the parking brake is applied, power will flow through the warning light and connector
                (12), pin 17, circuits A44 and A66K, the park brake switch (168) and circuit A66-G to cab ground. This
                will cause the park brake warning light to illuminate, indicating that the park brake is applied. The
                lamp will also illuminate when the key switch is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied
                through circuit A66H, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OIL/WATER: RE 200/RE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B, and the oil/water warning light receives
                power from fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 13. The
                warning light illuminates when a ground path is applied to natural instrument cluster connector (12),
                pin 14 by circuits A29A/35 and A97AF by the MSM1 (3114), pin 1. The alarm will also sound at a slow rate
                when a ground path is applied by the MSM1 in response to low oil pressure, high water temperature, or
                low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28/A28A, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 13 to the "OIL/WATER" indicator. The
                "OIL/WATER" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12
                and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of
                connector (9850), to the MSM1, circuits A5DD(+) and A5DD(-) to connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground
                is sent from the MSM1 connector (3114) through pin 1, circuit A97AF, to pin 1 of the audible alarm
                connector (211). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OIL/WATER: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B, and the oil/water warning light receives
                power from fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28D, and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 4. The
                warning light illuminates when a ground path is applied to natural instrument cluster connector (12),
                pin 14 by circuits A29/35 and A97AF by the MSM1 (3114), pin 1. The alarm will also sound at a slow rate
                when a ground path is applied by the MSM1 in response to low oil pressure, high water temperature, or
                low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28/A28D, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 4 to the "OIL/WATER" indicator. The "OIL/WATER"
                indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is
                transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector
                (9850), to the MSM1, circuits A5DD(+) and A5DD(-) to connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent
                from the MSM1 connector (3114) through pin 1, circuit A97AF, to pin 1 of the audible alarm connector
                (211). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WARN ENGINE: RE 200/RE 300</title>
            <para>When the ECM2 detects a faulty sensor or circuit, it will set a fault code and turn on the "WARN
                ENGINE" indicator. The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F,
                fuse F22, circuits A28/A28D, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 4 to the "WARN ENGINE"
                indicator. The "WARN ENGINE" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector
                (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins
                14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the MSM1 connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM1
                connector (3114) through pin 9, circuit A97T, to pin 15 of the natural instrument cluster connector
                (12). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE OIL: RE 200/RE 300</title>
            <para>The engine ECM2 is programmed to track engine hours and vehicle miles, and when the programmed values
                are achieved, the ECM2 will turn on the "CHANGE OIL" indicator. The battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28B, green instrument cluster
                connector (11), pin 10 to the "CHANGE OIL" indicator. The "CHANGE OIL" indicator is controlled by the
                ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link
                on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the MSM1 connector (3114)
                pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM2 connector (3115) through pin 2, circuit A97AA, to pin 6 of
                the natural instrument cluster connector (12). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Change Oil/Service interval light default setting is off. The customer can use the service
                        tool to activate the light and enter their own parameters into the ECM2 memory. The STI button
                        (diagnostics flash button) is used to reset the service interval reminder light.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#115 at connector (7204), pin 31. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12),
                pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A115, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (523),
                circuit K#115, and ECU connector (7204), pin 31, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III GEN 4 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12),
                pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A115, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (523),
                circuit K#129, and ECU connector (7150), pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#115 at connector (7204), pin 31. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12),
                pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (523),
                circuit K#115, and ECU connector (7204), pin 31, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III GEN 4 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to K#129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery voltage
                is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C, and
                natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12), pin
                7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (523), circuit
                K#129, and ECU connector (7150), pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison 2000 (LCT)</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                2000 (LCT) system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#125 at connector (7305), pin 25. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12),
                pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (9875),
                circuit K#125, and ECU connector (7305), pin 25, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison 1000/2000 GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                1000/2000 GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to circuit K#129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery
                voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C,
                and natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (12),
                pin 7, circuit A125, connector (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (9875),
                circuit K#129, and ECU connector (7150), pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: RE 200 (V8 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13A, fuse F20, circuits
                A19D, to the fuel heater relay (R5). With the key switch (20) in the on or start position, the
                water-in-fuel module (16) receives power at WIF connector (3116), pin A, from fuel heater relay (R5) and
                circuit A19E. When the key switch is moved to the start position, the key switch (20) ground is applied
                to circuit A19-GB going to the water-in-fuel module (16), pin C, to the WIF connector (3116), pin E.
                This initiates a bulb check by causing the module to apply power to connector (16), pin B, circuit A19F,
                to the WIF connector (3116), pin B, and the water-in-fuel module warning light (9). This causes the
                warning light, grounded through connector (9), circuit A19-G, to the WIF connector (3116), pin C,
                circuit A19-G, to the WIF connector (3116), pin D, circuits A19-GC/A11-G, to platform ground (1PG), to
                illuminate. When water is detected in the fuel filter by the water probe, a ground path is completed to
                the water-in-fuel module (16), pin D, circuit A19C, to the WIF connector (3116), pin F, circuit A19C, to
                connector (2), pin H6, circuit N19C, connector (9851), pin F, circuit K19C, fuel filter connector
                (6704), pin 2, and water probe (1WP), thus causing the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: RE 300 (I6 ENGINE)</title>
            <para>The I6 engine ECM2 will turn on the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light. The battery voltage is through the
                ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13A, fuse F20, circuits A97AC/A97AB, to the MSM1 connector
                (3114) pin 7 and to the WIF connector (3116), pin G, circuit A19K, to the WIF connector (3116), pin C,
                circuit A19-G, to the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light (9), pin B. The "WATER-IN-FUEL" indicator is
                controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred
                over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the
                MSM1 connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM2 connector (3115) through pin 3,
                circuit A19-GD, to the WIF connector (3116), pin H, circuit A19F, to the WIF connector (3116), pin B, to
                the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light (9), pin A, thus causing the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL FILTER: RE 200/RE 300</title>
            <para>When the fuel filter becomes restricted, the contacts of the fuel filter vacuum switch will close and
                the ECM2 will turn on the "FUEL FILTER" indicator. The battery voltage is through the ignition switch
                relay (1711), circuits A13/A13H, fuse F25, circuits A19J, to the "FUEL FILTER" warning light (69), pin
                A, in the instrument cluster. The "FUEL FILTER" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control
                from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and
                K5AA(-) through pins 14 and 15 of connector (9850), to the MSM1 connector (3114) pins 5 and 6. A ground
                is sent from the MSM2 connector (3115) through pin 1, circuit A19B, to the "FUEL FILTER" warning light
                (69), pin B, in the instrument cluster. This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRANS OIL TEMP: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III</title>
            <para>When the transmission temperature sensor senses that the transmission temperature is above 305 degrees
                F, its contacts close. The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits
                A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28B, green connector (11), pin 10, the "TRANS OIL TEMP" warning
                light, green connector (11), pin 6, circuit A31, connector (2), circuit A31A, connector (9850), circuit
                N31A, and the closed contacts of the temperature sensor to ground. This will cause the "TRANS OIL TEMP"
                warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LOW BRAKE FLUID: RE 200/RE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the on or start position, battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay
                (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A90R to the "LOW BRAKE FLUID" warning light
                (89-A). With the key switch held in the start position, the low brake fluid warning light will
                illuminate (bulb check is performed) as a ground is applied through circuits A90V and A90W, brake diode
                assy (82), and circuit A44-G (also A31-GD with pall transmission filter) to the key switch ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL: RE 200/RE 300 With Anti-lock Brake System (ABS) - Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28 and A94T, to the "TRAC CTRL" warning light, connector (1500), pin A, connector (1500), pin B,
                circuit A94U, connector (2), pin F6, circuit N94U, to the full power HCV connector (9808), pin 13. When
                the traction control switch (1101) is placed (on) position, the "TRAC CTRL" warning light to grounded
                through the full power HCV connector (9808), pin 8, circuit N94W, connector (2), pin A2, circuit A94W,
                the traction control switch (1101), circuits A94-GT and A11-G to the platform ground (1PG). The ABS
                module (ECU) (279) will enable the traction control mode and when the wheel sensors sense wheel slip,
                the module will apply 12 volts to the modulator valve for the brake to apply to the wheel that is
                slipping.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL: RE 200/RE 300 With WTEC or Allison 2000 ICT Anti-lock Brake System (ABS) - Air Brakes
            </title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13C, fuse F27, circuits
                A13M and A94BT/A94DT, to the traction control switch (1101) and is placed (on) position, circuit N94FT,
                connector (2), pin A7, circuit N94FT, to the ABS module (ECU) connector (288), pin F2. Also, the battery
                voltage is to circuits A94BT/A94GT, to the "TRAC CTRL" warning light, connector (3127), pin B, connector
                (3127), pin A, circuit A94CT, connector (2), pin A5, circuit N94CT, to the ABS module (ECU) connector
                (288), pin C2. The "TRAC CTRL" warning light and the traction control switch are grounded through the
                coil of the ABS power relay (283), circuits A94-GB and A11-GB to the platform ground (4PG). The ABS
                module (ECU) (288) will enable the traction control mode and when the wheel sensors sense wheel slip,
                the module will apply 12 volts to the modulator valve for the brake to apply to the wheel that is
                slipping.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD ON: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the key switch is in the ignition or start position, power from fuse F1C-1 flows through circuit
                V146A, connector (7101), pin U, circuit K#146A, to the ECU "S" connector (7204), pin 4, and the spliced
                circuit V146A/V146D, to the retard on warning light relay connector (7807), pin 1. When the retard on
                on/off switch (919) is moved to the on position, the switch (919), pin 1, circuit A163A, connector
                (644), pin F, circuit N163A, connector (523), pin L, circuit K#163A, spliced circuit K#163, to the ECU
                "S" connector (7204), pin 27, and through the switch (919), pin 2, circuit A143H, connector (644), pin
                H, circuit N143H, spliced circuit N143A, connector (523), pin J, circuit K#143A, to the ECU "S"
                connector (7204), pin 32, and the retarder enable function is completed. The retarder warning light
                relay circuit V146B to its coil and circuit V146D to its contacts, will become de-energized when the ECU
                removes its ground to circuit K#125 at connector (7202), pin 18, through spliced circuit K#125A,
                connector (7101), pin Q, circuit V125A, relay (7807), pin 5. This will allow power to flow through the
                contacts of the de-energized warning light relay (7807), circuit V92H, connector (7100), pin L, circuit
                K92H, connector (523), pin V, circuit N92H, connector (1601), pin A and circuit A92H to the "RETARD ON"
                warning light (926), pin A. This will cause the warning light (926), pin B, which is grounded through
                circuits A92-GA/A186, connector (377), pin A, circuits A186/A11-G to the platform ground (1PG), to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE TRANS FILTER: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with the automatic transmission filter warning light, power is supplied to fuse
                F10, circuit A31D, and the filter warning light (94). When the key switch (20) is held in the start
                position, power will flow through the filter warning light (94), circuit A31-GA, connector (344), a blue
                wire, and the pigtail of the filter pressure differential switch. This power will flow through the
                normally closed contacts of the pressure switch and its connector, a green wire, connector (344),
                circuit A31-GB, blocking diode (64), circuits A31-GC and A31-GD, and the key switch ground, thus causing
                the warning light to illuminate for a bulb check. When the transmission filter becomes restricted, the
                pressure differential switch's normally open contacts will close and power will flow through the warning
                light to the switch as above, but the power will flow through the normally open contacts of the switch
                and its connector, a brown wire, connector (344) and circuit A11-GE to platform ground, thus
                illuminating the change trans filter warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28 and A13J, connector (377), pin F, circuit A13J, to the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light, connector
                (925), pin B, connector (925), pin A, circuit A105B, connector (1601), pin B, circuit N105B, connector
                (523), pin U, circuit K#105B/K#105, to the ECU connector (7202), pin 19. When the transmission ECU
                detects that the transmission retarder is overheating, it will apply a ground (switch to low state) to
                illuminate the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT: RE 200/RE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28 and A13J, connector (377), pin F, circuit A13J, to the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light, connector
                (925), pin B, connector (925), pin A, circuit A164B, connector (1601), pin B, circuit N164B, connector
                (523), pin U, circuit K#164B/K#164, to the TCM connector (7150), pin 64. When the transmission TCM
                detects that the transmission retarder is overheating, it will apply a ground (switch to low state) to
                illuminate the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ALTERNATOR: RE 200/RE 300</title>
            <para>When the voltage output of the alternator is low, a ground will be provided on terminal (G) of the
                alternator, and through the VT365 or I6 circuit filters. This ground will be present on circuit 1C to
                pin 16, of the natural instrument cluster connector (12) and will cause the "ALTERNATOR" warning light,
                to illuminate. The battery voltage is through the ignition switch relay (1711), circuit A13/A13F, fuse
                F22, circuit A28/A28B, the green instrument cluster (11), pin 10 to the alternator warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
