<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Advanced Energy Hybrid CE Model Starting March, 2007 - ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S08328" division="truck" date="04/02/2007">
        <title>Advanced Energy Hybrid CE Model Starting March, 2007 - ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CE Bus</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Safety Information</title>
            <para>Portions of the circuitry in these circuit diagrams contain high voltages. Only trained technicians
                should perform maintenance on this circuitry. High voltage circuits will be identified by orange cables
                or conduit, but all circuits should be treated as potentially dangerous. Refer to TSI 06-08-05,
                <exhotlnk document="../tsis/060805.pdf" bookname="tsi">
                    https://evalue.internationaldelivers.com/service/tsipdf/060805.pdf</exhotlnk>, for proper procedures
                in dealing with high voltage circuits.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, refer to the manufacturer's service
                        information before working on any high voltage equipment. By definition high voltage circuits
                        and components contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage, electrical shock and/or
                        electrocution if handled incorrectly.
                    </para>
                    <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work
                        around or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, circuits must be checked using a voltmeter
                        for the presence of both dc and ac voltages. A voltmeter set to dc will not indicate the
                        presence of an ac voltage when connected to an ac circuit! Contacting an unknown ac or dc
                        voltage may cause equipment damage, electrical shock and/or electrocution.
                    </para>
                    <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work
                        around or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, permit only trained responsible and capable persons to
                        operate or maintain the equipment. Carelessly operating or neglecting maintenance despite the
                        safe design of any vehicle and its high voltage equipment may result in personal injury or
                        death.
                    </para>
                    <para>The danger of injury through electrical shock is possible whenever electrical power is
                        present. Most fatal injuries result from high-voltage exposure; however, people can sustain
                        severe injuries from low voltage power if it has a high current flow.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08328_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08328.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
