<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 - Electrical - Battery, Mounting and Cables - General Procedures</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="5">
        <title>General Procedures</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Disconnect - Dual: Disconnect</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries normally produce explosive gases which can cause personal injury. Therefore, do not
                        allow flames, sparks or lighted substances to come near the battery, always shield your face and
                        protect your eyes. Always provide ventilation. Failure to follow these instructions may result
                        in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When lifting a battery, excessive pressure on the end walls could cause acid to spew through
                        the vent caps, resulting in personal injury. Lift with a battery carrier or with your hands on
                        opposite corners. Failure to follow these instructions may result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Keep out of the reach of children. Batteries contain sulfuric acid. Avoid contact with the
                        skin, eyes or clothing. Also shield your eyes when working near the battery to protect against
                        possible splashing of the acid solution. In case of acid contact with skin or eyes, flush
                        immediately with water for a minimum of 15 minutes and get prompt medical attention. If acid is
                        swallowed, call a physician immediately. Failure to follow these instructions may result in
                        personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the battery is disconnected and reconnected, some abnormal drive symptoms may occur while
                        the vehicle relearns its adaptive strategy. The vehicle may need to be driven to relearn its
                        adaptive strategy.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Be sure the battery cover is reinstalled to avoid premature battery failure.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the battery cover.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the battery cover nuts.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the battery cover.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1401001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the primary battery ground cable (LH side of the battery tray).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1401002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024128.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the secondary battery ground cable (RH side of the battery tray).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1401003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024129.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the primary battery positive cable (LH side of the battery tray).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1401004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024130.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the secondary battery positive cable (RH side of the battery tray).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1401005" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0024131.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Battery Disconnect - Dual: Connect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To connect, reverse the disconnect procedure.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
