<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Engine Speed Control Features -
        60AJA - Remote Throttle Control Interlocked to Park Brake Applied - Recommended Application: Recovery
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB60AJA" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>60AJA - Remote Throttle Control Interlocked to Park Brake Applied - Recommended Application: Recovery
        </title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>60AJA - BDY INTG, THROTTLE CONTROL Accommodation for Single Customer-Mounted External Engine Speed Control
            Switch, Programmable Mode for Various Switch Actions and Engine Speed Control Option; Useable Only While
            Vehicle is Stopped and the Park Brake is Applied (requires one Remote Power Module (RPM) input)
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>TEM or customer-mounted single remote center stable, momentary switch; when the operator moves the switch
            to the up position, the switch supplies 12 volts to the RPM input to activate Remote engine speed control
            preset-1; when the operator returns the switch to the center position or stable position, the engine will
            remain at preset-1 until the operator moves the switch to the down position; in the down position, the
            switch then supplies a Ground (GND) to the RPM input to deactivate Remote engine speed control preset-1;
            when the operator returns the switch to the center position or stable position, the engine will remain at
            idle.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595AKJ</para>
        <para>Conflicts with software features: 595AKK, 595AKL, 595AKM, 595AKN</para>
        <para>Activation Parameters:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Momentary 12 volt input to RPM</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Park brake applied</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Transmission in neutral or park or clutch pedal not depressed</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle speed is less than one MPH</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine running and at idle</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Optional PTO feedback is true.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>Deactivation Parameters:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Momentary GND input to RPM</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Park brake not applied</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Transmission not in neutral or park or clutch pedal depressed</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle speed is greater than one MPH.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine not running</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Service brake depressed</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Optional PTO feedback not true</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE ORDERING NOTES:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>This feature requires one RPM input.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If 60AJA is ordered, 12VXU must also be ordered which requires entering TEM or customer-requested
                    Remote engine speed control preset-1 RPMs.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>TEM or customer must supply single pull, double throw, center stable, momentary switch and all
                    associated wiring from switch to RPM.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The optional PTO interlock is defaulted off; this interlock only works with International
                    pre-engineered PTO features. If the TEM or customer has one of the International pre-engineered PTO
                    features and needs to have this interlock turned on, this will require an additional parameter
                    change by someone who is at least Diamond Logic&#174; Builder Level 2 or 3 certified.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO INSTALL THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Software Installation:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Use Diamond Logic&#174; Builder to install Body Controller (BC) software feature code 595AKJ, and
                    set the feature code parameters to the following settings:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>595AKJ - Set parameter 2035 to 1. Reference feature configuration programmable
                            parameters.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>595AKJ - Set parameter 2158 to 3. Reference feature configuration programmable
                            parameters.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>595AKJ - Set parameter 2036 to on for optional PTO interlock. Reference feature
                            configuration programmable parameters.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use Diamond Logic&#174; Builder to remove BC software feature codes 595AKK, 595AKL, 595AKM, and
                    595AKN.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use Master Diagnostics to program Engine control module: PTO in-cab control: on</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use Master Diagnostics to program Engine control module: PTO in-cab mode: stationary pre-set
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use Master Diagnostics to program Engine control module: PTO Power Take Off mode: remote and
                    in-cab operation
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use Master Diagnostics to program Engine control module: PTO Preset-1 RPM set (700.00 to 2800.00)
                    (Note: this is the RPM the customer or TEM has requested)
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>1.&#9;2036 TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Ctrl_PTO_Ilock; This parameter sets the optional PTO interlock mode on or off.
            If set on, the Remote engine speed control preset-1 will be interlocked to all International pre-engineered
            PTO features that use a center panel switch. This means that the remote engine speed control will only be
            allowed to operate if the PTO is being requested to engage. If this parameter is not set, the engine speed
            control will operate regardless of the PTO request.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>On</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Off</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>2.&#9;2035 TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Control_Mode; This parameter sets the mode of operation for the TEM external
            engine speed control feature and should be set to 1.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>1, 12 volts on the engine speed control input causes engine to ramp to preset-1. GND on the same
                    input causes the engine to return to idle.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>3.&#9;2158 TEM_Ext_ Eng_Spd_ Ctrl_Active_State; This is the active state for the external engine speed
            control switch input to the RPM and should be set to 3.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="alphalc">
            <item>
                <para>3, 12 volts - The input is connected to 12 volts through a switch.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <table id="t7300084">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="SPAN1">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Off</emph>
                                - Indicates a 0 is set in for this parameter
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="SPAN1">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">On</emph>
                                - Indicates a 1 is set for the parameter
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Ext_ Eng_Spd_ Ctrl_PTO_ Ilock</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2036</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this parameter is a one, external engine speed controls will be interlocked to PTO
                                request.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>On/ Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Ext_ Eng_Speed_ Control_ Mode</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2035</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This parameter sets the mode of operation for the TEM external engine speed control
                                feature.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Ext_ Eng_Spd_ Ctrl_Active_ State</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2158</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This is the active state for the external engine speed control switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HARDWARE INSTALLATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Reference the connectors tab within Diamond Logic&#174; Builder to verify the correct RPM input
                    pin on the black 23-pin connector. The pin is named Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect an 18 gauge wire to input pin, and run this wire to the center pole on the switch.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect one of the remaining switch pole to a 12 volt power source.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect the only remaining switch pole to a chassis GND source.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Mount switch.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>Input connector part number - 2005482C1</para>
        <para>Input terminal part number - 1698937C1</para>
        <figure id="f73000b9" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0832386.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="502px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE TESTING:</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stationary Remote engine speed control preset-1 Activation; Start engine, set park brake,
                transmission in neutral or park, vehicle speed is less than one MPH, and take the switch to the up
                position, or supply 12 volts on the input pin labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input, or use Diamond Logic&#174;
                Builder to force the RPM input pin to the 12 volt state.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the RPM input labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input (pin position specified Diamond
                Logic&#174; Builder software) is receiving GND as long as the switch is closed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the engine ramps to the first preset speed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If engine does not ramp to the first preset speed, check engine programming to verify that
                the correct engine speed control parameters are set.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deactivate the remote engine speed control switch (release GND).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the RPM input labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input (pin position specified Diamond
                Logic&#174; Builder software) is an open circuit when switch is in the center stable position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the engine returns to idle.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB12VZA.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB60AJE.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
