<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        HVAC
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>HVAC</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>16WKB - Air Conditioning</title>
            <para>Refer to the Circuit Diagram in
                <exhotlnk document="../S08/S082853_CD16WKB.xml" bookname="S082853">S08285, Chapter 11, pages 1 and
                    2</exhotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>16WKB: Air Conditioner (International Blend Air) with integral heater, defroster and R134-A
                Refrigerant.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE / BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This is an electrical connection point for detecting when the air conditioner clutch is ON. No direct
                electrical connection point is provided for tapping into the A/C clutch wire. However, if an A/C Clutch
                connection is necessary, the body builder may use weather sealed splice techniques to tap into wire J77B
                at the ESC. The added load required by the body builder should not exceed 2 amps. This control wire
                shall be at battery volts when the A/C clutch is ON and 0 volts when OFF. The software in the ESC
                determines when this wire shall be ON or OFF based upon the mode of the HVAC controls in the cab and
                condenser temperatures and high side pressures of the A/C System. This control wire shall be OFF as
                necessary to protect the A/C compressor.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
                NONE
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f7300083" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg73/g73000ar.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Location: ESC on Engine Compartment Side</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>LOCATION: ESC on the engine compartment side</para>
            <para>WIRE GAUGE: 16GA</para>
            <para>WIRE NUMBER/COLOR: J77B-LTGN</para>
            <para>ESC CONNECTOR (4008): 3548933C1 (BLUE) Pin G</para>
            <para>LOCK: 3548943C1</para>
            <para>TERMINAL: 3535930C1</para>
            <para>SEAL: 3535936C1</para>
            <para>CIRCUIT DIAGRAM: See Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual S08285 Chapter 11</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Start the vehicle. Turn on air conditioner.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify that the wire feeding the body load is at battery volts when the A/C Clutch is ON and 0
                        volts when OFF.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Ensure that no faults codes are present when the truck is on.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">BODY BUILDER IMPORTANT INFORMATION:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In some applications it may be advantageous to add an additional AC evaporator to cool remote areas of
                the vehicle. The following procedures and part numbers will accommodate this addition.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not break into the A/C Clutch circuit (J77B, K77A) for the purpose of controlling the A/C
                        system.
                    </para>
                    <para>Do not connect to the high side of the pressure transducer.</para>
                    <para>Do not connect to either of the A/C system thermistors.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PARTS INFORMATION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Pre 2004 Emission DT 466 and 530 Engines</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6) - 2585758C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Post 2004 Emission DT 466 and 570 Engines, Low Cab Mount</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6) - 2588940C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Post 2004 Emission DT 466 and 570 Engines, Mid High Cab</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6) - 2588941C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For VT 365 Engines</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for V8) - 2585760C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for V8) - 2585761C91</para>
            <para>
                <title>PROCEDURE</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a level surface, set
                        the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear a face shield, or other adequate eye protection, and nonporous gloves when working with
                        refrigerant. The temperature of liquid refrigerant may cause injury or blindness if the
                        refrigerant contacts the eyes. Should liquid refrigerant come in contact with skin, remove
                        contaminated clothing, including shoes and treat the injury as though the skin had been
                        frostbitten. See a doctor immediately.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the
                        system are replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause personal
                        injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recover the refrigerant from the AC system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the AC hose from the condenser to the evaporator and install the new hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the AC hose from the accumulator to the compressor and install the new hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the AC hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed
                    hose from the condenser to the evaporator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the AC hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed
                    hose from the accumulator to the compressor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate the system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge the system using R-134a refrigerant. The original truck system holds 30 oz. and
                    the new evaporator should require an additional 16 oz. The additional requirement will vary from
                    system to system depending on the length of hoses and the capacity of the new evaporator. The
                    additional capacity will also require an additional 40 cc (1.2 fl. Oz.) of PAG oil in the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Failure to add additional PAG oil to the increased capacity AC system will result in improper
                        lubrication and lead to premature component failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate the vehicle to make sure the AC is performing properly and is not leaking.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB08WRB.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_63.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
