<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - FE 300 and IC Bus - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SPEEDOMETER GAUGE</title>
            <para>The sensor (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0831313">Figure 13</hotlnk>) is a magnetic pick up that senses the rotation of a
                speedometer gear mounted in the transmission. A permanent magnet located in the sensor establishes a
                magnetic field at the tip of the sensor. The field is repeatedly interrupted by the teeth of the
                speedometer gear in the transmission, creating voltage impulses from the vehicle speed sensor (VSS).
                When Fuller manual transmission, these are transmitted through connector (303), on circuits K47 and
                K47A, to connector (6021) on the ECM2. When Allison WTEC automatic transmission, these are transmitted
                from connector (7983), on circuits K139 and K148, to connector (7203) on the ECU, and these are
                transmitted from the control module connector (7204), on circuits K157, to connector (6021) on the ECM2.
                Or, Allison 2000 (LCT) automatic transmission, these are transmitted from connector (7600), on circuits
                K215 and K216, to connector (7304) on the TCM, and these are transmitted from the control module
                connector (7305), on circuits K126/K126W, to connector (6021) on the ECM2. The ECM2 converts the sensor
                signal to a digital data signal. This signal is transferred over the data link on circuits A98E(+) and
                A98F(-) to pins 7 and 9 of connector (11), into the instrument cluster. The instrument cluster's
                microprocessor drives the speedometer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0831313" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0831313" filename="../figg08/g0831313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Speedometer Operation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SENSOR OUTPUT VOLTAGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SENSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MAGNETIC FIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SPEEDOMETER GEAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TRANSMISSION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>A permanent magnet located in the sensor establishes a magnetic field at the tip of the sensor. The
                magnetic field is repeatedly interrupted by the teeth of the speedometer gear in the transmission,
                creating voltage impulses that are transmitted to the ECM2 which converts the analog signal to a digital
                data signal and feeds it to the speedometer.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
