<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        Battery, Ignition and Accessory Taps - 08WAD, 08WCS, 08WHX and 08WHY - Battery Disconnect Switch
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB08WAD" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>08WAD, 08WCS, 08WHX and 08WHY - Battery Disconnect Switch</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>08WAD - BATTERY DISCONNECT SWITCH {Joseph Pollak} Lever Operated</para>
        <para>08WCS - BATTERY DISCONNECT SWITCH {Joseph Pollak 51-315} Positive Type, Lever Operated, Mounted on Cab
            Floor
        </para>
        <para>08WHX - BATTERY DISCONNECT SWITCH {Pollak 51-316} Locking, Key Operated, Positive Type, Mounted on Battery
            Box
        </para>
        <para>08WHY - BATTERY DISCONNECT SWITCH {Joseph Pollak 51-316} Positive Type, Locking, Key Operated, Mounted on
            Cab Floor
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE / BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The disconnect switch is used to shut down the entire battery fed electrical system. When a vehicle is not
            going to be used for several days or longer, this switch will shut off the system so that the electrical
            components on the vehicle, if left on, do not drain the batteries of their charge. Customers have the choice
            between a key or lever operated battery disconnect switch.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The disconnect switch should never be used to shut off the engine as there is a possibility of the
                    alternator generating a high positive voltage spike which may result in electrical damage.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f7300089" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g7300089.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
            NONE
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>No additional wiring is necessary if the vehicle is ordered from International with the sales feature
            codes listed above.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the vehicle is providing 12-14 Volts to the starter motor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify vehicle will start.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn engine off.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open disconnect switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify vehicle systems do not have any electrical power.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW DO I ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The disconnect switch cannot be put into the battery ground cable as was previously done. The electronic
            modules will provide a ground path around the master disconnect switch if this is tried. The engine and
            transmission modules must always be connected to the batteries, even when the master disconnect switch is
            opened. Separate power and ground circuits are provided on each vehicle to the engine and transmission
            electronics. To install a master disconnect switch, break into the positive battery cable, or use OEM
            cables, going from the batteries to the cranking motor and insert disconnect switch into that circuit, as
            shown in Figure 1. Insure that adequate electrical insulation is used between the positive battery cable,
            the switch mounting, and the surrounding area. Place boots or covers over the disconnect switch studs to
            protect the batteries and cables from accidental shorting. Do not disturb the direct connections from the
            battery to the engine or transmission electronics. To reduce corrosion, dielectric grease should cover
            eyelets and studs.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Make sure that batteries are disconnected prior to performing any electrical work.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>If a non-OEM switch is to be used, make sure it is designed to handle at least 1,000 amp (intermittent
            duty)
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300090" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g7300090.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Installation Circuit For Battery Disconnect Switch</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If there is more than one positive cable, eyelet terminals will have to be stacked on the switch
                    stud. Some installations may not have ground strap to rail - if none exists, there is no need to add
                    one.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_31.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB60AAC.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
