<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        High Current In Cab Switch Controls for Body Accessories - 08WJA, 08WJB - Power Source For Lift Gate
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB08WJA" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="6">
        <title>08WJA, 08WJB - Power Source For Lift Gate</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>08WJA - POWER SOURCE, SPECIAL for Customer Installed Lift Gate; 200 Amp max, includes 2ga. power cable to
            end-of-frame, switch on instrument panel, with a time-out feature, battery discharge protection, controlling
            a mag switch which provides power.
        </para>
        <para>08WJB - POWER SOURCE, for Customer Installed Lift Gate; heavy duty, includes 0ga. power cable to
            end-of-frame, switch on instrument panel, with a time-out feature, battery discharge protection, controlling
            a mag switch which provides power.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Feature code 08WJA or 08WJB provides a factory-installed, dedicated power source for lift gate operation.
            This feature includes an instrument panel mounted master switch, which illuminates when the system is turned
            on, and an optional "AUX" button on the key fob to enable or disable the lift gate. The purpose of the
            in-cab master switch and the "AUX" button on the key fob is to help prevent unauthorized use of the lift
            gate. These switches also activate a 60 minute timer in the ESC that will disable the lift gate after 60
            minutes. For continued use of the lift gate the master switch, or the aux button on the key fob, must be
            used to activate the system for an additional 10 minutes. A Battery Protection Module, activated by the ESC
            60 minute timer, and a 200 Amp mag switch, mounted in or at the battery box, enables power to the lift gate
            motor. A circuit protected cable from battery to mag switch and a heavy gauge wire routed from the mag
            switch to the end of frame to provide power to the lift gate motor.
        </para>
        <para>This feature will provide battery discharge protection for users who operate the lift gate with or without
            the engine running. Without the engine running, key off, the Battery Protection Module will constantly
            monitor battery voltage and shut down the lift gate operation before battery voltage reaches a state of
            charge that will not allow the vehicle to restart. With the key switch in any position except start or off,
            an audible alarm will also sound in the cab during certain low voltage conditions. In addition to battery
            voltage monitoring, this feature has timeout functionality from the ESC to automatically disable the lift
            gate after a selected time. The default timeout is 60 minutes. A road speed interlock from the ESC is
            provided that activates above approximately 2 MPH. If activated the indicator light in the switch flashes
            and the Lift Gate is disabled by the ESC which prevents the lift gate from being operated while the vehicle
            is in motion. The lift gate master switch, or the aux button on the key fob, must be activated again to
            continue use of the lift gate after vehicle has stopped.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">The lift gate shall be activated for 60 minutes when:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Key switch is in any position and the lift gate switch is pressed to the momentary ON position (up
            position) or Key Fob AUX button is pressed, and the vehicle speed is lower than 2 MPH and voltage conditions
            are met.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">The lift gate shall be deactivated when:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The lift gate switch is pressed to the momentary OFF position (down position), OR the aux button on the
            key fob is pressed, OR the voltage is lower than the safe voltage value and the shutdown override time
            expires or the vehicle speed is greater than 2 MPH, or the programmable time limit, set at 60 minutes, has
            been reached.
        </para>
        <para>A cable accommodation is required to fit body van length of 14-26 feet and a relaxed extra cable of 40
            inches for feasible connectivity.
        </para>
        <para>Design accommodation for a lift gate with maximum current draw of up to 200 amps for code 08WJA and 200+
            amps for code 08WJB.
        </para>
        <para>This feature cannot exist with work light feature 08WLL or 08WMA. The lift gate feature will be using same
            cluster switch location and same ESC pin allocation as the work light feature. The body builder may power
            work lights from the lift gate motor power cable. This would allow the customer to have work lights in the
            van body and would not discharge the battery as the system shuts down after 60 minutes or if any of the
            other conditions listed above are met.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>*Software feature codes can be added through ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software.
            Programmable Parameters are also programmable through ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software.
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595293</para>
        <para>Software features that must be removed: 595025</para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Lift_Gate_Alarm_Time</emph>
            parameter is programmed to allow the operation of the lift gate for a period of 60 minutes. At the end of 60
            minutes the master switch or the AUX button on the key fob must be used to reactivate the system.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Lift_Gate_Enable_Timeout</emph>
            parameter is programmed to allow continual operation of the lift gate, in 10 minute increments, with the
            master switch or AUX button on the key fob after the timeout period of 60 minutes.
        </para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">Lift_Gate_Disable_Threshold</emph>
            parameter is programmed to sound a low voltage alarm if the battery voltage falls below 11.5 volts for more
            than 40 seconds while the lift gate is in operation. This parameter will also deactivate the lift gate if
            the battery voltage falls below 11.5 volts for more than 100 seconds. The lift gate cannot be reactivate
            until the battery voltage rises above 11.5 volts.
        </para>
        <table id="t73000a2a">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Set</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Alarm_Time</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PV-268</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift Gate Alarm Time Value</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>60</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>s</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>120</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Disable_ Threshold</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PV-267</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Voltage level that Lift Gate will be disabled at.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>11.5</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>V</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>11.5</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>13.8</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Enable_Timeout</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PV-56</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Amount of time, in 10 minute increments, that the lift gate will remain enabled.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>60</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>240</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>For 08WJA and 08AJB:</para>
        <figure id="f73000c7a" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091BB.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Lift Gate Function Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f73000c7b" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091CC.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Lift Gate Circuit Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">For 08WJA:</emph>:
        </para>
        <para>The body builder will be required to cut the straplocks at (2) securing the power cable and route and clip
            the power cable to the lift gate motor. Then trim the power cable to length and add a lug terminal for
            securing cable to the lift gate motor. Two product graphics, from the plastic bag for body builders, need to
            be installed on the van body in the approximate locations shown.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">For 08WJB:</emph>:
        </para>
        <para>The body builder will be required to route an 0 GA cable from the Mag Switch, back along the frame to the
            lift gate motor.
        </para>
        <para>Code 08WJB is identical to code 08WJA except that the 3592398C91 Cable Assy, Lift Gate Feed with "2" gauge
            cable and 2 - 10 Awg fusible links are replaced with 3598246C91 Cable Assy, Lift Gate Feed with "0" gauge
            cable and 3 - 10 Awg fusible links and the 3592400C93-REF "2" gauge Cable Assy, Lift Gate - 33.5 feet Ref -
            Cut to length is changed to "0" gauge cable. The body builder will be required to route the 2 GA cable from
            the Mag Switch, back along the frame to the lift gate motor is changed to "0" gauge cable.
        </para>
        <figure id="f73000c7c" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091DD.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Harness Routing Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f73000c7d" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091EE.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Warning Label Locations Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>The body builder or lift gate installer must bring the batteries up to a full charge before trying
                    to test the system for functionality.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With the batteries at a full charge, voltage in the 12.6 to 12.9 range, and the lift gate power
                    controlled by the Battery Protection System, the system will operate as described in the above
                    section.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software to add the following software feature:</para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595293</para>
        <para>Software features that must be removed: 595025</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Hardware:</emph>
        </para>
        <table id="t73000a2az">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col6" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN3"/>
                <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col5" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Part #</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2" align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>Quantity</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3593177C1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Switch, Momentary Multiplex</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3545544C92</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Harness, Dash - Work Light / Lift Gate Circuits</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3553986F92</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Harness, Center Chassis - Work Light / Lift Gate Circuits</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3542321C92</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Cable Assy, Work Light / Power Control</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3592395C3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Mag Switch Mounting Bracket</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3593085C92</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Control, Battery Discharge Protection</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3592818C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>200 Amp Mag Switch, Battery Disconnect</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3592398C91</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Cable Assy, Lift Gate Feed W/Fusible Links</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3592400C93-REF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Cable Assy, Lift Gate Power - 33.5 feet Ref - Cut to length</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>449632C1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>Conduit, Nylon 1/2 in. ID Slit</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>35 feet</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <figure id="f73000c7da" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091FF.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Connector Locations Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Install the 3593177C1 switch in the lower left, inner switch location of the cluster. Harness 3545544C92,
            insert circuit J65 into cavity "F" of BROWN Connector. See figure above for location of brown connector and
            figure below for location of "F" cavity. Install an eyelet terminal for a 5/16 stud on circuit J65-G and
            install on the ground stud. See figure above for location. Route harness with dash harness to connection
            with center chassis harness. Connect to harness 3553986F92 and route this harness back to the rear cab
            mounting Xmbr. Connect 3542321C92 Cable Assy and route this cable assy to the battery box and connect to the
            3593085C92 Bat Discharge Control. Mount the 3593085C92 Control and the 3592818C91 200 Amp Mag Sw on bracket
            3592395C3 and mount this assy in the battery box. Install 3592398C91 Cable Assy W/Fusible Links from battery
            "POS" terminal to Mag Switch. Install 3592400C93 2 AWG Cable Assy from mag sw to lift gate motor after
            installing 449632C1 conduit over this cable for protection against shorts. See
            <hotlnk xrefid="f73000c7b">Circuit Diagram</hotlnk>
            for the proper Circuit connections.
        </para>
        <figure id="f73000c7dc" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300091GG.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="152px"/>
            <caption>#4007 Connector Pin Locations Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <table id="t73000a2az1">
            <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.62*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.10*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="2.12*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col4" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">#4007 Brown Front End Output</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Engine Side Bottom 8-Way Connector</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">PIN</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">SOURCE</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">DESCRIPTION</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>A</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>20 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fog Lamps</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>B</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>10 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Right Front Turn Signal</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>C</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>10 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Left Front Turn Signal</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>D</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>20 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Headlamp, Low Beam</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>E</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>10 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Horn, Electric</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>F</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>10 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Work Lamp/Lift Gate</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>G</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>20 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Headlamp, High Beam</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>H</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>20 Amp FET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Park/Marker Lamps</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB08XBK.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_104.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
