<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3 Dynamic Power System Service/ Troubleshooting Guide - General
        Troubleshooting Procedures
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>General Troubleshooting Procedures</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface, set
                    the parking brake, turn the engine off, and chock the wheels.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>To properly check PowerPack 3 system operation, the truck must be stationary with the engine running.
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Place the transmission in neutral.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Set the Park Brake.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Start the engine.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Release the service brake pedal.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Make sure any PTO controls that could potentially override the system engine speed control are
                    turned off.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Set the 120 VAC switch to ON.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>At this point, the engine should automatically ramp to 935 rpm and the 120 VAC switch indicator should be
            ON solid (no flashing).
        </para>
        <para>If the switch indicator is flashing, or the engine does not ramp to and maintain 935 rpm or more, turn the
            switch off and check that all the interlock conditions (transmission in neutral, park brake set, engine
            running, PTO control OFF) are met. Turn the switch on again.
        </para>
        <para>If the switch indicator light continues to flash, check for fault codes SPN 168, FMI 4 or FMI 8. If one of
            these fault codes is present, check for proper connection of the 3 phase cables from the alternator to the
            PowerPack.
        </para>
        <para>If a communication fault is present, check for open circuits in the CAN bus and/or Ignition connections to
            the system.
        </para>
        <para>The switch indicator will flash to indicate a problem. It can flash slow (once per second) or fast (twice
            per second) to indicate the severity as shown in the diagnostic trouble code chart below.
        </para>
        <table id="t0830801" frame="all">
            <title>PowerPack 3 Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
            <tgroup cols="6">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.49*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.46*"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.58*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.54*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" colwidth="3.15*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>SPN</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>FMI</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Byte 7</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Byte 8</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Switch Indicator Blink Rate</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Condition Description/ Comments/ Probable Cause(s)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>2</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Communication fault from ESC to the PowerPack. Check for open circuit or short in
                                J1939 datalink. If switch is not blinking, verify vehicle is programmed for Powerpack
                                feature and the switchpack is operating correctly.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>DC module over voltage condition on vehicle DC bus. System detected voltage over 15
                                volts. Remove any external power supply/charger from vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Slow</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>AC module over voltage condition on high voltage DC bus. Likely an internal failure
                                for AC output. AC has been shut down. DC output remains on.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>4</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>DC module under voltage condition on vehicle DC Bus. System detected low DC voltage.
                                This could be due to insufficient input power from the alternator. Check the 3 phase
                                wires from the alternator to the PowerPack.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>4</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Slow</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>AC module under voltage condition on high voltage DC bus. System detected low internal
                                voltages. This could be due to insufficient input power from the alternator. Check the 3
                                phase wires from the alternator to the PowerPack.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>6</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Slow</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>AC module has shut down due to overload condition. AC overloaded, remove some or all
                                of AC load.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>8</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Phase missing fault/alternator fault. One of the three 3-phase wires has an open
                                circuit. Check the 3 phase wires from the alternator to the PowerPack.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>16</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>DC module over temperature condition. PowerPack is experiencing extremely high
                                internal temperatures. AC and DC has been shut down. Allow the system to cool down.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>16</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Slow</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>AC module over temperature condition. PowerPack has detected high internal
                                temperatures although less severe. AC inverter has shutdown, but DC output remains on.
                                Shut the system down to allow it to cool down or remove some of the loads.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>168</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>17</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PowerPack Fuse Open. Check DC battery charging connections from Powerpack. Check 150A
                                fuse.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>639</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>14</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>37</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>255</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Fast</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Communication fault between PowerPack and the ESC. Check for open circuit or short in
                                J1939 datalink. Also, check the ignition circuit to the Powerpack module.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>The following are the most common symptoms and solutions encountered.</para>
        <para>Prior to any troubleshooting, always check and verify that all PowerPack 3 and alternator connections are
            tight and secure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>PowerPack 3 is turned on but no output power is available.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SOLUTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the vehicle is running and all interlock conditions are met (see above).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the PowerPack 3 switch is turned on. Switch indicator should be ON solid. If it's
                    flashing, then the system is indicating a problem and may have a diagnostic code.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the PowerPack 3 is getting 12 Volts on the Ignition wire when the key is on. If not,
                    check the fuse and interconnects.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the CAN bus cable is connected to both the PowerPack 3 and the vehicle connectors.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the 30-Amp breaker on the side of the PowerPack 3 enclosure is not open.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the GFCI outlet is not open. The GFCI should have a green light on if 120VAC power is
                    available. A red light on the GFCI indicates a ground fault and needs reset (verify the short
                    circuit has been removed). Reset button is located on the GFCI.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the circuit breaker or GFCI was open, be sure to examine all grounding, and load conditions to
                    determine the cause.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SYMPTOM:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>PowerPack 3 won't support the desired load.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SOLUTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the engine ramps to the proper RPM (935) when the system is enabled.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the total PowerPack 3 load (AC Watts plus DC Watts) is less than 4100 total Watts. (AC
                    Volts x AC Amps = AC Watts + DC Volts x DC Amps = DC Watts.)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that all 3 AC input cables from alternator are securely connected to PowerPack 3 and
                    alternator.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the alternator field cable is securely connected to PowerPack 3 and to the alternator.
                    Also check that the special fuse for the alternator field circuit is not open.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify alternator is working properly. See Alternator Checkout Procedure below.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
