<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BODY CONTROLLER DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODES - Displaying Diagnostic Trouble Codes - Vehicles Equipped with
        Option to Display Codes
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Vehicles Equipped with Option to Display Codes</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>1.1.1. Displaying Codes on the Gauge Cluster (Non-VID equipped vehicles)</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">To display codes on vehicles not equipped with a VID:</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the key switch to the ACCESSORY position to view only previously active codes. Turn
                    the key switch to the IGNITION position to view both active and previously active codes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Momentarily press the Cruise "ON" switch and the Cruise "Resume" switch at the same
                    time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>A gauge sweep will be performed on the gauges. The gauge cluster will then display the following
                information for 5 seconds:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Software Rev: XXX</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hardware Rev: XXX</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Active Faults: XXX</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Total Faults: XXX</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The gauge cluster will only display "Software Rev" and "Hardware Rev" for 5 seconds followed
                        by the message "Diagnostic Trouble Codes are not available" if the vehicle is not equipped with
                        the option to display codes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If faults are present, the gauge cluster display will show each diagnostic trouble code for 10 seconds
                and then automatically scroll to the next entry and continue to cycle through the faults. Once all
                faults have been displayed the number of faults will be displayed again, then the cycle will repeat. To
                manually cycle through the fault list press and release the cluster display selector button. The
                following information will be displayed for each fault:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>SPN: XXXX FMI: XX</line>
                <line>Active</line>
                <line>OC: XXX SA: XXX</line>
            </verbatim>
            <verbatim>
                <line>SPN: XXXX FMI: XX</line>
                <line>Previously Active</line>
                <line>OC: XXX SA: XXX</line>
            </verbatim>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Turning the key switch off, turning the key switch to the CRANK position, or releasing the
                        park brake will take the gauge cluster out of the diagnostic mode.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>1.1.2. Displaying Codes on the VID (if equipped)</title>
            <para>The VID can be used to display all diagnostic trouble codes (DTC) on the vehicle. Suspect parameter
                number (SPN), failure mode indicator (FMI) and occurrence count numbers are listed. Source addresses and
                DTC descriptions are presented in plain text.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The VID will display "Not Available" if a DTC description is not available for a particular
                        fault.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Displaying codes will only be allowed if all of the following conditions are true:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The key switch is in the IGNITION position.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>AND displaying codes is allowed due to vehicle orderable options</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>AND the programmable parameter "
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostics</emph>" is enabled using Diamond Logic&#174; Builder (DLB).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The vehicle is not moving (the Vehicle Speed is equal to zero).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The feature is not password protected to prevent unauthorized access. Refer to the Vehicle
                        Information Display Owner's Manual for more information.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">Perform the following steps if all of the above conditions are met:</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Go to the main menu screen</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following selections will not be available if the vehicle is not equipped with the option
                        to display codes.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select "DIAGNOSTIC CODES"</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select "ACTIVE" or "INACTIVE". The VID may initiate a password prompt if the VID has
                    been password protected. Refer to the Vehicle Information Display Owner's Manual for more
                    information.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The VID will indicate "NO FAULT DETECTED" if faults are not found. Scroll through the list of faults
                if faults are present.
            </para>
            <para>The following information will be displayed for each fault:</para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>SPN : FMI OC</line>
                <line>SA</line>
                <line>DTC Description</line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08327_S0826301.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08327_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08327.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
