<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3 Dynamic Power System Service/ Troubleshooting Guide - Alternator Checkout
        Procedure
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Alternator Checkout Procedure</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The alternator may generate high voltage, particularly at high rpm, which can be harmful. Do not
                    touch the 3 phase outputs terminals. Failure to follow this warning may result in property damage,
                    personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>In order to determine if the alternator is functioning properly, perform the following troubleshooting
            procedure.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Before continuing with this procedure insure that the batteries and associated truck wiring is in
                    good working order.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>A. Check field voltage by turning the ignition switch to the run mode -
            <emph type="underscr">do not start the engine</emph>. Measure the voltage at each of the alternator F+ and
            F- terminals (see Figure 1). Voltage will be from .5V to 1.5V. If the voltage is not present then faulty
            wiring or the inverter is the problem. If voltage is present on one of the alternator's F terminals and not
            present on the other, then the alternator's field is open and the alternator is defective. See Figure 1 to
            properly test voltage at the alternator's field terminals.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0830801" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830801.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>B. Turn off the ignition switch, ensure that the Inverter switch is in the OFF position and any loads are
            disconnected from the Inverter.
        </para>
        <para>C. Disconnect the two (2) field leads from the alternator,
            <emph type="underscr">tape the end of each lead individually</emph>
            with electrical tape and tie back out of the way (see Figure 2).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0830802" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830802.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="208px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>D. Disconnect the three (3) phase leads marked AC on the back of the alternator (see Figure 3) and
            <emph type="underscr">tape the end of each lead individually</emph>
            with electrical tape and tie back out of the way.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0830803" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830803.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>E. Connect the alternator field terminals directly to the 12V batteries (see Figure 4).</para>
        <figure id="f0830804" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830804.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>F. Start the truck and run the engine at idle.</para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The Alternator output is a hazardous 3 phase AC voltage - Do not cut the cable or touch the
                    terminals. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>G. With the engine idling, measure the AC terminal voltages (alternator AC taps) 1 to 2, 2 to 3 and 1 to 3
            (see Figure 5). All three readings should be within one volt (1V).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The AC terminal voltage output varies directly with field input voltage and engine RPM. Therefore
                    the important reading is that each AC inter-phase reading is the same within one volt.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0830805" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830805.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>H. If the AC phase voltages fall within the specification listed above then the alternator is good.</para>
        <para>I. If the AC phase voltages fall outside the specification then the alternator is defective and needs to
            be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS TEST PLEASE CONTACT THE LEECE-NEVILLE TECHNICAL
                SERVICES HOT LINE AT 866-288-9853.
            </emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
