<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Lift Gate Accommodation Package
        - 08WJA, 08WJB - Power Source For Lift Gate
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB08WJA" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>08WJA, 08WJB - Power Source For Lift Gate</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>08WJA - POWER SOURCE, SPECIAL for Customer-Installed Lift Gate; 200 AMP max, includes 2 gauge power cable
            to end-of-frame, switch on Instrument Panel (IP), with a time out feature, battery discharge protection,
            controlling a mag switch which provides power
        </para>
        <para>08WJB - POWER SOURCE, for Customer-Installed Lift Gate; heavy duty, includes 0 gauge power cable to
            end-of-frame, switch on IP, with a time out feature, battery discharge protection, controlling a mag switch
            which provides power
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Feature code 08WJA or 08WJB provides a factory-installed, dedicated power source for lift gate operation.
            This feature includes an IP-mounted master switch, which illuminates when the system is turned on, and an
            optional "AUX" button on the key fob to enable or disable the lift gate. The purpose of the in-cab master
            switch and the "AUX" button on the key fob is to help prevent unauthorized use of the lift gate. These
            switches also activate a 60 minute timer in the BC that will disable the lift gate after 60 minutes. For
            continued use of the lift gate, the master switch or the aux button on the key fob must be used to activate
            the system for an additional ten minutes. A Battery Protection Module, activated by the BC 60 minute timer,
            and a 200 AMP mag switch, mounted in or at the battery box, enables power to the lift gate motor. A circuit
            protected cable from the battery to the mag switch and a heavy gauge wire routed from the mag switch to the
            end of frame, to provide power to the lift gate motor is also provided.
        </para>
        <para>This feature will provide battery discharge protection for users who operate the lift gate with or without
            the engine running. Without the engine running, key off, the Battery Protection Module will constantly
            monitor battery voltage and shut down the lift gate operation before battery voltage reaches a state of
            charge that will not allow the vehicle to restart. With the key switch in any position except start or off,
            an audible alarm will also sound in the cab during certain low voltage conditions. In addition to battery
            voltage monitoring, this feature has time out functionality from the BC to automatically disable the lift
            gate after a selected time. The default time out is 60 minutes. A road speed interlock from the BC is
            provided that activates above approximately 2 MPH. If activated, the indicator light in the switch flashes
            and the lift gate is disabled by the BC which prevents the lift gate from being operated while the vehicle
            is in motion. The lift gate master switch, or the aux button on the key fob, must be activated again to
            continue use of the lift gate after vehicle has stopped.
        </para>
        <para>The lift gate shall be activated for 60 minutes when the key switch is in any position and the lift gate
            switch is pressed to the momentary on position (up position), or key fob aux button is pressed, and the
            vehicle speed is lower than 2 MPH and voltage conditions are met.
        </para>
        <para>The lift gate shall be deactivated when any of the following conditions are met:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>The lift gate switch is pressed to the momentary off position (down position), or the push button
                    is cycled depending on the programmable feature on the vehicle.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The aux button on the key fob is pressed.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The voltage is lower than the safe voltage value, and the shutdown override time expires or the
                    vehicle speed is greater than 2 MPH.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The programmable time limit, set at 60 minutes, has been reached.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>A cable accommodation is required to fit body van length of 14-26 feet. An additional 40 inch cable length
            is provided for ease of installation.
        </para>
        <para>Design accommodation for a lift gate with maximum current draw of up to 200 AMPS for code 08WJA and 200+
            AMPS for code 08WJB is available.
        </para>
        <para>This feature can work with the work light feature but cannot work with the work light Remote Keyless Entry
            (RKE) key fob feature.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>*Software feature codes can be added through the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software. Programmable
            parameters are also programmable through the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software.
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595AYM for lift gate with rocker switch or 595AGN for lift gate with push
            button switch
        </para>
        <para>Software features that must be removed: 595ABT</para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Alarm_Time parameter is programmed to allow the operation of the lift gate for a period of
            60 seconds. At the end of 60 seconds, the master switch or the aux button on the key fob must be used to
            reactivate the system.
        </para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Enable_Timeout parameter is programmed to allow continual operation of the lift gate, in 10
            minute increments, with the master switch or aux button on the key fob after the time out period of 60
            minutes.
        </para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Enable_Hi_Current parameter will set an alarm if amperage load goes above the programmed
            value.
        </para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Enable_Lo_Current parameter will set an alarm if amperage load goes below the programmed
            value.
        </para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Enable_OC_Current parameter will set an alarm if amperage load goes below the programmed
            value.
        </para>
        <para>The Lift_Gate_Enable_Timeout parameter can be adjusted to vary the amount of time, in ten minute
            increments, that the lift gate will remain enabled. If this value is set to 6, the lift gate will remain
            enabled for 60 minutes from the time that it is enabled.
        </para>
        <table id="t73000a2a">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Set</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Alarm_Time</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2249</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift Gate Alarm Time Value</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>60</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>s</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>120</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Enable_Hi_ Current</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2234</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift Gate Enable High Current Detection Level (AMPS)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>A</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Enable_Lo_ Current</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2233</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Work Light Low Current Detection Level (AMPS)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>A</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Enable_OC_ Current</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2232</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift Gate Enable Open Circuit Detection Level (AMPS)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>A</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Lift_Gate_ Enable_Timeout</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2235</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Amount of time, in 10 minute increments, that the lift gate will remain enabled.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>60</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>240</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>For 08WJA and 08WJB, please refer to Circuit Diagram Manual S08322, Chapter 10, Chassis Accessories, Lift
            Gate.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">For 08WJA:</emph>:
        </para>
        <para>The Body Builder will be required to cut the 2 straplocks securing the power cable and route and clip the
            power cable to the lift gate motor. Then trim the power cable to length and add a lug terminal for securing
            cable to the lift gate motor. Two product graphics, from the plastic bag for Body Builders, need to be
            installed on the van body in the approximate locations shown.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">For 08WJB:</emph>:
        </para>
        <para>The Body Builder will be required to route a 0 gauge cable from the mag switch, back along the frame to
            the lift gate motor.
        </para>
        <para>Code 08WJB is identical to code 08WJA with the following exceptions:</para>
        <para>Added - 3598246C91 Cable Assy, Lift Gate Feed with "0" gauge cable and 3-10 Awg fusible links.</para>
        <para>Removed - 3592398C91 Cable Assy, Lift Gate Feed with "2" gauge cable and 2-10 Awg fusible links.</para>
        <para>Also the 3592400C93-REF "2" gauge Cable Assy, Lift Gate - 33.5 feet Ref - Cut to length is changed to "0"
            gauge cable. The Body Builder will be required to remove the "2" gauge cable from the mag switch, back along
            the frame to the lift gate motor and replace it with the "0" gauge cable.
        </para>
        <figure id="f73000c7c" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g7300091dd.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Harness Routing Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f73000c7d" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g7300091ee.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Warning Label Locations Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>The body builder or lift gate installer must bring the batteries up to a full charge before trying
                    to test the system for functionality.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With the batteries at a full charge, voltage in the 12.6 to 12.9 range, and the lift gate power
                    controlled by the Battery Protection System, the system will operate as described in the above
                    section.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Use the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software to add the following software feature:</para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595AYM for lift gate with rocker switch or 595AGN for lift gate with push
            button switch
        </para>
        <para>Software features that must be removed: 595ABT</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Hardware:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Please refer to Circuit Diagram Manual S08322, Chapter 10, Chassis Accessories, Lift Gate for circuit
            locations and routing and an International dealer for parts information.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_112.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_114.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
