<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 - Electrical - Exterior Lighting - General Procedures - Headlamp Aim Adjustment</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="3">
        <title>General Procedures - Headlamp Aim Adjustment</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the vehicle with the following conditions:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The area around the headlamps is not deformed.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The unloaded vehicle is parked on a flat level surface.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tire inflation pressure is at the specified value.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The vehicle is in a state ready for driving (with a full tank of fuel, oil level and
                    coolant).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The vehicle has been bounced several times.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To check the headlamp aiming:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Prepare a thick white paper.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Stand the paper perpendicular to the ground at a position 3 m (9.84 ft) away from the
                    headlamps.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the centerline of the vehicle is perpendicular to the paper face.</para>
                <figure id="faim1" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Draw a horizontal line (H line) on the paper, showing where the headlamps should strike
                    (at the same height from ground as the headlamp bulb center, which is marked on the headlamp lens by
                    a 2 mm by 2 mm square).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Draw a horizontal line (H LH and H RH lines) parallel to the H line but 20.9 mm (0.82
                    in) below it.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Take appropriate measures to prevent any influence of other lights.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Start the engine.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn the LOW beam headlamps ON.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On the paper, observe the portion of the light pattern that has a distinctly higher area
                    of intensity. Check that the top edge of this high intensity area is at the H RH/H LH reference line
                    and below the cross-hatched area as shown in the illustration below.
                </para>
                <figure id="faim3" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If not, adjust the lights in the vertical direction.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To adjust the headlamp aim:</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Both the inboard and outboard vertical aim screws must be turned the same amount in the same
                        direction. Do NOT turn the screws different amounts or in different directions.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not finish the aiming procedure by turning the screws in the counterclockwise screwdriver
                        direction. If you are adjusting in the counterclockwise screwdriver direction, overshoot the
                        adjustment by one full turn and then turn the screwdriver clockwise one full turn, so you finish
                        the adjustment in the clockwise direction and still line up with the vertical aiming line. This
                        applies to both screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="faim4" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0830703.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="264px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a #2 Phillips screwdriver with at least a 150 mm (6 in) long shaft.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Insert the screwdriver in the inboard aiming hole until it engages the gear at the back
                    of the headlamp. ALWAYS start with the inboard aiming screw as it is the primary vertical aiming
                    screw.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn the screwdriver in the counterclockwise direction to move the headlamp aim upward
                    or in the clockwise direction to move the headlamp aim downward, WHILE COUNTING THE NUMBER OF TURNS
                    MADE. Continue turning this screw until the vertical aim is properly adjusted, but make sure you
                    finish in the clockwise screwdriver direction. If you are adjusting in the counterclockwise
                    screwdriver direction, overshoot the adjustment by one full turn and then turn it clockwise one full
                    turn, so you finish the adjustment in the clockwise direction and still line up with the vertical
                    aiming line.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Then insert the screwdriver in the outboard aiming hole until it engages the gear at the
                    back of the headlamp.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Turn the screwdriver the same number of turns in the same direction as was done in the
                    inboard aiming hole, but make sure you finish in the clockwise screwdriver direction. If you are
                    adjusting in the counterclockwise screwdriver direction, overshoot the adjustment by one full turn
                    and then turn it clockwise one full turn, so you finish the adjustment in the clockwise direction
                    and still line up with the vertical aiming line.
                    <emph type="bold">Do NOT turn this outboard screw in a different direction or a different amount
                        than was done with the inboard aiming screw.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08307.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
