<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Remote Air Solenoid Module -
        08WEE - SWITCH, AIR HORN, PASSENGER, FIRE TRUCK
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB08WEE" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>08WEE - SWITCH, AIR HORN, PASSENGER, FIRE TRUCK</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>08WEE - SWITCH, AIR HORN, PASSENGER Fire Truck Application; Switch Located in Instrument Panel (IP) Close
            to Passenger; Driver Also To Activate Switch at Steering Wheel
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The passenger side air horn switch provides a method for an individual to activate the vehicle air horn
            from the passenger seat. The feature consists of a hard wired momentary switch that is located in the lower
            right corner of the central IP. This second rocker switch is used in conjunction with the air horn switch
            that is located in the steering wheel.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The air horn software feature code 595ALD must be enabled on the vehicle Body Controller (BC) using the
            Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software (see local dealer).
        </para>
        <para>There are no programmable parameters associated with this feature.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Both the hard wired rocker switch in the IP and the air horn switch in the steering wheel are connected to
            a single input on the BC connector 1602 Pin F8. The air solenoid is driven from the BC output connector 1602
            Pin E12.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0832377" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0832377.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Air Horn Switch Part Number 3551415C1</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING SYSTEM OPERATION</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Turn the Ignition (IGN) key to the accessory position.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Momentarily depress the air horn switch in the steering wheel. Note that the air horn sounds.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Momentarily depress the air horn rocker switch. Note that the air horn sounds.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the central IP trim piece.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832378" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0832378.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Center Panels to Remove</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate an open switch position in the lower right corner of the IP.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a switch hole punching tool to cut a hole in the plastic plate of the central IP
                plate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the storage box or 12-pack of switches located above plastic plate. Use a scribe or
                other marker tool to outline the hard wired switch openings in the steel plate located behind the
                plastic switch plate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drill a pilot hole in the center of the desired switch location.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the switch punch to open the hole in the plastic plate. The recommended method to create
                a rectangular switch slot is to use a Green Lee Punch (part number ZTSE4426 from SPX).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the air horn switch in the plastic plate.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wire the mating switch connector as Circuit Diagram Manual S08322, Chapter 4 Cab
                Accessories, Horn - Electric.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the switch connector to the air horn switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall the plastic switch plate and central IP trim piece.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832379" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0832379.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>General Circuit Diagram for Adding the Passenger Side Air Horn Switch</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB08WGA.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_109.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
