<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - FE 300 and IC Bus - OPERATION - INDICATOR AND WARNING
        LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INDICATOR AND WARNING LIGHTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OIL/WATER: FE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B, and the oil/water warning light receives
                power from fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin 5. The
                warning light illuminates when a ground path is applied to yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin
                10 by circuits A29A/35 and A97AF by the MSM1 (3111M), pin 1. The alarm will also sound at a slow rate
                when a ground path is applied by the MSM1 in response to low oil pressure, high water temperature, or
                low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28A, yellow instrument
                cluster connector (10), pin 5 to the "OIL/WATER" indicator. The "OIL/WATER" indicator is controlled by
                the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data
                link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the MSM1, circuits
                A5DMS(+) and A5DMS(-) to connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM1 connector (3111M)
                through pin 1, circuit A97AF, to pin 1 of the audible alarm connector (211). This causes the indicator
                to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OIL/WATER: FE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The alarm receives power from fuse F24 over circuit A13B, and the oil/water warning light receives
                power from fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin 5. The
                warning light illuminates when a ground path is applied to yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin
                10 by circuits A29A/35 and A97AF by the MSM1 (3111M), pin 1. The alarm will also sound at a slow rate
                when a ground path is applied by the MSM1 in response to low oil pressure, high water temperature, or
                low coolant level.
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28A, yellow instrument
                cluster connector (10), pin 5 to the "OIL/WATER" indicator. The "OIL/WATER" indicator is controlled by
                the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data
                link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the MSM1, circuits
                A5DMS(+) and A5DMS(-) to connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM1 connector (3111M)
                through pin 1, circuit A97AF, to pin 1 of the audible alarm connector (211). This causes the indicator
                to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil/Water: IC</title>
            <para>The engine ECM monitors the oil pressure, coolant temperature, and coolant level sensors, and when the
                oil pressure or coolant level drops below a programmed value or the water temperature climbs above a
                programmed value, the ECM will set its connector (379)/pin 54 to a low state (ground). This activates
                the warning alarm (20) at a slow rate by allowing current to flow from circuit 28D through the alarm
                (R1), through circuit 97AF, connector (2), circuit 97AF to the ECM (379).
            </para>
            <para>The battery voltage is through fuse F24, circuits A28/28D at the alarm is fed to the oil/water warning
                light connector (26)/pin 5. When the ECM (379) sets pin 54 to a low state (applies a ground), the
                oil/water light will illuminate and the alarm (R1) will sound at a slow rate as current flows through
                it, connector (26)/pin 10, circuits 29/35 and 97AF, connector (2), circuits 97AF.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BRAKE PRESS: FE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the hydraulic brake pressure system monitor module (86) detects a problem with the brake system,
                it applies a ground to circuit A90M, connector and blocking diode (25), and circuit A90NA to the alarm
                (211). Power will then flow from fuse F24 through circuit A13B and alarm connector (211), causing the
                alarm to sound at a fast rate. When a problem is detected, a ground is also applied by circuit A90M,
                connector (25), circuit A90N, and yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin 3 to the brake warning
                light, causing it to illuminate. The brake warning light, the battery voltage is through circuits
                A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28C, and yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin 1.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BRAKE PRESS: FE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The brake press warning light, the battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits
                A28 and A28A, and natural instrument cluster connector (10), pin 1. When the air pressure drops below 60
                psi, the pressure switch will close, and power will flow through the warning light, natural instrument
                cluster connector (10), pin 3, circuits A40A and A40, connector (2), pin A4, circuit K40 and the low air
                pressure switch (717) to ground (1LA). This will cause the brake press warning light to illuminate, and
                the warning alarm (211) to sound at a fast rate. The warning alarm receives power from fuse F24 over
                circuit A13B.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure: IC With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the hydraulic brake system monitor module (49) detects a problem with the brake system, it
                applies a ground to circuits 90S and 90T. The alarm (20) receives power from fuse F24 over circuit 28D,
                and when circuit 90S is switched to ground, the alarm will sound at a fast rate. The brake pressure
                warning light is supplied power from fuse F24, circuits 28 and 28A, and connector (26)/pin 1. When
                circuit 90T is switched to ground, power will flow through the brake pressure warning light (causing it
                to illuminate), connector (26)/pin 3, and circuit 90T to the brake monitor module (49).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure: IC With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The brake pressure warning light is fed power by fuse F24, circuits 28 and 28A, and connector (26)/pin
                1. When the air pressure drops below 60 psi, the pressure switch will close, and power will flow through
                the warning light, connector (26)/pin 3, circuits 40, 40B, and 40A, connector (2), and circuit 40
                through the low air pressure switch to ground. This will cause the brake pressure warning light to
                illuminate, and the warning alarm (20) to sound at a fast rate. The alarm receives power from fuse F24
                over circuit 28D.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>STOP ENGINE: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE OIL: FE 300</title>
            <para>The engine ECM2 is programmed to track engine hours and vehicle miles, and when the programmed values
                are achieved, the ECM2 will turn on the "CHANGE OIL" indicator. The battery voltage is through circuits
                A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28K, yellow instrument cluster connector (10), pin 4 to the "CHANGE
                OIL" indicator. The "CHANGE OIL" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2
                connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-)
                through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the MSM1 connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent
                from the MSM2 connector (3111) through pin 2, circuit A97AA, to pin 11 of the yellow instrument cluster
                connector (10). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Change Oil/Service interval light default setting is off. The customer can use the service
                        tool to activate the light and enter their own parameters into the ECM2 memory. The STI button
                        (diagnostics flash button) is used to reset the service interval reminder light.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE OIL: IC</title>
            <para>The engine ECM is programmed to track engine hours and vehicle miles, and when the programmed values
                are achieved, the ECM will apply a ground to connector (379)/pin 45, circuit 97AA, connector (2), and
                circuit 97AA to the change oil warning light connector (26)/pin 11. This will cause the change oil
                warning light, which is fed power from fuse F24 and circuits 28 and 28D through connector (26)/pin 4 to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WARN ENGINE: FE 300</title>
            <para>When the ECM2 detects a faulty sensor or circuit, it will set a fault code and turn on the "WARN
                ENGINE" indicator. The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28K, green
                instrument cluster connector (10), pin 4 to the "WARN ENGINE" indicator. The "WARN ENGINE" indicator is
                controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred
                over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the
                MSM1 connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM1 connector (3111) through pin 9,
                circuit A97T, to pin 12 of the yellow instrument cluster connector (10). This causes the indicator to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WARN ENGINE: IC</title>
            <para>When the ECM detects a faulty sensor or circuit, it will set a fault code and turn on the engine warn
                light by switching connector (379)/pin 55 to ground. This allows power to flow from fuse F24 through
                circuits 28 and 28D, connector (26)/pin 4, the engine warn light, connector (26)/pin 12, circuit 97T,
                connector (2), circuit 97T, and ECM connector (379/pin 55. This will cause the engine warn light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL: FE 300 With Anti-lock Brake System (ABS) - Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F27, circuits A13J and A94T, to the "TRAC CTRL"
                warning light, connector (1500), pin A, connector (1500), pin B, circuit A94U, connector (2), pin F6,
                circuit N94U, to the full power HCV connector (9808), pin 13. When the traction control switch (1101) is
                placed (on) position, the "TRAC CTRL" warning light to grounded through the full power HCV connector
                (9808), pin 8, circuit N94W, connector (2), pin A2, circuit A94W, the traction control switch (1101),
                circuits A94-GT and A11-G to the platform ground (1PG). The ABS module (ECU) (279) will enable the
                traction control mode and when the wheel sensors sense wheel slip, the module will apply 12 volts to the
                modulator valve for the brake to apply to the wheel that is slipping.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL: FE 300 With WTEC or Allison 2000 ICT Anti-lock Brake System (ABS) - Air Brakes</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13C, fuse F27, circuits A13J and A94BT/A94DT, to the
                traction control switch (1101) and is placed (on) position, circuit N94FT, connector (2), pin A7,
                circuit N94FT, to the ABS module (ECU) connector (288), pin F2. Also, the battery voltage is to circuits
                A94BT/A94GT, to the "TRAC CTRL" warning light, connector (3127), pin B, connector (3127), pin A, circuit
                A94CT, connector (2), pin A5, circuit N94CT, to the ABS module (ECU) connector (288), pin C2. The "TRAC
                CTRL" warning light and the traction control switch are grounded through the coil of the ABS power relay
                (283), circuits A94-GB and A11-GB to the platform ground (4PG). The ABS module (ECU) (288) will enable
                the traction control mode and when the wheel sensors sense wheel slip, the module will apply 12 volts to
                the modulator valve for the brake to apply to the wheel that is slipping.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL: IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III system, it will apply a ground to circuit K115 at connector (7204), pin 31. The battery voltage
                is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster connector
                (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector (377),
                circuit A115, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (523), circuit K115, and ECU connector (7204),
                pin 31, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III GEN 4 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to circuit K129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery
                voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster
                connector (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector
                (377), circuit A115, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (523), circuit K129, and ECU connector
                (7150), pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III system, it will apply a ground to circuit K115 at connector (7204), pin 31. The battery voltage
                is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster connector
                (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector (377),
                circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (523), circuit K115, and ECU connector (7204),
                pin 31, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III GEN 4 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                WTEC III GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to K129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery voltage
                is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster connector
                (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector (377),
                circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (523), circuit K129, and ECU connector (7150),
                pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison 2000 (LCT)</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                2000 (LCT) system, it will apply a ground to circuit K125 at connector (7305), pin 25. The battery
                voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster
                connector (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector
                (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N125, connector (9875), circuit K125, and ECU connector
                (7305), pin 25, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: FE 300 With Allison 1000/2000 GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                1000/2000 GEN 4 system, it will apply a ground to circuit K129 at connector (7150), pin 29. The battery
                voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A28A, and yellow instrument cluster
                connector (10), pin 2, the "CHECK TRANS" warning light, connector (10), pin 1, circuit A125, connector
                (377), circuit A125, connector (644), circuit N129, connector (9875), circuit K129, and ECU connector
                (7150), pin 29, to ground. This will cause the "CHECK TRANS" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS: IC With Allison MD</title>
            <para>When the Allison ECU detects that the transmission is overheating or that there is a problem with the
                Allison MD system, it will apply a ground to circuit 115 at connector (634)/pin 31. This will allow
                power to flow through fuse F24, circuits 28 and 28A, connector (26)/pin 1, the Check Trans. warning
                light, connector (26)/pin 2, circuit 92A, connector (377), circuit 115, connector (418), circuit 115,
                and ECU connector (634)/pin 31 to ground. This will cause the Check Transmission warning light to
                illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN: FE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the left turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and violet wire, connector (13)/pin D, circuits A56 and A56B to the left turn indicator connector
                (11)/pin 6. This will cause the left turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits
                A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN: FE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the left turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and yellow wire, connector (13)/pin E, circuits A56 and A56B to the left turn indicator connector
                (11)/pin 6. This will cause the left turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits
                A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN: IC With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column and Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the left turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and orange wire, connector (193) pin D, circuits 56, 56S, and 56C to the left turn indicator
                connector (27)/pin 6. This will cause the left turn indicator, grounded through connector (27)/pin 2 and
                circuits 28-GA and 11-G to cab ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn signal
                lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: FE 300 With WTEC or Allison 2000 ICT Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the air anti-lock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will set
                connector (288), pin E3, low (to ground). The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13C, fuse F27,
                circuits A13J connector (168) and A13E/A13K, the coil of the warning light relay (284), circuit A94B,
                connector (297), circuit A94E, A94H, connector (451), and a gray wire to the ABS module (288),pin E3.
                This energizes the warning light relay (284), and allows power to flow through fuse (F27), circuits A28,
                A94B, the anti-lock brake warning light (297), circuit A94E, the warning light relay (284). This will
                cause the warning light (297), which is grounded through circuit A94E, normally open contacts of the
                warning light relay (284), circuits A94-GA and A11-GB to platform ground (4PG), to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: FE300 With Hydraulic Brakes GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the hydraulic anti-lock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will
                set connector (279), pin 1, low (to ground). The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13C, fuse F27,
                circuits A94D, the coil of the warning light relay (R1), circuit A94H, connector (2), circuit K94H,
                connector (261), circuit A94H, and a gray wire to the ABS module (279), pin 7. This energizes the
                warning light relay (R1), and allows power to flow through fuse (F22), circuits A28, A94B, the anti-lock
                brake warning light (422), circuit A94E, the warning light relay (R1), circuit A94H, connector (2),
                circuit K94A, to the hydraulic ABS module (279), pin 1. This will cause the warning light (422), which
                is grounded through circuit A94E, normally open contacts of the warning light relay (R1), circuits
                A94-GB and A11-G to platform ground (4PG), to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: IC Air Brakes</title>
            <para>When the antilock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will set
                connector (288)/pin E3 low (to ground). This will allow power to flow from fuse F24 through circuits 28,
                94D, the coil of the warning light relay (R4), circuit 94H, connector (2), and a gray wire to the ABS
                module (288)/pin E3. This energizes the warning light relay (R4), and allows power to flow through fuse
                F24, circuits 94F, connector (422), and the antilock brake warning light. This will cause the warning
                light, which is grounded through circuit 94E, normally open contacts of the warning light relay (R4),
                circuits 94-GC and 11-G to cab ground, to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE: IC Hyd Brakes</title>
            <para>When the antilock brake control module performs a bulb check or logs a fault code, it will set
                connector (279)/pin 1 low (to ground). This will allow power to flow from fuse F24 through circuits 28,
                94D, the coil of the warning light relay (R4), circuit 94H, connector (2), and a gray wire to the ABS
                module (279)/pin 1. This energizes the warning light relay (R4), and allows power to flow through fuse
                F24, circuits 94F, connector (422), and the antilock brake warning light. This will cause the warning
                light, which is grounded through circuit 94E, normally open contacts of the warning light relay (R4),
                circuits 94-GC and 11-G to cab ground, to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HI BEAM: FE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is moved to the on position and the dimmer switch (4) is placed in the
                high beam position, power will flow through circuit A51, dimmer switch connector (4), a green wire, the
                switch contacts, a brown wire, connector (4), circuits A52 and A52A, and the high beam indicator lamp
                and connector (11)/pin 4. Thus the lamp, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits A28-G and
                A11-G to platform ground (1PG), will illuminate, indicating that the headlights are on and the dimmer
                switch is in the high beam position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HI BEAM: FE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is moved to the on position and the dimmer switch (6) is placed in the
                high beam position, power will flow through circuit A51, circuit A51A, the normally closed contacts of
                lift-to-dim headlight relay (100), circuits A52C and A52A, and the high beam indicator lamp and
                connector (11)/pin 4. Thus the lamp, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2 and circuits A28-G and A11-G
                to platform ground (1PG), will illuminate, indicating that the headlights are on and the dimmer switch
                is in the high beam position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HI BEAM: IC With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the headlight switch (23) is moved to the on position and the dimmer switch (6) is placed in the
                high beam position, power will flow through circuit 51, circuit 51A, the normally closed contacts of
                lift-to-dim headlight relay (100), circuits 52C and 52A, and the high beam indicator lamp and connector
                (27)/pin 4. Thus the lamp, grounded through connector ((27)/pin 2 and circuits 28-G and 11-G to platform
                ground (1PG), will illuminate, indicating that the headlights are on and the dimmer switch is in the
                high beam position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN: FE 300 With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the right turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and orange/red wire, connector (13)/pin F, circuits A57 and A57B to the right turn indicator
                connector (11)/pin 12. This will cause the right turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2
                and circuits A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks
                the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN: FE 300 With Douglas Turn Signal Switch (Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the right turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and light blue wire, connector (13)/pin F, circuits A57 and A57B to the right turn indicator
                connector (11)/pin 12. This will cause the right turn indicator, grounded through connector (11)/pin 2
                and circuits A28-G and A11-G to (1PG) platform ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks
                the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN: IC With International Turn Signal Switch (Stationary Column and Tilt Column)</title>
            <para>When the turn signal switch is placed in the right turn position, power flows through the turn signal
                switch and blue wire, connector (193)/pin F, circuits 57, 57S, and 57C to the right turn indicator
                connector (27)/pin 12. This will cause the right turn indicator, grounded through connector (27)/pin 2
                and circuits 28-GA and 11-G to cab ground, to illuminate as the turn signal flasher blinks the turn
                signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WAIT-TO-START: FE 300</title>
            <para>When the key switch is initially moved to the ignition position, the engine controller ECM2 (6020)
                will activate the glow plugs and the "WAIT-TO-START" indicator. The battery voltage is through circuits
                A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28/A28C, natural instrument cluster connector (12), pin 8 to the
                "WAIT-TO-START" indicator. The "WAIT-TO-START" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control
                from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and
                K5AA(-) through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the MSM1 connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground
                is sent from the MSM1 connector (3111) through pin 10, circuit A97AE, to pin 5 of the natural instrument
                cluster connector (12). This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WAIT-TO-START: IC With International T 444E Engine</title>
            <para>When the key switch is initially moved to the ignition position on vehicles equipped with T 444E
                engines, the engine controller (379) will activate the glow plugs and apply a ground to pin 53. This
                will illuminate the wait to start warning light, which is fed battery power through connector (28)/pin
                8, as a ground is applied to the light by connector (28) pin 5, circuit 18-G, connector (2), circuit
                18-G, and ECM and connector (379) pin 53.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PDL: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE: FE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C
                and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8. When the parking brake is applied,
                power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17, circuits A44A and K44A, the park
                brake switch (218), and circuits K44-G and K11-GD to start motor ground. This will cause the park brake
                warning light to illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is applied. The lamp will also illuminate
                when the key switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied through circuit A44, a
                brake diode (82), and circuit A90X, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE: FE 300 With Air Brakes</title>
            <para>Power is fed by the battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22 to circuits A28 and A28C
                and the "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light and connector (12)/pin 8. When the parking brake is applied,
                power will flow through the warning light and connector (12)/pin 17, circuits A44 to the park brake
                switch (218), and circuits A44GA to platform ground. This will cause the park brake warning light to
                illuminate, indicating that the parking brake is applied. The lamp will also illuminate when the key
                switch (20) is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied through circuit A44GB, a brake diode
                (64), and circuit A44, performing a bulb check.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE: IC With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>Power is applied by fuse 24 to circuits 28 and 28C and the park brake warning light and connector
                (28)/pin 8. When the parking brake is applied, power will flow through the warning light and connector
                (28)/pin 17, circuits 44 and 44A, connector (214), a black wire, connector (218), the park brake switch,
                connector (218), a white wire, connector (214), and circuit 44-G to ground. This will cause the park
                brake warning light to illuminate, indicating that the park brake is applied. With US and Canadian DRL,
                additional circuitry is connected between connector (214). The lamp will also illuminate when the key
                switch is moved to the start position, and a ground is applied through circuit 44A or 44B, performing a
                bulb check.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) LOW AIR: FE 300</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) LOW AIR: IC</title>
            <para>The "((P))"ark brake "LOW AIR" warning light is fed power by fuse F24, circuits 28 and 28C, and
                connector (28)/pin 8. When the air pressure drops below 60 psi, the pressure switch will close, and
                power will flow through the warning light, connector (28)/pin 9, circuits 40D, connector (1151), and
                circuit 40D through the low air pressure switch to ground. This will cause the "((P))"ark brake "LOW
                AIR" warning light to illuminate, and the warning alarm (3098) to sound at a fast rate. The alarm
                receives power from fuse F20 over circuit 40.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WINDSHIELD WASHER FLUID: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FRONT AXLE: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DIFF. LOCK ENGAGED: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SUSP LOW AIR: FE 300 AND IC With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: FE 300</title>
            <para>The I6 engine ECM2 will turn on the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light. The battery voltage is through
                circuits A13/A13A, fuse F20, circuits A97AC/A97AB, to the MSM1 connector (3111) pin 7 and to the WIF
                connector (3116), pin G, circuit A19K, to the WIF connector (3116), pin C, circuit A19-G, to the
                "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light (9), pin B. The "WATER-IN-FUEL" indicator is controlled by the ECM2
                (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins 12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on
                circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins A and C of connector (3084K), to the MSM1 connector (3111)
                pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM2 connector (3111) through pin 3, circuit A19-GD, to the WIF
                connector (3116), pin H, circuit A19F, to the WIF connector (3116), pin B, to the "WATER-IN-FUEL"
                warning light (9), pin A, thus causing the "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL: IC</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the ignition or start position, the water-in-fuel module receives power at
                connector (470)/pin A from fuse F22, circuit 13A, connector (3), and circuits 13A and 19A. When the key
                switch is moved to the start position, a ground is applied to circuit 19A, connector (1150), circuit
                19C, connector (2), circuit 19C, going to the water-in-fuel module (470)/pin C. This initiates a bulb
                check by causing the module to apply power to connector (470)/pin B, circuit 19B, connector (2), circuit
                19B, connector (1150), circuit 19B, and the water-in-fuel warning light and connector (433). This causes
                the warning light, grounded through connector (433) and circuit 19-G to cab ground, to illuminate. When
                water is detected in the fuel filter by the water probe, a ground path is completed to the water-in-fuel
                module (470)/pin D by circuit 19E, connector (401), circuit 19C, thus causing the water-in-fuel warning
                light to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL FILTER: FE 300</title>
            <para>When the fuel filter becomes restricted, the contacts of the fuel filter vacuum switch will close and
                the ECM2 will turn on the "FUEL FILTER" indicator. The battery voltage is through circuits A28/A19J,
                fuse F22, circuits A19J, to the "FUEL FILTER" warning light (69), pin A, in the instrument cluster. The
                "FUEL FILTER" indicator is controlled by the ECM2 (6020). The control from ECM2 connector (6020), pins
                12 and 13, is transferred over the data link on circuits K5AA(+) and K5AA(-) through pins A and C of
                connector (3084K), to the MSM1 connector (3111) pins 5 and 6. A ground is sent from the MSM2 connector
                (3111) through pin 1, circuit A19K, to the "FUEL FILTER" warning light (69), pin B, in the instrument
                cluster. This causes the indicator to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL FILTER: IC</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the on or start position, power is applied to fuse F24, circuits 28/19F,
                connector (1150), and circuit 19F to the fuel filter warning light (434). When the fuel filter becomes
                restricted, the contacts of the fuel filter vacuum switch will close and the fuel filter warning light
                will illuminate as a ground path is applied through circuit 19D, connector (1150), circuit 19D,
                connector (2), circuit 19D, connector (401), and circuit 19B to the switch and chassis ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>PTO: FE 300 AND IC</title>
            <para>Refer to information provided by body builder.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LOW BRAKE FLUID: FE 300 With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the on or start position, battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse
                F22, circuits A28 and A90R to the "LOW BRAKE FLUID" warning light (89-A). With the key switch held in
                the start position, the low brake fluid warning light will illuminate (bulb check is performed) as a
                ground is applied through circuits A90V and A90W, brake diode assy (82), and circuit A44-G (also A31-GD
                with pall transmission filter) to the key switch ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LOW BRAKE FLUID: IC With Hydraulic Brakes</title>
            <para>With the key switch in the on or start position, power is applied to fuse F19, and circuits 13E and
                90U to the low brake fluid warning light. With the key switch held in the start position, the low brake
                fluid warning light will illuminate (bulb check is performed) as a ground is applied through circuits
                90U and 90E, blocking diode (47), and circuit 90-G/11-G to the cab ground.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD ON: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>When the key switch is in the ignition or start position, power from fuse F1C-1 flows through circuit
                V146A, connector (7101), pin U, circuit K146A, to the ECU "S" connector (7204), pin 4, and the spliced
                circuit V146A/V146D, to the retard on warning light relay connector (7807), pin 1. When the retard on
                on/off switch (919) is moved to the on position, the switch (919), pin 1, circuit A163A, connector
                (644), pin F, circuit N163A, connector (523), pin L, circuit K163A, spliced circuit K163, to the ECU "S"
                connector (7204), pin 27, and through the switch (919), pin 2, circuit A143H, connector (644), pin H,
                circuit N143H, spliced circuit N143A, connector (523), pin J, circuit K143A, to the ECU "S" connector
                (7204), pin 32, and the retarder enable function is completed. The retarder warning light relay circuit
                V146B to its coil and circuit V146D to its contacts, will become de-energized when the ECU removes its
                ground to circuit K125 at connector (7202), pin 18, through spliced circuit K125A, connector (7101), pin
                Q, circuit V125A, relay (7807), pin 5. This will allow power to flow through the contacts of the
                de-energized warning light relay (7807), circuit V92H, connector (7100), pin L, circuit K92H, connector
                (523), pin V, circuit N92H, connector (1601), pin A and circuit A92H to the "RETARD ON" warning light
                (926), pin A. This will cause the warning light (926), pin B, which is grounded through circuits
                A92-GA/A186, connector (377), pin A, circuits A186/A11-G to the platform ground (1PG), to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD ON: IC With Allison MD and International Engines</title>
            <para>When the key switch is in the ignition or start position, power from fuse F24 flows through circuit
                97K, connector (3), circuits 97K and 24B, connector (372), circuit 24B, connector (789), circuit 24B,
                and the retarder enable relay coil (790). When the retarder on/off switch (917) is moved to the on
                position, a ground is applied to ECM connector (379)/pin 15 by circuit 24, connector (3), circuit 24,
                connector (377), circuit 24, connector (377), circuit 24V, switch (917), circuits 92-G, 92-GY, 94-GC,
                connector (377), and circuits 94-GC and 11-G to cab ground. This causes the ECM (379) to switch pin 47
                low (to apply a ground), and power to flow through the enable relay coil and circuit 24A, connector
                (789), circuit 24A, connector (372), circuit 24A, and the ECM at connector (379)/pin 47. This will
                activate the retarder enable relay, and complete a ground circuit from connector (632)/pin 31, circuits
                161 and 161D, the relay's normally open contacts, and circuit 163 to ECU connector (634)/pin 27. The
                retarder warning light relay (791), which receives power from fuse F24 through the same circuits as the
                retarder enable relay (790) [listed above] and circuit 146H to its coil and also circuit 146F to its
                contacts, will become de-energized when the ECU removes its ground to circuit 125 at connector (632)/pin
                18. This will allow power to flow through the contacts of the de-energized warning light relay (791),
                circuit 92H, connector (499), and circuit 92H to the retarder on warning light. This will cause the
                warning light, which is grounded through circuits 92-GZ, 92-GY, and 94-GC, connector (337), and circuits
                94-GC and 11-G to cab ground, to illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE TRANS FILTER: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with the automatic transmission filter warning light, power is supplied to fuse
                F10, circuit A31D, and the filter warning light (94). When the key switch (20) is held in the start
                position, power will flow through the filter warning light (94), circuit A31-GA, connector (344), a blue
                wire, and the pigtail of the filter pressure differential switch. This power will flow through the
                normally closed contacts of the pressure switch and its connector, a green wire, connector (344),
                circuit A31-GB, blocking diode (64), circuits A31-GC and A31-GD, and the key switch ground, thus causing
                the warning light to illuminate for a bulb check. When the transmission filter becomes restricted, the
                pressure differential switch's normally open contacts will close and power will flow through the warning
                light to the switch as above, but the power will flow through the normally open contacts of the switch
                and its connector, a brown wire, connector (344) and circuit A11-GE to platform ground, thus
                illuminating the change trans filter warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE TRANS FILTER: IC With Allison "AT"</title>
            <para>For vehicles equipped with the automatic transmission filter warning light, power is supplied to fuse
                F24, circuits 28/19F, connector (1150), 31B and the filter warning light (837). When the key switch (63)
                is held in the start position, power will flow through the filter warning light (837), circuit 31-GA,
                connector (760A), a blue wire, and the pigtail of the filter pressure differential switch. This power
                will flow through the normally closed contacts of the pressure switch and its connector, a green wire,
                connector (760B), circuit 31-GA, blocking diode (47), circuits 31D, and the key switch ground, thus
                causing the warning light to illuminate for a bulb check. When the transmission filter becomes
                restricted, the pressure differential switch's normally open contacts will close and power will flow
                through the warning light to the switch as above, but the power will flow through the normally open
                contacts of the switch and its connector, a brown wire, connector (760B) and circuit 31-G to cab ground,
                thus illuminating the change trans filter warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A13J, connector (377),
                pin F, circuit A13J, to the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light, connector (925), pin B, connector (925),
                pin A, circuit A105B, connector (1601), pin B, circuit N105B, connector (523), pin U, circuit
                K105B/K105, to the ECU connector (7202), pin 19. When the transmission ECU detects that the transmission
                retarder is overheating, it will apply a ground (switch to low state) to illuminate the "RETARD OVER
                HEAT" warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT: FE 300 With Allison WTEC III XMSN GEN 4</title>
            <para>The battery voltage is through circuits A13/A13F, fuse F22, circuits A28 and A13J, connector (377),
                pin F, circuit A13J, to the "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light, connector (925), pin B, connector (925),
                pin A, circuit A164B, connector (1601), pin B, circuit N164B, connector (523), pin U, circuit
                K164B/K164, to the TCM connector (7150), pin 64. When the transmission TCM detects that the transmission
                retarder is overheating, it will apply a ground (switch to low state) to illuminate the "RETARD OVER
                HEAT" warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT: IC With Allison MD</title>
            <para>When the transmission ECU detects that the transmission retarder is overheating, it will apply a
                ground (switch to low state) to (632)/pin 19 and circuit 105, connector (499), circuit 105 and the
                retarder overheat warning light. Thus the light that receives power from the key switch (63), circuit
                13E, connector (377), circuit 13E, will illuminate.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ALTERNATOR: FE 300</title>
            <para>When the voltage output of the alternator is low, a ground will be provided on terminal (G) of the
                alternator, and through the I6 circuit filters. This ground will be present on circuit A26 to pin 16, of
                the yellow instrument cluster connector (10) and will cause the "ALTERNATOR" warning light, to
                illuminate. The battery voltage is through circuit A26A, the yellow instrument cluster (10), pin 7 to
                the alternator warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ALTERNATOR: IC</title>
            <para>SE item not covered at this time.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
