<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - General Electrical - How Do I -
        General Information
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BBHDI" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>How Do I - General Information</title>
        <para>The International parts system is set up to give part information that is specific to a particular vehicle
            as built, including all optional features that were ordered. If a feature is to be added after the vehicle
            was built, provide the dealer with the vehicle VIN number and the feature code to be added. The dealer will
            contact "Parts Spec" to obtain a listing of parts required for that feature.
        </para>
        <para>The circuits provided for the feature will be what are referred to as "overlay circuits" and are to be
            layered on and taped to existing harnesses. In some cases, a total harness may be provided. The harness may
            include standard wiring circuits.
        </para>
        <para>The body builder will have to refer to the circuit diagram book for connector cavity information. If the
            decision is made to build the overlays locally, part numbers of the terminals can be found in the back of
            the circuit diagram manual S08322 (Connector Composites section).
        </para>
        <para>All hardware associated with a specific feature code, switches, brackets, etc. will be provided. The body
            builder must decide which parts are to be ordered - it is not required that all parts for a code be ordered.
            Generally, except for a few features, there are no "kits" available, hence, detailed instructions are not
            provided, and this section will cover some basic direction.
        </para>
        <para>If a feature is not available on a specific model, a parts list will not be provided.</para>
        <para>Some features will require reprogramming of the BC. If reprogramming is required, the vehicle must be
            returned to the dealer.
        </para>
        <para>If the body builder adds a feature, they must assume full responsibility for proper operation of that
            feature.
        </para>
        <para>International parts purchased from a dealer carry a one-year, unlimited mileage warranty. Other than the
            one year parts warranty, International assumes no warranty for body builder installed components or the
            labor to repair the body builder added feature if it is determined that the failure is not OEM related.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
