<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Gauges</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Gauges</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This chapter describes the optional gauges that are either installed or can be installed in the
                instrument cluster. If the vehicle was ordered without a desired gauge, one or more can be added in the
                field. Programming of the Body Controller (BC) and proper placement is critical. Certain gauges will
                only work in certain locations. Before adding the gauge to the vehicle, ensure that the vehicle can
                accept it. The outboard four gauges are the only ones that can be moved or added. They can be added by
                using the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software. Follow the steps below for adding a gauge to the cluster
                (those without Diamond Logic&#174; Builder should see an International dealer). The following
                instructions can be followed for any of the four auxiliary gauge positions.
            </para>
            <para>Adding and programming the vehicle:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Using Diamond Logic&#174; Builder, obtain a copy of the electronic vehicle file either by
                        getting it from the vehicle or from history.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Select the proper software feature code for the gauge to be added, and add this code to the
                        configuration.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Position the gauge in the desired location in the cluster by clicking and dragging it to an
                        open location identified by a large blue circle. If the gauge will not move to a particular
                        position, it is not designed to work in that location.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Once the location of the gauge is determined, save the configuration and program the
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>INSTALLING THE GAUGE:</title>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the "How Do I - General Information" section of this electrical guide for information
                        on how to obtain gauge, circuits, and sensor part numbers.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the cluster shroud from the Instrument Panel (IP).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the four screws which hold the cluster in place.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tilt the cluster forward to gain access to the back of the cluster (use caution not to scratch
                        the face of the cluster).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove all the connectors from the back of the cluster, and remove the cluster from the
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the ten screws from the metal panel on the back of the cluster.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Remove the proper filler plug. See below.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the gauge using caution not to move the needle, damage the face, or get the face of
                        the gauge dirty.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect the jumper wire in the socket directly next to the added gauge.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Replace the metal panel, and install in the vehicle in the reverse order of removing it.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0832301" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption></caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The standard cluster includes:</para>
            <para>ODOMETER DISPLAY: Miles, Trip Miles, Engine Hours, Trip Hours, Fault Code Readout (Odometer, trip
                odometer, and fault code readout electronic-liquid crystal display)
            </para>
            <para>WARNING SYSTEM: Low Fuel, Low Oil Pressure, High Engine Coolant Temp, and Low Battery Voltage (Visual
                and Audible)
            </para>
            <para>GAUGE CLUSTER GAUGES (6): Engine Oil Pressure (Electronic), Water Temperature (Electronic), Fuel
                (Electronic), Tachometer (Electronic), Voltmeter, Speedometer
            </para>
            <para>GAUGE, AIR PRESSURE: Air 1 and Air 2 Gauges; Located in Instrument Cluster (Air Chassis only)</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Use the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software to steer each gauge to test values.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB13AHE.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB04SBL.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
