<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        Remote Throttle - 60AJG - Remote Throttle Control Programmable Mode for Various Switch Actions
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB60AJG" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>60AJG - Remote Throttle Control Programmable Mode for Various Switch Actions</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
            BDY INTG, THROTTLE CONTROL Accommodation for Single Customer Mounted External Engine Speed Control Switch,
            for Utility Applications, Programmable Mode for Various Switch Actions and Engine Speed Control Option, Only
            with Vehicle Stopped and Park Brake is Applied (requires 1 Remote Power Module input)
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
            This feature provides the operator of
            <emph type="bold">Utility applications</emph>
            with external control of the engine speed with a customer-mounted switch. Activation of a customer-installed
            switch increases the engine speed to the first preset value. This feature utilizes one pin on the Black
            23-pin Remote Power Module input connector (Use ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software to
            determine correct pin location). The ESC reads the voltage on this input pin and communicates the correct
            action to the Engine Control Module. Use customer supplied single pull, double throw, center stable,
            momentary switch. This code is offered to add additional functionality and to provide a simpler alternative
            to the hardwired Remote Engine Speed Controls offered by 12VVW or 12VYC. All remote throttle switches and
            associated wiring should be customer supplied. Feature code 12VXU is required to program the engine for the
            desired mode of engine speed control. This option is only useable when Vehicle Speed is 0 Mph and Park Brake
            is applied.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">60AJG Default Switch Action:</emph>
            Applying momentary ground to the Remote Power Module ramps engine to first preset speed. Applying momentary
            ground a second time returns engine to idle.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595240</para>
        <para>Software feature codes that must be removed: 595241, 595172, 595196, 595263</para>
        <table id="t7300090">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Ext_ Eng_Speed_ Control_ Mode</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2035</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This parameter sets the mode of operation for the TEM External Engine Speed Control
                                feature.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Ext_ Eng_Spd_ Ctrl_Active_ State</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2158</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This is the active state for the external engine speed control switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>List</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>The engine speed control will only operate when the vehicle is stopped with the park brake applied and the
            transmission in neutral. The increased engine speed will be cancelled if any of these conditions are not met
            or if:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The cruise disable switch is depressed</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The brake pedal is depressed</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The clutch is depressed (if present)</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Control_Mode</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This parameter controls the mode in which the engine speed control feature operates. The setting of this
            parameter depends upon the type of switch that will be controlling the engine speed and the speed control
            action that is desired. The mode is described in terms of what the engine will do based on what state is on
            the Remote Power Module Input. The valid states on an RPM input are:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Ground - The input is connected to ground through a switch</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Floating - The input is not connected to anything</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>12 Volts - The input is connected to 12 Volts through a switch</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <table id="t7300091">
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.29*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.99*"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.74*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Setting</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Mode Explanation</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Diagram</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>In this mode, the feature will be expecting a momentary (not latched) type switch.
                                When the switch is depressed and released, the engine will ramp to engine preset 1. When
                                the switch is depressed and released again, the engine will return to idle. There are
                                two different connection diagrams shown for the two possible active states of the input.
                                The selecting of the active state is done with the active state parameter explained
                                below.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <graphic filename="../figg73/g73000ba.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Ctrl_PTO_Ilock</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This parameter can only be used on vehicles that have an International PTO feature.</para>
        <para>If this parameter is set, the remote engine speed control will be interlocked to PTO. This means that the
            remote engine speed control will only be allowed to operate if the PTO is being requested to engage. If this
            parameter is not set, the engine speed control will operate regardless of the PTO request.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Ctrl_Active_State</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This parameter tells the engine control feature what state to look for on the remote power module input.
            This parameter setting is only used when TEM_Ext_Eng_Spd_Control_Mode is set to 2, or 3. The valid settings
            for this parameter are:
        </para>
        <table id="t7300092">
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1" align="center" colwidth="0.31*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.69*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Setting</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Active State</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Floating (the plunger provides a floating input to the remote power module when
                                depressed. This setting is not recommended)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground (the plunger provides a ground to the remote power module input when
                                depressed)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>12 Volts (the plunger provides 12 Volts to the remote power module input when
                                depressed)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Customer provides a ground active momentary switch that is wired into the pin labeled
                    Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input on the Black 23-pin input connector on the Remote Power Module (See
                    ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software for correct pin location).
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f73000bb" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g73000bb.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="502px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Activate the Remote Engine Speed Control Switch (Close switch to active input condition that
                has been programmed; i.e., 12 volts or Ground).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the Remote Power Module Input labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input (Pin position
                specified by ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software is receiving Ground as long as the switch
                is closed).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the engine ramps to the first preset speed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If engine does not ramp to the first preset speed, check engine programming to verify that
                the correct engine speed control parameters are set.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deactivate the Remote Engine Speed Control switch (Release Ground).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify the Remote Power Module Input labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input (Pin position
                specified by ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software) is an open circuit.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the engine returns to idle.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Select software feature code 595240 using ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software (See
                    Local Dealer)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Using ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software, make sure that software feature codes
                    595241, 595172, 595196, and 595263 are removed from the vehicle (See Local Dealer)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software to determine which pin on the Black 23-pin
                    Remote Power Module input connector has been assigned to Remote Engine Speed Control
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Customer must install a remote-mounted switch to control Engine Speed and a wire that runs from
                    the switch to the pin labeled Remote_Engine_Speed_Sw_Input on the Remote Power Module input
                    connector.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB60AJE.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB60AJH.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
