<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcman mantype="truck" id="S08300" date="October 2005" formnum="PBB-73000B"/>
    <title>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007</title>
    <manapply>
        <truckmodelgroup/>

        <truckmodel>3200
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>4100
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>4200
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>4300
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>4400
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>7300
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>7400
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>7500
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>7600
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>7700
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>8500
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
        <truckmodel>8600
            <daterange>
                <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                <enddate>02/28/2007</enddate>
            </daterange>
        </truckmodel>
    </manapply>
    <foreword>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Contents</emph>
            - In this manual, International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation provides information about its different
            products to assist those who wish to modify these products for individual applications. International does
            not recommend or approve any firm nor make any judgements on the quality of the work performed by a
            particular firm. Individuals who use the services of a body builder must satisfy themselves as to the
            quality of the work.
        </para>
        <para>The party installing a body, a fifth wheel, any other equipment, or making any modifications to complete
            the vehicle for delivery and make it road-ready is responsible to see that the completed vehicle complies
            with all applicable certification procedures and safety standards, as may be set forth in Federal, State,
            and local statutes, rules and regulations.
        </para>
        <para>Specifications, descriptions and illustrative material in this literature are as accurate as known at time
            of publication but are subject to change without notice. Illustrations are not always to scale and may
            include optional equipment and accessories but may not include all standard equipment.
        </para>
        <para>In addition to this Body Builder Electrical Data Book, publication CT-471, Body Builder Data, may be
            required. The CT-471 - Body Builder Data is a set of booklets which includes a General Information Body
            Builder Data booklet for information about the International&#174; Truck and Engine product line; model
            series Body Builder Data booklets which contain information related to the features and specifications for
            each of their respective models; Component Body Builder Data booklet containing information for components
            which have common application in two or more truck series and any supplemental Body Builder Data booklets
            containing information for components which have common application in two or more truck series.
        </para>
    </foreword>
    <introduction>
        <geninfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DISCLAIMER:</emph>
                INTERNATIONAL DOES NOT TAKE ANY RESPONSIBILITY FOR CUSTOMER OR BODY BUILDER WIRING.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After-market installed wiring for engine speed control must comply with the following
                        guidelines:
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Sealed switches and connectors must be used for switches and connections that are exposed to
                        the weather or to salt spray emanating from the vehicle's tires.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Route and clip wiring to minimize chafing and exposure to weather. Use conduit, loom, and/or
                        tape to achieve this.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuse all power leads as close to the power source as possible. Remember fuses protect the
                        wiring - size fuses accordingly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All ground connections that will be made to the frame or body must be connected to clean bare
                        metal. Remove all dirt, paint, grease and rust that would insulate the terminal from ground.
                        After connecting the ground, seal the connection with a good quality grease or surface sealant
                        to protect the connection from corrosion.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Spliced wires should be twisted together and soldered. Use a heat shrink tube with a meltable
                        inner wall to seal the connection. Do not expose splices to the weather.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the vehicle, make sure the
                        transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set, and the wheels are blocked before undertaking
                        service procedures. In addition, turn off the engine when you leave the vehicle. Never leave the
                        vehicle unattended with the engine running.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, possible death, or damage to the vehicle when adding electrical
                        features, disconnect batteries. Reconnect batteries when installation is complete.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Whenever disconnecting battery terminals, always disconnect the ground terminal first.
                                When reconnecting, always connect the ground terminal last.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>To prevent injury to the eyes, face, limbs and body, it is imperative that lighted
                                materials, flames or sparks be kept away from the vent openings of the battery. The gas
                                mixture in the battery cells, which escapes through the vents, could ignite and/or cause
                                an explosion. This is particularly true when jumper cables are being used.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>In addition, inhaling of gas produced by the normal operation of the battery could
                                result in partial or permanent damage to the respiratory system.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Always wear eye protection when working around batteries. Do not attempt to jump-start
                                a vehicle having a frozen battery because the battery may explode. If a frozen battery
                                is suspected, examine all fill vents on the battery. If ice can be seen, do not attempt
                                to start with jumper cables as long as the battery remains frozen. Thaw out the battery
                                and recharge.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not check battery condition by shorting (flashing) across terminals.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Failure to observe these instructions could result in personal injury and/or damage to
                                the vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Battery cable terminals must be clean and tight. Use hot water and common baking soda for removing
                terminal corrosion and for cleaning the top of the battery. Brighten the contact surface with steel
                wool, apply a light coat of lubricant sealing grease such as Fleetrite &#174; 472141-C1 or equivalent
                and reassemble. Be sure the terminals are clamped tightly and that the battery is clamped securely in
                place.
            </para>
            <para>When working around the terminals and battery, use extra care to avoid shorting. A good practice is to
                insulate pliers and screwdrivers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Contents</emph>
                - In this Body Builder Electrical Data Book, International&#174; Truck and Engine Corporation provides
                information about its different electrical features to assist those who wish to modify these products
                for individual applications. This information is intended for use by properly trained, professional
                technicians who have the equipment, tools, safety instructions, and know-how to perform the
                modifications properly and safely. International does not recommend or approve any firm nor make any
                judgements on the quality of the work performed by a particular firm. Individuals who use the services
                of a body builder must satisfy themselves as to the quality of the work.
            </para>
            <para>The party installing a body, a fifth wheel, any other equipment, or making any modifications to
                complete the vehicle for delivery and make it road-ready is responsible to see that the completed
                vehicle complies with all applicable certification procedures and safety standards, as may be set forth
                in Federal, State, and local statues, rules and regulations.
            </para>
            <para>Specifications, descriptions and illustrative material in this literature are as accurate as known at
                time of publication but are subject to change without notice. Illustrations are not always to scale and
                may include optional equipment and accessories but may not include all standard equipment.
            </para>
            <para>International and the International logotype are registered trademarks of International Truck
                Intellectual Property Company, LLC.
            </para>
        </geninfo>
    </introduction>
    <safety>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Read the following before starting the service procedure.</para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>You must follow your company safety procedures when you service or repair equipment. Be sure to understand
            all of the procedures and instructions before you begin work on the unit.
        </para>
        <para>International uses the following types of notations to give warning of possible safety problems and to
            give information that will prevent damage to the equipment being serviced or repaired.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A warning indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. Personal injury or possible death,
                    along with damage to the vehicle, can occur if the procedure is not followed.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>A caution indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. If the procedure is not followed,
                    damage to equipment or components can occur.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A note indicates an operation, procedure or instruction that is important for correct service.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Some procedures require the use of special tools for safe and correct service. Failure to use these
            special tools when required can cause injury to service personnel or damage to vehicle components.
        </para>
    </safety>
    <title></title>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_0.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_SBB7300001.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
