<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        In Cab and External Switch (3-Way) Controls for Body Accessories - 60ACS - One Momentary Rocker Switch / Remote
        Switch Capability
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB60ACS" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>60ACS - One Momentary Rocker Switch / Remote Switch Capability</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
            BDY INTG, SWITCH MOMNTRY 3POS Rocker, Backlit, with "ON" Indicator Mounted on Dash, Latching Software, for 1
            Auxiliary Load 20 amp. Maximum; Power Available Only in "Ignition" or "Accessory" Position, Output Also
            Controlled by a Customer Remote Mounted Switch (requires 1 Remote Power Module input and 1 output)
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
            This feature provides a three-way switch control function for a remote power module output. An in-cab
            3-position momentary switch is connected to a remote power module (RPM) output. In addition, a customer
            supplied remote mounted momentary switch may be used to control the same RPM output. This switch must be
            active at 12 volts and must use ground to deactivate the output. Thus, a three-way switch control action may
            be performed with these two switch inputs. The RPM output may be turned OFF or ON from either switch,
            however, an OFF command from either switch takes precedence and will turn the RPM output OFF. This feature
            is useful when a lamp or other load requires control from both in the cab or from a remote location on the
            body.
        </para>
        <para>The in-cab switch provides a green lamp in the top section of the switch to indicate when the RPM output
            is ON. The RPM provides an active high output that will source up to 20 amps at battery voltage levels. The
            output current level may be limited through programmable parameters between .1 and 20 amps in .1 amp
            increments. This virtual fusing level is controlled in software and mimics the performance of an SAE fuse.
        </para>
        <para>The RPM output may be activated with the in-cab switch provided that the ignition key is in the Accessory
            or Ignition position. The RPM output may also be activated with the remote switch input with ignition key
            OFF or ON. It is important to turn off RPM outputs that have been enabled remotely before leaving a parked
            vehicle with the ignition key off. Otherwise, the system will remain active and drain the batteries.
        </para>
        <para>60AAA or 60AAB is a prerequisite feature that must be ordered along with 60ACS. 60ACS uses a single
            momentary switch in place of one of the latching switches that is provided with 60AAA and 60AAB. For
            example, instead of the 6 latching switches that are provided with 60AAA, a vehicle with 60ACS will have a
            switch pack of 5 latching switches and 1 momentary switch.
        </para>
        <para>&#8594; Please use ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software to determine pin and switch locations
            for RPM inputs and outputs and to set programmable parameters (refer to pin and switch location section)
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>*Software feature codes can be added through ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software.
            Programmable Parameters are also programmable through ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software.
        </para>
        <para>Required software feature code: 595200</para>
        <para>Conflicts with Software features: NONE</para>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">TEM_Aux1_w_Ext_Sw_Fuse_Level</emph>
            parameter sets the amount of current that flows through Auxiliary output 1. If current rises above this
            level, fusing takes place and the RPM output is shut down.
        </para>
        <para>By turning the
            <emph type="bold">TEM_Aux1_w_Ext_Switch_Init_State</emph>
            parameter ON, the ESC forces the Remote Power Module output to be ON whenever the truck's key-state is
            turned from OFF to ACCESSORY or IGNITION.
        </para>
        <table id="t7300099">
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.77*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.73*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Aux1_ w_Ext_Sw_ Fuse_Level</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1998</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This is the level above which the RPM will fuse the TEM Auxiliary output with external
                                switch.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>20</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>A</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>20</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TEM_Aux1_ w_Ext_Switch_ Init_State</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2032</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This program- mable parameter sets the init state of RPM channel used with TEM
                                Auxiliary with external switch #1.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>On/ Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>NA</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Customer may mount a switch and install the wiring into the pin labeled 3POS_SWITCH_AUX1_Input in
                    the Black 23-pin Remote Power Module input connector. Installation of the remote switch is optional
                    with this feature. (See ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software for input pin location)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Customer must install wiring from the pin labeled 3POS_SWITCH_AUX1_Output Brown 8-pin Remote Power
                    Module output connector to the electrical load that is to be controlled. (See ICAP or the Diamond
                    Logic&#8482; Builder software for output pin location)
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f73000c3" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g73000c3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="502px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">This feature allows the customer the ability to activate the output when the ignition key is
                turned from OFF to ACCESSORY or IGNITION. This functionality is obtained by turning programmable
                parameters (TEM_Aux1_w_Ext_Switch_Init_State and TEM_Aux2_w_Ext_Switch_Init_State) ON
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Activate the first remote Body Builder installed switch to 12 volts by using a momentary
                switch action.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the Remote Power Module output labeled 3POS_SWITCH_AUX1_Output is providing the
                battery volts at rated current levels. (As programmed in ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder
                software)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the green switch indicator light comes on.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the Remote Power Module input labeled 3POS_SWITCH_AUX1_Input is receiving
                battery volts from the customer-mounted switch. (As programmed in ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482;
                Builder software)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deactivate the first remote Body Builder installed switch by providing a momentary switch
                action to ground.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the Remote Power Module output goes OFF.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Activate the first in-cab switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the Remote Power Module output labeled 3POS_SWITCH_AUX1_Output is providing the
                battery volts (As programmed in ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the green switch indicator light comes on.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deactivate the first in-cab switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Select software feature code 595200 using ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software (See
                    Local Dealer)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Programmable Parameters must be set using ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software (See
                    Local Dealer)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The 3-position momentary switch with latching software must be installed in the in-cab switch
                    pack.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The customer must install wiring from the RPM output</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The customer may mount a remote switch and install the wiring into the RPM input</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_96.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB60ACT.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
