<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3 Dynamic Power System Service/ Troubleshooting Guide</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S08308" division="truck" date="02/06/2006">
        <title>Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3 Dynamic Power System Service/ Troubleshooting Guide</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7700</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>60AAC</ucode>
                <ucode>60AAE</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Safety Information</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Read the following before starting the service or troubleshooting procedure.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The information contained in this International Service Manual Section was current at the time of
                printing and is subject to change without notice or liability.
            </para>
            <para>You must follow your company safety procedures when you service or repair equipment. Be sure to
                understand all of the procedures and instructions before you begin work on the unit.
            </para>
            <para>International uses the following types of notations to give warning of possible safety problems and to
                give information that will prevent damage to the equipment being serviced or repaired.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A warning indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. Personal injury or possible
                        death can occur if the procedure is not followed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>A caution indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. If the procedure is not
                        followed, damage to equipment or components can occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A note indicates an operation, procedure or instruction that is important for correct
                        service.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Some procedures require the use of special tools for safe and/or correct service. Failure to use these
                special tools when required can cause injury to service personnel or damage to vehicle components.
            </para>
            <para>This service manual section is intended for use by professional technicians, NOT a "
                <emph type="bold">do-it-yourselfer</emph>." It is written to inform these technicians of conditions that
                may occur on some vehicles, or to provide information that could assist in the proper service of a
                vehicle. Properly trained technicians have the equipment, tools, safety instructions, and know-how to do
                a job properly and safely. If a condition is described, DO NOT assume that the service section applies
                to your vehicle. See your International Truck Dealer for information on whether this service section
                applies to your vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08308.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
