<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - International Diamond Logic&#174;
        Electrical System Overview - Remote Power Module (RPM)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Remote Power Module (RPM)</title>
        <para>RPMs provide a method of distributing and controlling power to various device loads on the vehicle,
            outside the cab, without running high current wires from in-cab switches to the loads or splicing into
            existing wiring.
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300015" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832384.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The RPM is connected to the BC via the Body Builder J1939 datalink (the BC is capable of controlling up to
            seven RPMs on the vehicle). The only factory-installed wires connected to the RPM are battery power for
            driving the loads and the datalink cable. Connectors for Body Builder-installed inputs and outputs are also
            provided. Power is fed to the RPM through a fusible link to the battery source. Each RPM has six
            independently controllable, 20 Ampere (AMP) outputs (80 maximum per RPM) with virtual (software
            programmable) fusing similar to the BC. If higher current capacity is needed, two outputs can be paralleled
            or the RPM can control a high current relay while still maintaining logic and diagnostic capability without
            having to wire to the inside of the cab.
        </para>
        <para>Because the RPM is connected to the BC via the datalink, it also serves as an "integration gateway" to the
            BC and the vehicle electrical system. Six inputs on each RPM allow information from body accessories to be
            communicated to the BC and processed for interlocks, operator information/warning, etc. These inputs also
            allow the Body Builder to add body-mounted switches to turn on or off the same electrical devices controlled
            by in-cab switches.
        </para>
        <para>Additional information concerning the use and installation of RPMs is contained in the applicable Feature
            sections that follow (see 60AAA/60AAB in particular for detailed data on RPM connectors/pin functions,
            wiring, and mounting).
        </para>
        <para>The following is an example of how a vehicle electrical system might be configured.</para>
        <figure id="f7300016" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832385.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The International Diamond Logic&#174; electrical system, along with the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder
            software, provide the Body Builder with an unprecedented flexibility in adding and customizing the
            electrical features on a vehicle.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
