<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Work Light and Outside Cab Power
        Features - 08XBK - Auxiliary 40 Amp Circuit, Switch Controlled
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB08XBK" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>08XBK - Auxiliary 40 Amp Circuit, Switch Controlled</title>
        <para>Refer to the Circuit Diagram Manual S08322, Chapter 10, Aux and Power Source.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>08XBK - SWITCH, AUXILIARY Switch 40 AMP Circuit for Customer Use; Includes Wiring Connection in the engine
            compartment near the megafuse
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Feature code 08XBK provides a 40 AMP battery feed for customer use. An in-cab rocker switch controls the
            circuit. A blank window switch is provided with this feature along with a graphic overlay kit that allows
            custom labeling of the switch function.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Software Feature Codes that must be added: 595AJH Body Controller (BC) Prog, SWITCH AUXILIARY In Center
            Panel, With 40 AMP Fuse Circuit, Accessory-Controlled
        </para>
        <para>Software Feature Codes that must be removed: NONE</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A blunt-cut wire (light green) taped back to the dash harness near the megafuse is provided for customer
            interface to this circuit. The battery feed to this wire is through a relay that is enabled by a 12V signal
            from the BC connector 1601 pin E16 when the switch is activated.
        </para>
        <figure id="f73000c7" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832350.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <para>To test this circuit, verify that battery voltage is present at the wire provided when the in-cab switch
            is activated with the IGN key in the on or accessory position. The green indicator in the rocker switch
            shall be illuminated when the output is on.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If the vehicle was not ordered with the feature, it may be added. For information on parts and components,
            see "How Do I" - General Information section of this electrical guide.
        </para>
        <para>Use the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software to add the following software feature: 595AJH BC Prog, SWITCH
            AUXILIARY In Center Panel, With 40 AMP Fuse Circuit, Accessory-Controlled.
        </para>
        <para>Also refer to the "Switches" section to determine the assigned location of the rocker switch for this
            feature.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_51.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
