<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - General Electrical -
        Electrical Dos and Don'ts
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electrical Dos and Don'ts</title>
        <para>The information in this section applies to all 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, and 7000 models.</para>
        <table frame="all">
            <title>Electrical Dos and Don'ts</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="117.16pt"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="233.24pt"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="139.07pt"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ITEM</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>DO</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>DON&apos;T</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Accessory (power taps with key in "Accessory" mode)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to accessory relay output in the inside cab fuse block; circuit A12B or
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Connect to optional Body Accessory relay located in the PDC, circuit R3-5.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to key switch accessory output.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Battery - Clean (unfused) power and maxi-fused power feeds and ground connection
                                points
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Use any unused Maxi-fuse position outside Power Distribution Center or</para>
                            <para>b) Use inline Maxi-holder from Mega-fuse unfused side.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Exceed additional 45 amps</para>
                            <para>b) Exceed 3 ring terminals total on Maxi-fuse stud.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground additional electrical loads (customer supplied devices) to chassis or ground
                                studs located on the dash panel.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground to vehicle batteries for additional loads.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground - with ammeter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground to frame or dash ground stud to allow for ammeter to register current.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ground directly to batteries for meter signal.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Ignition (power taps with key in "Ignition")</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to the ignition relay output in the inside cab fuse block; circuit A13AH
                                or
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Connect to the ignition relay output outside the cab PDC; circuit J13CW.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect circuits directly to key switch ignition circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Start (power taps with key in "Start")</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the starter relay input circuit J17 at the outside fuse block.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect circuits directly to the key switch start circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Electrical System Controller (access to pinouts of discrete circuits)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to ESC outputs only.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Exceed ESC outputs amperage refer to ESC section</para>
                            <para>b) Connect to signal inputs of the ESC.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Electric City Horn</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to circuit J85AA (Dash), M85E (Forward chassis) and M85J (Horn jumper) or
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Only use suppressed type horn assembly.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to Electric City Horn circuit without a diode for protection.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air Horn (or Air Horn Accommodation)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect air line to output side of the solenoid pack controlled through Electrical
                                System Controller.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to input side of air switch electrical circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>CB Radio (or CB Accommodation)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Use power connector 2303 and CB antenna connector 2306 at CB opening in overhead
                                console with optional code 08RCB.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 10 amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Radio installation for customer aftermarket radio accommodation</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to pigtail (A13B) owner/operator ignition feed</para>
                            <para>b) Use a relay if load exceeds 5 amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 5 amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cruise / Stationary Throttle via Remote Throttle module and via hardwire for remote
                                hook-up
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inline six engines without optional code 12VVW - Add circuit to Pins 37, 36, 32, and
                                31 of Engine ECM Connector 6007 depending on desired function; for 4200 with out
                                optional code 12VYC - Add circuits to Pin X3-19, X3-20, X3-21, and X3-14 of the ECM
                                connector depending on desired function Refer to 12VVW or 12VYC Component Information
                                Diamond Logic&#8482; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters for
                                vehicles equipped with these optional codes or the remote engine speed control module.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the ESC Cruise Control Input circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Engine Oil Pressure warning for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inline six engines without optional code 12VVW - Add circuit to Pin 54 of Engine ECM
                                Connector 6007; for 4200 optional is unavailable; Refer to 12VVW or 12VYC Component
                                Information Diamond Logic&#8482; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable
                                Parameters for vehicles equipped with these optional codes. Install discrete oil
                                pressure sensor or tap signal off the ATA or public J1939 Data Link.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect directly to oil pressure sensor circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle Speed output with Manual Transmission for optional feature control; i.e., sand
                                spreader
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inline six engines without optional code 12VVW - Add circuit to Pin 58 of Engine ECM
                                Connector 6007. For 4200 without optional code 12VYC - Add circuit to Pin 17 of Engine
                                ECM2 Connector 6020; provides 30,000 pulse/mile output for speed. Use an isolated Dual
                                wound sensor with manual transmission. Refer to Component Information Diamond Logic&#8482;
                                Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters for vehicles equipped
                                with 12VVW or 12VYC optional codes.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into the speedometer sensor circuit on the engine.</para>
                            <para>b) Wire into Speed sensor circuit on transmission. Use sensors in parallel with
                                existing output speed sensor it will cause VSS Diagnostic Trouble Code DTC to set.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle Speed output with Automatic Transmission for optional feature control; i.e.,
                                sand spreader
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inline six engines without optional code 12VVW - Add circuit to Pin 58 of Engine ECM
                                Connector 6007; For 4200 without optional code 12VYC - Add circuit to Pin 17 of Engine
                                ECM2 Connector 6020; provides 30,000 pulse/mile output for speed. Refer to Component
                                Information Diamond Logic&#8482; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable
                                Parameters for vehicles equipped with 12VVW or 12VYC optional codes. Allison
                                Transmission utilizes a variable frequency pulse generated by Transmission ECU for
                                vehicle speed information refer to Allison service information, with optional codes
                                13WTA or 13 WTE Connector 7205, cavity F; L92 # 167 Allison MD; Connector 7306, cavity
                                H; L92 # 122 LCT 2000/2400.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into the speedometer sensor circuit on the engine.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tachometer Signal Output for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inline six engines without optional code 12VVW - Add circuit to Pin 59 of Engine ECM
                                Connector 6007; for 4200 without optional code 12VYC - Add circuit to Pin 11 of Engine
                                ECM2 Connector 6020; provides a 12/pulse/eng rpm* Refer to Component Information Diamond
                                Logic&#8482; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters for vehicles
                                equipped with 12VVW or 12VY Optional codes.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the tachometer sensor circuits on the engine.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Engine Coolant Temperature Gauge Output Signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install discrete Engine Coolant Temperature sensor. Refer to Component Information
                                Diamond Logic&#8482; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters.
                                Refer to ATA Data Link or public J1939 support Information.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Engine Coolant Temperature sensor circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Alternator warning light output circuit for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect wire to alternator warning light output terminal and connect the other side of
                                the warning light circuit to ignition feed.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect warning light circuit to ground circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Low Air warning signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Tap into air line with additional sensor or</para>
                            <para>b) Refer to public J1939 Data Link information to extract Air PSI signal.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into electrical Low Air sensor circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Park Brake Warning Output Signal for circuit interlock features installed</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Tap into air line with additional switch for vehicles with air brakes or</para>
                            <para>b) Connect into ESC circuit pin 4; Connector 1600 with a ground active signal Air or
                                Hydraulic brake vehicles.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into existing air park brake switch electrical circuit b) Exceed 200 ma
                                total.*
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Trans Warning Output signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect wire to to ECU circuit 115 for WTC III and circuit 125 for LCT 2000/24000
                                transmission models. Circuit goes open to ground to actuate a remote mounted light. An
                                external relay is required if current is .05 Amps or greater.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Splice into the transmission harness for signal uses</para>
                            <para>b) Utilize this signal for vehicle shutdown system.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Transmission Interface (Body Builder Connections)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>See PBB-43100, 4300, 4400 Models : Medium Conventional Body Builder Diagrams and
                                PBB-50100, 7000 Series Model Medium &#38; Heavy Conventional Body Builder Diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Splice into the transmission harness for signal uses.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Back Up Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into body builder Connectors 4450; Cavity E circuit 71 or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303 Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 6 Amps total circuit</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clearance / Marker Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into body builder Connector 4450; Cavity D circuit 58 or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303 Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 Amps total circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dome Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into ESC Connector 1601; Pin C for output circuit</para>
                            <para>b) Theater Dimming must be turned off in the ESC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into any door switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 10 Amps total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fog Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into ESC Connector 4007; Pin A for the Fog Light output circuit.</para>
                            <para>b) Fog Light accommodation must be added to the ESC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into fog light switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 15 Amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Headlights (including Plow Lights without Plow Light option)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Plow Light 7-way Harness connector provided with optional code 08THJ.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into head light switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 20 Amps total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Panel Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into panel lamp Buss Connector 1002 located behind the instrument panel left
                                of the interior fuse panel.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into panel dimmer switch circuit or Panel light adapter circuit A62N.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 5 Amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Stop Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into body builder Connector (4450 cavity B and C; circuits 56 left/ 57 right
                                combined) (4460 cavity A and B; circuits 56 left /57 right separate) or connect into
                                tail light harness Connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit
                                diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the stop light switch circuit at the brake pedal.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 8 amps total.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tail Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into body builder Connector 4450; Cavity A circuits 68 or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 Amps Total Circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Turn Signals</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to body builder connector (4450 cavity B and C; circuits 56 left/ 57 right
                                combined) (4460 cavity A and B; circuits 56 left/ 57 right separate).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the input side of the turn signal switch or the electrical system
                                controller circuit inputs.
                            </para>
                            <para>Exceed 8 amps total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Work Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into ESC connector 4007 PIN F Work Light Output circuit</para>
                            <para>b) Work lamp accommodation must be programmed into the ESC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 10 Amps.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remote Power Module Connection</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to body builder connectors at the Remote Power Module (J3- output circuits and
                                J4- remote inputs). Refer to Remote Power Module Section.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 amps per channel output with a maximum 80 amps total draw per module.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remote mounted Fuel Level (Low Fuel Warning)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install additional fuel sender. Extract fuel gauge data from the Public J1939 data
                                link.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to fuel level gauge sender circuit or short existing fuel sending unit to
                                chassis ground.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>HVAC Interrupt (A/C compressor clutch &#38; Blower fan interrupts)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Add a secondary A/C Evaporator to cool remote areas by tapping into the refrigerant
                                lines with the authorized hoses. Use only the standard HVAC Control for controlling the
                                A/C system.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into HVAC A/C clutch circuit between the ESC and the A/C compressor clutch for
                                purposes of controlling the A/C system. Connect to the high side of the pressure
                                transducer or either of the A/C system thermistors.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clutch switch</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install additional switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the clutch switch or circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Brake Switch</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to the ESC connector 4004 Pin 21 active ground output circuit ESC must be
                                programmed with the Separate Stop Feature.
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Install additional switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the brake switch or circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BBHDI.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
