<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Air Conditioning - 16WKB - Air
        Conditioning
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB16WKB" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>16WKB - Air Conditioning</title>
        <para>Refer to the circuit diagram in S08322, Chapter 12, Air Conditioning.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>16WKB: Air Conditioner (International Blend Air) with integral heater, defroster and R134-A Refrigerant.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE / BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This is an electrical connection point for detecting when the air conditioner clutch is on. No direct
            electrical connection point is provided for tapping into the A/C clutch wire. However, if an A/C clutch
            connection is necessary, the Body Builder may use proper splice techniques to tap into wire AC77A. The added
            load required by the Body Builder should not exceed two Amperes (AMPS). This control wire shall be at
            battery volts when the A/C clutch is on and 0 volts when off. The software in the Body Controller (BC)
            determines when the A/C clutch should be on or off based upon the mode of the HVAC controls in the cab and
            condenser temperatures and high side pressures of the A/C system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
            NONE
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300083" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/G0832349.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>BC located in the cab behind the kickplate next to the driver's left foot</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>WIRE GAUGE: 16 Gauge</para>
        <para>WIRE NUMBER/COLOR: AC77A-LTGN</para>
        <para>BC connector (1603): Pin C</para>
        <para>TERMINAL: 3534163C1</para>
        <para>CIRCUIT DIAGRAM: See Electrical Circuit Diagram Manual S08322 Chapter 12, Air Conditioning.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Start the vehicle. Turn on air conditioner.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the wire feeding the body load is at battery volts when the A/C Clutch is ON and 0
                    volts when OFF.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Ensure that no faults codes are present when the truck is on.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">BODY BUILDER IMPORTANT INFORMATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>In some applications it may be advantageous to add an additional A/C evaporator to cool remote areas of
            the vehicle. The following procedures and part numbers will accommodate this addition.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Do not break into the A/C clutch circuit for the purpose of controlling the A/C system.</para>
                <para>Do not connect to the high side of the pressure transducer.</para>
                <para>Do not connect to either of the A/C system thermistors.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">PARTS INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">2007 MaxxForce DT and MaxxForce 9 Engines, Low Cab Mount</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor - 3613035C92</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator - 3613034C93</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy compressor to condenser - 3613033C94</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">2007 MaxxForce DT, MaxxForce 9 and MaxxForce 10 Engines, Mid High Cab</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor - 3613038C92</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator - 3616067C93</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy compressor to condenser - 3613036C92</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">2007 MaxxForce 7</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor - 3612962C93</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator - 3613034C93</para>
        <para>Hose, A/C assy compressor to condenser - 3612960C94</para>
        <para>
            <title>PROCEDURE</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a level surface, set the
                    parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear a face shield, or other adequate eye protection, and nonporous gloves when working with
                    refrigerant. The temperature of liquid refrigerant may cause injury or blindness if the refrigerant
                    contacts the eyes. Should liquid refrigerant come in contact with skin, remove contaminated
                    clothing, including shoes and treat the injury as though the skin had been frostbitten. See a doctor
                    immediately.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the system
                    are replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause personal injury or
                    death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recover the refrigerant from the A/C system.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the A/C hose from the condenser to the evaporator and install the new hose.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the A/C hose from the accumulator to the compressor and install the new hose.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the A/C hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed hose
                from the condenser to the evaporator.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the A/C hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed hose
                from the accumulator to the compressor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Evacuate the system.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recharge the system using R-134A refrigerant. The original truck system holds 30 oz. and the
                new evaporator should require an additional 16 oz. The additional requirement will vary from system to
                system depending on the length of hoses and the capacity of the new evaporator. The additional capacity
                will also require an additional 40 cc (1.2 fl. Oz.) of PAG oil in the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Failure to add additional PAG oil to the increased capacity A/C system will result in improper
                    lubrication and lead to premature component failure.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate the vehicle to make sure the A/C is performing properly and is not leaking.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_56.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_58.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
