<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - RE 200 and RE 300 - CLUSTER FAILURE DIAGNOSIS -
        SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER, HOURMETER, VOLTMETER, OIL PRESSURE GAUGE, AND WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE FAILURE
        ISOLATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER, HOURMETER, VOLTMETER, OIL PRESSURE GAUGE, AND WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE
            FAILURE ISOLATION
        </title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>If the speedometer, odometer, tachometer, hourmeter, voltmeter, oil pressure, or water temperature
                gauge indicates a failure, the circuits serving the instrument in question must be checked for clean,
                tight, unbroken and non-shorted connections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure all relays in the vehicle are the suppressed type.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Make sure the accessory voltage to the cluster is within a range of 11 to 16 volts.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>The instrument cluster has self testing capabilities that will identify various failures in the
                electronic portions of the unit. The self testing diagnostics provide a strong indication of exactly
                what is wrong with the unit, without removing the cluster from the vehicle or spending a large amount of
                time troubleshooting.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pass Indications</title>
            <para>The cluster will test itself each time the vehicle is powered up. If all tests pass, the unit will
                drive the speedometer, tachometer, voltmeter, oil pressure gauge, and water temperature gauge needles
                through one complete sweep. This indicates that all input circuits are good and tells the driver that
                all output circuits driving the gauges are good.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fail Indications</title>
            <para>The cluster will provide failure indications in two ways:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Does not provide a proper gauge sweep on power up.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The speedometer, tachometer, voltmeter, oil pressure gauge, and water temperature gauge
                    needles "wave" on power up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the unit senses a circuit problem at power up, the speedometer, tachometer, voltmeter, oil pressure
                gauge, and water temperature gauge needles will simultaneously wave from 0 and one of the numbers on the
                speedometer and tachometer dial faces three times. Corrective action is defined in the following failure
                chart.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Service Tool (EST) Diagnostics</title>
            <para>Operation and accuracy of the speedometer, tachometer, fuel, oil pressure, water temperature and
                voltmeter can be verified with an EST, without removing the cluster. The EZ-Tech, with the instrument
                cluster software, can be used to exercise the speedometer/tachometer, through the J1708 data link .
                Refer to the instrument cluster software manual for instructions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_40.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_42.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
