<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        High Current In Cab Switch Controls for Body Accessories - 08XBK - Auxiliary 40 Amp Circuit, Switch Controlled
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB08XBK" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>08XBK - Auxiliary 40 Amp Circuit, Switch Controlled</title>
        <para>Refer to the Circuit Diagram in
            <exhotlnk document="../S08/S082853_CD08XBK.xml" bookname="S082853">S08285, Chapter 9, page 29</exhotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
            08XBK - SWITCH, AUXILIARY Switch 40 amp Circuit for Customer Use; Includes Wiring Connection at PDC and
            Control in Cab.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE/BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
            Feature code 08XBK provides a 40 Amp battery feed for customer use. An in cab rocker switch controls the
            circuit. A blank window switch is provided with this feature along with a graphic overlay kit that allows
            custom labeling of the switch function.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Software Feature Codes that must be added: 595265 (TEM) ESC Prog, High Current Relay Load Output</para>
        <para>Software Feature Codes that must be removed: NONE</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A blunt cut wire (Light Green) taped back to the Dash Harness near the PDC is provided for customer
            interface to this circuit. The battery feed to this wire is through a relay that is enabled by a ground from
            ESC connector 1601 when the switch is activated.
        </para>
        <figure id="f73000c7" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/g73000c7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING</emph>
        </para>
        <para>To test this circuit, verify that battery voltage is present at the wire provided when the in cab switch
            is activated with the ignition key in the ON or ACCESSORY position. The green indicator in the rocker switch
            shall be illuminated when the output is ON.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If the vehicle was not ordered with the feature, it may be added. For information on parts and components,
            see "How Do I" - General Information section of the body builder book.
        </para>
        <para>Use ICAP or the Diamond Logic&#8482; Builder software to add the following software feature:
            <emph type="bold">595265 (TEM) ESC Prog, High Current Relay Load Output</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Also refer to the "How Do I Add Additional Rocker Switches" section to determine the assigned location of
            the rocker switch for this feature.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB60ACE.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB08WJA.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
