<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - RE 200 and RE 300 - DESCRIPTION - INDICATOR AND WARNING
        LIGHTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INDICATOR AND WARNING LIGHTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LEFT TURN</title>
            <para>The left turn arrow indicator light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 1</hotlnk>) and green lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the turn signal switch is in the left turn position by
                blinking in unison with the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(ABS) ANTI-LOCK BRAKE</title>
            <para>The "ABS" indicator light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 2</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the anti-lock brake system is activating and overriding
                the engine retarder. The light will also illuminate when a fault in the ABS system is detected by the
                ABS controller.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HIGH BEAM</title>
            <para>The high beam indicator light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 6</hotlnk>) and blue lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the headlights are on and switched to the bright
                position.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RIGHT TURN</title>
            <para>The right turn arrow indicator light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 7</hotlnk>) and green lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the turn signal switch is in the right turn position by
                blinking in unison with the turn signal lights.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WAIT-TO-START</title>
            <para>The "WAIT-TO-START" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.A</hotlnk>) and yellow lens signals
                the driver to hold off on cranking over the engine until the glow plugs have heated up.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>BRAKE PRESS</title>
            <para>The "BRAKE PRESS" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.B</hotlnk>) and red lens provide a
                warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that one of the following conditions is present: the air pressure
                has dropped below an acceptable level to keep the brakes fully released with an air brake system, or
                that there is an abnormal condition detected by the hydraulic brake monitor module.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) LOW AIR</title>
            <para>The "((P)) LOW AIR" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.B</hotlnk>) and red lens warns the
                driver that the air brake system has either not yet pumped up to a pressure that will reliably for the
                brake or that the system is losing air pressure to apply the brakes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SERVICE</title>
            <para>The "SERVICE" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.C</hotlnk>) and red lens were used
                with mechanical engines to provide a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the level of the engine
                coolant is down to a minimum level for safe operation. With electronic engines, the coolant level is
                monitored by the engine ECM2. The red Oil/Water warning lamp is used to warn of a low coolant condition.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>((P)) PARK BRAKE</title>
            <para>The "((P)) PARK BRAKE" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.C</hotlnk>) and red lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the parking brake is applied. This light is utilized with
                both air and hydraulic brake systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OIL/WATER</title>
            <para>The "OIL/WATER" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.D</hotlnk>) and red lens provide a
                warning, to driver of the vehicle, that the engine's oil pressure is running low, that its coolant
                temperature is running high, or the coolant level is low (with electronic engines). Thus the driver can
                take the necessary actions to protect the engine. This light is also used with International engines to
                signal that the engine is going to shut down in 30 seconds due to either idle shutdown counter or engine
                protection system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WARN ENGINE</title>
            <para>The "WARN ENGINE" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.E</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide a
                warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that a sensor or system of the engine is not performing as it
                should. This condition could be affecting performance and or emissions, and indicates that the driver
                should get the vehicle into a shop for servicing. This light is also used in conjunction with the (STI)
                Self Test Initialization switch and "STOP ENGINE" light to display active and inactive engine fault
                codes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE OIL</title>
            <para>The "CHANGE OIL" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.F</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that it is time to get the vehicle in for an oil change.
                This feature, available on vehicles with the International consolidated engine controller (CEC), keeps
                track of mileage and engine hours by using a programmed service interval counter to determine that it is
                time to change the engine oil and turn on the warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHECK TRANS</title>
            <para>The "CHECK TRANS" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 8.G</hotlnk>) and red lens provide a
                warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the transmission is overheating (with Allison nonelectronic
                transmissions), or that the transmission is overheating, or the ECU senses a problem with the Allison
                WTEC III electronic transmissions or with the Allison 2000 (LCT) transmissions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>WATER-IN-FUEL</title>
            <para>The "WATER-IN-FUEL" warning (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 12.A</hotlnk>) light and yellow lens
                provide an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that there is water up to the probe in the fuel
                filter. Thus the driver knows that the filter must be drained or changed to prevent water from getting
                into the engine.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FUEL FILTER</title>
            <para>The "FUEL FILTER" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 12.B</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the fuel filter is becoming excessively plugged or
                restricted. Thus the filter should be changed to prevent hard starting, power limiting, or stalling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRANS OIL TEMP</title>
            <para>The "TRANS OIL TEMP" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 12.C</hotlnk>) and red lens provide a
                warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the transmission is overheating (with Allison nonelectronic
                transmissions), or that the transmission is overheating, or the ECU senses a problem with the Allison
                WTEC III electronic transmissions or with the Allison 2000 (LCT) transmissions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LOW BRAKE FLUID</title>
            <para>A "LOW BRAKE FLUID" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 12.D</hotlnk>) and red lens is used to
                warn the driver of the vehicle that the brake master cylinder is low on fluid.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL</title>
            <para>The "TRAC CTRL" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 12.D</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the optional traction control circuitry has been engaged,
                and that the anti-lock braking has been switched off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD ON</title>
            <para>The "RETARD ON" indicator light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 17.A</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the transmission retarder has been enabled. Thus the
                driver will be reminded to turn off the retarder when road surfaces are slippery.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CHANGE TRANS FILTER</title>
            <para>The "CHANGE TRANS FILTER" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 17.B</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                a warning, to the driver of the vehicle, that the transmission fluid filter has become restricted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RETARD OVER HEAT</title>
            <para>The "RETARD OVER HEAT" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 17.C</hotlnk>) and red lens provide an
                indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the transmission retarder has reached an unsafe operating
                temperature. At this point the driver should switch off the retarder and allow it to cool before turning
                it back on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ALTERNATOR</title>
            <para>The "ALTERNATOR" warning light (
                <hotlnk document="s08314_2.xml" xrefid="f0831401">Figure 1, Item 17.D</hotlnk>) and yellow lens provide
                an indication, to the driver of the vehicle, that the charging voltage to the battery is low.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08314.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
