<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INSTRUMENTS (Data Link Driven Instrument Cluster) - FE 300 and IC Bus - CLUSTER FAILURE DIAGNOSIS -
        SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER, HOUR-METER, VOLTMETER, OIL PRESSURE GAUGE, AND WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE
        FAILURE CHART
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SPEEDOMETER, ODOMETER, TACHOMETER, HOUR-METER, VOLTMETER, OIL PRESSURE GAUGE, AND WATER TEMPERATURE GAUGE
            FAILURE CHART
        </title>
        <table id="t0831306" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="all">
            <title>Speedometer, Odometer, Tachometer, Hour-meter, Voltmeter, Oil Pressure Gauge, and Water Temperature
                Gauge Failure Chart
            </title>
            <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colwidth="2.00in"/>
                <colspec colwidth="2.57in"/>
                <colspec colwidth="2.00in"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>FAILURE MODE</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>FIRST ACTION</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>SECOND ACTION</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1. Speedometer, tachometer, voltmeter, oil pressure gauge, and water temperature gauge
                                needles do not move on power up.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify that ignition voltage and ground are provided to cluster. Refer to
                                <hotlnk document="s08313_HL0831303.xml" xrefid="hl0831303">CLUSTER HARNESS CONNECTORS
                                </hotlnk>
                                and GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Circuit Diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace cluster.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2. Speedometer, tachometer, voltmeter, oil pressure or water temperature gauge needle
                                moves erratically on power up sweep.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Swap the speedometer and tachometer in the cluster, or water temperature gauge for
                                another temperature gauge, etc. in the cluster. If the defect follows the meter, replace
                                the meter.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If the defect stays at the same meter location, replace the cluster.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3. Speedometer and tachometer sweep in unison and the tachometer needle points to
                                three (3) times.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>J1587/J1708 Data Link failure. Insure that the vehicle Data Link is not shorted or
                                wired incorrectly. With the ignition on, voltage from Positive data link circuit to
                                ground should be approximately 4 volts. Voltage from Negative data link circuit to
                                ground should be approximately 1 volt. Refer to
                                <hotlnk document="s08313_HL0831303.xml" xrefid="hl0831303">CLUSTER HARNESS CONNECTORS
                                </hotlnk>
                                and GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Circuit Diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify data from the ECM2 by using an electronic service tool (EST), such as the
                                EZ-Tech&#8482; or Pro-Link&#174; 9000, with the applicable engine software. If data is
                                present replace cluster.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>4. Speedometer and tachometer sweep in unison and the tachometer needle points to
                                three (3) times.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cluster electronics failed. Replace cluster.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>5. Speedometer and tachometer sweep in unison and the tachometer needle points to
                                three (3) times.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Odometer drive circuit failed, odometer is disconnected, or odometer coil is open.
                                Insure odometer connector is properly seated to the printed wiring board connector.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Disconnect odometer connector, swap with hour-meter or connect to hour-meter
                                connector, start engine, and note if odometer advances once every 6 minutes. If odometer
                                advances, replace cluster. If odometer does not advance, replace odometer.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>6. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but
                                <emph type="bold">speedometer does not work</emph>
                                when driving.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check speedometer sensor wiring continuity and sensor output signal levels. Refer to
                                <hotlnk document="s08313_HL0831303.xml" xrefid="hl0831303">CLUSTER HARNESS CONNECTORS
                                </hotlnk>
                                and GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL, Circuit Diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify signal to ECM2 by using an electronic service tool (EST), such as the EZ-Tech&#8482;
                                or Pro-Link&#174; 9000.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>7. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but
                                <emph type="bold">tachometer does not work</emph>
                                when driving.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Verify signal to ECM2 by using an electronic service tool.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>8. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but
                                <emph type="bold">odometer does not work</emph>
                                when driving.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remove odometer and swap with hour-meter or connect to hour-meter connector, start
                                engine, and note if odometer advances every 6 minutes. If odometer advances, replace the
                                cluster.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If odometer does not advance, replace odometer.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>9. Speedometer and tachometer go through a good power up sweep, but hour-meter does
                                not work when driving.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Swap hour-meter with odometer, drive truck and note if the hour-meter (placed in
                                odometer location) advances every tenth of a mile. If the hour-meter operates, replace
                                the cluster.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If the hour-meter does not advance, replace the hour-meter.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_41.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313_43.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08313.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
