<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - General Electrical - Electrical
        Dos and Don'ts
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Electrical Dos and Don'ts</title>
        <para>The information in this section applies to all 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400, and 7000 models.</para>
        <table frame="all">
            <title>Electrical Dos and Don'ts</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="117.16pt"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="233.24pt"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="139.07pt"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ITEM</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>DO</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>DON&apos;T</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Accessory (power taps with key in "Accessory" mode)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to accessory relay output in the inside cab fuse block; circuit A12B</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to key switch accessory output.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Battery - Clean (unfused) power and maxi-fused power feeds and GND connection points
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Use inline Maxi-holder from Mega-fuse unfused side.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Exceed additional 45 AMPS</para>
                            <para>b) Exceed 3 ring terminals total on Maxi-fuse stud.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND additional electrical loads (customer supplied devices) to chassis or GND studs
                                located on the dash panel.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND to vehicle batteries for additional loads.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND - with ammeter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND to frame or dash GND stud to allow for ammeter to register current.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>GND directly to batteries for meter signal.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>IGN (power taps with key in "IGN")</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to the IGN relay output in the inside cab fuse block; circuit A13AH or
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Connect to the IGN relay output outside the cab PDC; circuit J13CW.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect circuits directly to key switch IGN circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Start (power taps with key in "Start")</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the starter relay input circuit J17 at the outside fuse block.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect circuits directly to the key switch start circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>BC (access to pinouts of discrete circuits)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to BC outputs only.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Exceed BC outputs amperage refer to BC section</para>
                            <para>b) Connect to signal inputs of the BC.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Electric City Horn</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to circuit A85E (Dash), M85E, M85N, or M85L (Forward chassis) and M85J
                                (Horn jumper) or
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Only use suppressed type horn assembly.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to Electric City Horn circuit without a diode for protection.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air Horn (or Air Horn Accommodation)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect air line to output side of the solenoid pack controlled through BC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to input side of air switch electrical circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>CB Radio (or CB Accommodation)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Use power connector 2303 and CB antenna connector 2306 at CB opening in overhead
                                console with optional code 08RCB.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 10 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Radio installation for customer aftermarket radio accommodation</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to pigtail (A13B) owner/operator IGN feed</para>
                            <para>b) Use a relay if load exceeds 5 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 5 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cruise / Stationary Throttle via Remote Throttle module and via hardwire for remote
                                hook-up
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For I6 or V8 engines without optional code 12VZA - Add circuit to Pins 16, 49, 60, and
                                68 of Engine ECM connector 6020 depending on desired function, or add a Remote Engine
                                Speed Control Module (RESCM). Refer to 12VZA Component Information Diamond Logic&#174;
                                Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters for vehicles equipped
                                with these optional codes or the RESCM.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the BC Cruise Control Input circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Engine Oil Pressure warning for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For I6 or V8 engines without optional code 12VZA - Add circuit to Pin 22 of Engine ECM
                                connector 6020 depending on desired function; or add a RESCM. Refer to 12VZA Component
                                Information Diamond Logic&#174; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable
                                Parameters for vehicles equipped with these optional codes. Install discrete oil
                                pressure sensor or tap signal off the ATA or public J1939 Datalink.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect directly to oil pressure sensor circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle Speed output with Manual Transmission for optional feature control; i.e., sand
                                spreader
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For I6 or V8 engines without optional code 12VZA - Add circuit to Pin 72 of Engine ECM
                                connector 6020 depending on desired function; or add a RESCM. This provides 30,000
                                pulse/mile output for speed. Use an isolated Dual wound sensor with manual transmission.
                                Refer to Component Information Diamond Logic&#174; Controller Engine Control Features
                                and Programmable Parameters for vehicles equipped with 12VZA optional code.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into the speedometer sensor circuit on the engine.</para>
                            <para>b) Wire into Speed sensor circuit on transmission. Use sensors in parallel with
                                existing output speed sensor. It will cause VSS Diagnostic Trouble Code DTC to set.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle Speed output with Automatic Transmission for optional feature control; i.e.,
                                sand spreader
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For I6 or V8 engines without optional code 12VZA - Add circuit to Pin 72 of Engine ECM
                                connector 6020 depending on desired function; or add a RESCM. This provides 30,000
                                pulse/mile output for speed. Use an isolated Dual wound sensor with manual transmission.
                                Refer to Component Information Diamond Logic&#61650; Controller Engine Control Features
                                and Programmable Parameters for vehicles equipped with 12VZA optional code. This
                                provides 30,000 pulse/mile output for speed. Refer to Component Information Diamond
                                Logic&#174; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters for vehicles
                                equipped with 12VZA optional code. Allison Transmission utilizes a variable frequency
                                pulse generated by Transmission ECU. For vehicle speed information, refer to Allison
                                service information, Connector 7205, cavity F (provides this signal connection point).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into the speedometer sensor circuit on the engine.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tachometer Signal Output for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For I6 or V8 engines without optional code 12VZA - Add circuit to Pin 71 of Engine ECM
                                connector 6020 depending on desired function; or add a RESCM. This provides a
                                12/pulse/eng RPM. Refer to Component Information Diamond Logic&#61650; Controller Engine
                                Control Features and Programmable Parameters for vehicles equipped with 12VZA optional
                                code.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the tachometer sensor circuits on the engine.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Engine Coolant Temperature Gauge Output Signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install discrete Engine Coolant Temperature sensor. Refer to Component Information
                                Diamond Logic&#174; Controller Engine Control Features and Programmable Parameters.
                                Refer to ATA Datalink or public J1939 support information.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Engine Coolant Temperature sensor circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Alternator warning light output circuit for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect wire to alternator warning light output terminal and connect the other side of
                                the warning light circuit to IGN feed.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect warning light circuit to GND circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Low Air warning signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Tap into air line with additional sensor or</para>
                            <para>b) Refer to public J1939 Data Link information to extract Air PSI signal.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into electrical Low Air sensor circuits.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Park Brake Warning Output Signal for circuit interlock features installed</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Tap into air line with additional switch for vehicles with air brakes or</para>
                            <para>b) Connect into BC circuit pin F1; Connector 1601 with a 12 volt active signal Air or
                                Hydraulic brake vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into existing air park brake switch electrical circuit b) Exceed 200 ma
                                total.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Trans Warning Output signal for remote panel display</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect wire to ECU circuit 115 for WTC III and circuit 125 for LCT 2000/24000
                                transmission models. Circuit goes open to GND to actuate a remote mounted light. An
                                external relay is required if current is .05 AMPS or greater.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Splice into the transmission harness for signal uses</para>
                            <para>b) Utilize this signal for vehicle shutdown system.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Transmission Interface (Body Builder Connections)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>See the Transmission section in this manual S08323 for Body Builder connection
                                information.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Splice into the transmission harness for signal uses.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Back Up Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Body Builder connectors 4450; Cavity E circuit 71, or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 6 AMPS total circuit</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clearance / Marker Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Body Builder connector 4450; Cavity D circuit 58, or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 AMPS total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dome Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into BC connector 1604; Pin J for output circuit.</para>
                            <para>b) Theater Dimming must be turned off in the BC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into any door switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 10 AMPS total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Fog Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into BC connector 1603; Pin F for the left Fog Lamp and Pin K for the right
                                Fog Lamp output circuit.
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Fog Light accommodation must be added to the BC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into fog light switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 10 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Headlights (including Plow Lights without Plow Light option)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Plow Light 7-way Harness connector provided with optional code 08THJ.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into headlight switch circuit.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 20 AMPS total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Panel Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into panel lamp Bus connector 1002 located behind the Instrument Panel (IP)
                                left of the interior fuse panel.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into panel dimmer switch circuit or Panel light adapter circuit A62N.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 5 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Stop Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Body Builder connector (4450 cavity B and C; circuits 56 left/ 57 right
                                combined) (4460 cavity A and B; circuits 56 left /57 right separate), or connect into
                                tail light harness connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit
                                diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the stop light switch circuit at the brake pedal.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 8 AMPS total.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tail Lights</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into Body Builder connector 4450; Cavity A circuits 68 or connect into tail
                                light harness Connector 9303. Refer to Body Builder Connections and circuit diagrams.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 AMPS Total Circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Turn Signals</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to Body Builder connector (4450 cavity B and C; circuits 56 left/57 right
                                combined) (4460 cavity A and B; circuits 56 left/57 right separate).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to the input side of the turn signal switch or the BC circuit inputs.</para>
                            <para>Exceed 8 AMPS total circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Work Light</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect into BC connector 1603 Pin G Work Light Output circuit.</para>
                            <para>b) Work lamp accommodation must be programmed into the BC.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 10 AMPS.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>RPM Connection</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to Body Builder connectors at the RPM (J3-output circuits and J4- remote
                                inputs). Refer to RPM Section.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Exceed 20 AMPS per channel output with a maximum 80 AMPS total draw per module.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remote mounted Fuel Level (Low Fuel Warning)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install additional fuel sender. Extract fuel gauge data from the Public J1939 data
                                link.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect to fuel level gauge sender circuit or short existing fuel sending unit to
                                chassis GND.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>HVAC Interrupt (A/C compressor clutch and Blower fan interrupts)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Add a secondary A/C Evaporator to cool remote areas by tapping into the refrigerant
                                lines with the authorized hoses. Use only the standard HVAC Control for controlling the
                                A/C system.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into HVAC A/C clutch circuit between the BC and the A/C compressor clutch for
                                purposes of controlling the A/C system. Connect to the high side of the pressure
                                transducer or either of the A/C system thermistors.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clutch switch</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Install additional switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the clutch switch or circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Brake Switch</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>a) Connect to the BC connector 1605 Pin E5 active GND output circuit BC must be
                                programmed with the Separate Stop Feature.
                            </para>
                            <para>b) Install additional switch.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Connect into the brake switch or circuit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BBHDI.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
