<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - General Electrical - HIGH
        VOLTAGE CIRCUITS (GREATER THAN 50 VOLTS) ON INTERNATIONAL TRUCKS AND BUSES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HIGH VOLTAGE CIRCUITS (GREATER THAN 50 VOLTS) ON INTERNATIONAL TRUCKS AND BUSES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, refer to the manufacturer's service
                        information before working on any high voltage equipment. By definition, high voltage circuits
                        and components contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage, electrical shock, and/or
                        electrocution if handled incorrectly.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. When
                    working around or maintaining high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The intent of this section IS to provide some basic guidelines when working on or around
                        International vehicles that are equipped with high voltage electrical equipment and circuits.
                        For specific instructions, maintenance, or service information on specific equipment or options,
                        refer to the service manuals for the specified truck models and component(s). It IS NOT the
                        intent of this section to provide detailed service instructions for high voltage equipment and
                        circuits.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>High voltage systems require the maintainer to be familiar with two types of electrical systems.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">DC (Direct Current)</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>Most DC systems on today's trucks use 12 volt negative GND. Some systems can store DC
                        electricity in batteries with operating voltages as high as 600 DC volts.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AC (Alternating Current)</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The main difference between AC and DC systems is that the voltage levels in DC systems remain
                        constant while the voltage levels in AC systems are constantly changing. When measuring an AC
                        system, it is important to know that the average voltage is zero, and that is why
                        <emph type="boldital">A VOLTMETER SET TO DC WILL NOT INDICATE THE PRESENCE OF AN AC VOLTAGE WHEN
                            CONNECTED TO AN AC CIRCUIT!
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>High voltage can be lethal. Always refer to the manufacturer of the high voltage component when
                maintenance or repairs are needed. In most cases, diagnostics and repair are performed after the high
                voltage circuits are disabled. If working around or maintaining high voltage circuits, please seek high
                voltage training.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, circuits must be checked using a
                        voltmeter for the presence of both DC and AC voltages. A voltmeter set to DC will not indicate
                        the presence of an AC voltage when connected to an AC circuit! Contacting an unknown AC or DC
                        voltage may cause equipment damage, electrical shock, and/or electrocution.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If
                    working around or maintaining high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Understanding High Voltage Equipment and Circuits on International Products</title>
            <para>Some examples of high voltage equipment that can be encountered on products are as follows:</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">- Auxiliary Power Units (APUs)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>APUs are basically small diesel powered generator units that are integrated into the vehicle
                electrical system. APUs are utilized in combination with inverters and battery chargers. APUs are often
                set up to automatically start when the electrical management system deems it necessary to maintain
                battery charge or electrical demand requires it.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>APU high voltage wiring may NOT be marked for easy identification as high voltage.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">- Shore Power</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Shore power is a connection from a vehicle to an external 120 volt AC power source. The vehicle is
                equipped with an exterior receptacle that allows connection to an external "shore" power source.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>High voltage shore power wiring may NOT be marked for easy identification as high voltage.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">- Inverters</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Inverters are electronic devices used to change DC (Direct Current) into AC (Alternating Current).
                Some inverters contain converters that also convert AC to DC for battery charging or running 12V
                equipment.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>High voltage wiring for inverters may NOT be marked for easy identification as high voltage.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">- Hybrid Electric Vehicles (HEVs)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>HEVs combine internal combustion engines with high voltage batteries, electric motors, and inverters
                to offer higher fuel efficiency and lower emissions without compromising power, range, and convenient
                fueling of conventional vehicles. Regardless of the HEV design, high electrical voltages and currents
                are present.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The industry standard for high voltage cables is for the cables to be covered in ORANGE
                        CONDUIT.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If orange conduit is observed on a vehicle, please review the safety precautions for that system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>How to Identify High Voltage Circuits</title>
            <para>High voltage circuits are not always connected with large wires. The best way to identify high voltage
                equipment or circuits is to be familiar with the equipment and circuit diagrams as well as to look for
                high voltage warning labels and orange conduit.
                <emph type="bold">Inspect the vehicle for any equipment or circuits added after the truck was built
                    (owner/operators may add high voltage components such as inverters or APUs).
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>All electrical circuits associated with APUs, shore power, inverters, and HEVs should be considered
                high voltage. The standard for high voltage cabling on HEVs is orange. APUs, inverters, shore power, and
                cabin 110/120V outlet wiring may not indicate high voltage by visual inspection (they may not be marked
                and are NOT orange in color).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Servicing International Products</title>
            <para>The following steps outline the appropriate method to follow to identify and address any maintenance
                or service on International products with factory-installed high voltage equipment.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Complete related training prior to attempting to identify and service any high voltage
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Review the line-set ticket provided with the vehicle or from ISIS, and identify all high
                    voltage components. Inspect the vehicle for any equipment or circuits added after the truck was
                    built (owner/operators may add high voltage components such as inverters or APUs that could be live
                    and powering circuits in the vehicle EVEN WITH THE IGN OFF AND THE BATTERIES DISCONNECTED).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to manufacturer's service publications for identified high voltage components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Physically locate high voltage components on the vehicle and disable them according to
                    manufacturer's instructions (some components may require a waiting period or special procedures to
                    discharge the voltage completely).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use Best Work Practices (see below) when performing work on electrical systems.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Best Work Practices</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, permit only trained responsible and capable persons to
                        operate or maintain the equipment. Carelessly operating or neglecting maintenance despite the
                        safe design of any vehicle and its high voltage equipment may result in personal injury or
                        death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The danger of injury through electrical shock is possible whenever electrical power is
                    present. Most fatal injuries result from high-voltage exposure; however, people can sustain severe
                    injuries from low voltage power if it has a high current flow.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Be aware of ALL high voltage equipment on the vehicle; review line-set/build ticket and the
                        owner and service manuals of high voltage equipment
                        <emph type="bold">BEFORE</emph>
                        starting any work.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When working on this equipment, remain alert at all times. Never work on the equipment when
                        physically or mentally fatigued, and never work alone near high voltage equipment.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Always stand on an insulated, dry surface when working on any electrical circuit. Do not
                        handle any kind of electrical device while standing in water, while barefoot, or while hands or
                        feet are wet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Always work in an adequately illuminated area.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Always use appropriate protective equipment: insulated gloves, rubber gloves, goggles/face
                        shield, safety shoes, protective clothing, and insulated tools when working on electrical
                        components/circuits of the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never wear jewelry when working on this equipment. Jewelry can conduct electricity resulting
                        in electric shock or burns and may get caught in moving components causing injury.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When working on vehicles that have high voltage devices or equipment, use appropriate alerting
                        techniques in plain view to warn people that may be in the general area and to prevent
                        inadvertent activation of any disabled high voltage circuit(s) during service: safety signs,
                        safety symbols, tags, barricades, cones, etc.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Keep a fire extinguisher close by at all times. Extinguishers rated "ABC" by the National Fire
                        Protection Association are appropriate for use on the electrical system. Make sure the
                        extinguisher is properly charged and be familiar with its use. Consult the local fire department
                        with any question pertaining to fire extinguishers.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Ensure that the high voltage power, high voltage power generating equipment, and high voltage
                        storage devices are disconnected, locked out, or otherwise disabled BEFORE working on or around
                        the vehicle, its electrical circuits, or components. Unless disabled, Auxiliary Power Units
                        (APUs) may start at any time without warning; when this occurs, the circuits associated with the
                        APU become energized with potentially lethal high voltage. Some components may require a waiting
                        period or special procedures to discharge the voltage completely.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use an appropriate electrical tester and procedures to confirm that the power is disconnected
                        <emph type="bold">BEFORE performing any work on or near any high voltage components/circuits.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exercise caution around output circuits even when the input power is off. Parallel power
                        sources and energy storage devices can still be dangerous. Be familiar with the high voltage
                        equipment installed on the vehicle. Some systems contain high voltage condensers that may
                        require time to discharge after power is removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After disconnecting or exposing a high-voltage connector or terminal, insulate it immediately
                        using insulation tape.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After completion of any electrical work,
                        <emph type="bold">BEFORE restoring the power, verify that parts and/ or tools are removed from
                            the work area and that the fasteners are firmly tightened to the specified torque and the
                            connectors are correctly connected.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Voltage can be fatal at levels greater than 60 volts. High voltage can jump a
                            larger air gap than low voltage. If contact is made with high voltage, it may not be
                            possible to simply "let go".
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Towing a HEV with its drive wheels on the ground may cause the motor to
                            generate electricity. Consult the operator's/owner's manual for proper towing procedures.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">If a high voltage fuse or circuit protection device trips, do not re-energize
                            the circuit until it has been determined that the circuit is safe. See manufacturer's
                            troubleshooting procedures before servicing a high voltage system.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Reference OSHA Regulations as necessary and applicable.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
