<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built Starting March 1, 2007 - Power Pack 3 for Mobile
        Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="BB60AJN" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="14">
        <title>Power Pack 3 for Mobile Operation</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>60AJN - BDY INTG, POWER INVERTER 3000 Watt Dynamic (With Engine Running); On/Off Switch in Instrument
            Panel (IP); Includes 120 volt AC Wiring; Connection for Customer-Mounted Power Outlet
        </para>
        <para>60AJP - BDY INTG, POWER INVERTER Temporary Mount on Frame Rail for Customer Installation; 3000 Watt
            Dynamic (With Engine Running); On/Off Switch in IP; Includes 120 volt AC Wiring Connection for
            Customer-Mounted Power Outlet
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Shock hazard. Only trained technicians should service high voltage components. High voltage
                    circuits and components contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage, electric shock,
                    and/or deadly electrocution if handled incorrectly.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>DO NOT OPEN the Power Pack 3. Hazardous voltages exist internally even after the Power Pack 3 is
                    removed from the vehicle. Only a Qualified Technician may perform service inside the Power Pack 3.
                    Failure to follow this warning may result in property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Shock Hazard. The alternator may generate high voltage, particularly at high rpm, which can be
                    harmful. Do not touch the 3-phase output terminals. Failure to follow this warning may result in
                    property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Shock Hazard. The alternator output is a hazardous 3-phase AC voltage - Do not cut the cable or
                    touch the terminals. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal
                    injury, or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE / BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The Power Pack 3 Inverter system is an advanced Power Generation and Power Management system to provide
            both DC power and an on-board 120 volt AC power source. The Power Pack 3 system is integrated with the
            Diamond Logic&#61650; Electrical system. The DC portion of the system provides 14 volts DC at a maximum of
            100 Amperes (AMPS) to charge the vehicle batteries. The AC portion of the system provides a 120 VAC single
            phase 60 Hertz output at a maximum of 25 AMPS. The system may be ordered from International,
            factory-installed either mounted in the battery box or as a temporary mounted inverter module behind the
            cab. The body builder is tasked with mounting the inverter in a body compartment with the temporary mounted
            feature.
        </para>
        <para>The Power Pack system consists of an inverter module, a special 3-phase 42 volt AC alternator, a
            multiplexed switch in the cab, and associated wiring harness. The engine must be running in order for the
            Power Pack system to generate AC or DC voltages. The 120 volt AC output is only functional when the vehicle
            is stationary with the park brake set. The 120 volt AC output contains a Ground (GND) fault interrupter
            device and a weather sealed power plug.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If 120 volts AC Shore power is integrated into the body wiring, the shore power connection must
                    never be directly connected to the Power Pack 3 AC output.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0832392" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832392.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="288px"/>
            <caption>Power Pack 3 Block Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0832393" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832393.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"
                     scalefitheight="288px"/>
            <caption>Battery Box Mounted Power Pack 3</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0832394" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832394.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="328px"/>
            <caption>Remote Mount Power Pack 3</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0832364" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832364.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                     scalefitheight="288px"/>
            <caption>AC Derating Curve</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0832365" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832365.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="288px"
                     scalefitheight="288px"/>
            <caption>DC Derating Curve</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">USING POWER PACK 3 WITH REMOTE ENGINE SPEED CONTROL:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Power Pack 3 provides full power output for the 120 volt AC section at any engine speed. Vehicles equipped
            with the mobile version of Power Pack 3 may be used with any of the following engine speed control
            functions.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Preset or variable engine speed control using the steering wheel cruise control switches</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Preset variable or remote pedal/throttle using the Remote Engine Speed Control Module (RESCM).
                    Requires Body Controller (BC) feature 595AHA
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Preset 1 using Remote Power Module (RPM) inputs; i.e., feature code 60AJE</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Preset or variable engine speed control using Diamond Logic&#174; Advanced Ladder Logic</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>12VZA which provides remote engine speed control through hard wires connected directly to the
                    engine ECM.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">Body Controller: Software Feature Codes / Programmable Parameters: Mobile
                Operation
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>Software feature code
            <emph type="bold">595BAH</emph>
            must be enabled on the vehicle Body Controller using the Diamond Logic&#174; Builder software (see local
            dealer).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_Stationary or Mobile:</emph>
            In Stationary mode the AC function can be used only while the trucked is parked with the park brake set.
            Mobile operation enables 120 AC anytime the engine is running. These features are defaulted to Mobile
            Operation.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_Auto ON or Manual ON:</emph>
            Allows the AC power to turn ON automatically each time the vehicle is started. These features are defaulted
            to AUTO ON.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_Auto Restart:</emph>
            Allows the Power Pack to restart should there be an over current situation. The number restart retries and
            duration before the restart is also programmable. These features are defaulted to
            <emph type="bold">Auto Restart ON</emph>
            with
            <emph type="bold">3 retries with 40 seconds</emph>
            between retries.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_ReStart_Attempts:</emph>
            Number of times the Power Pack will attempt to re-start the system after an overload. These features are
            defaulted to
            <emph type="bold">3 retries</emph>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_ReStart_Delay:</emph>
            The amount of time between re-start attempts should there be an over current situation. These features are
            defaulted to
            <emph type="bold">40 seconds</emph>
            between retries.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_param_incrThrottle_rqst_enable</emph>
            will enable the automatic throttle request. This will automatically ramp the engine to the value set in
            parameter 2344 when the Power Pack is requested on. This parameter is defaulted OFF for these features.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_param_incrThrottle_startDelay</emph>
            is the amount of time that the Power Pack will wait to turn on. This is to allow the engine to ramp to the
            operating RPM before the Power Pack is activated. This parameter is defaulted to 2 seconds for these
            features.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_param_incrThrottle_targetRPMs</emph>
            is the target RPM for the engine to ramp to when the Power Pack is activated. This parameter is defaulted to
            935 RPM for these features.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Parameter: PPE3_param_incrThrottle_timeout</emph>
            is the amount of time that the inverter is inhibited from coming back on due to inadequate engine speed.
            This parameter is defaulted to 5 seconds for these features.
        </para>
        <table id="t0832306" tblwidth="pg-wide">
            <title>Programmable Parameters used with 595BAH</title>
            <tgroup cols="8">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.68*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                <colspec colname="col5" align="center" colwidth="0.75*"/>
                <colspec colname="col6" align="center" colwidth="0.74*"/>
                <colspec colname="col7" align="center" colwidth="0.70*"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col7" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Parameter</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>ID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Default</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Units</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Min</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Max</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Step</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ Auto_or_Manual_ ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2473</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this is true, then the AC Power is automatically activated when the engine is
                                started.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>On/Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ mobile_or_ stationary</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2487</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this is true, then the AC Power is available any time the engine is running</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>On/Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ Auto_ReStart</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2488</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this is true, then the Power Pack 3 system will automatically attempt a re-start
                                after an over load event.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>On/Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ ReStart_Attempts</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2490</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This number indicates the number of re-start attempts after an overload event.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Number</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>7</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ ReStart_Delay</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2489</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this is true, then the automatic throttle increase request has been enabled.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>40</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Seconds</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>60</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>10</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ incrThrottle_ requst_enable</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2357</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If this is true, then the automatic throttle increase request has been enabled.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>On/Off</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ incrThrottle_ startDelay</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2399</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This parameter allows the throttle to ramp to the target RPM prior to enabling the
                                PPE. The logic for this parameter is that a maximum load on the PPE would turn off the
                                inverter if the alternator RPMs are not at target.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>2</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Seconds</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ incrThrottle_ targetRPMs</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2344</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>This is the target RPM rate for the throttle increase feature.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>935</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>RPM</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>900</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>2000</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>PPE3_param_ incrThrottle_ timeout</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2345</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The amount of time until the inverter is inhibited because the engine speed is not at
                                an adequate level
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>Seconds</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>30</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>0.1</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>All electrical connections to the Power Pack 3 must be made by a qualified electrician. Failure to
                    follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>A Hubbell Watertight Safety-Shroud male plug (Hubbell part number HBL2611SW) is needed to connect to the
            AC output plug to mate with the Power Pack supplied Hubbell Watertight Safety-Shroud female socket (Hubbell
            part number HBL2613SW). These plugs are available at electrical and industrial supply houses.
        </para>
        <para>Using this part combination will allow for a weather resistant connection to the Power Pack 3 unit.
            Alteration of the AC output plug, failure to use the correct male plug, or removal of the supplied socket
            will not guarantee a watertight connection.
        </para>
        <para>The AC output from the Power Pack 3 is wired to a Ground Fault Circuit Interrupter (GFCI) to ensure
            protection against GND fault conditions. Be aware that standard duplex GFCI and non-GFCI receptacles need to
            be protected with a circuit breaker, usually rated for 15 or 20 AMPS.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0832366" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832366.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="288px"/>
            <caption>Power Pack 3 Inverter/Regulator Component Detail</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Power Pack 3 Kit, Left Side under Cab for vehicles built after March 2007.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Power Pack 3 Kit, Right Side under Cab for vehicles built after March 2007.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Power Pack 3 Kit, Remote Mount for vehicles built after March 2007.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Fuse, 58 volt, 10 amp: Alternator Field Wire fuse. International Part Number: 2590768C1
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">TESTING SYSTEM OPERATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Start the engine. Verify that the batteries are being charged. The voltmeter should be reading
                    greater than 13.5 volts.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify green light in rocker switch is ON solid within five seconds.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify 120 volt AC output voltage.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <figure id="f0832397" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832397.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                     scalefitheight="128px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Power Pack 3 Troubleshooting</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If the Power Pack 3 output does not power up or shuts down during vehicle operation, follow these steps to
            troubleshoot the system:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Set the 120VAC ON/OFF switch to OFF position, and ensure interlocks are satisfied, as described
                    above, correcting as necessary.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Attempt to restart the Power Pack 3 by pressing the ON switch.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the unit continues to shut-down, (blinking green light in the rocker switch and red warning
                    light illuminated) disconnect any AC loads before restarting the Power Pack 3.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Check for green light on GFCI. If there is a red light press the reset button on GFCI.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Press the 120VAC switch to OFF, check the 30-Amp circuit breaker, and reset if necessary.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wait several minutes to allow the system alternator and Power Pack 3 unit to cool, and then
                    attempt to restart.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the unit does not restart, then turn the vehicle's ignition OFF, and then back ON again. This
                    will restart the Power Pack 3 output protection circuits.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the above steps fail to restart the Power Pack 3 unit, then have the system serviced by a
                    qualified technician.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the unit does not restart, the problem could be caused by overheating or other circuit
                    protection devices. If the Power Pack 3 circuit breaker or the GFCI device is tripped, the green
                    light in rocker switch will continue to show an indication that AC power is ON. Be advised to check
                    these other elements of the system if 120 volt AC power is not present as expected.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Indications Using the In-Cab Rocker Switch or Diamond Logic&#174; Builder
            </emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f0832367" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832367.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="562px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A complete after market parts kit is under development. The Power Pack 3 kit part number is not
                    available at this time.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW TO ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove power from batteries.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the lid from the battery box.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove all battery cables from the batteries and battery box, starting with the negative
                    terminals.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the 3 battery box with a 4 battery box.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove cab steps from the battery box.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the front side of the battery box.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove all batteries.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove old battery box from the frame rail.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove any options that may be on box, and transfer to new box.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach new 4 battery box to the frame rail. Some new mounting holes may need drilled in
                    the frame rail. Re-use existing holes as much as possible.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Add cover hold downs, and add new box to frame. 777937C1 retainers, 934871R1 nuts,
                    30278R1 screws, 30264R1 washers.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Put batteries in the two forward locations of the 4 battery box.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the Power Pack 3 Inverter Module in the most rearward location of the battery
                    box. Align the PP3 module such that the mounting stud on the rear panel of the module projects
                    through the rear of the battery box.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the PP3 harnesses are carefully routed through the openings in the rear
                    panel of the battery box without kinking or pinching.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach the battery box hold down bracket to secure the batteries and the PP3 Inverter
                    Module.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach the retainer nut to the PP3 module stud on the back side of the battery box.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach vent tubes to each battery, and route out of battery box.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832368" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832396.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Sample Inverter on Installation on the Driver's Side of the Vehicle</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add new alternator.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove air filter and
                    <emph type="bold">cover turbo intake to prevent items from falling into intake</emph>.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove serpentine belt and old alternator.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Tie off old cables.</para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Seal terminal ends with heat shrink tube, fold back onto trunk of harness, and tape to trunk
                        of harness.
                    </para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach the Leece-Neville alternator (part number 3606039C91) to the engine. Transfer
                    belt pulley from old alternator to the new alternator.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check alternator mounting bolt torque. DO NOT OVER TORQUE.</para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Alternator to bracket mounting bolts 30 to 35 lb ft</para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Add new alternator harness overlay.</para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Route the PP3 harness next to existing engine harness to the starter; then follow battery
                        cables to the battery box.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>At base of battery box, route inverter cables to back of battery box by going under the frame
                        rail.
                    </para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use tie wraps, every 12 inches, to attach the alternator harness to the battery
                    cables.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Alternator Harness</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The harness from the Power Pack 3 to the alternator must be properly routed and securely fastened
                    to avoid any hot or sharp areas and to prevent cable movement. Failure to use the proper size wire
                    can result in overheating conditions that could cause fire, personal injury, and void of warranty.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Add Ignition (IGN) lead to the in-cab fuse relay panel.</para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect an 18 gauge wire from the Power Pack 3 IGN feed connector to the dash pass thru
                        connector 1702 pin 5.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect an 18 gauge wire from the dash pass thru connector 1702 pin 5 to an IGN feed in the
                        cab fuse/relay panel cavity G2-H2 (see fuse box detail).
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Add 10 AMP fuse to fuse locations G2-H2.</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect to inverter overlay harness (connector 9740 at the center of valve cover). Strap lock
                        the connector to the main center chassis harness.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Remove terminating resistor from J1939 datalink back bone harness (connector 7801M located on
                        the top center of the engine valve cover). Connect the PP3 J1939 datalink harness (connector
                        7801M) to J1939 inverter (connector 7801N). Save J1939 terminator resistor assembly.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Strap harness to existing harnesses.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Keep clear of sharp edges or anything that can rub or damage wire
                            insulation.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect harness wires to the alternator.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach 3-Phase AC output ring terminal wires to bolt studs on the back of alternator.
                    80-120 in lb (inch-pounds, NOT foot-pounds) Three phase wire attachment order to the alternator does
                    not matter.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Attach field coil wires to the top of alternator using two nuts 15-20
                    <emph type="bold">in lb</emph>
                    (inch- pounds, NOT foot-pounds).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832369" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832369.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>3-Phase and Field Wire Alternator Connections</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make connections from the Power Pack 3 wire harness to the inverter module.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">At back of the battery box:</para>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect 3-Phase AC alternator connectors (9741, 9742, 9743) which are large 4 gauge, 1-pin
                        connectors. Ensure the connectors are fully mated with a positive click of the male connector
                        into the female connector.
                    </para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect inverter IGNITION connector (7899) 1-pin connector.</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect inverter J1939 connector (7801R) 3-pin connector.</para>
                </step3>
                <step3>
                    <para>Connect field voltage connector (9740) 2-pin connector.</para>
                </step3>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect terminating resistor connector to (7801L) located on inverter harness near
                    inverter connection to the J1939 data bus connector.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure Power Pack 3 harness to the chassis harness.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Keep harness clear of sharp edges or anything that can rub or damage wire insulation.
                    Use tie wraps every 12 inches to attach the PP3 alternator harness to battery cables.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Confirm connections.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cloth from air intake, and reinstall air filter.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Shock Hazard. Never make electrical connections to a "live" unit. Make the connections to the
                        Power Pack 3 first and the batteries last. Failure to follow this warning may result in property
                        damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Installing battery cables</para>
            <para>Step 1:&#9;Make sure that the batteries are disconnected from the vehicle.</para>
            <para>Step 2: &#9;Install the in-line fuse on the positive battery terminal or within 18 inches of the
                battery or DC wiring bus system.
            </para>
            <para>Step 3:&#9;Route, but DO NOT connect, the positive DC (red) input cable from the Power Pack 3 to the
                in-line fuse on the battery or DC wiring bus system. Make sure to protect all cables from where they
                contact hard or sharp edges.
            </para>
            <para>Step 4: &#9;
                <emph type="bold">Connect the Power Pack 3 to the battery in THIS order.</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Install washers and nuts, and torque terminal nuts. (120 inch-pounds)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect red cables to the positive battery posts.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect black cables to the negative battery posts.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Step 5:&#9;Verify that all connections are tight and the cables are secure.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">General Cable Installation Tips:</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Fire and Explosion Hazard. Double check the polarity of the DC input connections. Reverse
                        polarity may severely damage the Power Pack 3. Fire and/or explosion of the batteries may also
                        occur as a result of reversed polarity. Failure to follow this warning may result in property
                        damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>DC cables should be as short as possible. The optional installation kit includes all DC cables. The
                Power Pack 3 is polarity sensitive, and careful attention must be paid to the polarity. The black DC
                cable must be connected to the battery negative (-) and the negative (-) Power Pack 3 terminal, located
                under the top cover (orange).
            </para>
            <para>The red DC cable must be connected to the fuse which is connected to the positive (+) battery
                connection and the positive (+) Power Pack 3 terminal, located under the red cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832370" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832370.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Fuse Wiring</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Route the AC power wiring separately from the DC wiring and low voltage wiring such as audio and video
            signal wires with as much physical separation from the AC wires as possible.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Fire Hazard. Make sure all connections are tight and properly made. Failure to follow this warning
                    may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>An in-line 150 AMP DC fuse is REQUIRED on the positive battery cable to properly protect the Power
                    Pack 3 and batteries. Failure to properly fuse the input leads to the Power Pack 3 can result in
                    damage to the unit.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Add switch to switch pack.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Removal/Replacement of Switches and Switch Packs</emph>
            </para>
            <para>To remove a switch pack from the IP, use the DIN radio removal tool part number 2504954C1.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0832371" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832371.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Insert the extraction tools (2) into the two holes on either side of a switch pack housing until the
            locking tabs are fully depressed. The switch pack can then be removed from the panel and the extraction
            tools removed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0832372" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832372.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To remove individual switches or blanks from a switch pack, squeeze the locking tabs on the rear of the
            switch or blank (top and bottom) and push it from the housing.
        </para>
        <para>To install a switch pack in the panel, make the necessary connections, then simply push the assembly into
            place until the locking tabs are fully engaged.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The switch pack can be inadvertently installed upside down. To avoid this when no switches are
                    present in the housing, make sure the white wire in the lead assemblies on the rear of the housing
                    are towards the top.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0832373" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg08/g0832373.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To install a switch in the switch pack housing, insert the switch in the proper slot, and push in until
            the switch locking tabs are fully engaged (switches are keyed and cannot be installed upside down).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">LED Installation</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The LEDs are installed from the rear of the switch housing (snap fit rear cover must first be removed).
            The amber backlight LED (part number 3533928C1) must be installed in the lower position and the green
            indicator LED (part number 3578733C1) in the upper position. The LEDs can be identified by the color of the
            base - black for the amber LED and white for the green LED.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">To install an LED, insert it into the hole in the printed wiring board and, with a small
                flat blade screwdriver, turn the LED clockwise until locked. Replace the rear cover when complete.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Program Vehicle.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Using DLB, activate feature 0595AJU "BC PROG, INVERTER ON In-Cab Multiplex Switch
                    enables 3kw Inverter."
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">After 0595AJU is activated, use DLB to locate position for 120 volt on switch location.
                    Make note of location for switch install. Exit DLB.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Checking system operation</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Start engine, and ensure that the park brake is set.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Verify that the batteries are being charged. Voltmeter should be reading greater than
                    13.5 volts.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Verify green light in rocker switch is ON solid within 5 seconds.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check 120 volt AC output voltage.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB60AAC.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323_BB60ACX.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08323.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
