<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - Electrical Features -
        Battery, Ignition and Accessory Taps - 60AAC - International&#174; Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="BB60AAC" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>60AAC - International&#174; Diamond Logic&#174; PowerPack 3</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE CODE DESCRIPTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>60AAC - BODY INTG, POWER INVERTER - 3000 Watt dynamic (with engine running), on/off switch in instrument
            panel and includes 120 volt AC wiring connection for customer mounted power outlet.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">FEATURE / BODY FUNCTION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This feature provides heavy duty mobile AC power (up to 3000 Watts with a 5000 Watt surge capability) for
            power tools, lights, pumps and compressors.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The surge capability may
                    <emph type="underscr">not</emph>
                    be sufficient to start all makes/models of compressors.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The pure sine wave output also provides the necessary requirements for sensitive equipment such as
            computers and test equipment.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">SOFTWARE FEATURE CODES / PROGRAMMABLE PARAMETERS:</emph>
            NONE
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">WIRING INFORMATION:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This feature is factory installed along with special alternator, 08GGC. The wiring that must be done to
            complete this feature involves location and of the 120 VAC GFCI, circuit breaker and ground.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>All electrical wiring and connections should be performed by a licensed, qualified electrician.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    <emph type="boldundersc">DO NOT OPEN</emph>
                    the PowerPack 3. Potentially fatal electric shock and/or serious damage may result even after the
                    PowerPack 3 is removed from the vehicle. Only a Qualified Technician may perform service inside the
                    PowerPack 3. Failure to comply could result in injury including death and will void the warranty.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">Preliminary Considerations:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Output Voltage: The AC output voltage of the PowerPack 3 is 120 VAC, 25 Amps, 60 Hz, single phase,
                    3 wire.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>AC wire size selection: To properly size the AC output wiring, use wire that is rated for 30 Amps.
                    Failure to use cable of large enough gauge may result in over temperature conditions, fire or
                    personal injury and damage due to improper cable size. This condition is not covered under warranty.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The AC output plug (Hubbell inline socket) is connected to the back side of the PowerPack 3 as the
                    end of a 4 foot pigtail. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f60AAC001">PowerPack 3 Wiring Diagram</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>To connect to the AC output plug, you will need a Hubbell Watertight Safety-Shroud mail plug
                    (Hubbell part No. HBL2611SW) to mate to the supplied Hubbell Watertight Safety-Shroud female socket
                    (Hubbell part No. HBL2613SW). Using this part combination will allow for a weather resistant
                    connection to the unit. Alteration of the AC output plug, failure to use the correct mail plug, or
                    removal of the supplied socket will not guarantee a watertight connection and will void the
                    warranty.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The power distribution circuits must be designed to prevent AC power feeding back from an external
                    source (shore power or a generator) into the PowerPack 3 AC output. Failure to appropriately
                    safeguard this connection is not covered under warranty.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The AC output from the PowerPack 3 is wired to a Ground Fault Circuit Interrupter (GFCI) to ensure
                    protection against ground fault conditions. Be aware that standard duplex GFCI and non-GFCI
                    receptacles need to be protected with a circuit breaker, usually rated for 15 or 20 Amps.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The ground terminal in the AC output wiring compartment must be tied to chassis ground for safety
                    to prevent possible shock hazards. Damage due to improper grounding will void the warranty. Make
                    sure a #8 AWG or larger wire is connected.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Reverse feeding AC voltage into the Power Pack 3 will cause damage to the unit.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Failure to have a connection from the PowerPack 3 to the vehicle's grounding system may result in
                    a LETHAL shock hazard.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f60AAC001" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg60/G60AAC001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="432px"/>
            <caption>PowerPack 3 Wiring Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">AC Wiring Procedure:</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Locate and install properly rated GFCI and circuit breaker.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect the wiring - Hubbell part No. HBL2611SW plug to the circuit breaker and GFCI. Ensure that
                    all wiring is properly sized and protected from moving parts, sharp edges, etc.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect the bonding lug to ground. Use a #10 AWG or larger copper conductor to connect the ground
                    terminal to the chassis of the vehicle, the installation's grounding system, or to the earth ground.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect to the AC output.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify the installation. Verify all connections are tight and secure for maximum performance.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para></para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">TESTING:</emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set the park brake and start the engine.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn on the PowerPack 3 from dash mounted switch.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that 120 VAC is present at the output GFCI.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refer to the Owner's Manual provided with this feature for troubleshooting procedures.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">HOW DO I ADD THIS FEATURE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This is a factory installed feature.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_BB08WAD.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
