<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Body Builder Electrical Data Book for Models Built January 2001 to February 28, 2007 - International&#174;
        Diamond Logic&#8482; Electrical System Overview - Remote Power Module (RPM)
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Remote Power Module (RPM)</title>
        <para>Remote Power Modules provide a method of distributing and controlling power to various device loads on the
            vehicle, outside the cab, without running high current wires from in-cab switches to the loads or splicing
            into existing wiring.
        </para>
        <figure id="f7300015" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300006.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The RPM is connected to the Electrical System Controller (ESC) via the Body Builder J1939 data link (the
            ESC is capable of controlling up to three RPM's on the vehicle). The only wires connected to the RPM are
            battery power for driving the loads, the data link cable and connections to the load devices being operated
            by the RPM. Power is fed to the RPM through a fusible link to the battery source. Each RPM has 6
            independently controllable, 20 Amp outputs (80 maximum per RPM) with virtual (software programmable) fusing
            similar to the ESC. If higher current capacity is needed, two outputs can be paralleled or the RPM can
            control a high current relay while still maintaining logic and diagnostic capability without having to wire
            to the inside of the cab.
        </para>
        <para>Because the RPM is connected to the ESC via the data link, it also serves as an "integration gateway" to
            the ESC and the vehicle electrical system. Six inputs on each RPM allow information from body accessories to
            be communicated to the ESC and processed for interlocks, operator information/warning, etc. These inputs
            also allow the Body Builder to add body-mounted switches to turn on or off the same electrical devices
            controlled by in-cab switches.
        </para>
        <para>Additional information concerning the use and installation of RPM's is contained in the applicable Feature
            sections that follow (see 60AAA / 60AAB in particular for detailed data on RPM connectors/pin functions,
            wiring and mounting).
        </para>
        <para>The following is an example of how a vehicle electrical system might be configured.</para>
        <figure id="f7300016" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg73/G7300007.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption></caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The International&#174; Diamond Logic&#8482; electrical system, along with ICAP&#8482; and the new Diamond
            Logic&#8482; Builder software, provide the body builder with an unprecedented flexibility in adding and
            customizing the electrical features on a vehicle.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300_SBB7300003.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s08300.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
