<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HOOD, GRILLE, FENDERS, AND BUMPER - PROSTAR&#8482; - REMOVE AND INSTALL PROCEDURES - Hood and fender
        panels
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="Remove and Install" graphiccount="13">
        <title>Hood and fender panels</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f09011134" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901134.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Hood/Fender Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RIGHT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. RIGHT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. HOOD HINGE ROD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid possible personal injury, wear protective clothing, use safety glasses, face mask,
                        and rubber gloves during this procedure. Use a NIOSH or MSHA approved respirator to avoid
                        breathing dust and fumes. Work in a separate area away from other operations.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>All panels of the hood replace in a similar manner. This procedure covers replacement of the
                        left fender section. The same steps can be followed to replace the other hood panels.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">MATERIALS AND EQUIPMENT REQUIRED</emph>
            </para>
            <para>To complete the removal and replacement of the left fender section, the following materials and
                equipment will be necessary;
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Fusor repair adhesive</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>adhesive application gun</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>heat gun (250 degrees)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>putty knife and hammer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>C-clamps</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>180-grit sandpaper</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>clean rags</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>masking tape</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>cutting disk and/or saw</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>face mask</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>rubber gloves.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Before performing this procedure, remove the hood and place in a secure place to prevent damage to the
                hood. Refer to
                <emph type="bold">Hood - Removal</emph>
                procedures in this manual.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hood and Fender Panel - Removal</title>
            <para>Before removing the left fender section, certain hood/fender components will have to be removed, such
                as the headlight assembly, splash shield, hood mirror, and sound insulation. Remove the necessary
                components at this time.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0901135" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901135.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Cut Fender Section Away</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CUT LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside the hood, mark a reference cut line along the left fender section as close
                    as possible to the hood top panel, front hood support, and left hood reinforcement panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a saw and/or cutting disk to cut along the entire cut line and remove the left
                    fender section from the hood top panel, front hood support, and left hood reinforcement panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901136" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901136.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Fender Section Cut Out</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CUT LINES</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark four cut lines along the remaining left fender section at the left hood
                    reinforcement.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be careful not to cut into the left hood reinforcement panel.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a cutting disk, score through the left fender section remaining at the left hood
                    reinforcement panel. This will make it easier to heat and remove the remaining left fender section
                    pieces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901137" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901137.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Fender Section Removal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEFT FRONT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a heat gun, apply heat to the remaining left fender section pieces at the left
                    hood reinforcement panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and putty knife and work the putty knife between the left fender section
                    pieces and the left hood reinforcement panel to remove the remaining left fender section pieces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901138" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901138.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Cut Fender Section Pieces</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD HINGE ROD MOUNT BOLTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CUT LINES</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LEFT FRONT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove three bolts from the left fender section and front hood support.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark four cut lines along the remaining left fender section at the front hood support.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be careful not to cut into the front hood support.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a cutting disk, cut out the fender section and score through the fender section
                    remaining at the front hood support. This will make it easier to heat and remove the remaining left
                    front fender section pieces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901139" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901139.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Remaining Fender Section Pieces</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEFT FRONT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a heat gun, apply heat to the remaining left fender section pieces at the front
                    hood support.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be careful not to crack the front hood support while working the putty knife between the left
                        fender section pieces and front hood support.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a hammer and putty knife and work the putty knife between the left fender section
                    pieces and the front hood support to remove the remaining left front fender section pieces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901140" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901140.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Fender Section at Hood Top and Side Hood Support</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEFT FENDER SECTION PIECE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be careful not to crack the hood top panel.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Starting at the rear edge of the hood/fender assembly, use a heat gun to heat the left
                    fender section piece from inside the hood top panel. Push a putty knife between the hood top panel
                    and the left fender section piece to separate them. Work toward the front hood support at the front
                    of the hood.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be careful not to crack the hood top panel while working the putty knife between the hood top
                        panel and the left fender section piece.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Where the left fender section piece is bonded to both the left hood reinforcement panel
                    and top hood panel, heat will also need to be applied to the hood top panel. Be careful not to apply
                    to much heat to the hood top panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue to apply heat to both the left fender section piece and front hood support. Use
                    the putty knife and pliers to work the left fender section piece out from between the front hood
                    support and hood top panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901141" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901141.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Clean Surfaces</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADHESIVE SURFACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the damaged fender section is completely removed, use a sanding disk and clean the
                    remaining adhesive. Remove all adhesive from the front hood support, left hood reinforcement panel,
                    and inside surface of hood top panel where the new fender section will be secured with adhesive.
                    Then, with a lint-free cloth and alcohol, clean these surfaces and scuff with 180-grit sandpaper.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901142" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901142.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Scuff These Surfaces</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. INSIDE MATING SURFACES</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. OUTSIDE MATING SURFACES</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NEW FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clean, lint-free cloth and alcohol to clean the surfaces on both the inside and
                    outside of the new left fender section where it will be secured with adhesive to the front hood
                    support, hood top panel, and left hood reinforcement panel. Scuff these surfaces with 180-grit
                    sandpaper.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clean, dry, lint-free cloth to wipe any loose fiberglass and dust from the front
                    hood support, hood top panel, left hood reinforcement panel and the new left fender section before
                    applying the adhesive.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hood and Fender Panel - Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Avoid contact with eyes, skin, and clothing. Avoid breathing vapor or mist. Do not breathe
                        dust. Use with adequate ventilation and appropriate breathing apparatus. Refer to Fusor
                        Corporate Material Safety Data Sheet before using this material. Fusor may be contacted by
                        calling 1-800-234-Fusor. More information can be found on the ISIS &#174; Web site (Supplier&#8594;
                        Fusor).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0901143" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901143.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Fit New Fender</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. MASKING TAPE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before applying adhesive to any components, slide the new left fender section into
                    position on the hood and check the fit. Use clamps to hold the new left fender section in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply masking tape vertically on the front hood support and along the front of the left
                    fender section to aid in the cleanup of excessive adhesive.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply masking tape horizontally on the left fender section and the hood top panel,
                    starting at the front edge of the fender section and hood top panel to the rear edge of each panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the left fender section from the hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901144" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901144.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Apply Adhesive</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADHESIVE POINTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LEFT HOOD REINFORCEMENT PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Fusor adhesive to all mating surfaces with the left fender section on the front
                    hood support, left hood reinforcement panel, and hood top panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the adhesive has been applied, with assistance from a coworker, position the front
                    of the new fender section between the front hood support and the top hood panel. Position the offset
                    of the left fender section behind the hood top panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901145" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901145.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Adhesive Clean Up</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HOOD TOP PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ADHESIVE SEAMS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clamp the left fender section in place along the front hood support, at the rear of the
                    top hood panel, and bottom of the left hood reinforcement panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a piece of plastic or wood to remove the excess adhesive from the seam between the
                    top of the hood and the new fender section. Also, remove excess adhesive from the front hood support
                    and the front of the left fender section before it starts to cure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the masking tape from the left fender section, front hood support, and top hood
                    panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0901146" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0901146.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Fender\Hood Hinge Mount Holes</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LEFT FENDER SECTION</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FRONT HOOD SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MOUNT HOLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HOOD HINGE ROD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the hood hinge rod as a template and, from inside the hood assembly, drill three
                    holes through the left fender section for mounting the hood hinge rod to the left fender section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the left fender section to the front hood support and hood hinge rod with three
                    bolts and nuts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0901138">Figure 36</hotlnk>). Torque bolts to 21 to 27 lbf-ft (28 to 37 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow the adhesive to cure for at least four hours before removing the clamps.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>At 70&#176;F/21&#176;C, the adhesive will fully cure in 24 to 48 hours (or 1 hour at 140&#176;F/60&#176;C).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the adhesive has cured properly, install the headlight assembly, splash shield,
                    hood mirror, and sound insulation as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the hood on the vehicle. Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Hood - Installation</emph>
                    procedures in this manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09011_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09011_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
