<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HOOD, GRILLE, FENDERS AND BUMPER - 7000 - REMOVE AND INSTALL - FENDERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
        <title>FENDERS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FENDERS - REMOVE</title>
            <para>The 7000 Series fender assemblies are comprised of multiple components: the air intake frame, the
                upper fender section, the wheel well opening " valance", headlights, clearance lights and lower hood
                latch. To remove the valance and headlight assemblies; the grille and shroud should be removed first.
                The fender sections consist of three separate assemblies, the fender top section, the fender extension
                and the valance. The valance depending on chassis configuration, is supplied in two different
                variations. The standard for 7300 series is the set forward axle, the variation for 7400, 7500 and 7600
                chassis can be either valance assembly (
                <hotlnk document="s09007_9.xml" xrefid="f0900709">Figure 9, Item 4 and 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0900738" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0900738.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="272px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Fender Assembly And Related Parts (Drivers Side Shown)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOOD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR INLET OPENING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FENDER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. VALANCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HEADLAMP/DIRECTIONAL HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. GRILLE SHROUD MOUNTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. OPTIONAL HOOD HATCH</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FENDER LOWER SECTION - REMOVE</title>
            <para>The 7000 Series fender upper section is bonded to the hood assembly. The lower fender section or
                "valance" encapsulates the headlight housing and wheel well. The Valance is a separate assembly and can
                be removed. The 7000 series valance may be one of two valance assemblies available. The valance for the
                7300 series chassis is the shorter version due to the set forward axle application. The 7400 and 7500
                may have either the set back or set forward axle depending on the chassis application. Check the axle
                location to determine which valance is applicable. The 7600 series valance has a set forward axle
                application which requires a shorter valance assembly (
                <hotlnk document="s09007_9.xml" xrefid="f0900709">Figure 9, Items 4 and 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0900739" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg09/G0900739.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Valance and Spacer Panels (Spacer Panels 7600 only)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FENDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. VALANCE MOUNTING HOLE AND CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. VALANCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HEADLIGHT/DIRECTIONAL HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LOWER VALANCE SPACER PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the valance mounting bolts under headlight housing and fender assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove the valance mounting screws from the mounting tabs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the fender valance.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fender Valance and Wheel Well Fenderette- Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the valance mounting screws located in the mounting holes along the inside flange
                    between the fender flange and the valance flange assembly.
                </para>
                <para>Wheel well fenderette removal, (if supplied) refer to Figure 66.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Locate mounting bolts and nut along valance and fender extension.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loosen and remove forward fenderette section bolts with hood tilted.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove rubber fenderette.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove rear section bolts and nuts.</para>
                    <para>Follow the same procedure for the opposite side fenderette removal.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fender Lower Section and Valance -Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Beginning with the valance assembly, locate the mounting holes in the fender flange.
                    Align the valance assembly mounting holes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0900739">Figure 39, Item 2</hotlnk>) in position with the holes in the fender
                    flange.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the screws and tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the valance and headlight assembly lower mounting holes and insert the mounting
                    screws into the valance and headlight assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is supplied with optional wheel well fenderettes, follow procedures:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the rear fenderette mounting hole with mounting holes in fender extension.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert mounting bolts and tighten as required.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place forward fenderette at valance and align mounting holes.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert bolts and tighten as required.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Follow same procedure for opposite side valance and fenderette install.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09007_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09007_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s09007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
