<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Exhaust System - Exhaust System - Exhaust System Diagnosis and Testing</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Exhaust System Diagnosis and Testing</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection and Verification</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify the concern by running the engine (with the vehicle on the ground) or road
                    testing the vehicle to duplicate the condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the components of the exhaust system and related controls that may
                    affect exhaust gas quality or loss of power.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect for obvious signs of mechanical damage. Refer to the following chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0900007">
                <title>Visual Inspection Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.96*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Mechanical</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust pipe pinched or crushed</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Damaged catalytic converter and muffler assembly</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Broken or damaged exhaust hanger brackets</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Cracked exhaust manifold</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Dirty engine air cleaner</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para></para>
            <para></para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the exhaust system is installed correctly, with the coupling correctly
                    located and tightened to specification.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the fault is not visually evident, determine the symptom. GO to the Symptom Chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symptom Chart</title>
            <table id="t0900008" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Symptom Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.07*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Possible Sources</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Action</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Rattle, squeaks or buzz type noise - from the bottom of vehicle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Loose or damaged exhaust isolators.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Damaged exhaust isolator hanger bracket.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Loose or damaged catalytic converter and muffler assembly.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust grounded to chassis.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK to make sure the exhaust isolators are correctly installed. INSPECT
                                            the exhaust isolators for wear or damage. INSTALL new isolators as
                                            necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the exhaust system components for damage or broken hangers.
                                            INSTALL new components as necessary. CHECK for loose or damaged exhaust
                                            hanger brackets or fasteners. TIGHTEN the bolts to specification or INSTALL
                                            new components as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MOVE the exhaust system to simulate the bouncing action of the vehicle,
                                            checking for exhaust-to-body contact while moving the exhaust system. Using
                                            a rubber mallet, TAP on the exhaust components to duplicate the noise
                                            concern. Lightly tap on the catalytic converter and muffler assembly.
                                            Determine if there are loose or broken baffles in the muffler, or a loose or
                                            broken element in the catalytic converter. REPAIR or INSTALL a new component
                                            as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT for signs of exhaust components-to-body contact. If necessary,
                                            CARRY OUT the Exhaust System Alignment in this section.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Drone or clunk type noise - from bottom of vehicle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Loose or damaged exhaust isolators.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust grounded to chassis.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the exhaust isolators for wear or damage. INSTALL new isolators as
                                            necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT for signs of exhaust components-to-body contact. If necessary,
                                            CARRY OUT the Exhaust System Alignment in this section.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Whistles, boom, hum or ticking type noise - noise tends to change as engine warms.
                                    Noises are often accompanied by exhaust fumes
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Punctures in the muffler.</para>
                                        <para>Broken, loose or missing exhaust manifold fasteners or gaskets.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust system leak.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Catalytic converter and muffler assembly.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>REPAIR as necessary.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the entire exhaust system for leaks. CHECK for punctures, loose or
                                            damaged clamps/fasteners or broken welds. EXAMINE the chassis for
                                            grayish-white or black exhaust soot, which would indicate exhaust leakage at
                                            that point. To magnify a small leak, have an assistant hold a rag over the
                                            tailpipe outlet, while listening for a leak. REPAIR or INSTALL new
                                            components as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>MOVE the exhaust system to simulate the bouncing action of the vehicle,
                                            checking for exhaust-to-body contact while moving the exhaust system. Using
                                            a rubber mallet, TAP on the exhaust components to duplicate the noise
                                            concern. Lightly TAP on the catalytic converter and muffler assembly.
                                            DETERMINE if there are loose or broken baffles in the muffler, or a loose or
                                            broken element in the catalytic converter. REPAIR or INSTALL a new component
                                            as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Hissing or rushing noise - high frequency sound. Vehicle performance is
                                    unaffected
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Exhaust system. Exhaust flow through pipes.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>CHECK the exhaust system for leaks. Using a rubber mallet, TAP on the exhaust
                                    components to duplicate the noise concern. Lightly TAP on the catalytic converter
                                    and muffler assembly. DETERMINE if there are loose or broken baffles in the muffler,
                                    or a loose or broken element in the catalytic converter. REPAIR or INSTALL new
                                    components as necessary.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pinging noise - occurs when exhaust system is hot, engine turned off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Catalytic converter and muffler assembly/exhaust system.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cool down pinging is the exhaust system expanding and contracting during heating
                                    and cooling. Condition is normal.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vibration - occurs at idle and at low speeds. Also accompanied by clunk or buzz
                                    type noise
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Loose or damaged exhaust isolators.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Loose or damaged exhaust isolator hanger brackets.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust system grounded to chassis.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the exhaust isolators for wear or damage. INSTALL new isolators as
                                            necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the exhaust isolator hanger brackets for wear or damage. INSTALL
                                            or REPAIR as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CARRY OUT the Exhaust System Alignment in this section.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vehicle has low or no power - vehicle performance complaint</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Exhaust pipe pinched or crushed.</para>
                                        <para>Damaged catalytic converter and muffler assembly.</para>
                                        <para>Loose obstruction in exhaust.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Restricted exhaust (possible frozen condensate in muffler).</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>GO to Pinpoint Test A to test for restricted exhaust.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>PARK the vehicle inside to thaw. TEST the vehicle for normal operation. If
                                            concern is still present, GO to Pinpoint Test A.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Burning smell - usually occurs at idle, with possible traces of smoke</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Foreign material caught in exhaust system.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>INSPECT the exhaust system for foreign material or missing heat shields. REPAIR or
                                    INSTALL new components as necessary.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Visible rust on surface of exhaust pipes</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Catalytic converter and muffler assembly/exhaust system.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Surface rust is a characteristic of materials used on exhaust systems. Exposure to
                                    heat or road salt may result in surface rust. INSPECT for perforations. If there are
                                    no perforations, condition is normal.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pinpoint Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The vehicle can have a lack/loss of power, odor, a noise or a "no start" concern. These
                        concerns may be related to the exhaust system. Carry out the following test, if no trouble codes
                        were stored. This test is for diagnosing the source for these conditions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t0900050" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>PINPOINT TEST A: RESTRICTED EXHAUST SYSTEM TEST</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.14*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.86*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Test Step</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Result / Action to Take</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">A1 EXHAUST SYSTEM INSPECTION</emph>
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Inspect the exhaust system for damage or deterioration. Look for cracks,
                                            punctures, leaks, loose connections, dents or unusual bending.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Is the exhaust system OK?</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Yes</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>GO to A2.</para>
                                <para></para>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">No</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>REPAIR or INSTALL any damaged or deteriorated exhaust components. TEST the system
                                    for normal operation.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">A2 BACK PRESSURE TEST</emph>
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Position the vehicle on a hoist. Refer to Jacking and Lifting in S10019.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Remove the catalytic converter and muffler assembly. Refer to Exhaust
                                            System in this section.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Start the engine and gradually increase the engine speed to 2,000 rpm with
                                            the transmission in NEUTRAL.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Is the restriction gone?</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Yes</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>Install a new catalytic converter and muffler assembly.</para>
                                <para></para>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">No</emph>
                                </para>
                                <para>No indications of a restriction have been detected. CONDUCT a diagnosis on other
                                    suspect systems. CLEAR the DTCs.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s07002_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s07002_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s07002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
