<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERABLE DRIVE AXLE END UNIT: FABCO - REASSEMBLE - WHEEL BEARINGS, HUB, AND BRAKE DRUM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="2">
        <title>WHEEL BEARINGS, HUB, AND BRAKE DRUM</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use of flanged-end bearing drivers is recommended for the installation of bearings and races.
                    These drivers only apply force to the races of the bearing, preventing damage and maintaining
                    alignment with the shaft and bore. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s02011_26.xml" xrefid="hl0201101">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press both wheel bearing cups into the hub. Thoroughly pack both bearing cones with grease,
                and coat the inside surfaces of the hub and bearing cups. Install the inner wheel bearing cone and the
                hub seal in the hub (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201117">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Lightly coat the outer surface of the spindle with grease
                to reduce the chance of the inner wheel bearing cocking upon installation of the hub.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201117" filename="../figg02/g0201117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Installing the Inner Wheel Bearing Cone and Seal</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Grasping the outer circumference of the hub at the 12 and 6 o'clock positions, push the hub
                straight on to the spindle. If difficulty is encountered, try rocking the hub slightly to free the inner
                bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the outer bearing and adjusting nut.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the bearing adjusting nut to 50 ft-lbs. (68 N&#183;m) while simultaneously rotating
                the hub assembly. Loosen the nut and repeat this procedure 2-3 times to ensure that the bearings are
                seated properly. After the final tightening, back off the nut 1/4 turn (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201118">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201118" filename="../figg02/g0201118.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Wheel Bearing Adjustment</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the wheel bearing lockwasher, and back off the adjusting nut just enough to allow
                its dowel pin to engage in the lockwasher's closest hole. Install and tighten the locknut to 400 ft-lbs.
                (542 N&#183;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The wheel bearing end play should be checked with a dial indicator as part of the adjustment
                procedure. The correct end play is .002"-.010" (0.05-0.25 mm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the drive flange shims and drive flange over the drive studs. Install the drive
                flange locknuts and tighten to 100 ft-lbs. (136 N&#183;m). Install and tighten the flanged axle locknut
                to 400 ft-lbs. (542 N&#183;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the brake drum over the wheel studs.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Grease all lubrication points before returning the vehicle to service.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
