<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Adjustments - Adjust Maximum Turn
        Angle
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Adjust Maximum Turn Angle</title>
        <para>The stop bolt on the back of the knuckle controls the maximum turn angle.</para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not exceed the maximum turn angle specified by the vehicle manufacturer. If the angle is
                    exceeded, the steering arms, the cross tube and the tie rod ends will be damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Check the angle if the front tires rub against the frame or if the steering gear has been serviced. Use an
            alignment machine to check the angle. Refer to procedures from the manufacturer of the alignment equipment.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">For manual steering systems</emph>, Meritor recommends a stop bolt clearance of 1/16-inch
            (1.5 mm). Stop bolt contact is acceptable if no other stops are used for the maximum turn angle of the
            steering knuckle.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If the stop bolt is missing, bent or broken, the system requires adjustment.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the steering system is out-of-adjustment, inspect the steering arm for damage. Use a magnetic
                    particle or liquid dye penetrant inspection procedure to inspect the steering arm. Pay particular
                    attention to the bend, the taper and the area near the ball stud. Refer to the manual from the
                    vehicle manufacturer for additional inspection procedures.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>In power steering. systems, the hydraulic pressure should relieve or "drop off' at the end of the
                    steering stroke (with 1/16-inch or 1.5 mm minimum clearance at the stop bolt). If the pressure does
                    not relieve, the components of the front axle will be damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <title>Two-Piece Steering 3/4-inch Stop Bolt</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Screw in the stop screw to a starting depth.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel until the stop bolt contacts the axle housing. Measure the turn
                angle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the maximum turn angle does not meet vehicle manufacturer's specifications, correct the
                maximum angle by screwing the stop bolt in or out.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Once the correct turn angle is achieved, lock down the stop screw with the jam nut. Tighten
                the jam nut to 65-85 lbf-ft (68-101 Nm).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_36.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_38.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
