<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: ROCKWELL - GENERAL INFORMATION - WELDING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WELDING</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Welding is permitted
                <emph type="bold">only</emph>
                in the following areas:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cover welds.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Housing seam welds between the suspension attaching brackets.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Welding can be done when the crack or damaged area is within OLD WELD MATERIAL. Replace
                            the axle housing if the crack extends into the metal next to the old weld. A housing that
                            has damage in the seam weld or cover weld because of over load conditions can be repaired. A
                            REPAIRED HOUSING MUST BE USED IN CORRECT APPLICATIONS.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Using wrong welding procedures or welding at locations other than the two areas permitted
                            will make the heat-treated component weak. A weak component will cause poor or unsafe
                            operation of the axle and early failure.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The following procedure must be used to make welding repairs.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Drain the lubricant from the axle assembly.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the axle shafts and differential carrier from the axle housing.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be careful when using a cleaning solvent. Follow the instructions supplied by the solvent
                            manufacturer for safe use.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the damaged area inside and outside the housing. Cleaning solvent can be used.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Grind the damaged weld to the base metal.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Warm the complete axle housing to a temperature of 70&#176;F to 80&#176;F (21&#176;C to
                    27&#176;C) or higher.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Use a 70,000 psi tensile weld material and the correct voltage and amperage for the
                    diameter weld rod used. Examples of weld rods that can be used are E-7018 or ER-70S-3.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>If the E-7018 weld rod is used, the rod MUST be dried according to specifications supplied
                            by the weld rod manufacturers.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill in the Weld Gap as Follows:</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>DO NOT connect the ground cable at any point on the axle assembly that will put a bearing
                        between the ground cable and weld area. If a bearing is between the ground cable and weld, the
                        bearing will be damaged because of electricity arcing. A good location to connect the ground
                        cable is the spring mounting pad of the housing.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The opening in cover welds MUST be filled level with the old weld.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The opening in seam welds MUST be ground out to 70% of the wall thickness. The wall
                    thickness can be measured at the carrier opening of housing.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Clean the new weld area. Carefully remove all rough weld material.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Install the differential carrier and axle shafts.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fill the axle assembly with the correct amount of lubricant. Refer to GROUP
                    10-LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
