<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT NON-DRIVE STEERING AXLE: ROCKWELL - CLEAN AND INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0200502">
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REPAIRING OF PARTS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The repair or reconditioning of front axle components is not allowed. International specifies
                        that damaged or out of specification components be replaced. All major components are heat
                        treated and tempered.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The components cannot be bent, welded, heated or repaired in any way without reducing the
                        strength or life of the component, voiding the warranty, and possibly causing an accident which
                        could result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following operations are
                <emph type="bold">prohibited</emph>
                on front axle components.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Welding of or to the steering arms, tie rod arms, the knuckles, the king pins, the axle
                    beams, the tie rod assemblies, the hubs, the drums or the brakes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hot or cold bending of the knuckles, steering arms, tie rod arms, ball studs, axle beams
                    or tie rod assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drilling out of the holes in the axle beam for the king pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drilling out of the draw key holes in the knuckle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray welding of bearing diameters on the knuckles or in the machined bores.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Milling or machining of any component.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If you use cleaning solvents, hot solution tanks or alkaline solutions incorrectly, serious
                        personal injury can occur. To prevent injury, follow the instructions supplied by the
                        manufacturer. Do NOT use gasoline to clean parts. Gasoline can explode.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
