<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERABLE DRIVE AXLE END UNIT: FABCO - REMOVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="5">
        <title>REMOVE</title>
        <para>In cases where complete teardown is not required, such as when servicing the inner axle seal, the
            steerable drive end assembly can be removed from the axle as a unit.
        </para>
        <para>Removal of the steerable end is easier if you use a steerable end mounting tool (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0201102">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The tool is available from Fabco, or it can be fabricated from
            the drawings in
            <hotlnk document="s02011_26.xml" xrefid="hl0201101">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201102" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0201102" filename="../figg02/g0201102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Steerable End Mounting Tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block the rear wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the front of the truck with a jack and secure with jackstands of suitable capacity.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                        performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle
                        with floor stands.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the front wheel for the side being serviced.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the tie rod end from the spindle assembly.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all eight 12-point capscrews that secure the universal joint to the axle shaft and
                yoke shaft (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201103">Figure 3</hotlnk>). Pry the joint away from the shafts and remove it.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201103" filename="../figg02/g0201103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Removing Capscrews From U-Joint</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the upper kingpin adjusting screw jam nut and back out the adjusting screw until the
                spindle yoke stops moving downward and is resting on the suspension yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the four 3/4" steering arm or upper kingpin cap locknuts, and pull the arm or cap up
                off its mounting studs. If difficulty is encountered, turn the adjusting screw back in to force the arm
                or cap off the studs (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201104">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201104" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201104" filename="../figg02/g0201104.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Removing the Upper Kingpin Cap</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the steerable end removal tool to a jack and mount it to the steerable end by means
                of the lowest three wheel studs and nuts. Thread the 3/4"-16 x 3.5 inch bolt up through the bottom of
                the base plate and into the nut furthest from the vertical plate. Adjust the bolt to contact and support
                the brake drum. If the tool is not available, alternate means to support the steerable end must be found
                before continuing this procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the lower kingpin locknut and completely remove the locknut, lock washer and lower
                kingpin ball stud from the spindle yoke.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the 7/8 inch upper kingpin bolt and its locknut and two attendant washers from the
                suspension yoke. Use special tool number 866706 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201105">Figure 5</hotlnk>) to pull the upper kingpin ball stud from the suspension
                yoke. The tool is available from Fabco, or it can be fabricated from the drawings in
                <hotlnk document="s02011_26.xml" xrefid="hl0201101">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>. Fit the tool's two tubes
                over two diagonally located steering arm or upper kingpin cap studs. Insert the 1 inch-14 bolt through
                the washer and the tool's central hole and start it in the threads in the top of the upper kingpin ball
                stud. Tighten the bolt until the ball stud is pulled free of the suspension yoke.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201105" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201105" filename="../figg02/g0201105.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Upper Kingpin Ball Stud Remover</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the air line from the brake chamber.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Roll the jack backward to disengage the steerable end from the axle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201106">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201106" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201106" filename="../figg02/g0201106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Disengaging the Steerable End From the Axle</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
