<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: ROCKWELL - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 10-LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the correct lubricants.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="1">
            <title>LUBRICATION FREQUENCIES</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All steering universal joints, knuckle bushings or bearings, grease lubricated wheel
                    bearings, drive shaft splines and splines of the outer universal joint shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200839">Figure 39</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200839" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200839.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 39. Points of Lubrication</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The frequency of lubricant changes depends on operating conditions, speed and loads. Change
                    lubricants when seals are replaced, when brakes are relined, at 30,000 miles (48,000 km) or 2000
                    hours of operation. If mileage is less than 30,000 miles or 2000 hours of operation a year, change
                    two times a year (spring and fall).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>If the front drive axle is the vehicle's only drive axle, lubricate the universal joints,
                            drive shaft splines and splines of the outer universal joint shaft every 15,000 miles
                            (24,000 km) or 1000 hours of operation.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tie Rod End Assemblies:</para>
                <para>Every 3000 miles (4800 km) or 200 hours of operation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive Units (Differentials):</para>
                <para>Every 25,000 to 30,000 miles (40,000 to 48,000 km) or 1600 to 2000 hours of operation when yearly
                    use is more than 60,000 miles (96,500 km). If mileage is less than 60,000 miles, change two times a
                    year (spring and fall).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
