<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT NON-DRIVE STEERING AXLE: ROCKWELL - ASSEMBLE - TIE ROD ARMS, TIE ROD ENDS AND CROSS TUBE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TIE ROD ARMS, TIE ROD ENDS AND CROSS TUBE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the key in the slot in the arm (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200538">Figure 38</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200538" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200538" filename="../figg02/g0200538.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Key in the Slot</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the tie rod arm in the knuckle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200538">Figure 38</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Tighten the nuts to the specified torque. If the nuts are not tightened to the specified
                        torque, the parts will be damaged.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nut on the tie rod arm. Tighten to the specified torque. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s02005r_32.xml" xrefid="hl0200506">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the cotter pins. Tighten nut until the holes are aligned.
                <emph type="bold">Do not loosen nut to install the cotter pin.</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For detailed information on service of the tie rods and drag links, refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT
                        AXLES, STEERING, GENERAL INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                        Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The cross tube has right hand threads on one end and left hand threads on the other end. Make
                        sure the ends are installed on the tube.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, install the tie rod ends on the cross tube to the position marked during removal
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200539">Figure 39</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200539" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200539" filename="../figg02/g0200539.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Install Tie Rod Ends on Cross Tube</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If new tie rod ends are installed, thread the ends equally on the cross tube to the required length.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nuts and the bolts in the clamps. Tighten to the specified torque. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s02005r_32.xml" xrefid="hl0200506">Torque Chart</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The rotating style clamp on the cross tube can be rotated for easier accessibility when
                installing the clamp bolt and nut. Tighten nut sufficiently to engage the locking element of the nut
                with the bolt. Clamp and tie rod end must be free to rotate (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200540">Figure 40</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200540" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200540" filename="../figg02/g0200540.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Free to Rotate</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the tie rod ends into the tie rod arms.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nuts on the tie rod ends. Tighten to the specified torque. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s02005r_32.xml" xrefid="hl0200506">Torque Chart</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the cotter pins. Tighten nut until the holes are aligned.
                <emph type="bold">Do not loosen nut to install the cotter pin.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and, if necessary, adjust the toe-in. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES, Steering
                General Information and Front Wheel Alignment in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_HL0200504.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
