<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS (NON-DRIVE AXLES) - WHEEL SEALS - CLEAN AND INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The contact surfaces where the new seal will be installed must be free from rust, scale, old sealant,
                nicks, burrs, and any roughness that would prevent a good seal. Clean contact surfaces with scrapers
                that are softer than the hub material to avoid scratching the hub or seal bore. When cleaning aluminum
                hubs, use non-metallic scrapers to prevent damage.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspecting and Preparing the Hub Bore</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the bore into which the seal fits. Check for nicks or gouges that could cause
                    leakage. Sharp corners at the bore entrance can score the seal O.D. when it is pressed in and can
                    cause oil leakage (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200223">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200223" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200223.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px" resolution="150"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Check for Burrs at Bore Entrance</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any rust, scale, old sealant, and roughness with a scraper. Then use fine emery
                    or crocus cloth for a final cleaning. If there are any deep grooves, fill them in with a hardening
                    gasket material. Redress the filled area with emery or crocus cloth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Sharp edges on the bore entrance should be chamfered or rounded off with a scraper, then
                    carefully smoothed with an abrasive cloth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean and dry the entire area. Make certain it is completely free of dirt,
                    grit, chips or other abrasives which will score or mar the seal's outer surface and cause leakage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure all oil is removed from the lubricant cavity. Wipe the cavity clean using a
                    clean, dry cloth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for porous or cracked hub which could allow oil leakage. This is important where
                    leakage has been encountered.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspecting and Preparing the Spindle</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean the spindle with solvent and a clean, dry shop rag, then examine the
                    spindle for flaws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any rust, old sealant, and roughness with a scraper and use crocus cloth to
                    polish the spindle area that contacts the sealing surface. Fill deep scratches or chisel marks with
                    a hardening gasket material and redress the damaged area. Clean all threads and keyways thoroughly
                    with a wire brush to avoid false bearing adjustment and to avoid introduction of contaminants into
                    the lubricant cavity.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe the entire spindle surface with a clean, dry cloth, making certain the spindle is
                    completely free of dirt, grit, chips or other abrasives which could damage the seal's inner surface
                    and cause oil leakage. Clean all threads and keyways.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all parts as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
