<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT STEER AXLE: EATON E1200I I-BEAM - INSPECTION - GENERAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL</title>
        <para>Perform a thorough visual inspection of the axle to ensure proper assembly and to identify broken parts
            and loose fasteners each time the vehicle is lubricated. Make sure spring to axle beam mounting nuts and
            steering connection fasteners are secure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Wheel Alignment:</emph>
            If excessive tire wear is evident, check wheel alignment. Refer to GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL SERVICE
            INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for wheel alignment inspection
            intervals and procedures.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Steering Axle Stops:</emph>
            Inspect for missing, loose or bent steer stops. Damaged or missing steering axle stops may indicate other
            problems with the steering system. This can result in damage to the steering system components. Replace
            missing or damaged stops and reset steering system geometry. Refer to GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL SERVICE
            INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Tie Rod Ends:</emph>
            Inspect each time axle is lubricated. Check for seal damage, worn ball socket or loose fasteners. Refer to
            GROUP 02 - STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service
            Manual.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Knuckle Thrust Bearings:</emph>
            When disassembled, visually inspect for any damage and check for smooth operation. For maximum service life,
            replace the thrust bearing whenever the knuckle assembly is serviced.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Kingpins:</emph>
            For maximum service life, replace kingpins when servicing knuckle assembly.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02007_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02007_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
