<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - FRONT DRIVE AXLE: SPICER S-9000 - RING GEAR AND PINION TOOTH CONTACT PATTERN -
        ADJUST RING GEAR PATTERN (BACKLASH)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="7">
        <title>ADJUST RING GEAR PATTERN (BACKLASH)</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Paint ring gear teeth with marking compound and rotate with pinion to obtain contact pattern
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200952">Figure 52</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200952" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200952" filename="../figg02/G0200952.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 52. Paint Ring Gear Teeth with Marking Compound</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The tooth contact patterns should have the same general shape and position as the ring gear
                teeth shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200953">Figure 53</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200953" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200953" filename="../figg02/G0200953.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 53. Correct Tooth Contact</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated more toward the heel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200954">Figure 54</hotlnk>), backlash must be reduced. Re-check backlash as described
                in
                <hotlnk document="s02009_18.xml" xrefid="hl0200902">step 6</hotlnk>. To reduce backlash, loosen the
                right side adjusting ring until the measured backlash is within specification. The tooth contact pattern
                should now have the same general shape and location as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200953">Figure 53</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, less
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid reducing differential bearing preload excessively, further
                loosening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal tightening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Place a dial indicator directly on each adjusting ring to measure the exact amount of
                additional adjustment. Decreasing backlash moves the ring gear toward the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200954" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200954" filename="../figg02/G0200954.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 54. If Pattern is Concentrated Toward Heel</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the pattern is concentrated at the toe (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200955">Figure 55</hotlnk>), more backlash is required. Re-check backlash. To increase
                backlash, tighten the right side adjusting ring further until the measured backlash is within
                specification. The tooth contact pattern should now spread across the ring gear tooth as in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200953">Figure 53</hotlnk>. If the contact pattern still does not conform, more
                backlash than normal is required. To avoid increasing differential bearing preload excessively, further
                tightening of the right hand adjusting ring should be accompanied by equal loosening of the left hand
                adjusting ring. Place a dial indicator directly on each adjusting ring to measure the exact amount of
                the additional adjustment. Increasing backlash moves the ring gear away from the pinion.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200955" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200955" filename="../figg02/G0200955.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 55. If Pattern is Concentrated At Toe</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If a pattern is concentrated at the ring gear tooth root as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200956">Figure 56</hotlnk>, the pinion is too close to the ring gear. It must be moved
                out and away to establish its proper mounting distance and contact pattern as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200953">Figure 53</hotlnk>. This is accomplished by choosing a thicker pinion bearing
                cage shim. Readjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash, as required, once proper pinion mounting distance has
                been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200956" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200956" filename="../figg02/G0200956.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 56. If Pattern is Concentrated At The Ring Gear Tooth Root</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If pattern is concentrated at the tooth top land (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200957">Figure 57</hotlnk>), the pinion is too far away from the ring gear and must be
                moved closer to the ring gear to establish its proper mounting distance and tooth contact pattern. This
                is accomplished by selecting a thinner pinion bearing cage shim. Readjust pinion-to-ring gear backlash
                as required once proper mounting distance has been established.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200957" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200957" filename="../figg02/G0200957.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 57. If Pattern is Concentrated At The Tooth Top</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After proper ring gear pattern is achieved, again tighten the differential bearing cap bolts
                to 115 to 125 ft-lbs. (156 to 169 Nm). Install adjusting ring retainers and new cotter keys of proper
                size (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200958">Figure 58</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200958" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200958" filename="../figg02/G0200958.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 58. Install Adjusting Ring Retainers</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02009_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02009_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
