<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: ROCKWELL - ASSEMBLY - STEERING UNIVERSAL JOINT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>STEERING UNIVERSAL JOINT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Round Bearing Yokes</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the cross must be replaced, the needle bearing also must be replaced.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                    mix new and used bearings. Replacement must be made in sets of four.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a needle bearing cap into the ear of the yoke.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a vise to press the needle bearing cap into the correct position. Be careful not to
                    damage the polish surface of the cap (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200826">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200826" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/g0200826.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Installing Bearing Cap</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the yoke from the vise and carefully work one arm of the cross into the yoke and
                    bearing cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the opposite bearing cap into the yoke by hand and line up the cross arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the vise to press the bearing cap into the yoke and on to the arm of the cross (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200827">Figure 27</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200827" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/g0200827.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. Assemble Bearing and Yoke</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The cross must move freely in both caps. If the cross does not move freely, remove the cap
                            and check for correct alignment of the needle bearings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a short plug to move the bearing cups past the snap ring grooves. Install the snap
                    rings in the grooves, one in each bearing cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat these procedures (1 through 7) to install the remaining caps and yoke.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wing Bearing Yokes</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the cross and cap assembly is damaged, replace all the parts with a new assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the cross assembly to the yokes with eight capscrews and nuts. Tighten the
                    capscrews and jam nuts to the correct torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
