<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - KING PIN ANGLE (INCLINATION) - TURNING
        ANGLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TURNING ANGLE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Turning angle is the degree of movement from a straight-ahead position of the front wheels to either
                an extreme right or left position. Two factors of major importance when adjusting the angle are: tire
                interference with chassis and steering gear travel.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid tire interference or bottoming of the steering gear, adjustable stop bolts are located on the
                steering knuckles. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_HL0200103.xml" xrefid="hl0200103">STEERING KNUCKLE STOP ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Turning Angle (Wheel Cut) Charts are located in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_HL0200104.xml" xrefid="hl0200104">ALIGNMENT SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                for special applications. Use the turning radius plates as outlined in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_HL0200105.xml" xrefid="hl0200105">ACKERMAN ANGLE (TOE-OUT ON TURNS)</hotlnk>,
                and adjust the turning angle.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Manual Steering Gear</title>
            <para>If the specifications chart does not include the particular vehicle being aligned, proceed as follows.
                Loosen the jam nuts and turn the steering knuckle stop bolts in. Position support stands under the front
                axle so that the wheels are off the floor. Turn the wheels to extreme right turn until the steering gear
                bottoms or contact of the tire to chassis is made. Then back off the steering wheel &#188; turn or back
                off the steering wheel until &#189; to 1 inch (12.7 to 25.4 mm) clearance is obtained between the tire
                and chassis.
            </para>
            <para>Be sure to check both front tires for clearance. When the proper clearance is determined, back the
                wheel stop bolt out and tighten the jam nut.
            </para>
            <para>Repeat the same procedure on the left extreme turn and adjust the left steering knuckle stop bolt.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power Steering</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If vehicle is equipped with power steering, adjust the steering gear end of travel relief
                        valves to relieve pressure before contact is made with the knuckle stop bolt.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Hydraulic pressure relief must occur prior to contact between the knuckle stop bolt and I-beam
                        pad to avoid potential overstressing of steering linkage components. If linkage is overstressed
                        repeatedly, subsequent damage may result in failure of linkage components and steering control
                        of the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 05-STEERING in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the steering gear being
                serviced.
            </para>
            <para>The adjustment of both axle steering stops and power steering unit should be periodically checked and
                corrected if necessary.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_HL0200105.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
