<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT STEER AXLE: EATON EFA-12 - INSPECT - WHEEL BEARING INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="3">
        <title>WHEEL BEARING INSPECTION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove bearings. Clean bearings, spindle, hub cap and hub cavity with a suitable commercial
                solvent.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect cups, rollers and cones for wear or damage. The photographs in this section of the
                manual can be used as a guide to inspect the bearings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bearings normally fail after they have lived their expected life. Premature wear or fatigue
                        can be caused by improper installation, incorrect adjustment or lack of lubrication.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <para>As a guide for inspecting bearing condition, the three photographs (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0200617">Figure 17</hotlnk>,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0200618">Figure 18</hotlnk>,
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0200619">Figure 19</hotlnk>) illustrate various stages of wear.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0200617" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200617.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 17. Uneven Wear</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0200618" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200618.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 18. Normal Wear</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0200619" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200619.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 19. Damaged</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <title>Break-In (uneven wear) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200617">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
            </title>
            This cup displays an uneven wear pattern typical in low mileage with light or moderate loads. It is caused
            by the bearing preload applied during assembly and will gradually become more even as mileage increases. If
            not otherwise damaged, parts showing this wear pattern can be reused.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>High mileage (normal wear) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200618">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
            </title>
            This bearing cup is evenly worn in a manner common for advanced mileage with normal loading. It is lightly
            pitted because of contaminants in the lubricant and would be replaced before it reached an advanced stage.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Bearing failure (damaged) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200619">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
            </title>
            This cup has been badly bruised by hard metal particles in the lubricant. If reused, it would probably begin
            spalling or flaking within a short time. It should be replaced.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
