<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - TOE-IN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TOE-IN</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Toe-in is the amount in fractions of an inch (mm) that the front wheels are closer together at the
                front than at the back
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200114">(Figure 14)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200114" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Toe Setting (Front View)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Another reason for toe-in, and the most familiar, is that when the vehicle is being driven, the forces
                acting on the front wheels tend to make the wheels toe-out.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Toe-In Adjustment</title>
            <para>If electronic alignment equipment is used to set the toe-in, it is very important that the equipment
                be in calibration to insure an accurate toe reading.
            </para>
            <para>The following procedure may be used to set the toe-in when electronic alignment equipment is not
                available. To obtain an accurate toe reading, two mechanics are required to insure that the pointers are
                always placed or adjusted to be exactly in front of the line scribed on both front tires.
            </para>
            <para>Turn the front wheels to the exact straight-ahead position.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block rear wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up front axle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe off excess dirt and moisture from the center of both front tire treads (360&#176;).
                    Use a piece of chalk to mark the center area of both front tires around the complete circumference.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a scribe or pointed instrument against the center of the whitened part of each tire
                    and rotate the tires 360&#176;. The scribe must be held in place so that a single straight line is
                    marked all the way around the tires.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put a full floating radius gauge plate under each wheel. Lower the vehicle and remove
                    the lock pins from the radius gauge plates to allow the front wheels to return to the normal
                    operating position. If full floating radius gauge plates are not available, lower the vehicle to the
                    floor and roll it forward 12 to 15 feet (3.65 to 4.57 m) to neutralize the front suspension.
                    Neutralizing the front suspension is extremely important especially if the vehicle has been jacked
                    up to scribe the tires; otherwise, the front wheels will not return to the normal operating position
                    due to the tires gripping the floor surface when the vehicle is lowered.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the sliding scale end of a trammel bar to zero (0)
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200115">(Figure 15)</hotlnk>
                    and lock the scale in place.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200115" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200115.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Sliding Scale Set to Zero</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SCRIBED LINE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the trammel bar at the rear of the front tires so that the sliding scale that was
                    set to zero in step 6 is centered against the scribed line on one of the tires
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200115">(Figure 15)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the pointer on the end of the trammel bar opposite the sliding scale so it lines
                    up with the scribed line on the rear of the opposite front tire. Lock the pointer in place on the
                    trammel bar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put the trammel bar against the front of the tires so the pointer end is against the
                    scribed line on the front tire. Loosen and move the sliding scale pointer on the opposite end of the
                    trammel bar so it is against the scribed line on the opposite tire. Lock the scale in place
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200116">(Figure 16)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200116" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200116.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Trammel Bar Against Front of Tires</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. POINTER END</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SLIDING SCALE END ADJUSTED TO SCRIBED LINE TO INDICATE ACTUAL TOE SETTING
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Read the toe-in or toe-out on the sliding scale. If toe-in is correct, it will read 1/16
                    inch &#177; 1/16 inch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If toe-in adjustment is necessary, use the following procedure:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the tie rod clamps that secure the tie rod ends in position in the tie rod. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s02001k_5.xml" xrefid="f0200110">Figure 10</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the sliding scale on the trammel bar to read 1/16 inch toe-in.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the tie rod to set the toe-in. After the toe-in is set, the sliding scale and the
                    pointer should both be on the scribed line of the tire each is in front of.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the steering wheel in each direction to center the steering linkage (if the vehicle
                    has power steering, start the engine before turning the wheel). Make sure the front wheels are in a
                    straight ahead position (stop engine), and re-check the toe-in setting. Make any necessary
                    adjustments.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat step 4 until the toe-in reading is 1/16 inch &#177; 1/16 inch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position and tighten the tie rod clamp bolts to the value found in the
                    <hotlnk document="s02001k_27.xml" xrefid="hl0200101">TORQUE CHART.</hotlnk>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>When repositioning the tie rod clamps, check bolt clearance between the bolt and axle
                            I-Beam at the maximum turn position, right and left (turn). Interference may restrict proper
                            steering linkage movement, and/or cause damage to clamp bolts.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <para>Be sure the tie rod ends are properly indexed or aligned (left tie rod end parallel to the right tie
                rod end)
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_5.xml" xrefid="f0200109">(Figure 9)</hotlnk>. Proper indexing will eliminate
                restricted movement of the tie rod assembly. Restriction could cause premature failure of tie rod ends.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When the tie rod, drag link or power steering linkage ends are replaced, they must be threaded
                        into the tie rod sufficiently so that when the clamp is applied, the clamping action will be
                        directly over the threads on the ball joint end
                        <hotlnk document="s02001k_5.xml" xrefid="f0200108">(Figure 8)</hotlnk>. Be sure that the end is
                        in far enough (past the clamp) to provide adequate clamping.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
