<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: FABCO SDA-12 - ADJUSTMENTS - TIE ROD ENDS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0201011" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TIE ROD ENDS</title>
        <para>The tie rods are of three-piece construction, consisting of a tie rod and two rod end assemblies. The ends
            are threaded to the rod and locked with clamp bolts (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0201014">Figure 14</hotlnk>). Right and left hand threads are provided for toe-in
            adjustment. Tension on ball stud in the rod ends is self-adjusting and requires no attention in service
            other than periodic inspection to see that ball studs are tight in the steering knuckle arms.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201014" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201014.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. Typical Tie Rod End</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. TIE ROD END EXTENDS BEYOND CLAMP ON TIE ROD</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SLOT</callout1>
                <callout1>3. TIE ROD</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BALL STUD</callout1>
                <callout1>5. BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1>6. CLAMP</callout1>
                <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>8. BALL SOCKET ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>9. STEERING ARM</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Fittings are provided for periodic lubrication on some types of tie rod ends. Where no fittings are used,
            the tie rods have been lubricated at assembly and
            <emph type="bold">no further lubrication is necessary.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>If the tie rod taper joint is loose or the cotter pin is missing, remove, inspect and replace the tie rod
            arm/tie rod end if the contact surfaces are worn.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Replacement Criteria</title>
            The tie rod must be free to rotate within the ball stud socket. Replace the tie rod end if it moves more
            than 1/16 of an inch in the axial direction (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0201015">Figure 15</hotlnk>) when measured on-vehicle.
            <emph type="bold">Do not pry on</emph>
            steering linkages with a bar as damage may result.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201015" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201015.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 15. Checking Tie Rod And Drag Link End Movement</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>A. MOVEMENT IN THE AXIAL DIRECTION MUST BE LESS THAN 1/16 INCH</callout1>
                <callout1>B. TIE ROD/DRAG LINK FREE TO ROTATE WITHIN STEERING ARM SOCKET</callout1>
                <callout1>1. TIE ROD/DRAG LINK END</callout1>
                <callout1>2. STEERING ARM</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>An alternate method of evaluating the tie rod end is by rotating the ball stud with the stud removed from
            the lower steering arm. Torque to rotate the stud in the end cap should be 5.0 in-lbs. (0.565 N&#183;m) or
            more (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0201016">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201016" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201016.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 16. Rotating Tie Rod And Drag Link Ball Stud</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>A. BALL STUD SHOULD ROTATE WITH 5.0 IN-LB. TORQUE OR MORE</callout1>
                <callout1>1. TIE ROD/DRAG LINK END</callout1>
                <callout1>2. BALL STUD</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>At assembly, insure that the slotted nut is torqued to the minimum value specified in the torque chart. If
            cotter pin cannot be installed, tighten nut to the next slot.
            <emph type="bold">Do not back off</emph>
            once minimum torque is reached.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When tie rod, drag link or power steering linkage ends are replaced, they must be threaded into
                    the tie rod sufficiently so that when the clamp is applied, the clamping action will be directly
                    over the threads on the ball joint end. Be sure that the end is in far enough (past the clamp) to
                    provide adequate clamping and the bolt in the clamp is installed next to (over) the slot in the tie
                    rod.
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0201014">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                    illustrates a typical tie rod design for these axles.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
