<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The alignment of the chassis according to the vehicle manufacturer's specifications should provide
                optimum tire life and vehicle handling. Check front tires at regular intervals. Check front alignment
                only if tires show incorrect wear or front suspension has been subjected to extremely heavy service or
                severe impact loads. Before checking and adjusting alignment, components such as wheel bearings, tie rod
                ends, drag link, steering gear, shock absorbers and tire inflation should be inspected and corrected
                where necessary.
            </para>
            <para>The toe-in adjustment is the most important alignment factor to check when attempting to extend tire
                life.
                <emph type="bold">Toe-in should be set only by trained mechanics using calibrated equipment.</emph>
                The setting should be re-checked after any correction to be sure it is correct.
            </para>
            <para>Incorrect toe-in will result in rapid tire wear. Tire wear on radial tires due to excessive toe-in
                shows up initially as irregular wear; more so on the outside grooves than the inside grooves of the tire
                and more so on the right front than on the left front tire. Excessive toe-out will show a reversed
                effect: more wear on the inside than the outside grooves and more so on the left front than the right
                front tire.
            </para>
            <para>At large values of toe-in or toe-out and at relatively early mileage, the tread of the outside or
                inside ribs can be completely worn away. For a 5/16-inch toe-in condition, this can occur after only
                19,000 miles of highway travel.
            </para>
            <para>If front axle tire wear pattern has
                <emph type="bold">heavy</emph>
                wear on the outside of one tire tread and on the inside tread of its mate, the tandem rear axle
                suspension alignment should be inspected as indicated in GROUP 03 - SPRINGS, SUSPENSION ALIGNMENT in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>The caster, camber and toe-in dimensions are for vehicles at no-load (no payload condition). If the
                frame is not level, the frame angle must be considered. This is especially important when making a
                caster check. The frame angle must be added to or subtracted from the caster angle to obtain a true
                caster reading.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
