<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT STEER AXLE: EATON EFA-12 - INSPECT - INSPECTION RECOMMENDATIONS AND INTERVALS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSPECTION RECOMMENDATIONS AND INTERVALS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Prior to performing inspections, the following preliminary steps should be accomplished:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Set parking brake and block drive wheels to prevent vehicle movement.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jack vehicle until steering axle wheels are raised from the ground. Support raised vehicle
                        with safety stands.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never work under a vehicle supported only by a jack.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General Recommendations</title>
            <para>Intervals of inspection or service are recommended for general or average vehicle use. It may be
                appropriate to increase frequency of intervals depending on vehicle service.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General Inspection</title>
            <para>Perform a thorough visual inspection for proper assembly, broken parts, and looseness each time the
                vehicle is lubricated. Make certain spring to axle beam mounting nuts and steering connection fasteners
                are secure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment</title>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for information on intervals of
                inspecting wheel alignment. However, if excessive steering effort, vehicle wander or uneven and
                excessive tire wear is evident, then check wheel alignment. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s02006_16.xml" xrefid="hl0200602">WHEEL ALIGNMENT INSPECTION</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Steering Axle Stops</title>
            <para>No specific interval is recommended. However, if steering turning radius is insufficient or excessive,
                adjust stops. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tie Rod Ends</title>
            <para>Inspect each time axle is lubricated. Check for seal damage, worn ball socket or loose fasteners.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Knuckle Thrust Bearings</title>
            <para>Adjust knuckle vertical play each time knuckle pin is removed for service, at axle overhaul or when
                excessive knuckle vertical movement is noted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Knuckle Pins</title>
            <para>Inspect pin fit in bushings when pin is removed for service, at axle overhaul or when looseness is
                noted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Bearings and Knuckle Thrust Bearings</title>
            <para>Inspect wheel and knuckle thrust bearings for damage or wear each time hub/drum is removed or steering
                knuckle repaired.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
