<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: FABCO SDA-12 - LUBRICATION - WHEEL BEARINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WHEEL BEARINGS</title>
        <para>Wheel bearings require cleaning, inspection, packing with grease or an oil change at each brake re-line.
            Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for wheel bearing lubricant. They may
            either be grease packed or oil lubricated. A 1/4-inch pipe plug (as shown in
            <hotlnk document="s02010_31.xml" xrefid="f0201042">Figure 42</hotlnk>) is located in the outer axle shaft
            flange. Oil filled wheel hubs should be filled to the level of this plug when it is in a position on the
            axle horizontal centerline. Grease packed bearings require that the section of the wheel hub between the
            bearing cups be filled to the level of the inner diameter of the bearing cups.
        </para>
        <para>The outer axle shaft inner bearing should also be packed with grease, if the hubs are not lubricated with
            oil. With the outer shaft out for access to the wheel bearings, disconnect the joint from the inner and
            outer drive yokes, and push the outer drive yoke from the bearing and seal. The bearing rollers are now
            accessible and may be packed by hand. Do not use anything to apply grease that would cut the seal. If oil
            lubricated, the bearing will receive its supply from the wheel bearing reservoir, and repacking is not
            required.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_38.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_40.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
