<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: ROCKWELL - INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="5">
        <title>INSPECT</title>
        <para>It is very important to inspect all parts carefully and completely before the axle is assembled. Check all
            parts for wear or stress and replace damaged parts. Replacement of damaged parts can prevent complete
            failure of the assembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect Tapered Roller Bearings.</para>
            <para>Inspect the cup, cone, rollers and cage of all tapered roller bearings in the assembly. If any of the
                following conditions exist, the bearing MUST be replaced (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200821">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200821" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200821.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Tapered Roller Bearing Wear</caption>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The center of large diameter end of rollers worn level with or below the outer
                    surface.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The radius at large diameter end of rollers worn to a sharp edge.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">. A visible roller groove in the cup or cone inner race surfaces. The groove can be seen
                    at the small or large diameter end of both parts.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Deep cracks or breaks in the cup, cone inner race or roller surfaces (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200822">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200822" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200822.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Bearing Inspection</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Bright wear marks on the outer surface of the roller cage (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200823">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200823" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200823.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Taper Bearing Inspection</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Damage on rollers and on surfaces of the cup and cone inner race that touch the rollers
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200824">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200824" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200824.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24. Bright Wear Marks on Tapered Rollers and Inner Race</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Damage on the cup and cone inner race surfaces that touch the rollers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200825">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200825" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200825.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25. Spalling and Flaking on Bearing Race Surfaces</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect Tie Rod Assembly.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check seals for damage. Check that seals are correctly fastened on socket. If tie rod
                    ends have grease fittings, replace damaged seals. If tie rod ends do not have grease fittings, the
                    complete end assembly must be replaced.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>DO NOT repair tie rod ends. Damaged tie rod ends MUST be replaced.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check the turning torque value between the tie rod end stud and the ball cavity. If the
                    torque value is less than five inch pounds, the tie rod end must be replaced.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect Axle Housing.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove all dirt from housing and sleeves.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Check for cracks, loose studs and damage to machined surfaces. Repair or replace damaged
                    parts.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect axle shafts for wear, stress, and cracks at the splines, shaft and yoke ears.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
