<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Lubrication, Inspection and
        Maintenance - Greasing Wheel Bearings
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Greasing Wheel Bearings</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface. Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Support
                    the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip
                    and fall over. Serious personal injury can result.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>For specific service information, refer to the correct maintenance manual listed under Additional
                    Information at the front of this manual.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the vehicle so that the wheels are off the ground. Support the vehicle with safety
                stands.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the tire and wheel assembly. Remove and disassemble the hub.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the correct cleaning solvent to remove the old grease from all parts. Discard the seals.
                Inspect the wheel bearings for wear or damage. Replace worn or damaged bearings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a pressure packer to force the specified grease from the large end of the cones into the
                cavities between the rollers and cage. Pack the hub between the bearing cups with grease to the level of
                the smallest diameter of the cups. If a pressure packer is not available, grease the bearings by hand.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the inner and outer bearing cones into the cups in the hubs. The bearing cups must
                be pressed tight against the shoulder in the hubs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install new wheel seals in the hubs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the hub and the wheel and tire assembly. Install the outer wheel bearing cone in the
                hub. Install the adjusting nut.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the wheel bearings.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_53.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_55.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
