<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Adjustments - Caster Angle
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Caster Angle</title>
        <para>Caster is the forward or rearward tilt of the king pin center line when viewed from the side of the
            vehicle. The caster angle is the angle from the vertical position to the center line of the king pin. If the
            top of the king pin axis is toward the rear of the vehicle, the caster is positive. A slight positive caster
            creates a self-aligning action that helps to stabilize the vehicle after turning and stabilizes it for
            driving straight ahead (Figure 64).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201264" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201264.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 64. Caster</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. NEGATIVE CASTER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. POSITIVE CASTER</callout1>
                <callout1>3. FORWARD</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Always use an alignment machine to check the caster angle. When checking caster, refer to the
            instructional procedures from the alignment equipment manufacturer.
        </para>
        <para>If caster is too much, steering effort will increase or may amplify a shimmy condition.</para>
        <para>The caster angle is controlled by the angle of the housing pad or by tapered shims installed under the
            leaf springs. Adjust caster according to the specifications and procedures of the vehicle manufacturer.
        </para>
        <para>Caster specifications are set by the vehicle manufacturer. Refer to the specifications of the vehicle
            manufacturer for the caster setting. If caster specifications are not available from the vehicle
            manufacturer, Meritor recommends a caster setting of +1 degrees to +2-1/2 degrees for vehicles with manual
            steering and +2 degrees to +4-1/2 degrees for vehicles with power steering.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_40.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_42.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
