<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: FABCO SDA-12 - DISASSEMBLY - SEPARATE LOWER KING PIN BRACKET AND KING PIN
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SEPARATE LOWER KING PIN BRACKET AND KING PIN</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The lower kingpin ball stud and the lower kingpin bearing are exposed for inspection after
                the spindle yoke has been removed (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201027">Figure 27</hotlnk>). Back off the lower kingpin locknut before removing the
                kingpin and steering arm bracket from the spindle yoke.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201027" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201027.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Separating Lower King Pin Bracket from Spindle Yoke</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>After the locknut is loose, remove the four bracket to yoke bolts.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the lower kingpin ball stud assembly.</para>
            <para>An Allen wrench or six-pointed socket may be used to turn the stud. In the event neither of the tools
                are available, a tool to turn the ball stud can be made locally by welding a nut to a capscrew with same
                size head to fit the stud socket. A standard socket or wrench may be used to turn out the stud.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the kingpin stud from the bracket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the lower kingpin bearing is to be replaced, drive the bearing out of the suspension yoke
                by pushing on the lower kingpin disc.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
