<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HUBS, BEARINGS, AND SEALS (NON-DRIVE AXLES) - INSTALLATION (WHEEL BEARINGS - OIL LUBRICATED) - FRONT WHEEL
        HUB CAP/OIL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>FRONT WHEEL HUB CAP/OIL</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200210">Figure 10</hotlnk>
                is the new style hub cap for 6,000 and 8,000 lb. axles manufactured June 1995 and after.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200210" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. New Style Hub Cap - June, 1995 and Later</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200211">Figure 11</hotlnk>
                is for 9,000 - 20,000 lb. axles manufactured August 1993 and after.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200211" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Hub Cap, 1993 and Later</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>During normal vehicle driving, the lube and air inside the hub/wheel cavity expands, and if not vented
                causes pressure build-up in the wheel cavity resulting in accelerated seal wear.
            </para>
            <para>The vent plug has a slit in it to allow the pressure in the hub/wheel cavity to be maintained in a
                safe operating range. International uses the slit type of venting because it allows less contamination
                (moisture, dust, etc.) to get into the hub/wheel cavity during normal operation, including chassis
                cleaning operations.
            </para>
            <para>As the air and oil expand, an oil/air mist is expelled through the vent. It is normal for a slight
                film of oil to be present on the outside of the hub cap around the vent slit or hole.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Over a period of time, if not wiped off, the film of oil that gathers around the vent slit or hole may
                collect dust and become unsightly.
            </para>
            <para>If the hub cap is not routinely cleaned, a slight film of oil can collect dirt around the rubber fill
                plug and face which could be perceived as a leak. Furthermore, routine cleaning ensures that the lube
                level can be easily observed through the clear window as intended.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not clean the hub cap with a high pressure cleaner as cleaning fluid, water and/or steam
                        may be forced through the vent and contaminate the oil.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>In a case where the window is clear on the outside but discolored on the inside from the type of
                lubricant used, the lube level may be checked by removing the rubber vent plug and inserting a finger
                through the hole in the face plate.
            </para>
            <para>The specified lube level for clear window type hub caps is from the minimum line to 5/16 inch above
                the minimum line.
            </para>
            <para>If the lube level should suddenly drop below the minimum level indicator during inspection intervals,
                it is an indication that there may be a possible leak problem. Take the following steps:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the area around the gasket to determine if the gasket is leaking. A dry hub cap
                    and a wet area around the gasket indicate the gasket could be leaking or the hub cap mounting bolts
                    may be loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check to be sure the mounting bolts are tight. Torque should be 16 to 20 ft-lbs. (13.5
                    to 27 N&#183;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for a leaking wheel seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the rubber vent for nicks or other damage that could cause leakage between the
                    rubber plug and the outer edge of the plug opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace any defective parts as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is no leak, add same lube as used in hub to raise level to MIN line.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                    exceed 5/16 inch above MIN line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If these steps do not reveal leakage, the hub cap can be pressure checked to determine
                    if it is leaking between the clear window and the hub cap body.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Test Procedures</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hub cap from vehicle and mount securely to a flat plate with silicone or
                    similar sealer between the hub cap mounting surface and the plate.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is best to remove the hub cap from the vehicle before pressure checking. Air pressure
                            inside the hub could cause some wheel seals to move, thus causing premature seal wear.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean the hub cap and the area around the mounting surface with a hot
                    water/soap solution.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the threaded fill plug in the side of the hub cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Screw an air line adapter in the fill plug hole. The standard aluminum International hub
                    cap is tapped with 3/8-18 NBTF threads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a pressure regulator (1 - 10 PSI) and control valve to the adapter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap and water solution to entire hub cap body and around mounting flange.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold finger or thumb over slit in rubber vent plug or hole in clear face.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Slowly</emph>
                    open air valve and raise pressure to 10 PSI.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for air leaking between face and body or around rubber vent and face. There should
                    be no air escaping from these two potential leak areas.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air escapes between window face and body, discard the hub cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air escapes between rubber vent and/or face/body interface area, replace rubber vent
                    plug or hub cap as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air escapes between hub mounting face and cap, install new gasket, and check cap for
                    warpage. If cap is warped, replace cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02002s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
