<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - CASTER ANGLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CASTER ANGLE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Keep in mind that if the caster is changed, the toe adjustment must be re-checked.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Caster is the amount in degrees the top of the kingpin is tilted toward the front or rear of the
                truck, as viewed from the side of the truck. The caster angle can range from a positive angle to a
                negative angle
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200117">(Figure 17)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Caster</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Positive caster is the tilting of the top of the king pin toward the rear of the truck
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200117">(Figure 17)</hotlnk>, while negative, or reverse caster, is the tilting of the
                top of the king pin toward the front of the truck
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200117">(Figure 17)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Positive caster imparts a trailing action to the front wheels, while negative, or reverse caster,
                causes a leading action. The correct amount of caster helps to keep the front wheels in the
                straight-ahead position. When in a turn, caster acts as a lever, assisting the driver to return the
                front wheels to the straight-ahead position.
            </para>
            <para>Caster specifications are based on vehicle design load, which will usually result in a level frame. If
                the frame is not level when alignment checks are made, this must be considered in determining whether
                the caster setting is correct.
            </para>
            <para>With the vehicle on a smooth, level surface, frame angle should be measured with a bubble protractor
                placed on the frame rail
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200118">(Figure 18)</hotlnk>. The degree of tilt from the level frame position is the
                angle that must be used in determining a correct caster setting. Positive frame angle is defined as
                forward tilt (front end down) and negative angle as tilt to rear (front end height).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200118.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Measuring Frame Angle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PLACE PROTRACTOR HAVING LEVEL INDICATOR ON TOP OR BOTTOM OF FRAME</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TYPICAL POSITIVE FRAME ANGLE "FA"</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEVEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0200106">
            <title>Adjusting For Frame Angle</title>
            <para>The measured frame angle should be added to or subtracted from, as required, the specified level frame
                caster setting to obtain the caster that should actually be measured on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Positive frame angle should be subtracted from specified setting.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Negative frame angle should be added to specified setting.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>As an example, if the specified caster setting is a positive 1 degree and it is found that the vehicle
                has a positive 1 degree frame angle, then the measured caster should be 0&#177; &#189; degree. This
                would result in the desired 1 degree &#177;&#189; degree caster angle when the chassis settled to level
                frame under load.
            </para>
            <para>Possible causes of incorrect caster are sagging springs, bent or twisted axle, or unequally tightened
                spring U-bolts. In most cases a twisted axle would be the cause if caster varies more than the specified
                &#189; degree between left and right side.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle drifts or pulls to the right, raise the caster on that side &#189; to 1 degree to
                correct the condition.
            </para>
            <para>Caster adjustment is made by inserting a wedge between spring and axle.</para>
            <para>To increase caster, insert the wedge so the thick part faces the rear of the truck (to front for
                underslung axles).
            </para>
            <para>To decrease caster, place the wedge so that the thick end is toward the front of the truck (to rear
                for underslung axles).
            </para>
            <para>If an excessively thick wedge is required for a truck that has high mileage, check the contour of the
                springs and replace springs if necessary. Be sure center bolt drops into I-beam.
            </para>
            <para>The truck will lead to the side that has the most negative or lowest caster setting.</para>
            <para>Spring U-bolts should be tightened evenly and to specified torque listed in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_27.xml" xrefid="hl0200101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>, after the addition or
                removal of shims.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be sure spring center bolt drops into I-beam pilot. Also, when tightening U-bolt nuts, be sure
                        at least one full thread of U-bolt is visible when nut is tightened to specified torque. If not
                        visible, use longer U-bolts.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When U-bolts are replaced, the new U-bolt must be Grade 7 minimum incorporated rolled threads.
                        U-bolt nuts are to be flanged head type or those having a nylon insert locking feature, Grade 7
                        minimum.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
