<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERABLE DRIVE AXLE END UNIT: FABCO - DISASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DISASSEMBLE</title>
        <svcproc id="hl0201102" svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="1">
            <title>HUB AND WHEEL BEARINGS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prepare a clean place to work. It is important that no dirt or foreign material be allowed to
                        enter the unit during repairs. The outside of the unit should be carefully cleaned before
                        starting disassembly. If steam cleaning, ensure that breather and air fittings are covered to
                        prevent moisture from entering assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the rear wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the front of the truck with a jack and support with jackstands of suitable
                    capacity.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the front wheel for the side that you are working on.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Follow all procedures for working with brake material dust. Refer to the Warning.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the brake drum.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the eight outer drive flange locknuts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the flanged axle locknut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The drive flange should be loose enough to remove by hand. If it is not, use two 3/8-16
                    bolts in the extractor holes provided for this purpose. Set the colored drive flange shims aside for
                    later reuse
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Remove bearings in a manner which will not damage those bearings that will be re-used.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel bearing locknut, washer, and adjusting nut from the spindle. Rock the
                    hub in place to loosen the outer wheel bearing cone. Remove the cone and wrap it protectively.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hub, and pull the assembly straight off to avoid cocking the inner bearing
                    cone (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0201107">Figure 7</hotlnk>). If the cone binds against the spindle, try rocking the
                    hub to free it.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0201107" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0201107" filename="../figg02/g0201107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Proper Hub Removal</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To free the inner bearing cone, it may be necessary to use a pry bar under the inner
                            surface of the hub. To avoid damaging the inner seal, pry against the hub only. If the inner
                            bearing remains on the spindle when the hub is removed, use a suitable puller to remove it,
                            pulling only against the bearing race. Alternately tap on the race's outboard surface with a
                            small drift to correct its misalignment and attempt to remove it by hand.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wheel bearing cups may be removed from the hub using a suitable puller in the slots
                    provided in the hub's inner cavity. Pull the cup out evenly by using both slots.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
