<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: FABCO SDA-12 - ADJUSTMENTS - KING PIN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>KING PIN</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The front of the vehicle should be raised and properly supported. Front wheels should be off
                the axle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The lower kingpin jam nut should be loose or loosened and the lower kingpin ball stud backed
                down all the way. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201006">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201006" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201006.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Loosening Lower King Pin Ball Stud</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the wheel hub, spindle yoke and kingpin bracket assemblies with a hydraulic jack
                located under the drum. On units with an upper kingpin adjusting screw projecting through the upper
                kingpin cap or steering arm, adjust the screw to raise the aforementioned parts. Raise unit until the
                upward movement is resisted by the bottom of the upper kingpin bearing coming into contact with the
                lower spherical surface of the upper kingpin ball stud.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Put a stack of feeler gauges between the lower kingpin bracket and the suspension yoke. The
                feeler gauges should fill the gap snugly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the lower kingpin ball stud upward until the stack of feeler gauges loosen (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201007">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201007" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201007.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Turning Lower King Pin Ball Stud Upward</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Back off the lower kingpin ball stud one quarter turn (90&#176;).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the jam nut to the correct torque while restraining the lower kingpin ball stud from
                turning. On units with an upper kingpin adjusting screw, back off the screw 1/4 turn. Restrain screw
                while tightening locknut.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On units without upper adjustment screws, remove the jack or hoist supporting the brake
                drum. Using a pry bar under the upper kingpin bracket, 1/32 to 3/32-inch play may be observed on a new
                assembly. After loading, up to 1/8-inch play is acceptable. More than this requires inspection for wear
                or distortion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The kingpins should be readjusted after any loosening or removal and reassembly of the upper
                or lower kingpin brackets, replacement of kingpin bushings, etc.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
