<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s02001k" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5027K" revno="k" date="03/05/1996">
        <title>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION</title>
                    <para>Front wheel alignment is part of
                        <emph type="bold">Total Vehicle Alignment</emph>
                        which involves both steering and drive axles. Correct front wheel alignment is important. It
                        promotes longer tire wear by reducing lateral forces on tires, better known as side scrub.
                        Reduced side scrub promotes slow tire wear and a greater tread mileage potential. It promotes
                        ease of handling and reduces strain on the steering and axle components.
                    </para>
                    <para>It is important to recognize the symptoms of proper alignment as well as those of improper
                        alignment. It is also important to be able to recognize treadwear tendencies not related to
                        alignment.
                    </para>
                    <para>Proper alignment will improve miles per 32nd of tread wear, resulting in higher mileage at the
                        removal stage.
                    </para>
                    <para>Inspect tires at regular intervals. Unbalanced tread wear patterns may indicate worn front
                        axle and/or steering parts, out-of-balance tires, or an out-of-alignment condition.
                    </para>
                    <para>The following is a list of symptoms that typically do not require resetting alignment.</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Good Tire Mileage</emph>
                                - Indicates proper alignment unless the vehicle has been involved in an accident or has
                                some unusual complaint.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Uniform Tire Wear</emph>
                                - Generally indicates good alignment, but also that the treadwear rate is relatively
                                fast.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Symmetrical Tire Wear</emph>
                                - Both shoulders of both front tires show the same type and magnitude of wear. Shoulder
                                wear (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200101">Figure 1</hotlnk>), chamfer wear (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200102">Figure 2</hotlnk>) and river wear (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200103">Figure 3</hotlnk>) that are equal on each tread half indicates
                                good alignment.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Small Left/Right Tire Wear Difference</emph>
                                - A small wear differential between the left front and right front tire also indicates
                                good alignment. A 15 to 20 percent faster rate on the left front tire is acceptable.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Progressive Erosion or Chamfer Wear</emph>
                                - Late tire life irregular wear that has progressed from a symmetrical to erratic
                                condition does not always signal misalignment. Compare tire mileage to the fleet
                                average.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <figure id="f0200101" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg02/g0200101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Shoulder Wear</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f0200102" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg02/g0200102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Chamfer Wear</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f0200103" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg02/g0200103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. River Wear</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <title>P &#38; D Service</title>In P &#38; D service where a vehicle makes many turns per mile,
                        the left front tire may wear faster than the right front tire. To balance this condition, it is
                        recommended that steer tires be swapped side to side when "half" worn. P &#38; D service may
                        also create what appears as camber wear due to many turns. Bending the axle will not correct
                        this condition.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <title>Line Haul Service</title>Left front tires in line haul service generally wear slightly
                        faster than right front tires, primarily because of steering gear box locations and the high
                        frequency of steering inputs to the left side. Also, left front tires wear more uniformly than
                        right front tires because the slower-wearing right tires tend to show more irregularity.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>Try to read the symptoms of proper alignment before the tire is 60 percent worn.
                                Proper diagnosis becomes more difficult during late wear stages because "wear
                                progression" generally does not occur in a uniform fashion.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Before checking and adjusting the alignment, components such as wheel bearings, tie rod and
                        drag link ends, steering gear, shock absorbers and tire inflation should be inspected and
                        corrected where necessary.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>INSPECTION</title>
                        <para>It is impossible to over-stress the importance of careful and thorough inspection of
                            steering components. Thorough visual inspection for indications of wear or stress and the
                            replacement of such parts as are necessary will eliminate costly and avoidable front end
                            difficulties.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Inspect the steering knuckle king pin thrust bearing, wheel bearing cones and
                                    cups. Replace if rollers or cups are worn, pitted or damaged in any way.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If wheel bearing cups are to be replaced, remove from hubs with a suitable puller.
                                    Avoid the use of drift and hammers as they may easily mutilate cup bores.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Inspect the steering knuckles and replace if indications of weakness or excessive
                                    wear is found.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Check wear of the king pins and bushings; compare with correct specification.
                                    Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the type
                                    axle being serviced.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Check the tightness of the steering connections such as tie rod arms, steering
                                    arm, pitman arm to the steering gear, etc.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>REPAIR OF FORGED PARTS</title>
                        <para>In deciding whether to repair or scrap a damaged part, always keep in mind that we, as
                            manufacturers, never hesitate to scrap any part which is in any way doubtful.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>Do not attempt to straighten bent steering arms or knuckles. These parts must be
                                    replaced.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
