<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Lubrication, Inspection and
        Maintenance - Inspection and Maintenance
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="12">
        <title>Inspection and Maintenance</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection Tools</title>
            <para>Before performing an inspection of axle components, verify that the proper tools are available. Using
                the proper tools will ensure safety and provide the most accurate results. Check for the following
                tools:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Dial Indicator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tire Blocks</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Jack</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Safety Stands</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pry Bar</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque Wrench</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not repair or recondition front axle components, which are heat-treated and tempered.
                        Replace damaged or out-of-specification components. If you bend, weld or heat front axle
                        components, you will reduce the axle's strength and void Meritor's warranty. A weakened axle can
                        cause a vehicle accident, serious personal injury and damage to components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Check the following during an inspection.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Fasteners.</emph>
                        Verify that all fasteners are tightened to the specified torque. Use a torque wrench to check
                        the torque in a tightening direction. As soon as the fastener starts to move, record the torque.
                        Correct if necessary. Replace any worn or damaged fasteners.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Wear and Damage.</emph>
                        Inspect the parts of the axle for wear and damage. Look for bent or cracked parts. Replace all
                        worn or damaged parts.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Pivot Points.</emph>
                        Verify that looseness does not exist at the pivot points. Verify that the pivot points are
                        lubricated.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Operation.</emph>
                        Verify that all the parts move freely through the complete turning radius.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Tire Wear.</emph>
                        Inspect the tires for wear patterns that indicate suspension damage or misalignment.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Steering Arm Bolts.</emph>Check torque every 200,000 miles (320 000 km). Refer
                        to Checking Steering Arm Bolts in this section.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking Steering Knuckle Vertical End Play</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place blocks in front and behind the rear wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Set
                    the parking brakes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface. Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        Support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                        Jacks can slip and fall over. Serious personal injury can result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a jack to raise the vehicle until the front wheels are off the ground. Support the
                    front axle with safety stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a dial indicator for each side of the axle beam as follows:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn wheels straight ahead.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install dial base on axle beam.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place dial indicator tip to upper knuckle cap.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place a jack and a wood block (with hole that allows clearance for lower grease fitting)
                            under the lower king pin cap area (Figure 73).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set the dial indicator on 'zero.'</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Raise the jack until you start to lift the axle beam off the safety stands. Measure and
                            record dial indicator reading.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Lower the jack.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201273" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201273.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 73. Read Dial Indicator</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DIAL INDICATOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The reading must be 0.001 to 0.065-inch (0.025 - 1.650 mm) for new axles and 0.001 to
                    0.075-inch (0.025 - 1.905 mm) for axles in service (Figure 73). If the reading is not within
                    specification, axle components are damaged and must be replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking Upper and Lower Knuckle Bushings for Wear</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place blocks in front and behind the rear wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface. Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        Support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                        Jacks can slip and fall over. Serious personal injury can result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a jack to raise the vehicle until the wheels are off the ground. Support the vehicle
                    with safety stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the upper king pin bushing for wear. Install the base of a dial indicator onto the
                    axle beam. Place the indicator tip against the side of the knuckle top (curb side) or place
                    indicator tip against king pin cap (driver side) (Figure 74).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201274" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201274.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 74. Check Upper King Pin Bushing for Wear</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. DRIVER SIDE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the dial indicator on 'zero.'</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If one bushing must be replaced, replace both bushings in the knuckle.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the top of the tire side-to-side towards and away from the vehicle. If the dial
                    indicator moves a total of 0.010-inch (0.254 mm), the upper bushing is worn or damaged. Replace both
                    bushings. Refer to REMOVAL AND DISASSEMBLY, AND ASSEMBLY AND INSTALLATION Sections in this manual
                    (Figure 74).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the lower king pin bushing. Install a dial indicator so that the base is on the
                    I-beam and that the tip is against the side of the bottom of the knuckle (Figure 75).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201275" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201275.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 75. Check Lower King Pin Bushing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>B. FRONT VIEW CURB SIDE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the dial indicator on "zero."</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the bottom of the tire side-to-side towards and away from the vehicle. If the dial
                    indicator moves a total of 0.010-inch (0.254 mm), the lower bushing is worn or damaged. Replace both
                    bushings. Refer to PREPARE PARTS FOR ASSEMBLY, ASSEMBLY AND INSTALLATION, AND ADJUSTMENTS Sections
                    in this manual (Figure 75).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection of Sealed Hub Units</title>
            <para>Inspect the truck hub unit end play every 200,000 miles (320 000 km) or 24 months.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface. Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        Support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                        Jacks can slip and fall over. Serious personal injury can result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake. Place wheel blocks in front and behind each rear wheel. Place safety
                    stands under front axle. Jack up the truck so that the front wheel is off the ground. Remove the
                    wheel and tire.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hubcap.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>As the truck hub unit warms up during operation, some small amounts of grease will purge out
                        the outboard dust seal as pressure is released from inside the truck hub unit. The grease purge
                        is permissible if it does not exceed 2 grams or about 1/2 teaspoon. Do not replace the truck hub
                        unit if the grease purge does not exceed 2 grams.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the magnetic base of a dial indicator stand to the end of the spindle. Touch the
                    indicator stem against the face of the wheel pilot of the truck hub unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the dial indicator on "zero."</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slightly rotate the truck hub unit in both directions while pushing inward until the
                    dial indicator does not change. Repeat this step while pulling outward. The difference between the
                    two readings is the end play.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">An end play of 0.0-inches is permissible for the truck hub unit. Do not replace the
                    truck hub unit if the reading is 0.0-inches. However, you must replace the truck hub unit if it is
                    noisy or rough during rotation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the end play is greater than 0.003-inch, recheck the torque on the inner wheel
                    bearing nut as specified in ADJUSTMENTS Section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat Step 5. Record measurements greater than 0.003-inch (0.076 mm) and less than
                    0.009-inch (0.229 mm) in a maintenance log.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that the truck hub unit rotates smoothly.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The truck hub unit is sealed and greased for life and requires no maintenance. Any
                        disassembly, relubrication or repair of the truck hub unit will void the manufacturer's
                        warranty.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the end play reaches 0.009-inch or is very rough or noisy while rotating, replace the
                    truck hub unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspect Tie Rod Ends</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle with the steering wheels in the straight-ahead position (Figure 76).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201276" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201276.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 76. Inspect Tie Rod Ends</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TIE ROD ARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CROSS TUBE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place blocks in front and behind the rear wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. Set
                    the parking brake.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove dirt and grease from the tie rod end seals.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place indicator base on the bottom of the tie rod arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the indicator tip near the ball stud center (grease fitting) of the tie rod end
                    (Figure 77).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201277" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201277.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 77. Place Indicator Tip Near Ball Stud Center</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. UP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DOWN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the dial indicator on "zero."</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Check the tie red end play by hand. Do not use a pry bar. If a pry bar is used, readings from
                        the dial indicator will not be accurate.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the tie rod and cross tube assembly up and down by hand.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the dial indicator reading. If the dial indicates a reading of more than
                    0.060-inch (1.52 mm), tie rod end replacement is required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the dial indicator on the tie rod end assembly at the opposite side of vehicle and
                    repeat Steps 1 through 8.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspect Tie Rod Assembly for Movement</title>
            <para>This procedure applies to all tie rod assemblies.</para>
            <para>To perform this inspection, the entire system must be 'unloaded' (i.e., the front end of the vehicle
                must be raised and supported with stands).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not grease the tie rod assembly before performing the inspection. Doing so may provide
                        inaccurate results. Replace the entire tie rod end if the boot is torn or missing. Do not
                        replace the boot only.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place blocks in front of and behind the vehicle's rear wheels. Using the bottom of the
                    I-beam or frame rails, raise the front end off the ground, and support with stands.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine off, turn wheels from full left to full right, and then return to the
                    straight-ahead position. (This step will require more force for vehicles with the power steering
                    turned off.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that the boot is in place and completely installed over the tie rod end.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The boot may be missing completely or may not completely cover the ball joint.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for cracking or tears in the boot. Also check the boot seals for damage. Replace
                    the entire tie rod end if the boot is damaged (Figure 78).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201278" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201278.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 78. Check for Cracks or Tears in Boot</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Cracked or torn boot requires entire tie rod end replacement</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>A cotter pin must be installed through the tie rod end with the tie rod end nut tightened to
                        torque specification to securely attach the tie rod. Loss of the cotter pin will allow the tie
                        rod end nut to become loose and affect vehicle steering and possibly result in loss of steering
                        control.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that the tie rod nut is installed and secured with a cotter pin. If the cotter pin
                    is missing, check the nut torque specification and then install a new cotter pin. Always tighten tie
                    rod nut to specified torque when setting the cotter pin (Figure 79).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201279" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201279.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 79. Check that Tie Rod Nut is Installed and Secured</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Missing cotter pin indicates unsafe condition and requires immediate replacement
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The tie rod ends must be at the end of the cross tube slot to ensure adequate thread
                        engagement.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that the tie rod end is threaded correctly into the cross tube and engaged deeper
                    than the end of the cross tube slot. The tie rod end must be visible the entire length of the cross
                    tube slot (Figure 80).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201280" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201280.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 80. Check that Tie Rod End is Threaded Correctly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Tie rod end engaged deeper than the end of the cross tube slot.</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TIE ROD CROSS TUBE SLOT END</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Tie rod threads must be visible the entire length of the cross tube slot.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that zerk fittings are installed. Replace a damaged zerk fitting with a new one.
                    Some tie rod ends are non-greaseable and will not have zerk fittings. Do not install fitting if tie
                    rod end is non-greaseable type.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use the following items or methods to check for movement of the tie rod assembly.
                        Damage to components can result if:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>A crow bar, pickle fork or 2x4 is used.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>A tool instead of your hands is used to grasp the cross tube assembly that results in
                                cross tube damage.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Pressure or force is applied to the ends or the joints of the assembly.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The tires are rocked either with the vehicle on the ground or with the wheels
                                raised.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">By hand or using a pipe wrench with jaw protectors to avoid gouging the cross tube,
                    rotate the cross tube toward the front of the vehicle and then toward the rear. After rotating,
                    center the cross tube. If the cross tube will not rotate in either direction, replace both tie rod
                    ends.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position yourself directly below the ball stud socket. Using both hands, grab the
                    assembly end as close to the socket as possible (no more than 6-inches or 152.4 mm). Apply hand
                    pressure (approximately 100 pounds) vertically (up and down) in a push-and-pull motion several
                    times. Check for any movement or looseness at both tie rod end locations (Figure 81).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is any movement in the tie rod assembly, replace both tie rod ends.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201281" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201281.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 81. Check Movement by Hand by Pushing and Pulling</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tie Rod End Shop Inspection</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Replace the entire tie rod end if the boot is torn or missing. Do not replace the boot only.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the tie rod boot for cracks, tears or other damage. All tie rod ends with a
                    damaged boot require that the entire tie rod end be replaced (Figure 78).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grab by hand (or using a pipe wrench with jaw protectors to avoid gouging the cross
                    tube) and slightly rotate the cross tube toward the front of the vehicle and then slightly toward
                    the rear. After this movement, check in both directions, centering the cross tube between the stop
                    positions. If the cross tube will not rotate in either direction, replace both tie rod ends.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position yourself directly below the ball stud socket. Using both hands, grab the end as
                    close to the socket as possible (no more than 6-inches or 152.4 mm from the end). Firmly apply hand
                    pressure (approximately 100 pounds) in a vertical push-and-pull motion several times. When moving
                    the assembly, check for any movement at both tie rod ends (Figure 81).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If any movement is detected by hand, replace the worn components with new components before
                        releasing the vehicle back into service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If any movement is detected at one tie rod end, replace it and also the other tie rod
                    end. Always replace tie rod ends in pairs, even if only one tie rod is found damaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to straighten a bent cross tube. Damage to the axle can result. Be certain to
                        replace any cross tube with an original equipment cross tube (with the same length, diameter and
                        threads).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the cross tube and clamps for damage (Figure 82).</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace the cross tube if it is cracked or bent.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace the clamps if any are damaged.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace the entire cross tube assembly if either clamp is welded onto it.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201282" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201282.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 82. Inspect Cross Tube and Clamps for Damage</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CROSS TUBE CLAMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CRACK DAMAGE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for proper installation of the tie rod end clamp to-the cross tube. Verify that
                    tie rod ends are threaded in the cross tube past the clamps and the slots at the cross tube ends.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that zerk fittings are installed. Replace damaged zerk fittings (Figure 83). Some
                    tie rod ends have no zerk fittings because they are not greaseable. Do not install a zerk fitting on
                    a non-greaseable design tie rod end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check that the cotter pin is in place. Replace if missing. Tighten the tie rod end nut
                    to the specified torque and then insert the cotter pin through the castellated nut and the hole in
                    the tie rod end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0201283" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201283.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 83. Check that Zerk Fittings are Installed</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ALTERNATE ZERK FITTING LOCATIONS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tie Rod Service Tips</title>
            <para>If available, a service pit is recommended for tie rod inspection and maintenance. If a service pit is
                not available, use the following method:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use jacks to raise the vehicle using the following:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The vehicle must be on a level surface.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place blocks under the wheels not being raised to keep the vehicle from moving.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Raise the vehicle so that the area to be serviced is off the ground. Support the
                        vehicle with safety stands.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect and lubricate the tie rod ends.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive-on ramps may also be used. Observe all of the manufacturer's safety
                    recommendations.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tie Rods</title>
            <para>
                <title>Effect of Tie Rod End Wear an Steering Linkage</title>
            </para>
            <para>Unless tie rod end wear becomes excessive, a safe steering linkage is maintained. However, tie rod end
                wear can affect uniform steering control and, ultimately, wear to the front tires.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Detecting Tie Rod End Wear During Vehicle Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>A driver may not always detect a loose tie rod end condition during vehicle travel conditions. This is
                why it is important to inspect tie rod ends for wear and allowable movement at regular intervals.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Tie Rod End Wear</title>
            </para>
            <para>It is imperative that inspection and maintenance is performed at the recommended intervals to minimize
                the impact of tie rod end wear. Tie rod end wear occurs over time, under normal operating conditions. As
                wear occurs, the preload bearings inside each tie rod end provide less resistance. Excessive tie rod end
                wear will affect steering and contribute to premature wear of the tires and other axle components
                (Figure 84).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201284" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="532px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 84. Check Tie Rod End Wear</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BALL/STUD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. NATURAL PIVOT WEAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BALL/STUD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. NATURAL BEARING WEAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. BALL/STUD</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SOLID STEEL BEARING SURFACE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking Steering Arm Bolts</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Take care when you use Loctite, to avoid serious personal injury. Follow the manufacturer's
                        instructions to prevent irritation to the eyes and skin.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure applies to ALL axles included in this manual.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Check steering arm bolts for minimum 300 lbf-ft (406 Nm) torque. If steering arm bolt torque has
                fallen below 300 lbf-ft (406 Nm), remove bolts, clean all threads, and install new Loctite. Tighten
                bolts from 300-450 lbf-ft (406-610 Nm) torque. Check steering arm bolt torque every 200,000 miles (320
                000 km) or 24 months.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Old Loctite must be removed from bolt threads and internal threads of knuckle itself. Re-apply
                        new Loctite 680 (Meritor #2297-K-5523).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_57.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_59.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
