<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT DRIVE AXLE WHEEL ENDS: FABCO SDA-12 - DISASSEMBLY - HUB, DRUM AND WHEEL BEARING REMOVAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0201002" svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>HUB, DRUM AND WHEEL BEARING REMOVAL</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise the front of the vehicle with a jack and secure vehicle with floor stands.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove front wheels from vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the brake drum (disc wheel style hubs only).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the end turned to full steering lock, remove the bolt and washer retaining the outer
                drive yoke (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s02010_3.xml" xrefid="f0201002">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the nuts from the outer axle shaft drive studs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The flange should be loose enough to remove by hand. If not, use suitable bolts in the
                extractor holes to remove the outer axle shaft (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s02010_3.xml" xrefid="f0201003">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If oil is used for wheel bearing lubrication, care should be exercised to protect brake
                        linings, etc.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the wheel bearing lock nut (as shown in
                <hotlnk document="s02010_3.xml" xrefid="f0201004">Figure 4</hotlnk>). Then remove the lockwasher from
                spindle. Loosen wheel bearing adjusting nut as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201018">Figure 18</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201018.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Removing Bearing Adjusting Nut</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rock hub lightly to loosen the outer wheel bearing cone. Remove the cone and protect it from
                dirt. If wheel bearings are oil lubricated, some oil may fall on the brake shoe when the hub is removed
                in the next step, unless suitable protection is used.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lift the hub (or hub and drum assembly) off the spindle, (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201019">Figure 19</hotlnk>) using care to avoid damage to the bearing surfaces and to
                the threads. Wipe off any oil that may have reached the brake shoe before it reaches the lining.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201019" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/g0201019.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Removing Hub Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not remove the axle shaft studs unless replacing them.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the hub seal from the hub and discard.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the inner wheel bearing cone and protect it from dirt.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cover the spindle with a clean shop rag to protect it from damage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press wheel bearing cups from hub, if replacement is necessary.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>This is the limit of what is termed routine disassembly. It allows access to brakes for relining and to
            wheel bearings for repacking.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
