<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - TIE ROD - INSTALL TIE ROD STEERING ARM AND
        TIE ROD ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>INSTALL TIE ROD STEERING ARM AND TIE ROD ASSEMBLY</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>When tie rod, drag link or power steering linkage ends are replaced, they must be threaded into
                    the tie rod or drag link sufficiently to allow positioning of the clamp over the threads if not
                    welded on the ball joint end. Position the clamp bolt so it crosses the slot in the rod end.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>This procedure includes installing the tie rod ends to the tie rod.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press key in the slot in the tie rod steering arm.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the tie rod steering arm in the knuckle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200107">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200107" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Separate Tie Rod End From Tie Rod Arm</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TIE ROD STEERING ARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. KNUCKLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. NUT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nut on the tie rod steering arm. Tighten to the specified value in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_27.xml" xrefid="hl0200101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the cotter pins. If necessary, tighten the nut until the holes are aligned.
                <emph type="bold">Do not loosen the nut to install the cotter pin. If the cotter pin cannot be
                    installed, tighten nut to the next stop.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The tie rod has right hand threads on one end and left hand threads on the other end. Make
                        sure the tie rod ends are installed properly on the tie rod.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When tie rod ends are replaced or toe-in is adjusted, both ends must be threaded into the tie rod tube
                far enough to completely cover the slots in the tube. There should be no binding or looseness in the tie
                rod threads as the tie rod end is being threaded into the tie rod
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200108">(Figure 8)</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200108" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Tie Rod End Threads Extended Through Clamp</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CLAMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, install the tie rod ends on the tie rod to the position marked during removal.
            </para>
            <para>If new tie rod ends are installed, thread the ends equally on the tie rod to the required length.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the nuts and the bolts in the clamps. Tighten finger tight.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the tie rod ends into the tie rod steering arms. Install the tie rod stud nuts.
                Tighten to specified value in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_27.xml" xrefid="hl0200101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the cotter pins. Tighten the nut until the holes are aligned.
                <emph type="bold">Do not loosen the nut to install the cotter pin.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate tie rod ends. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                Manual for the proper lubricant.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and, if necessary, adjust the toe-in. After checking and adjusting the toe-in, be sure
                the tie rod ends are properly indexed or aligned (left tie rod end parallel to the right tie rod end)
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200109">(Figure 9)</hotlnk>. Proper indexing will eliminate restricted movement of the
                tie rod assembly. Restriction could cause premature failure of tie rod ends. Tighten the tie rod clamp
                bolts to the value in
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_27.xml" xrefid="hl0200101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200109" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200109.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Proper and Improper Tie Rod End Installations</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TIE ROD STEERING ARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LEFT TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RIGHT TIE ROD END</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BOTH TIE ROD ENDS ALIGNED</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Some tie rod clamps will be free to rotate around the tie rod allowing setting of toe-in while
                avoiding contact of the axle. There are two ways mechanical stops will position the clamps. One style
                clamp is limited by a spot weld on the tube. The second style clamp is limited by a tab that will lock
                against the end of tube. Both styles are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200110">Figure 10</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200110" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200110.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Types of Tie Rod Clamps</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TAB</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When repositioning the tie rod clamps, check bolt clearance between the bolt and axle I-Beam
                        at the maximum turn position, right and left (turn). Interference may restrict proper steering
                        linkage movement, and/or cause damage to clamp bolts.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
