<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT NON-DRIVE STEERING AXLE: ROCKWELL - ASSEMBLE - KNUCKLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0200504" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="12">
        <title>KNUCKLE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Clean the bores of the knuckle and the axle beam.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Put the knuckle on the axle beam.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the seal on the thrust bearing.</para>
                    <para>On `cover' type seals, install the seal over the open end of the bearing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200526">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <para>On `flat'-type seals, put the seal over the closed part of the bearing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200526">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0200526" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200526" filename="../figg02/g0200526.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Seal Types</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Integral Thrust Bearing and Seal</title>
            <para>The one-piece thrust bearing with an integrated grease seal is completely interchangeable with the
                two-piece design. It has a specified top and bottom orientation:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The surface with the inner diameter seal must be on top.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The surface with the outer diameter seal must be on the bottom (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200527">Figure 27</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f0200527" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200527" filename="../figg02/g0200527.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Outer Diameter Seal on Bottom</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the seal and thrust bearing assembly between the bottom of the axle beam and the
                    knuckle. Make sure the seal is toward the beam (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200528">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200528" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0200528" filename="../figg02/g0200528.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. Thrust Bearing Seal Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent personal injury, wear gloves when installing shims. The shims have sharp
                            edges.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the shims according to the following procedure:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the shims. Replace damaged shims.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If a new shim pack must be deter- mined, select the amount of shims that will give
                        the smallest end play.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Put a pry bar between the steering arm boss and the axle beam. Lift the knuckle and
                        slide the shim pack between the top of the beam and the knuckle (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200529">Figure 29</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0200529" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0200529" filename="../figg02/g0200529.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 29. Using Pry Bar</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure all the bores are aligned. If the bores are not aligned, the parts will be
                        damaged when the king pin is installed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the pry bar.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the king pin according to the following procedure (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200530">Figure 30</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200530" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0200530" filename="../figg02/g0200530.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 30. Installing the King Pin</caption>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply the lubricant to the bottom half of the king pin. Refer to GROUP 10 -
                        LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the pin in the top of the knuckle. Make sure the word "TOP" is toward you.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the pin so that the slots are aligned with the holes in the knuckle.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Do not force the pin through the top bushing or the shims will be damaged.</para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Push the pin through the top bushing, the seal and the shim pack. If the pin is
                        difficult to install, make sure the parts are aligned.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Wear eye protection. Do not hit steel parts with a steel hammer. Parts can break and
                                cause serious personal injury.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Push the pin into the bottom bushing. If necessary, use a brass hammer to drive the
                        pin into the bushing. Make sure all parts are aligned.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the slots in the pin are aligned with the holes in the axle beam.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not drive or tighten the draw keys into the knuckle until the end play is checked
                                and adjusted.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>All models covered in this service manual section use threaded draw keys.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the top draw key in the front of the knuckle. Install the bottom draw key in the
                    back of the knuckle. Make sure the key goes through the slot in the pin (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200531">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200531" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0200531" filename="../figg02/g0200531.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 31. Installing the Top Draw Key</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the end play of the knuckle according to the following procedure:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Hit the boss of the knuckle with a rubber mallet to move the parts in position (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200532">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0200532" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0200532" filename="../figg02/g0200532.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 32. Hit the Boss of the Knuckle</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Turn the knuckle to the straight (forward) position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach a dial indicator. Put the base on the knuckle. Put the tip on the center of
                        the king pin. Set the dial indicator on zero (0) (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0200533">Figure 33</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0200533" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0200533" filename="../figg02/g0200533.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 33. Set Dial Indicator on Zero</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use one of the following methods to measure the end play.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Method 1. Put a pry bar between the knuckle and the top of the axle center. Push the
                            knuckle up and measure the end play (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0200534">Figure 34</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0200534" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g0200534" filename="../figg02/g0200534.webp" type="webp"/>
                            <caption>Figure 34. Using Pry Bar</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <specpara>
                            <warning>
                                <para>If a hydraulic jack is used to measure end play, use two safety stands to support
                                    the axle. If safety stands are not used, the axle can fall and cause serious
                                    personal injury.
                                </para>
                            </warning>
                        </specpara>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Method 2. Put a block of wood and a hydraulic jack under the bottom of the knuckle. Raise
                            the knuckle until the pointer on the dial indicator stops (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0200535">Figure 35</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0200535" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g0200535" filename="../figg02/g0200535.webp" type="webp"/>
                            <caption>Figure 35. Raise the Knuckle</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat steps C and D with the axle in the full right and full left turn positions.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The end play must be 0.001 to 0.025 inch (0.025 to 0.635mm) in all positions.</para>
                    <para>If the knuckle binds or zero (0) end play is measured, remove the shims from the shim pack.
                    </para>
                    <para>If more than 0.025 inch (0.635mm) end play is measured, add shims to the shim pack.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Wear eye protection. Do not hit steel parts with a steel hammer. Parts can break and
                                cause serious personal injury.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Make sure the draw key is installed completely or the locknut is tightened to the
                                specified torque. If not installed correctly, the knuckle pin and the axle beam will be
                                damaged.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>All models covered in this service manual section use threaded draw keys.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the threaded draw keys.</para>
                <para>Install the lock nut and tighten to 30 to 45 ft-lbs. (41 to 61 N&#183;m) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200536">Figure 36</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200536" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0200536" filename="../figg02/g0200536.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 36. Install the Lock Nut</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new gaskets and the caps on the top and the bottom of the knuckle. Install the
                    bolts and the washers and tighten to 20 to 30 ft-lbs. (27 to 41 N&#183;m) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200537">Figure 37</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0200537" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0200537" filename="../figg02/g0200537.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 37. Installing New Gaskets and Caps</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the tie rod arm to the knuckle. See the procedure in this section.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the brake assembly on the knuckle. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the drum and the wheel and tire assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the wheel bearings. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES, Hubs, Bearings and Seals
                    in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the outer wheel bearing cone in the hub. Install the adjusting nut.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the wheel bearings. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES, Hubs, Bearings and Seals in
                    the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the cap and the gasket on the hub. Install the bolts and tighten to 20 to 30
                    ft-lbs. (27 to 41 N&#183;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the vehicle to the ground. Check for correct operation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and adjust the toe-in. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLES, Steering General
                    Information and Front Wheel Alignment in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02005r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
