<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Adjustments - Major Front Wheel
        Alignment
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="align" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Major Front Wheel Alignment</title>
        <para>Perform a major front wheel alignment to correct steering and tire wear conditions.</para>
        <para>To perform the major front wheel alignment, refer to the following sequence:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect all the systems that affect the wheel alignment. Refer to Inspection Before
                Alignment in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and adjust the wheel bearings. For models with unitized hubs, check wheel bearing end
                play for the truck hub unit. Refer to Inspection of Sealed Hub Units in LUBRICATION, INSPECTION AND
                MAINTENANCE Section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and adjust the maximum turn angle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the vehicle has power steering, check and adjust the pressure relief in the power
                steering system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and adjust the turning radius angle (toe-out on turns or Ackerman angle). Refer to
                Turning Radius Angle in this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the king pin (or steering axis) inclination. Refer to Steering Axis Inclination in
                this section.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the camber angle. Refer to Camber Angle in this section.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Axle camber is not adjustable. Do not change the axle camber angle or bend the axle beam. Bending
                    the axle beam to change the camber angle can damage the axle and reduce axle strength, and will void
                    Meritar's warranty. A bent axle beam can also cause a vehicle accident and serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and adjust the caster angle. Refer to Caster Angle in this section.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and adjust the toe-in. Refer to Adjust the Toe in this section.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
