<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FRONT AXLES: INTERNATIONAL BY SPICER I-BEAM - MAXIMUM LIMITS FOR FRONT AXLE KING PIN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAXIMUM LIMITS FOR FRONT AXLE KING PIN</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This procedure is for determining if front axle king pin bushing wear (side play) and spindle vertical
                end play measurements exceed the maximum wear limits for normal service and decide if maintenance is
                necessary.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>The International method for checking king pin looseness is to use a dial indicator. Instructions for
                the use of the dial indicator in this particular operation are as follows (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200404">Figure 4</hotlnk>):
            </para>
            <figure id="f0200404" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0200404" filename="../figg02/G0200404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. King Pin Bushing Wear Measurement</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. 17.5 INCHES (443 MM) RADIUS</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. MEASURE MOVEMENT HERE 1/8 INCH (3.175 MM) MAXIMUM MOVEMENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. DIAL INDICATOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>King pins and bushings must NOT have been recently lubricated before making this check.
                        Measurements must be made BEFORE lubrication
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the rear wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise and support axle on
                    <emph type="bold">two</emph>
                    jack stands. If the axle is supported on only one jack stand, a false reading will be obtained.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the tire at 17.5 inch (444.5 mm) radius from the center of the spindle. Position a
                    dial indicator at the 17.5 inch (444.5 mm) mark to measure tire movement.
                    <emph type="bold">Accurate results depend upon measurement at specified radius.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply brakes to eliminate wheel bearing play and to assure getting a correct reading.
                    Failure to do so will result in a false reading.
                </para>
                <para>Push the wheel inward at the top and measure the movement obtained on the dial indicator at the
                    17.5#inch (444.5 mm) radius mark on the tire (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0200404">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If more than 1/8 inch (3.175 mm) is obtained at the 17.5 inch (444.5 mm) mark (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0200404">Figure 4</hotlnk>), the king pin bushings should be replaced at the next
                scheduled service interval. Vehicles with more than 3/8 inch (9.515 mm) should be taken out of service
                until vehicle is repaired.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02004t_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02004t_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02004t.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
