<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERING GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND FRONT WHEEL ALIGNMENT - DRAG LINKS - REMOVE DRAG LINK AND DRAG LINK
        STEERING ARM ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVE DRAG LINK AND DRAG LINK STEERING ARM ASSEMBLY</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cotter pins and nuts from drag link ends where they fasten onto the drag link
                steering arm and pitman arm.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Separate drag link from pitman arm and drag link steering arm. Use a removal tool to
                separate drag link from drag link steering arm.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the drag link steering arm from the knuckle in the same manner as the tie rod
                steering arm. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s02001k_HL0200102.xml" xrefid="hl0200102">TIE ROD</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove key from drag link steering arm.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Observe the following precautions in regard to the power steering gear when the drag link or
                        steering linkage is disconnected.
                    </para>
                    <para>A. Do not move the steering gear output shaft by way of the pitman arm when the drag link is
                        disconnected. This may cause air to be introduced into the steering fluid.
                    </para>
                    <para>B. Do not turn steering gear input shaft more the 1.5 turns from center with the steering
                        linkage disconnected on a TRW steering gear. If turned more than 1.5 turns, it may cause the
                        automatic poppets to reset, affecting end of travel pressure relief.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
