<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>STEERABLE DRIVE AXLE END UNIT: FABCO - ADJUSTMENTS - KINGPIN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>KINGPIN</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block the rear wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The front of the vehicle should be raised, properly supported, and the front wheels removed
                from the axle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                        performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle
                        with floor stands.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the lower kingpin locknut and back it down enough to allow the lower kingpin
                lockwasher to disengage from its retaining dowel pin. Back the lower kingpin ball stud down four
                complete turns.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the upper kingpin adjustment jam nut and back out the adjusting screw four full
                turns. The drive end assembly will begin to lower as the screw is turned out (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0201121">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0201121" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0201121" filename="../figg02/G0201121.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Loosening the Upper Kingpin Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the adjusting screw until upward motion of the drive end stops. If a finger is
                placed near the gap between the suspension and spindle yokes, the point at which upward travel stops can
                be determined. Significant additional resistance will also be felt in the effort required to turn the
                adjusting screw.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the gap between the suspension and spindle yokes in the area of the lower kingpin ball
                stud with a stack of feeler gauges. There should be enough gauges in the stack to fit the gap snugly (
                <hotlnk document="s02011_10.xml" xrefid="f0201114">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the lower kingpin ball stud until the feeler gauge stack loosens, indicating that
                the ball stud threads are actually beginning to spread the suspension and spindle yokes apart. Back off
                the ball stud 1/4 turn.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the lower kingpin ball stud just enough (either direction) to allow the closest hole in
                the lower kingpin lockwasher to engage the locating pin. Tighten locknut to 600 ft-lbs. (813 N&#183;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Back out the upper kingpin adjusting screw 1/4 turn and tighten the jam nut to 45 ft-lbs.
                (61 N&#183;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
