<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - Meritor Medium Duty Front Drive Steer Axle - Adjustments - Camber Angle
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Camber Angle</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Axle camber is not adjustable. Do not change the axle camber angle or bend the axle beam. Bending
                    the axle beam to change the camber angle can damage the axle and reduce axle strength, and will void
                    Meritor's warranty. A bent axle beam can also cause a vehicle accident and serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Camber is the angle of the tire with respect to the ground. Camber is positive when the distance between
            the top of the wheels is greater than the distance at the ground (Figure 63).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0201263" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg02/G0201263.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 63. Camber</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. POSITIVE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. ZERO OR NEUTRAL</callout1>
                <callout1>3. LOAD</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>A small amount of positive camber is built into the knuckle because camber changes with load. This results
            in a zero camber angle when the vehicle is operated at the normal load.
        </para>
        <para>If camber is out of specification by more than 1-1/2 degrees, rapid or uneven tire wear will occur. Bias
            ply tires will show excess camber easily, while with vehicles equipped with radial tires, excess camber will
            not be as evident.
        </para>
        <para>The camber angle is not adjustable. The camber angle is machined into both the axle beam and the knuckle.
            If the camber angle is not at the specified angle, check the axle beam and the steering knuckle for damage.
            Service as necessary.
        </para>
        <table id="t0201204">
            <title>Camber Angle Recommendations</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1"/>
                <colspec colname="col2"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>Conditions</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>Left and Right Sides</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>Camber angles machined into axles</para>
                            <para>Load not applied on axle.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>+1/4&#176; Nominal</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>Camber angles under load</para>
                            <para>Axle installed in vehicle.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col2">
                            <para>+3/16&#176; to -3/16&#176; (final reading)</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>Use an alignment machine to check the camber angle. Refer to the procedure of the manufacturer of the
            alignment equipment. Refer to OEM vehicle manufacturer to determine specifications for the correct camber
            setting. The Table above gives the specification Meritor builds into the axle, but always use the
            specification from the manufacturer of the vehicle.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s02012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
