<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - BUSHING REPLACEMENT - BEAM ASSEMBLY (BOTH)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BEAM ASSEMBLY (BOTH)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block front wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise axles and support vehicle by the frame. Use frame stands.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            per- formed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove ALL wheels from both rear axles. Refer to Group 17-RIMS, WHEELS and TIRES in the
                    CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all beam ends. Use procedures as described in preceding instructions pertaining
                    to specific beam end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Support axles with stands placed under or supporting differential carriers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With beam being supported with jack, remove saddle caps from both beams.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower jack supporting beams. If beams are stuck, pry beams free.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Take care when prying the beam that the beam does not fall and cause personal injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With beams lowered, slide beam off cross tube. Remove beams and cross tube from under
                    carriage.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate tube ends with chassis grease and slide cross tube and beam under vehicle rear
                    suspension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide cross tube into beams. Using jacks and an assistant if necessary, raise beam
                    assembly into position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install beam ends as described previously in Beam End Installation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install saddle caps; tighten cap nuts to specifications. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all jacks, supporting axles and beams.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheels. Refer to GROUP 17- RIMS, WHEELS AND TIRES in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                    Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove frame stands and lower vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test vehicle for proper operation before putting vehicle back into service.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
