<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL RIDE OPTIMIZED SUSPENSION (IROS) - component installation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>component installation</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This manual section is set up for the component installation.
                <emph type="bold">Only International Truck and Engine certified parts should be used for the
                    installation procedures to insure proper fit and service of the vehicle suspension system.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>suspension air springs</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install replacement air spring assembly and tighten fasteners to specified torque
                    values. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air line to air spring and install height control valve linkage at lower end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build vehicle system air pressure to governor cutout pressure and use soap solution to
                    check for leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for proper ride height adjustment. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_X0301301.xml" xrefid="x0301301">RIDE HEIGHT ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>chassis shock absorbers</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position shock absorber and install mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten shock mounting fasteners to specified torque values. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>main support members</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                        performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle
                        with floor stands.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all parts for wear, cracks or failed welds. Repair or replace.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not repair a cracked spring, U-bolt or spacer plates. The listed parts must be replaced
                            if cracks are present.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <para>Prior to installing the MAIN SUPPORT MEMBER assembly, a careful inspection of component parts
                including tapered leaf spring mounting bushing should be undertaken. Only authorized International parts
                should be used in the installation procedure.
            </para>
            <para>Position spring to approximate installed position
                <hotlnk document="s03013_11.xml" xrefid="f0301315">(Figure 17)</hotlnk>
                and install the bar pin in hanger
                <emph type="bold">on the forward side of the spring hanger</emph>. Also install lower shock bracket end
                and
                <emph type="bold">do not</emph>
                tighten fasteners
                <hotlnk document="s03013_13.xml" xrefid="f0301321">(Figure 21).</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate main support member end with
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_9.xml" xrefid="f0301313">(Figure 13, Item 5)</hotlnk>
                    bushing assembly, at the forward suspension mounting bracket
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_14.xml" xrefid="f0301322">(Figure 22, Item 1)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert bolt and hand tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place axle seat bracket on main support member with alignment pin, axle seat bracket
                    forward mark indicator should be facing in forward direction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place u-bolts and u-bolt axle top mounting bracket on axle assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install air spring assembly to top bracket mounted on chassis frame
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_12.xml" xrefid="f0301316">(Figure 16, Item 4).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align and install lower u-bolt mounting plate, install u-bolt nuts and hand tighten
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_14.xml" xrefid="f0301322">(Figure 22, Items 2 and 3)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert mounting nut on air spring threaded stud and hand tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and install shock absorber to upper shock absorber mounting bracket. Install
                    bolts and hand tighten
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_13.xml" xrefid="f0301320">(Figure 20, Items 1, 2 and 3).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place lower air spring mounting stud in applicable mounting hole in rear of tapered leaf
                    spring
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_9.xml" xrefid="f0301313">(Figure 13, Item 1).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all mounting hardware to appropriate values as indicated in the torque chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When all torque requirements are met and installations complete, follow procedures for
                    re-inflating suspension to proper ride height. See the first section and appropriate subsection for
                    correct ride height procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place U-bolt seat on top of spring
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_12.xml" xrefid="f0301319">(Figure 23, Item 2)</hotlnk>
                    with tab towards vehicle frame then install U-bolt assembly to spring and axle.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                    tighten fasteners to specified values at this time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point assemble the spring clamp group and main support member to the axle, align
                    the suspension and tighten assembly. Tighten to specifications in the following sequence: U-bolts
                    (tighten diagonally),
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_17.xml" xrefid="f0301326">(Figure 28)</hotlnk>
                    front torque rod nuts, rear torque rod nuts, and the lower shock absorber mounting plate on the
                    transverse beam. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect lower air spring, shock absorbers and height control valve linkage and any air
                    lines that were removed. Tighten all fasteners to values specified. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install tires/wheels. Refer to GROUP 17 - WHEELS in the Master Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower vehicle. Remove all stands.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build vehicle air pressure to governor cutout pressure and use soap and water solution
                    to check for leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque rods</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install replacement torque rods (be sure to use correct length torque rods for vehicle),
                    connecting the end to the frame side rail first and end to axles second (for transverse rods).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten fasteners to specified torque values. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recheck axle alignment. Adjust if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>main support member bushings</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For all bushing types:</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">TO INSURE PROPER MOUNTING OF NEW BUSHING, CLEAN MAIN SUPPORT MEMBER WHERE BUSHING
                        IS TO BE PRESS FITTED WITH DEGREASING FLUID AND WIRE BRUSH. USE DRILL MOUNTED WIRE BRUSH
                        ONLY</emph>.
                </para>
            </specpara>
            <para>Apply 1/4- 1/2" wide ring of bonding agent to lower quarter of bushing as shown
                <hotlnk document="s03013_17.xml" xrefid="f0301326">(Figure 26, Item 2)</hotlnk>, before pressing into
                spring eye.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>APPROVED COMPOUNDS ARE:</para>
                    <para>1. PERMABOUND HM160</para>
                    <para>2. LOCTITE RC/680</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">LOCTITE RC/680 IS PREFERRED</emph>
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Apply 1/4- 1/2" ring of bonding agent to top edge of eye I.D.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301327">(Figure 27, Items 1 and 3),</hotlnk>
                as shown, before installing bushing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301327" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301327.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Bonded Bushings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRESSED BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BONDING AGENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREADED BUSHINGS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BONDING AGENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TAPERED LEAF SPRING END</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. BUSHING FLANGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. BUSHING MOUNTING ENDS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE: Unless otherwise specified, minimum push out force after 24 hours cure is 6750
                    lbs. for threaded bushings and 4000 lbs. for all other bushings.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Bushing must be clean and free of oil and grease prior to installation.</para>
            <para>After bushing installation, residual bonding agent must be removed.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>u-bolts</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When tightening spring U-bolts, torque rod fasteners and other related mounting fasteners to
                        specifications, the vehicle must be at proper ride height to avoid introducing unnecessary
                        stress on the bushings. Refer to the
                        <hotlnk document="s03013_22.xml" xrefid="x0301302">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                        for specified torque values.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the U-bolt threads and U-bolt nuts for rust and debris and clean the threads if
                    contaminated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the U-bolts and nuts and torque the nuts to 15 lbf-ft, using a diagonal
                    pattern.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-torque the nuts to 100 lbf-ft, using a diagonal pattern.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re- torque the nuts to 200 lbf-ft, using a diagonal pattern.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-torque the nuts to 300 lbf-ft, using a diagonal pattern.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-torque the nuts to 425 lbf-ft, using a diagonal pattern.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the same diagonal pattern with each U-bolt nut re-torque.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0301328" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG03/G0301328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. U-Bolt Torque Patterns</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
