<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL AIR SUSPENSION WITH TAPERED LEAF SPRINGS - HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE - RIDE HEIGHT ADJUSTMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0300102" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>RIDE HEIGHT ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the center punch mark on the leveling valve capscrew is positioned toward the
                axle end of lever arm (
                <hotlnk document="s03001k_2.xml" xrefid="f0300103">Figure 3</hotlnk>) and that both clamps are on the
                inside locations (bolt head end toward the center of the vertical rod) of the rubber links.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assure that approximately 100 psi (689.5 kPa) air pressure is available in the reservoir
                systems (check cab gauges).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the vertical link from the height control valve lever.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The height adjustment is checked at the rear axle on a 4x2 chassis and the rear-rear axle on
                a 6x4 chassis.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Place a straight edge on the center line of the top metal plate on the air springs (
                    <hotlnk document="s03001k_4.xml" xrefid="f0300105">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Do not position the straight
                    edge on the frame rails. Measure the distance from the bottom edge of the straight edge to the top
                    edge of the transverse crossmember.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">See
                    <hotlnk document="s03001k_HL0300101.xml" xrefid="hl0300101">RIDE HEIGHT DIMENSIONS</hotlnk>, for the
                    appropriate "A" dimension as illustrated in
                    <hotlnk document="s03001k_4.xml" xrefid="f0300105">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If distance is less than specified:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Raise valve control lever and hold up until distance is correct. Center lever.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle height is greater than in the
                    <hotlnk document="s03001k_HL0300101.xml" xrefid="hl0300101">RIDE HEIGHT DIMENSIONS</hotlnk>, lower
                    the valve control lever and hold down until the specified distance has been attained.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">When the specified height has been attained, install two centering pins (use two No. 21,
                    or 5/32 inch drill bits) in the valve body (
                    <hotlnk document="s03001k_2.xml" xrefid="f0300103">Figure 3</hotlnk>) to maintain the lever arm in
                    the centered position (horizontal) while installing and adjusting the vertical link to the lever
                    arm.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the vertical linkage on the height control valve lever. Verify that the vertical
                linkage rod is centered between the upper and lower clamps. Tighten the clamp bolt(s) and install the
                washer and cotter pin.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fine adjustment of the vertical linkage can be made by loosening the nuts on the
                    vertical linkage rod, lower anchor and moving the nuts up or down. Tighten the nuts when completed.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove the centering pins.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03001k_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03001k_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03001k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
