<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>NEWAY AIR SUSPENSION - REMOVE AND INSTALL - SUSPENSION AIR SPRINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SUSPENSION AIR SPRINGS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When replacing air springs, use only approved International part for vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unload vehicle and block wheels to prevent vehicle from rolling. Support vehicle with
                    floor stands.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Exhaust air from vehicle and suspension system. Exhaust air by:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Even if air spring has a leak and is deflated, the air must still be exhausted from
                            system.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Automatic control - height control valve - disconnect link at lower connection, then
                        rotate control arm to exhaust (approximately 45 degrees down) position.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect air supply line from air spring.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Exhaust air from reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air spring assembly.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install replacement air spring assembly and tighten base bolts to 50 to 60 ft-lbs. (68
                    to 81 N&#8226;m), and hex lock on top of air spring to 31 to 38 ft-lbs. (42 to 52 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air line to air spring and install height control valve linkage at lower end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build vehicle system air pressure to governor cut-out pressure and use soap solution to
                    check for leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for proper ride height adjustment.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
