<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL RIDE OPTIMIZED SUSPENSION (IROS) - HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE - SERVICE CHECKS (VALVE ON TRUCK)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS (VALVE ON TRUCK)</title>
        <para>Often a valve is unnecessarily replaced. There are basic steps to be performed to determine if the valve
            is defective or if proper adjustment has not been performed. To determine the status of a valve, perform the
            following service checks:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove cotter pin and washer from upper link. Loosen the clamp and detach the vertical
                linkage from the height control lever arm.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assure that brake air reservoir pressure is at governor cutoff pressure or about 100 psi
                (689.5 kPa).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees above horizontal. Air pressure at
                the air springs should begin to increase within 15 seconds which will cause the truck frame to rise.
                This can easily be detected by feeling the shock absorber extend at the dust tube to shock absorber body
                joint.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees below horizontal. Air pressure at
                the air springs should begin to decrease. Let air escape until air spring height is approximately 10
                inches (254 mm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise valve lever to 45 degrees above horizontal again, until air spring height is to
                dimension shown in
                <hotlnk document="s03013_X0301301.xml" xrefid="x0301301">RIDE HEIGHT DIMENSIONS</hotlnk>. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03013_X0301301.xml" xrefid="f0301306">Figure 6, Item 2</hotlnk>. Release the valve
                lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check valve body and all tubing connections and air springs for air leaks with soapy water.
                Repair as necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recheck air spring height 15 minutes after step 5 above has been completed. If the air
                spring height has changed, return to step 5 and repeat until the correct height is obtained.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no leaks are found, and the height control valve functions as described above, and air
                spring height is at the specified dimension after 15 minutes, the valve is functioning properly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03013_X0301301.xml" xrefid="x0301301">RIDE HEIGHT ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>
                and perform the adjustment.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_X0301301.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
