<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <para>Proper service and repair are important to the safe and reliable operation of the tandem suspension. The
            service procedures recommended by International and described in this technical publication are effective
            methods of performing maintenance.
        </para>
        <para>There are various warnings and cautions that should be read carefully to minimize the risk of personal
            injury and to assure that proper methods are used. Improper servicing may damage the vehicle or render it
            unsafe in operation.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Hendrickson Suspension reminds users to adhere to the published capacity ratings for the
                    suspensions. Add-on axle attachments and other load transferring devices can increase the suspension
                    load above the rated and approved capacities which could result in failure and loss of vehicle
                    control, possibly causing personal injury or property damage.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not modify or rework parts. Do not use substitute parts. Use of a modified or substitute part
                    is not recommended because the part may not meet Hendrickson's specifications, which could result in
                    failure of the part, loss of vehicle control, and possible personal injury or property damage.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not use a cutting torch to remove any attaching fasteners. Do not use a cutting torch to remove
                    the equalizing beams from the axles or to remove the bushings from the beam centers or ends.
                    Welding, torching or attaching material to the equalizing beams must never be performed. The use of
                    heat on suspension components will adversely affect the strength of these parts. A component damaged
                    in this manner may result in the loss of vehicle control and possible personal injury or property
                    damage.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A mechanic using a service procedure or tool which has not been recommended by International must
                    be satisfied that no safety will be jeopardized by the method or tool selected.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
