<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL 4X2 AND 6X4 SPRING SUSPENSION WITH TORQUE RODS - SERVICE - INSTALL SUSPENSION (SPRINGS)
        (Figure 7 and Figure 8 )
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTALL SUSPENSION (SPRINGS) (
            <hotlnk document="s03008_8.xml" xrefid="f0300807">Figure 7</hotlnk>and
            <hotlnk document="s03008_8.xml" xrefid="f0300808">Figure 8</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <para>When assembling suspension, all bolts are to be installed with bolt heads to the inside of frame unless
            otherwise specified.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install leaf spring assemblies on bottom U-bolt seat with short end of spring assembly
                toward equalizer. Install spacers in same location from which they were removed in disassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install spring retaining pins in spring brackets and equalizer bracket.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble top U-bolt seat, U-bolts and U-bolt plate. Install U-bolt nuts and tighten
                securely.
                <emph type="bold">Do not torque at this time.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">nstall torque rods. Position alignment shims in the locations from which they were removed
                in disassembly. Tighten torque rod mounting bolts and nuts to specified torque. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03008_HL0300803.xml" xrefid="hl0300803">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install wheels and tires. Refer to GROUP 17 WHEELS in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque U-bolts diagonally and evenly with wheels on the ground. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03008_HL0300803.xml" xrefid="hl0300803">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                for specifications.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After suspension has been assembled, it must be checked for alignment before returning
                vehicle to service. Refer to GROUP 03 - SPRING SUSPENSION ALIGNMENT in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                manual.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After vehicle has been returned to service, spring U-bolts must be retightened at the
                        intervals specified under
                        <hotlnk document="s03008_HL0300801.xml" xrefid="hl0300801">MAINTENANCE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03008_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03008_HL0300802.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
