<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>NEWAY AIR SUSPENSION - OPERATION - CAB AIR RELEASE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CAB AIR RELEASE</title>
        <para>With "Cab Air Control," the air piping for the system includes a cab air switch (
            <hotlnk document="s03002r_1.xml" xrefid="f0300205">Figure 5</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0300209">Figure 9</hotlnk>) and two pilot valves (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0300210">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0300209" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0300209" filename="../figg03/G0300209.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. CAB AIR PIPING WITH CAB AIR CONTROL SYSTEM</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>A.VIEW IN DIRECTION OF ARROW A</callout1>
                <callout1>1.AIR SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>2.PRODUCT GRAPHIC</callout1>
                <callout1>3.CONTROL VALVE GUARD</callout1>
                <callout1>4.SWITCH GROUNDING</callout1>
                <callout1>5.CAB AIR SWITCH</callout1>
                <callout1>6.PLUG</callout1>
                <callout1>7.3/8" BLACK TUBE (SUPPLY)</callout1>
                <callout1>8.3/8" BLACK TUBE (DELIVERY)</callout1>
                <callout1>9.3/8" BLUE TUBE</callout1>
                <callout1>10.TO PILOT VALVES</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0300210" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0300210" filename="../figg03/G0300210.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. AIR SPRING PIPING WITH CAB AIR CONTROL SYSTEM</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1.AIR SUPPLY TO RT FRT AIR SPRING FROM REAR AIR SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>2.PILOT VALVE DIRECTS AIR SUPPLY TO AIR SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>3.PILOT VALVE (EXHAUST POINTS DOWN)</callout1>
                <callout1>4.AIR SUPPLY FROM RT HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE TO PILOT VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>5.HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>6.LT HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE AIR TO PILOT VALVE ON OUTBOARD SIDE</callout1>
                <callout1>7.AIR SUPPLY TO LT AIR SPRINGS FROM PILOT VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>8.PRESSURE PROTECTION VALVE AIR SUPPLY DIRECTED TO HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>9.HOSE WRAP</callout1>
                <callout1>10.PRESSURE PROTECTION VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>11.AIR SUPPLY TO LT FWD AIR SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>12.AIR SUPPLY FROM VEHICLE SYSTEM AND CAB AIR CONTROLS</callout1>
                <callout1>13.CAB AIR CONTROL LINE TO PILOT VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>14.HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE LINKAGE CONNECTS TO BEAM</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The cab air switch in the instrument panel has two positions. In the RUN position, the valve
                is closed. Placing the valve in the DUMP position opens the valve and directs air pressure to the pilot
                valves located near the height control valves. With the cab air switch in the DUMP position, a ground
                circuit is closed, illuminating a warning light on the instrument panel. Refer to the circuit diagram
                furnished with vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the cab air controls, the rear hosing incorporates the pilot valve as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The air supply to the height control valves comes from the pressure protection valve.
                    Air is delivered from the height control valves to the pilot valves (one on each side), which
                    distribute air to the right and left air spring systems. The pilot valve has no other function with
                    the cab control valve in the RUN position.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Placing the cab air switch in the DUMP position directs air to each pilot valve causing
                    it to stop the air supply to the air springs and dump the air from the air springs through the
                    exhaust port on the bottom of the pilot valves.
                </para>
                <para>Placing the cab air switch back into the RUN position returns air spring control to the height
                    control valves and the air springs will inflate until the vehicle is level.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
