<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>NEWAY AIR SUSPENSION - SERVICE CHECKS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <para>Often a valve is unnecessarily replaced. There are basic steps to be performed to determine if the valve
            is defective or if proper adjustment has not been performed. To determine the status of a valve, perform the
            following service checks:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the vertical links.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assure that brake air reservoir pressure is at governor cut-off pressure or about 100 psi.
                If the air pressure at the control valves is significantly less than system air pressure, check the air
                lines for any restrictions and check the pressure protection valve for proper operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees above horizontal. Air pressure at
                the air springs should begin to increase within 15 seconds which will cause the truck frame to rise.
                This can easily be detected by feeling the shock absorber extend at the dust tube to shock absorber body
                joint.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the control lever arm to the neutral position. The air flow should stop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees below horizontal. Air should begin
                to exhaust from the valve within 15 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Move the control arm to the neutral position. The valve should shut off air flow.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise or lower the air pressure in the air springs to achieve the correct air spring height.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03002r_HL0300202.xml" xrefid="hl0300202">RIDE HEIGHT DIMENSION / CODES CHART</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check valve bodies and all tubing connections and air springs for air leaks using soap and
                water solution. Correct any leak conditions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Recheck air spring height 15 minutes after Step 8 above has been completed. If the air
                spring height has changed, return to Step 8 and repeat operation until the leaks are corrected.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no leaks are found, and the height control valve functions as described above, and air
                spring height is at the specified dimension after 15 minutes, the valve is functioning properly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03002r_17.xml" xrefid="f0300223">Figure 23</hotlnk>, and perform the adjustment.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
