<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - REPLACE - BAR PIN BEAM END BUSHINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="8">
        <title>BAR PIN BEAM END BUSHINGS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a penetrating oil to the threads of 1 inch diameter bolts and locknuts that connect
                the end bushing inner metal to the axle bracket. While supporting the end of the beam, remove the bolts.
                If the fasteners are rusted in place, an air hammer chisel may be used to loosen the bolt from the axle
                bracket and bushing.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury, support the end of the beam as it may drop when the through bolts
                        are removed. After all fasteners are removed, they should be discarded. DO NOT RE-USE THE
                        FASTENERS.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When removing and installing bushings in equalizing beams, follow the procedures outlined in
                        this publication. Do not use a cutting torch to remove the bushing outer metals pressed in the
                        beam bores. Welding, torching or attaching material to the equalizing beam must never be
                        performed. The use of heat adversely affects the strength of the beams.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After removing the equalizing beam bushings, thoroughly inspect each beam bore.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If torch undercutting is found from previous rebushing, replace with a new equalizing beam. Do
                        not take the responsibility for possible road failure by rebushing a beam in this condition.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Bar Pin Style rubber end bushings can be removed with the SPECIAL TOOLS,
                        <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301106.xml" xrefid="f0301130">Figure 30</hotlnk>, or with shop made
                        tools. When using these tools, it is important that they are positioned against the edge of the
                        outer metal of the bushing for pressing into the end bore of the equalizing beam.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the confinement washer from one end of the bushing for pushing tool clearance. This
                may require the use of a chisel where the washer has been staked to the inner casting of the bushing as
                shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301117">Figure 17</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301118">Figure 18</hotlnk>. Then cut the protruding rubber on the same end of the beam
                end bushing as shown in
                <hotlnk document="s03011_9.xml" xrefid="f0301114">Figure 14</hotlnk>. This permits the pushing tool to
                contact the outer metal of the bushing.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301117" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301117" filename="../figg03/G0301117.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Removal of Bar Pin Beam End Bushings</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0301118" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301118" filename="../figg03/G0301118.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Removing Confinement Washer</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A piece of 4-1/4 inch O.D. by 5 inch long steel tubing can be used to remove the bushing.
                Use a shop press with a capacity of at least 80 tons. Place the equalizing beam in the shop press with
                the beam end bore squarely supported on the press bed for safety and to avoid bending the equalizing
                beam. Center the pushing tool on the outer metal of the bushing and push the bushing out of the beam
                bore.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The outer metals of some rubber bushings are covered with a phosphate coating which acts as
                a rust preventive. This coating must be removed with emery cloth before installation. Also apply a
                coating of grease to the cleaned outer metals of the bushings and to the beam bores to facilitate
                pressing the new bushings into the beam bores.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When installing, do not push on the inner metal or bushing damage will result.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If shop made tooling is to be used, a piece of 1/2 inch wall by 5 inch O.D. by 4-5/8 inch
                long steel tubing must be reworked as detailed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301119">Figure 19</hotlnk>to install the bar pin end bushings. The assembly tool must
                be split in half, then clamped or bolted together to compress the rubber to allow contact with the
                bushing outer metal, as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301119">Figure 19</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301119" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301119" filename="../figg03/G0301119.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Reworking Steel Tubing</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the equalizing beam in the shop press with the beam end bore squarely supported on the
                bed for safety and to avoid bending the equalizing beam.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before pressing the bar pin bushing, the holes in the end of the bar pin bushing should be
                in line with the centerline of the equalizing beam to facilitate assembly into the axle brackets on the
                vehicle. Care should be taken during the assembly process to assure the orientation of the bar pin
                bushing in the beam bore. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301120">Figure 20</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301120" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301120" filename="../figg03/G0301120.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Orientation of Bar Pin Bushing</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After installation, verify that the new bushings are centered in the end of the beam.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When using the bushings with the alignment shims, it is mandatory that the shims be in place
                        and fasteners properly tightened before operating the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A shim must be installed at each bolt location. The same part number shim in the same
                        orientation must be used at both bolt locations on any one bushing assembly. Do not install or
                        stack more than one shim at each bolt location. Use genuine International&#174; shims. Do not
                        use standard washers. The failure to follow this warning may result in the fracture of either
                        the bracket or bar pin which could result in the loss of vehicle control and possible personal
                        injury or property damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Prior to assembly, axle bracket cleaning inspection is required. For beam end adapter style, inspect
                the 2-1/2 inch diameter holes in each of the axle bracket legs as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301121">Figure 21</hotlnk>. Remove any burrs or material left there by the old
                adapters. Use a new adapter as a gauge for fit, being sure it enters the holes from the outside of each
                bracket leg. The dimension between the inside surfaces of the axle bracket legs for beam end adapter
                style, shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301121">Figure 21</hotlnk>as Dimension A, must be 5.760/5.770 inches for the HN-460
                series suspensions with 5-3/4 inch long end bushings.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301121" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301121" filename="../figg03/G0301121.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Axle Bracket Legs</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>For beam end bar pin style, inspect the 1-3/32 inch diameter holes in each of the four axle bracket
                legs as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301122">Figure 22</hotlnk>. Look for hairline cracks between the edge of the axle
                bracket leg and the 1-3/32 inch hole. Excessive wear caused by contact with the 1 inch diameter bar pin
                connection bolts should also be cause for axle bracket replacement. Refer to GROUP 14 - REAR AXLES in
                the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for bracket replacement information for the type of axle used in the
                vehicle being serviced.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301122" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301122" filename="../figg03/G0301122.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Inspect Holes in Axle Bracket Legs</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The dimensions between the inside surfaces of the axle bracket legs must be 2.313/2.263 inches as
                shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301123">Figure 23</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301123" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301123" filename="../figg03/G0301123.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Look For Cracks</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Any cracks detected near the top of the axle bracket legs as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301123">Figure 23</hotlnk>require replacement of the axle bracket.
            </para>
            <para>Remove any burrs prior to assembly; this will aid in the assembly process. Raise the beam end into the
                axle bracket and support it with a jack. If the axle pinion angle causes difficulty in assembly,
                disconnect the upper torque rod and rotate the axle so that the bar pin slips into the bracket. For
                minor adjustments, there are lugs on the ends of the bar pin bushing. With an open-end wrench or a
                SPECIAL TOOLS,
                <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301106.xml" xrefid="f0301130">Figure 30</hotlnk>, the inner metal of the
                bushing can be rotated slightly to ease assembly.
            </para>
            <para>Prior to assembly of the fasteners, the operator must reconfirm that if the shim style bar pin bushing
                is used, all the shims are installed.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A shim must be installed at each bolt location. The same part number shim in the same
                        orientation must be used at both bolt locations on any one bushing assembly. Do not install or
                        stack more than one shim at each bolt location. Use genuine International&#174; shims. Do not
                        use standard washers. The failure to follow this warning may result in the fracture of either
                        the bracket or bar pin which could result in the loss of vehicle control and possible personal
                        injury or property damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>With the longitudinal torque rods disconnected, assemble the bolts, washers and locknuts. Tighten the
                locknuts to 450 to 600 ft-lbs. (610 to 813 N&#8226;m). Re-connect the torque rods prior to moving the
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>For detailed alignment procedures and instructions, refer to GROUP 03 - SUSPENSIONS in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301124">Figure 24</hotlnk>shows the part numbers for both styles of bar pin bushings
                along with attaching hardware. Each kit contains all the components required for one beam end.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301124" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301124" filename="../figg03/G0301124.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Part Numbers for Bar Pin Bushings</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301103.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
