<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>NEWAY AD-123/246 DRIVE AXLE AIR SUSPENSIONS - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This suspension uses air drawn from the truck/tractor air system to pressurize the air springs. The
                height control valve regulates the air pressure required for varying loads. This suspension can provide
                a cushioned ride throughout the load range, from empty to fully loaded. The suspension also provides
                excellent side-to-side and axle-to-axle loading which helps equalize and control braking.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CAB AIR RELEASE</title>
            <para>With "Cab Air Control," air piping for the system includes a cab air switch (
                <hotlnk document="s03010_1.xml" xrefid="f0301002">Figure 2</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301004">Figure 4</hotlnk>) and an inversion valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301005">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301004" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301004" filename="../figg03/g0301004.png" type="png" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Cab Air Control - Air Piping</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A.VIEW IN DIRECTION OF ARROW A</callout1>
                    <callout1>1.AIR SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.PRODUCT GRAPHIC</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.CONTROL VALVE GUARD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4.SWITCH GROUNDING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5.CAB AIR SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>6.PLUG</callout1>
                    <callout1>7.3/8" BLACK TUBE (SUPPLY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8.3/8" BLACK TUBE (DELIVERY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9.3/8" BLUE TUBE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10.TO INVERSION VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0301005" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301005" filename="../figg03/g0301005.png" type="png" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Cab Air Control - Inversion Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.AIR SUPPLY TO RIGHT FRONT AIR SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.AIR SUPPLY TO RIGHT REAR AIR SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4.AIR SUPPLY TO LEFT REAR AIR SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5.INVERSION (TR-3) VALVE (WITH CAB AIR CONTROL SYSTEM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6.AIR SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7.AIR SUPPLY TO LEFT FRONT AIR SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The cab air switch in the instrument panel has two positions: RUN and DUMP. In the RUN
                    position, the valve is closed. Placing the valve in the DUMP position opens the valve and directs
                    air pressure to the inversion valve located near the height control valve, which dumps air from the
                    air springs. With the cab air switch in the DUMP position, a ground circuit is closed, illuminating
                    a warning light on the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With cab air control, the system operates as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The air supply to the height control valve comes from the primary reservoir. On
                        vehicles with Cab Air Control, the air supply to the height control valve comes from the
                        inversion (TR-3) valve. Air is delivered from the height control valve to the air springs.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Placing the cab air switch in the DUMP position directs air to the inversion valve,
                        causing it to stop the air supply to the height control valve and dumps the air from the air
                        springs through the exhaust port on the inversion valve.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Placing the cab air switch in the RUN position returns air spring control to the
                        height control valve and the air springs will inflate to the pre- determined vehicle ride
                        height.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
