<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Suspension - Suspension System - General Information - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Caster and camber correction requirements are factory-determined. Adjusters are available to correct a
                caster measurement that does not meet specification. Before adjusting the caster, thoroughly inspect the
                suspension system to locate worn or damaged components that may have caused the setting to change.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Camber</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Negative and Positive Camber</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f040001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200119.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Camber is the vertical tilt of the wheel when viewed from the front. Camber can be positive or
                negative and has a direct effect on tire wear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Caster</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Caster and Frame Angle</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f040002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200117.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Caster is the deviation from vertical of an imaginary line drawn through the ball joints when viewed
                from the side. The caster specifications in this section will give the vehicle the best directional
                stability characteristics when loaded and driven. The caster setting is not related to tire wear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Toe</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Positive Toe (Toe In) and Negative Toe (Toe Out)</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f040003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg02/G0200114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>The vehicle toe setting:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>affects tire wear and directional stability.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>must be checked after adding aftermarket equipment, such as a snowplow or body.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Wheel Track</title>
            <figure id="f040005" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGH0/GH0158A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front Track</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Rear Track</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Dogtracking</title>
            <figure id="f040006" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/G0301401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Front Track</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Rear track dogtracking</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Dogtracking is the condition in which the rear axle is not square to the chassis. Heavily crowned
                roads can give the illusion of dogtracking.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Wander</title>
            <para>Wander is the tendency of the vehicle to require frequent, random left and right steering wheel
                corrections to maintain a straight path down a level road.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Shimmy</title>
            <para>Shimmy, as observed by the driver, is large, consistent, rotational oscillations of the steering wheel
                resulting from large, side-to-side (lateral) tire/wheel movements.
            </para>
            <para>Shimmy is usually experienced near 64 km/h (40 mph), and can begin or be amplified when the tire
                contacts pot holes or irregularities in the road surface.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Nibble</title>
            <para>Sometimes confused with shimmy, nibble is a condition resulting from tire interaction with various
                road surfaces and observed by the driver as small rotational oscillations of the steering wheel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Poor Returnability/ Sticky Steering</title>
            <para>Poor returnability and sticky steering is used to described the poor return of the steering wheel to
                center after a turn or the steering correction is completed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Drift/Pull</title>
            <para>Pull is a tugging sensation, felt by the hands on the steering wheel, that must be overcome to keep
                the vehicle going straight.
            </para>
            <para>Drift describes what a vehicle with this condition does with hands off the steering wheel.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A vehicle-related drift/pull, on a flat road, will cause a consistent deviation from the
                        straight-ahead path and require constant steering input in the opposite direction to counteract
                        the effect.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Drift/pull may be induced by conditions external to the vehicle (for example, wind or road
                        camber).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Alignment Angles - Poor Groove Feel</title>
            <para>Poor groove feel is characterized by little or no buildup of turning effort felt in the steering wheel
                as the wheel is rocked slowly left and right within very small turns around center or straight-ahead
                (under 20 degrees of steering wheel turn). Efforts may be said to be "flat on center."
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Under 20 degrees of turn, most of the turning effort that builds up comes from the mesh of
                        gear teeth in the steering gear. In this range, the steering wheel is not yet turned enough to
                        feel the effort from the self-aligning forces at the road wheel or tire patch.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>In the diagnosis of a roadability problem, it is important to understand the difference
                        between wander and poor groove feel.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014_X2040017.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
