<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>MOR/RYDE RUBBER SPRING SUSPENSION - REPLACEMENT - RUBBER SPRINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0300905" svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
        <title>RUBBER SPRINGS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The rubber springs are vulcanized (bonded) to plates (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0300903">Figure 3</hotlnk>). There are two conditions that may occur with the rubber
                springs.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0300903" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0300903" filename="../figg03/G0300903.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. RUBBER SPRING ASSEMBLY</caption>
            </figure>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The first condition is a bond failure. The rubber separates from the metal plate.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The second condition is a rubber failure. The rubber tears or delaminates and generally occurs
                        in the middle of the rubber spring between the metal plates.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Either of the conditions described above would not always necessitate replacement of the rubber
                spring. If there is a question about the integrity of a marginal rubber spring, a 3" (76mm) wide object
                (such as a 3" putty knife) can be used to probe the rubber spring in the affected area. If the probe
                penetrates the crack or separated area .75 inch (19mm) or more, the spring should be replaced.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The rubber spring assembly is actually two (2) individual rubber springs with the 8.50 x 11.0
                        steel plates bolted back-to-back (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0300903">Figure 3</hotlnk>). If only one spring in the assembly is defective,
                        it is necessary to replace only the defective individual rubber spring - not the entire
                        assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure vehicle is elevated, chassis is supported with safety stands, the front wheels
                    blocked, and the suspension hanging unsupported.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove 3/8" bolts securing the rubber spring assembly to beam assembly and to frame
                    hanger assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0300904">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0300904" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0300904" filename="../figg03/G0300904.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. RUBBER SPRING ASSEMBLY AND HANGER ASSEMBLY</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rubber spring assembly can now be removed by pulling downward and out. (Spring assembly
                    cannot be removed by forcing upward.)
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Install new spring assembly by pushing spring assembly upward (either by hand or with jack) between
                the beam assembly and frame hanger assemblies until the bolt holes are aligned (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0300904">Figure 4</hotlnk>). Secure spring assembly with 3/8" x 7/8" Grade 8 bolts.
                Tighten bolts to 35 ft-lbs. (47 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03009_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03009_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
