<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Proper preventive maintenance programs will help control repair costs and downtime. This is important
                for safe and reliable operation. All new equipment should be given an initial pre-service inspection.
                This includes checking all the tightening torques as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301101.xml" xrefid="hl0301101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. We also recommend that
                all the tightening torques be checked with a torque wrench at least once a year.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="6">
            <title>BEAM END CONNECTIONS</title>
            <para>The beam end connections for the HN suspension are available in two styles. Shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301102">Figure 2</hotlnk>is a three-piece design with a 1 inch diameter Grade 8
                through bolt. The two end adapters pilot into the bushing inner metal, and into the intermediate tube,
                giving full support to the bushing. The tightening torque for the through bolt locknut is 445 to 495
                ft-lbs. (603 to 671 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301102" filename="../figg03/g0301102.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Three Piece Beam End Connections</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The beam end adapter assemblies require that the fasteners be kept tight to maintain the clamp of the
                rubber bushing inner metals to the inside surface of the axle bracket legs. All bushing motion is
                accommodated by rubber deflection and there should be no motion between mating metal surfaces.
            </para>
            <para>The flange of the adapters is cut off for assembly clearance with the axle housing bowl. The flat must
                be positioned in the vertical position as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301103">Figure 3</hotlnk>when the through bolt locknut is tightened.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301103" filename="../figg03/g0301103.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Adapter Flats in Vertical Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The beam end adapters require that the through bolt locknut torque be checked with a torque wrench
                before a new or repaired vehicle is placed in service. Check the torque again after 1,000 miles of
                off-highway or severe service, or 10,000 miles of on-highway service. Do not exceed torque
                specifications.
            </para>
            <para>The other beam end connection is a bar pin style bushing. This bushing uses a beam hanger design as
                shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301104">Figure 4</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301105">Figure 5</hotlnk>for both truck and trailer suspensions, and is a rubber
                bushing assembly consisting of a rubber insert, an outer metal tube, and an inner casting. It is
                fastened to the axle by two (2) one inch diameter, Grade 8 bolts and two (2) one inch, Grade C locknuts.
                One inch hardened, flat washers are located under both the bolt heads and the locknuts. The bolts are
                installed from the end of the beam toward the centerline and are positioned parallel to the vehicle
                longitudinal axis making removal and assembly easy. The tightening torque for the Bar Pin connection
                with one inch bolts to be tightened at the head of the bolt is 500 to 650 ft-lbs. (678 to 881 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301104" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301104" filename="../figg03/g0301104.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Beam Hanger Design No. 1</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0301105" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301105" filename="../figg03/g0301105.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Beam Hanger Design No. 2</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The beam end connection requires that the fasteners be kept tight to maintain the clamp of the axle
                bracket legs to the bushing inner metals. All bushing motion is accommodated by rubber deflection. The
                torque should be checked when a new or repaired vehicle is placed in service and again after 1,000 miles
                of off-highway service or 10,000 miles of on-highway service.
            </para>
            <para>When it is necessary to have a vehicle in the shop for major repair work or preventive maintenance,
                place a jack under each beam end, as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301106">Figure 6</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301107">Figure 7</hotlnk>, to check for movement of the rubber end bushing inner
                metal. This movement cannot be eliminated by tightening the locknut due to excessive wear to mating
                parts and increasing clearances. If movement is noted, do not operate the vehicle. Replace rubber end
                bushing and all connecting parts.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301106" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301106" filename="../figg03/g0301106.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Jack Under Beam End</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0301107" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301107" filename="../figg03/g0301107.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Jack Under Beam End</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Periodic visual inspection by the driver and service personnel is also recommended. Look for the beam
                being lower in the beam hanger, or distorted or frayed rubber. Off-highway and severe service operating
                conditions require more frequent inspections than on-highway service operation.
            </para>
            <para>The gap on each side of the visible rubber at the lower end of the end bushing is normal and is not an
                indication to replace the bushing. Because all rubber end bushings are in compression, with the load
                bearing on the top side, the lower side of the rubber is slightly relieved, allowing the rubber to move
                inward, and a gap appears.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
