<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - CLEAN AND INSPECT - LOAD CUSHION SUSPENSIONS - RS SERIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="2">
        <title>LOAD CUSHION SUSPENSIONS - RS SERIES</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Frame Bracket Flanges</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect each frame bracket for cracks or other damage in the vertical mounting flange.
                </para>
                <para>Remove the bracket from the frame to inspect for cracks or other damage in the horizontal mounting
                    flange next to the vertical drive pin areas. Replace a bracket that has any cracks (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0300631">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0300631" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0300631" filename="../figg03/G0300631.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 31. Inspect Bracket for Cracks</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. CRACKS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To check for complete flange fracture, lift the chassis by the frame and look for
                    separation of the vertical drive pin from the bracket flange. Replace any broken frame brackets.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not operate a vehicle with cracked or broken frame brackets. This can lead to
                            separation of components, loss of vehicle control, and possible property damage and personal
                            injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Load Cushions</title>
            <para>Inspect cushions for proper shape, proper height and proper position. Be sure there are no cuts,
                swelling or dirt accumulation. Replace load cushions that are damaged.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Normal free height of a load cushion is 3-15/16 inches (100 mm). A permanent set of not more
                        than 1/4 inch (6 mm) is acceptable.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Replace a load cushion with free height under 3-11/16 inches (94 mm).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If cushions are cut by the retaining lips of the saddles or frame brackets, the cushions may
                        not be the right type for the vehicle application.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Dump and transit mix environments can cause a buildup of dirt and other material under the
                        cushions, causing them to escape the saddle retainer lips, and to twist out of position.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vertical Drive Pin Bushings</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the lower side of these bushings for torn or shredded rubber. Remove the bushing
                    retainer caps to facilitate the inspection (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0300632">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0300632" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0300632" filename="../figg03/G0300632.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 32. Vertical Drive Pine Bushings</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1.BUSHING RETAINER CAP</callout1>
                        <callout1>2.WASHER</callout1>
                        <callout1>3.SADDLE CAP STUD NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>4.SADDLE CAP STUD</callout1>
                        <callout1>5.SADDLE CAP</callout1>
                        <callout1>6.MAINTAIN AN EVEN GAP</callout1>
                        <callout1>7.SADDLE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be certain that the concave washers are installed with the lips pointing downward. Press
                    the bushings out of the saddles from the top.
                </para>
                <para>If the outer sleeve is "frozen" to the saddle wall, press the inner sleeve and rubber out of the
                    bushing, then work the outer sleeve out of the saddle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the bushing cavities with solvent. Remove nicks with an emery cloth.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hand press new bushings into place.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bushing caps and locknuts. Tighten to the values found in the
                    <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Aluminum saddles are heat-treated. Do not cut them with a torch, or use excessive heat
                            during repair procedures.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Saddle Cap Fasteners</title>
            <para>Tighten the saddle cap locknuts to the values found in the
                <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>, to prevent wear of the beam
                center bushings into the legs of the saddles.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
