<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - MAINTENANCE - TORQUE RODS AND TRANSVERSE RODS ( FIGURE 9 )</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TORQUE RODS AND TRANSVERSE RODS (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301109">FIGURE 9</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <figure id="f0301109" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301109" filename="../figg03/G0301109.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Torque Rods and Transverse Rods</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The length of the torque rods is determined by the vehicle manufacturer for optimum drive line angles. The
            torque rods control these angles and also absorb driving and braking forces. The length of the transverse
            rods is determined by the vehicle manufacturer to center the axles under the frame. The transverse rods
            control axle walk-out during cornering. The mounting brackets at the axle ends for both rods are furnished
            and welded into position on the axle housings by the axle manufacturer.
        </para>
        <para>Both types of rods may have attaching ends designated "straddle mount" or "tapered stud" as shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301110">Figure 10</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0301110" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301110" filename="../figg03/G0301110.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Tapered Stud</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Straddle mount rod end attaching fasteners are furnished by the vehicle manufacturer. It is important that
            the tightening torque of the locknuts be checked during preventive maintenance service. Follow the vehicle
            manufacturer's specifications for tightening torque values.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>International recommends Grade 8 bolts and Grade C locknuts be used for all straddle mount torque
                    rod and straddle mount transverse rod attachments.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Tapered stud rod locknuts also should be checked. The tightening torque is 175 to 225 ft-lbs. (237 to 305
            N&#8226;m).
        </para>
        <para>Inspect all rods for looseness, or torn or shredded rubber. A lever check can be made with a long pry bar
            placed under each rod end and pressure applied. Longitudinal torque rods can be checked by slowly rocking an
            empty vehicle with power and the brakes applied, while a mechanic visually checks the action at both ends.
        </para>
        <para>Whether the rod ends are straddle mount or tapered stud, they can be renewed by pressing out the worn end
            and installing a cartridge type replacement. A two-piece rod is also available to cut and weld to the
            desired length.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
