<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - INSTALL AXLE AND BEAMS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTALL AXLE AND BEAMS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Roll the axles with the beams attached under the vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install both torque rods at the frame bracket ends, then at the axle bracket ends.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the saddle caps removed, lower the chassis so that the saddles contact the beam center
                bushings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With vehicle weight on the beam center bushings, install saddle caps, washers, and locknuts.
                Evenly tighten the locknuts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the wheels from the front or rear axle. This will give you access to tighten the
                saddle cap nuts properly. Refer to GROUP 17-RIMS, WHEELS AND TIRES in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten saddle cap nuts to specifications. Refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install wheels. Refer to GROUP 17- RIMS, WHEELS AND TIRES in the CTS-5000 Master Service
                Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release all spring parking brakes on the tandem axles and connect the drive shaft to the
                front of the forward drive axle. Refer to GROUP 04-AIR BRAKES AND GROUP 06-PROPELLER SHAFT in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect all air lines leading to the rear axles and charge the vehicle air system. Remove
                the blocks from the front wheels.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Road test vehicle for proper operation before putting vehicle back into service.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When installing the rubber-bushed beams to the axles and saddles, do not tighten the nuts
                        until the torque rods are installed and the equalizing beams are level with the frame. When
                        these conditions are met, tighten all nuts to the values found in the TORQUE CHART,
                        <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">13.0.</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
