<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - REPLACE - TORQUE ROD AND TRANSVERSE ROD BUSHINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
        <title>TORQUE ROD AND TRANSVERSE ROD BUSHINGS</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>It is possible that the equalizing beam end connections to the axle brackets are loose. If they
                    are, the axles could be free to pivot on the beam ends. Use necessary blocking to prevent harm to
                    personnel and to avoid damage to the drive lines, power divider and differential carriers.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>Straddle mount rod ends, as shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301126">Figure 26</hotlnk>and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301127">Figure 27</hotlnk>, may be removed by removing the locknuts, bolts, washers and
            any adjustment shims. Note the number of shims at each location as they must be re-installed in the same
            manner to avoid affecting axle settings.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0301126" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301126" filename="../figg03/g0301126.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 26. Straddle Mount Rod Ends</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0301127" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301127" filename="../figg03/g0301127.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 27. Straddle Mount Rod Ends</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Tapered stud rod ends, as shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301128">Figure 28</hotlnk>, may be removed from the bracket by removing the locknut and
            spacer washer and rapping the axle bracket with a hammer to break the stud free.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0301128" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301128" filename="../figg03/g0301128.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Tapered Stud Rod Ends</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Use the SPECIAL TOOLS,
            <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301106.xml" xrefid="f0301130">Figure 30</hotlnk>, to remove and install the rod
            bushings. Follow the tool manufacturer's instructions.
        </para>
        <para>Two-piece rods with either tapered stud or straddle mount ends are also available. They are cut and welded
            to the desired length in the field.
        </para>
        <para>To install a straddle mount end, position the rod end at the bracket, and assemble the bolts, washers,
            locknuts and any adjustment shims as noted during disassembly. Tighten to 200 to 240 ft-lbs. (271 to 325 N&#8226;m).
        </para>
        <para>To install a tapered stud end, the bracket hole must be free of all foreign matter. Place the stud in the
            bracket and assemble the locknut with spacer washer. Tighten locknut to 175 to 225 ft-lbs. (237 to 305 N&#8226;m).
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_HL0301103.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
