<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Suspension - Front Suspension - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Suspension</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>All vehicles are equipped with gas-pressurized shock absorbers which will extend unassisted.
                        Do not apply heat or flame to the shock absorbers during removal or component servicing. Failure
                        to follow these instructions can result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Suspension fasteners are critical parts because they affect performance of vital parts and
                        systems and their failure can result in major service expense. A new part with the same part
                        number must be installed if installation becomes necessary. Do not use a replacement part of
                        lesser quality or substitute design. Torque values must be used as specified during reassembly
                        to make sure of correct retention of these parts.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The front suspension system is a leaf spring and shock type design. The wheel spindles are attached to
                the front axle with spindle pins (king pins) instead of ball joints and the axle is a single I-Beam,
                non-driving type. The front suspension consists of the following additional components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Leaf springs and shackles</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Gas-pressurized shock absorbers</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Stabilizer bar and links</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014_X2040111.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
