<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SUSPENSION ALIGNMENT - REAR AXLE ALIGNMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REAR AXLE ALIGNMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Before performing axle alignment or upper torque rod adjustment, remove all road debris from
                suspension and perform the preliminary procedures listed below.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Wheel not being aligned should be blocked at all times during alignment procedures.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Park vehicle on a level floor.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Block front wheels.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Release parking brake.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check rear wheels for run-out and correct if necessary.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the front wheels in the straight ahead position, remove wheel blocks and move vehicle
                        forward and rearward several times to relieve internal stress; then block front wheels.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>On vehicles equipped with air suspension, verify that the suspension height is correct.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The straightedge and trammel method should only be used when laser or computer alignment
                        equipment is not available. The more accurate alignment equipment is preferable.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Due to the different varieties of alignment equipment, always refer to the manufacturer's recommended
                operating procedures.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="align" graphiccount="2">
            <title>LASER</title>
            <para>Alignment equipment using laser technology can be used to check rear axle alignment of a tractor or
                trailer.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0300306">Figure 6</hotlnk>shows a laser aligner connected to a tandem axle tractor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0300306" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/G0300306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Laser Aligner</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REAR FRAME GAUGE TARGET</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LASER PROJECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Laser aligners use a "soft" laser light that is projected from the center of the rear frame gauge
                target to the front frame gauge target. The self-centering frame gauge targets are used to find the
                centerline of the chassis. The rear axle is in precise alignment when the beam of light is centered
                between the front and rear frame gauge targets. If the beam of light is not centered, the rear axle must
                be adjusted. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03003x_5.xml" xrefid="hl0300301">REAR AXLE ADJUSTMENT.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>After the rear axle is properly aligned, the position of the forward rear axle is found using a tram
                bar (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0300307">Figure 7</hotlnk>). The forward rear axle is then adjusted until it is
                parallel with the rear rear axle.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0300307" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/G0300307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Tram Bar</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAM BAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. REAR REAR AXLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FRONT REAR AXLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03003x_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03003x_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03003x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
