<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL RIDE OPTIMIZED SUSPENSION (IROS) - HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE - CHECKING RIDE HEIGHT PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0301301" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CHECKING RIDE HEIGHT PROCEDURE</title>
        <para>Procedure for checking air spring height on the International Ride Optimized Suspension (IROS):</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Chassis ride height is not measured directly. Instead, axle travel measurement will be taken.
                    Specifications for axle travel have been calculated to result in the correct chassis ride height.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle unloaded on a level surface with a light application of the brakes.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not apply the parking brake. Chock wheels to prevent vehicle movement.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure at least 100 psi is in the vehicle air system, and then shut off engine.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dump air from system, then re-pressurize and allow it to return to the ride height. (See
                Ride Height Adjustment Section.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To measure the axle travel you will need a tape measure that will remain rigid when extended
                to 6 inches and one (1) 6-inch straight edge such as a piece of 3/8" flat bar.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0301306" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption>Figure 6. Axle Travel Measurement</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. AXLE STOP</callout1>
                <callout1>2. RIDE HEIGHT DIMENSION</callout1>
                <callout1>3. 3/8" FLAT BAR</callout1>
                <callout1>4. SUSPENSION U-BOLTS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measurements are taken at the air spring assembly closest to the height control valve
                (usually forward left).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the vertical distance from the bottom of the straight edge that is resting against
                the u-bolts, to the bottommost position of the axle stop.
                <emph type="bold">There should be no angle created between the two measurement points.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The measurement you obtain should fall within the values listed in the tables.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If they do not fall within the listed values on the table, the height control valve will
                need to be adjusted as per the instructions listed in the Ride Adjustment Section of this service
                manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
