<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - BUSHING REPLACEMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0300605">
        <title>BUSHING REPLACEMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not modify or substitute parts.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Do not use a cutting torch to remove any attaching fasteners, to remove the beams from the axles or to
                remove the bushings from the beam centers or ends.
            </para>
            <para>All Hendrickson beams are heat-treated for strength and long service life. The use of heat (cutting
                torch or welding) on suspension components will shorten the life of these parts. A part that is damaged
                in this manner may fail in operation.
            </para>
            <para>Aluminum components (such as beams) can be damaged with prolonged exposure to salt or acid wash, or by
                contact with hard objects that gouge the parts. A part which is excessively damaged may fail in
                operation.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Aluminum components are lightweight options to be used where weight reduction is desirable.
                        Use aluminum parts only where the rated capacity of the suspension will not be exceeded.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bushings for 340 through 450 Series suspension systems are available with the end plug as a
                        separate item, for use only with special tools (portable hydraulic service equipment). Refer to
                        SPECIAL TOOLS,
                        <hotlnk document="s03006s_30.xml" xrefid="f0300644">Figure 44</hotlnk>,
                        <hotlnk document="s03006s_30.xml" xrefid="f0300645">Figure 45</hotlnk>, and
                        <hotlnk document="s03006s_30.xml" xrefid="f0300646">Figure 46</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If you are using Special Tools, follow the instructions supplied by the tool manufacturer.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To inspect bushings for replacement, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s03006s_17.xml" xrefid="hl0300606">CLEAN AND INSPECT</hotlnk>, for
                        specifications.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
