<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON AIR SUSPENSION WITH TRAILING LEAF SPRINGS - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE</title>
        <para>U-bolt locknuts: Retighten after the first 1000 miles (1609 km/h) on a new vehicle, or when the vehicle
            main support member has been serviced. Also when the vehicle comes in for regular maintenance service, not
            to exceed 100,000 miles (160,900 km/h). Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s03007_35.xml" xrefid="hl0300701">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>, for specifications.
        </para>
        <para>Ride height control valve setting: Adjustment of the ride height control valve linkage can be achieved by
            loosening the hose clamps on the rubber connector and sliding them on the vertical rod.
        </para>
        <para>When performing regular maintenance service, check the suspension air lines and valves for air leaks.
            Check the air lines for chafing and kinks. Repair or replace as necessary.
        </para>
        <para>Before changing any valve, be sure that there are no air leaks and check the suspected valve to be sure
            that it is defective.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not use a cutting torch to remove any attaching fasteners. The use of heat on suspension
                    components will adversely affect the strength of these parts. When performing any maintenance in the
                    area of the main support members. Do not connect an arc welding machine ground cable, or strike an
                    arc with an electrode on the main support member. Do not nick or gouge the main support member. Any
                    of the above mentioned conditions may cause the component to fail causing loss of vehicle control
                    and possible personal injury or property damage.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
