<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON AIR SUSPENSION WITH TRAILING LEAF SPRINGS - TORQUE RODS - REMOVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Rod Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block front wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove straddle mount bar pin locknuts and washers at axle end of torque rod (
                    <hotlnk document="s03007_10.xml" xrefid="f0300713">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen rebound bolt locknut in the frame hanger.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove straddle mount locknuts, bolts, and washers, and any alignment shims at frame
                    hanger ends of torque rod. Remove torque rod. Note the number of shims as they must be reinstalled
                    in the same position to avoid affecting the axle alignment.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Replacing Torque Rod Bushing</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use heat or a cutting torch to remove the bushing from the torque rod. The use of heat
                        will adversely affect the strength of the torque rod.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be sure torque rod is squarely supported on press table for safety precautions.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using shop press, push out old bushing. A 5 inch long with 2 inch I.D. and 1/4 inch wall
                    steel tube tool is required. Support torque rod end on tube tool and center bushing. Push directly
                    on bushing straddle mount bar pin until bushing clears torque rod end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean and inspect I.D. of torque rod ends; remove any nicks with emery cloth.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate I.D. of torque rod ends and new rubber bushings with a vegetable base oil
                    (cooking oil or lard).
                    <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                    use a petroleum or soap base lubricant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press in new bushings.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Support torque rod end on receiving tool with end tube of torque rod centered on receiving
                            tool. The straddle mounted bar pin bushing must have flats positioned ten degrees
                            counterclockwise to shank of torque rod as shown in
                            <hotlnk document="s03007_8.xml" xrefid="f0300709">Figure 9</hotlnk>. Press directly on
                            straddle mount bar pin bushing. Bushing must be centered within torque rod end tubes. When
                            pressing in new bushings, press past desired final position by approximately 3/16 inch and
                            press bushing again from opposite side to center bushing within torque rod end.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be sure torque rod is squarely supported on press table for safety precautions.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
