<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>NEWAY AD-123/246 DRIVE AXLE AIR SUSPENSIONS - ADJUSTMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0301002">
        <title>ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
            <title>AIR SPRING HEIGHT</title>
            <para>Prior to adjustment, the vehicle must be unloaded.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cotter pin and washer from upper link. Loosen the clamp and detach the vertical
                    linkage from the height control lever arm.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the center punch mark at the leveling valve capscrew is positioned toward
                    the vertical linkage (
                    <hotlnk document="s03010_12.xml" xrefid="f0301012">Figure 12</hotlnk>) and that both clamps are on
                    the inside locations (bolt head end toward the center of vertical rod) of the rubber links.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build and maintain air pressure in excess of 65 psi. Check all air fittings and valve
                    for leaks. Repair as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the height adjustment by measuring air spring height (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0301013">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0301013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0301013" filename="../figg03/G0301013.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Air Spring Height</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees above horizontal. Air pressure
                    at the air springs should begin to increase within 15 seconds which will cause the truck frame to
                    rise. This can easily be detected by feeling the shock absorber extend at the dust tube to shock
                    absorber body joint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower height control valve lever approximately 45 degrees below horizontal. Air pressure
                    at the air springs should begin to decrease. Let air escape until air spring height is approximately
                    10 inches (254mm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise valve lever to 45 degrees above horizontal again, until air spring height is to
                    dimension shown in
                    <hotlnk document="s03010_15.xml" xrefid="hl0301001">RIDE HEIGHT CAPACITY CHART</hotlnk>. Return
                    lever to horizontal position.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Always check and set proper air spring height by adding air to the system.</para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two centering pins (use two No. 21, or 5/32 inch drill bits) in the valve body
                    to maintain the lever arm in the centered position (horizontal) while installing and adjusting the
                    vertical link to the lever arm.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lengthen or shorten the vertical linkage such that the rubber links can be slipped over
                    the lever arm and lower anchor. The vertical linkage will slide through the upper and lower rubber
                    links. Be sure the vertical linkage is flush with the top of the upper rubber link. Tighten the
                    upper clamp screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pressurize the air system with a constant supply of air in excess of 65 psi. All air
                    springs should inflate and be at proper air spring height. Inspect air system and eliminate any air
                    leaks.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If proper air spring height is not obtained, or air springs do not inflate properly, check
                            air pressure, check for proper piping and repeat above steps.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
