<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON SUSPENSION SYSTEMS - CLEAN AND INSPECT - ALL SUSPENSIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="3">
        <title>ALL SUSPENSIONS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Inspect the beam to be certain it is not distorted or cracked.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bronze Center Bushing</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise each beam end with a jack. Movement of 1/8 inch (3 mm) or more before the axle is
                    raised indicates excessive wear; replace the bronze center bushing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After removing the bushings, thoroughly inspect the beam bores. If torch under cutting
                    is found from previous maintenance procedures, replace the beam.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>If torch undercutting is found from previous maintenance procedures, replace the beam. Do
                            not take responsibility for possible road failure by rebushing a defective beam.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rubber End Bushings</title>
            <para>Raise the rubber bushed beam ends to check for movement of the bushing inner metal sleeve.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Movement of the inner metal sleeve is due to excessive wear on mating parts which is beyond
                        tolerance range.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Do not attempt to eliminate movement of the metal sleeves by tightening fasteners beyond values found
                in the
                <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>If you detect any movement, do not operate the vehicle. Replace the rubber end bushing and all
                connecting parts. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03006s_7.xml" xrefid="hl0300605">BUSHING REPLACEMENT</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Because rubber bushings are compressed and loaded on the top side, bushings are slightly
                        relieved (gapping) at the bottom side of the ends. These gaps are normal, not an indication to
                        replace bushing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0300626">Figure 26</hotlnk>and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0300627">Figure 27</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0300626" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0300626" filename="../figg03/g0300626.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Bushing Gap</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.LOAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.RUBBER BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.GAP IN BUSHING END</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0300627" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0300627" filename="../figg03/g0300627.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Bushing Gap</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.LOAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.RUBBER BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.GAP IN BUSHING END</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Axle Brackets, Rubber End Bushing</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the holes in the axle bracket legs. Remove any burrs, or remains of the old
                    adapter. Use a new adapter as a gauge for fit, being certain it enters the holes from the outside of
                    each bracket leg.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the dimension between the inside surfaces of the axle bracket, per dimension "A"
                    in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0300628">Figure 28</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0300628" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0300628" filename="../figg03/g0300628.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28.</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>A.FOR 5-1/4 INCH (133.35 MM) LONG END BUSHINGS, "A" DIM. TO BE 5.26/5.27 INCH
                            (133.604/133.858 MM)
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>FOR 5-3/4 INCH (146.05 MM) LONG END BUSHINGS, "A" DIM. TO BE 5.76/5.77 INCH
                            (146.304/146.558 MM)
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>FOR 6.00 INCH (152.4 MM) LONG END BUSHINGS, "A" DIM. TO BE 6.010/6.020 INCH
                            (152.654/152.908 MM)
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1>1.AXLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2.AXLE BRACKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>3.2-1/2 INCHES (63.5 MM) DIA.</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Beam Center Cross Tube</title>
            <para>Clean the cross tube. Inspect it for cracks or excessive wear 8 to 10 inches (203 to 254 mm) from each
                end where it enters into the beam center bushings. Check straightness of the cross tube with a
                straightedge.
            </para>
            <para>If there is any doubt about the integrity of the cross tube, replace it. The cross tube ends can only
                be checked if the center bushing is removed for replacement, then the tube removed and installed before
                the new bushing (cap) end is installed, or the beam is removed from the suspension.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Axle Stops</title>
            <para>The four axle stops are furnished and installed by International. The location of these stops on the
                frame limits axle articulation to ensure that driveline action and brake chamber clearance
                specifications are not exceeded.
            </para>
            <para>Check the tightening torque of the axle-stop-to-frame fasteners. Refer to the value in the
                <hotlnk document="s03006s_29.xml" xrefid="hl0300604">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the axle stops are peening the top of the axle housing, contact International to advise
                        them of this condition.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03006s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
