<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The HN-460 suspension, as shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0301101">Figure 1</hotlnk>for truck/tractor applications, uses four solid rubber bolster
            springs operating in shear and compression to cushion road shocks. The springs are mounted between the
            equalizing beams and the saddles. Effective operation relies on the characteristic of rubber that as it is
            compressed, it becomes progressively stiffer, thereby providing similar ride characteristics empty or
            loaded.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0301101" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0301101" filename="../figg03/G0301101.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Hendrickson HN-460 Suspension</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Four shock absorbers add dampening.</para>
        <para>The bolster springs together with rubber bushings in the equalizing beam ends accommodate the articulation
            of the axles without friction or metal-to-metal contact.
        </para>
        <para>Upper longitudinal torque rods absorb axle braking and accelerating torques. Transverse rods provide
            positive lateral positioning of the axles and control axle walk-out during cornering. All rods use rubber
            bushings.
        </para>
        <para>The HN suspension incorporates transverse rod axle brackets and torque rods for vehicle stability. If
            these components are disconnected or are non-functional, the vehicle should not be operated.
        </para>
        <para>Rebound control as well as enhanced roll stability is accomplished through the use of two auxiliary spring
            assemblies.
        </para>
        <para>The beam center cross tube connects the two equalizing beams through nylon bushings in the beams and adds
            stability to the suspension.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
