<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HENDRICKSON HN-460 SUSPENSION - MAINTENANCE - BOLSTER SPRINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
        <title>BOLSTER SPRINGS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Inspect all four bolster springs. Wide variations in operating conditions make it difficult to fix
                definite limits for the suitability of bolster springs for further use. The following points are for
                guidance and intended to assist persons examining the springs in reaching their decision to replace
                them. Hendrickson recommends that both bolster springs on one beam be replaced even if only one shows
                wear. When the bolster springs are replaced on one side only, you may find that the vehicle leans
                slightly. The new bolster springs will tend to settle to some degree, and return the vehicle to its
                original condition.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bent or Cracked Metal Parts</title>
            <para>Overhanging edges of metal plates are occasionally bent or burred through mishandling in service.
                Providing the rubber is not trapped, and there are no sharp metal edges in contact with the free surface
                of the rubber, the damage is acceptable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bonding Defects</title>
            <para>Lifting of the rubber from the bonded metal surface to a depth of approximately 1-1/2 inches is
                acceptable (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301108">Figure 8</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0301102">Unloaded Bolster Spring</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0301108" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0301108" filename="../figg03/G0301108.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Damage to Rubber</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Damage to Rubber</title>
            <para>Cuts or splits in the rubber surface to a depth of approximately 3/4 inch, caused by fatigue or
                mechanical damage, are acceptable, providing that they are local and of a reasonable number. Bolster
                springs having two or three splits per layer of average depth of 1/2 inch to 3/4 inch and length around
                3 inches have been retested after service, giving stiffness measurements of approximately 10 to 15%
                softer than the original. Splits of over 3 inches in length and of an average depth of 1 inch should be
                considered as possible points of failure. A certain amount of gradual breakup of the rubber surface is
                usual. The most probable areas of damage are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301108">Figure 8</hotlnk>as ////////.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Creases</title>
            <para>Creases formed by folding of the rubber surface under load should be ignored. These appear as strips
                on the surface, polished by wear or covered with tacky rubber.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil and Grease Contamination</title>
            <para>Due to the type of application on which bolster springs are used, oil and grease contamination is not
                usually a problem. Certain softening of the rubber surface can be accepted, but springs should be
                rejected if any swelling due to contamination increases the rubber diameter to 1/4 inch beyond its
                normal position. It is important that the slight change in shape due to permanent set is not mistaken
                for oil and grease contamination.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0301102">
            <title>Unloaded Bolster Spring</title>
            <para>An unloaded bolster spring may be inspected by inserting a feeler gauge at points indicated ////////
                in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0301108">Figure 8</hotlnk>. Recommended feeler is 1/2 inch wide x .010 inch thick. If
                gauge can be inserted to a depth of 1-1/2 inches or more, the bolster spring should be replaced. Feather
                edge of 3/8 inch may be ignored when inspecting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
