<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>INTERNATIONAL RIDE OPTIMIZED SUSPENSION (IROS) - REMOVE AND INSTALL - MAIN SUPPORT MEMBERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>MAIN SUPPORT MEMBERS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s03012_X0301205.xml" xrefid="f0301214">Figure 13</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing main support members, it is recommended that you replace all hardware items
                        also.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unload vehicle and block wheels to prevent vehicle from rolling. Raise vehicle frame 2
                    inches and support with floor stands. Place floor stand in position to support transverse
                    crossmember in present position (to maintain position when spring U-bolts are removed).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel assembly from axle side being serviced. Refer to GROUP 17 - WHEELS in the
                    Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Exhaust air from vehicle and suspension system. Exhaust air by:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Even if air spring has a leak and is deflated, the air must still be exhausted from
                            system.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Automatic control - height control valve - disconnect link at lower connection, then
                        rotate control arm to exhaust (approximately 45 degrees down) position.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect air supply line from air spring.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Exhaust air from reservoir.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect shock absorbers and air springs at lower end.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect torque rod at spring hangar end and remove spring pin from spring hangar.
                    Also loosen rear torque rod mounting nuts (Do not normally need to be removed).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower shock absorber plate from transverse beam.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove spring U-bolts while supporting lower U-bolt plate and related parts. Remove and
                    discard spring liner.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all parts for wear, cracks or failed welds. Repair or replace.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not repair a cracked spring, U-bolt or spacer plates. The listed parts must be replaced
                            if cracks are present
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When tightening spring U-bolts, torque rod fasteners and other related mounting fasteners to
                        specifications, the vehicle must be at proper ride height to avoid introducing unnecessary
                        stress on the bushings. Refer to the
                        <hotlnk document="s03012_24.xml" xrefid="x0301202">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                        for specified torque values.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0301223" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/G0301223.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Suspension Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TAPERED LEAF BUSHING MOUNT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. U-BOLT SADDLE SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOWER U-BOLT MOUNTING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TAPERED LEAF SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. AIR SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position spring to approximate installed position
                    <hotlnk document="s03012_16.xml" xrefid="f0301216">(Figure 15, Items 2 and 3)</hotlnk>
                    and install the bar pin in hanger
                    <emph type="bold">on the forward side of the spring hanger</emph>. Also install lower shock bracket
                    end and
                    <emph type="bold">do not</emph>
                    tighten fasteners.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place U-bolt seat on top of spring
                    <hotlnk document="s03012_17.xml" xrefid="f0301220">(Figure 19, Item 2)</hotlnk>
                    with tab towards vehicle frame then install U-bolt assembly to spring and axle.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                    tighten fasteners to specified values at this time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point assemble the spring clamp group and main support member to the axle, align
                    the suspension and tighten assembly. Tighten to specifications in the following sequence: U-bolts
                    (tighten diagonally),
                    <hotlnk document="s03012_21.xml" xrefid="f0301227">(Figure 26)</hotlnk>
                    front torque rod nuts, rear torque rod nuts, and the lower shock absorber mounting plate on the
                    transverse beam. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03012_24.xml" xrefid="x0301202">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect lower air spring, shock absorbers and height control valve linkage and any air
                    lines that were removed. Tighten all fasteners to values specified. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s03012_24.xml" xrefid="x0301202">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install tires/wheels. Refer to GROUP 17 - WHEELS in the Master Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower vehicle. Remove all stands.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build vehicle air pressure to governor cutout pressure and use soap and water solution
                    to check for leaks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03012_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03012_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
