<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPRING ASSEMBLIES AND SHOCK ABSORBERS - MAINTENANCE - WEAR LIMITS FOR REAR SUSPENSION TORQUE LEAF BUSHINGS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
        <title>WEAR LIMITS FOR REAR SUSPENSION TORQUE LEAF BUSHINGS</title>
        <para>The following procedures may be used to determine when Vari-Rate rear suspension torque leaf bushing
            service is required.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The following bushing wear check should be made PRIOR to lubrication.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert a 12" to 16" (305 to 406 mm) bar between the spring bracket rebound pin and the
                torque leaf spring eye. Observe movement of the torque leaf spring eye while pushing up and down on the
                outer end of the bar. If movement of the torque leaf spring eye at the frame mount bracket appears to be
                more than 1/8 inch (3.2 mm), go to step 2.
            </para>
            <para>It should be noted that a bar of greater length than 16" (406 mm) could possibly exert undue force
                causing the spring to be deformed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The only accurate measurement of bushing wear requires removing the spring eye pin,
                measuring the outside diameter of the pin and the inside diameter of the spring eye bushing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0300405">Figure 5</hotlnk>). The difference between the two measurements is the amount
                of clearance between the spring eye bushing and the spring eye pin. If a measurement of .007 to .012
                inch (.1778 to .3048 mm) is noted, the bushing is new. A measurement of .080 to .090 inch (2.032 to
                2.286 mm) indicates that the bushing should be replaced during the next vehicle service interval; if the
                measurement is .120 inch (3.048 mm) or more, the bushing should be replaced immediately.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0300405" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0300405" filename="../figg03/G0300405.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 5. Vari-Rate Spring Suspension</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. SPRING BRACKET</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>3. TORQUE LEAF</callout1>
                <callout1>4. SPRING EYE</callout1>
                <callout1>5. SPRING EYE BUSHING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. SPRING EYE PIN</callout1>
                <callout1>7. REBOUND PIN</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03004r_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03004r_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03004r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
