<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>MULTI-LINK FRONT AIR SUSPENSION - CHECKS AND ADJUSTMENTS - FRONT AXLE CASTER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="c02" svcproctype="Checks and adjustments" graphiccount="4">
        <title>FRONT AXLE CASTER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f0301520" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301520.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Left Front Wheel Caster Angle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT OF VEHICLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. VERTICAL (0&#176;)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. POSITIVE CASTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. KING PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. NEGATIVE CASTER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Caster is the amount in degrees the top of the kingpin is tilted toward the front or rear of the
                truck, as viewed from the side of the truck. The caster angle can range from a positive angle to a
                negative angle and this angle is measured in degrees.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Positive caster is the tilting of the top of the king pin toward the rear of the truck.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Negative, or sometimes called reverse caster, is the tilting of the top of the king pin toward
                        the front of the truck.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Proper caster is important for directional stability and return-ability. Too much positive caster can
                cause shimmy, excessive steering effort, and is normally a vehicle performance and handling
                consideration. Uneven positive caster may create a steering pull toward the side with the lower caster.
                This attribute may be used to compensate for crowned roads. The correct amount of caster helps to keep
                the front wheels in the straight-ahead position. When in a turn, caster acts as a lever, assisting the
                driver to return the front wheels to the straight-ahead position.
            </para>
            <para>Caster specifications are based on vehicle design load, which will usually result in a level frame. If
                the frame is not level when alignment checks are made, this must be considered in determining whether
                the caster setting is correct.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Frame Angle</title>
            <figure id="f0301525" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301525.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Rear Frame Angle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BUBBLE PROTRACTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TYPICAL POSITIVE FRAME ANGLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LEVEL FRAME</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>With the vehicle on a smooth, level surface, frame angle should be measured with a bubble protractor
                placed on the frame rail. The degree of tilt from the level frame position is the angle that must be
                used in determining a correct caster setting. Positive frame angle is defined as forward tilt (front end
                down) and negative angle as tilt to rear (front end height).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The degree of tilt from the level frame position is the angle that must be used in determining
                        a correct caster setting. Positive frame angle is defined as forward tilt (front end down) and
                        negative angle as tilt to rear (front end up or high).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The measured frame angle should be added to, or subtracted from, as required, the specified level
                frame caster setting to obtain the caster that should actually be measured on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Positive frame angle should be subtracted from specified setting.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Negative frame angle should be added to specified setting.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>As an example, if the specified caster setting is a positive 1&#176; and it is found that the vehicle
                has a positive 1&#176; frame angle, then the measured caster should be 0&#176; &#177; &#189;&#176;. This
                would result in the desired 1&#176; &#177;&#189;&#176; caster angle when the chassis settled to level
                frame under load.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Checking Caster</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Prior to checking caster, confirm that the vehicle is at its proper ride height on the rear
                        suspension (if applicable). The rear ride height must be correct to achieve proper caster.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle unloaded on a level surface.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Chock wheels to prevent vehicle movement.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the rear frame angle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check front axle caster.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Decreasing Caster Adjustment</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Keep in mind that if the caster is changed, the toe adjustment must be checked after
                        completing the caster adjustment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0301523" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301523.webp" type="webp" scalefitwidth="312px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Decreasing Caster Shim</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AXLE MOUNT BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CASTER SHIM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOWER TORQUE ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. NUTS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up the front of the vehicle, at the frame, and support the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen but do not remove two locknuts from the lower torque rod and two axle mount
                    bracket studs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a pry bar, pry the lower torque rod forward and install the appropriate shim
                    between the lower torque rod and the axle mount bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the two locknuts on the lower torque rod and axle mount bracket. Torque locknuts
                    to 170 to 185 lbf-ft (230 to 251 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Increasing Caster Adjustment</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Keep in mind that if the caster is changed, the toe adjustment must be checked after
                        completing the caster adjustment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0301526" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg03/g0301526.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Increasing Caster Shim</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOWER TORQUE ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MEGA BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MOUNT BOLT AND NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SHIM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Jack up the front of the vehicle, at the frame, and support the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen two bolts and nuts at the mega bracket and lower torque rod.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a pry bar, pry the lower torque rod forward and install the appropriate shim
                    between the lower torque rod and the mega bracket on both bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the two bolts and nuts on the lower torque rod and mega bracket. Torque nuts to
                    195 to 240 lbf-ft (265 to 325 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03015_C01.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03015_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s03015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
