<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR 4100, 4300, 4400, MXT, and RXT MODELS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S10009" division="truck" date="07/12/2007">
        <title>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR 4100, 4300, 4400, MXT, and RXT MODELS</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>MXT</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RXT</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL INFORMATION</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>Use these instructions along with the Form (S00021) when inspecting these models.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>These instructions explain how to inspect the vehicle to be sure it is ready for delivery to
                        the customer. Each inspection operation on the report has a corresponding procedure on the
                        following pages.
                    </para>
                    <para>Original should be retained at the PDI Facility.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Fill in the information block on the report after the vehicle is driven into the
                                inspection area.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>The instructions described in this manual follow the order of operations listed in the
                        Pre-Delivery/Quality Inspection Report. If, while performing an inspection a question comes up,
                        use the form as a guide to help find the correct reference information inside this manual.
                    </para>
                    <para>EXAMPLE: For a question about engine coolant level, refer to the operation on the report :
                        number 41. Go to Step 41.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <title>Non-Reimbursement Addendum</title>
                    </para>
                    <para>Adjustments which are a part of the PDI (
                        <emph type="boldital">not reimbursable as PTD warranty expense</emph>) are as follows:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Fluid level adjustments - Labor</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Wire harness route and clip - Tie Strapping</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Tire inflation</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Re-torque operations</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Installation of loose shipped items (except air deflector)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Chassis Lubrication</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                    <para>Consumables such as windshield washer solvent, diesel fuel, coolant additives, etc. will not
                        be reimbursed as warranty expense.
                    </para>
                    <para>Damage due to shipping should be claimed with the shipping carrier. All other repair
                        operations should be claimed to PTD 03 warranty.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
