<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>3200 Integrated Mobility Option Service Manual - Hadley Smart Air Management System - Appendix A - SAMS
        Wiring Harness Installation Precautions
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Appendix A - SAMS Wiring Harness Installation Precautions</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the utilized vehicle power source is not overloaded or undersized. Sufficient system
                power is required to optimize the manifold solenoid-valve operation; i.e., 10VDC- 16VDC, 1.2A per
                solenoid.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the power and ground connections are clean and tight and the manifold ground wire(s)
                are connected to a good chassis ground.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the harness is routed correctly so as the height sensor connectors are installed to
                the correct sensor on the vehicle. The following describes the center wire color of the main harness
                connector and its associated sensor connection:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Blue Wire</emph>
                        = Front Sensor Connector
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Yellow Wire</emph>
                        = Rear Drive Sensor Connector
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Green Wire</emph>
                        = Rear Curb Sensor Connector
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                pull on the harness connectors excessively during the installation process. Too much force on these
                components can pull wires from the connector or break wires from their pin crimp connection.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Keep the harness away from engine exhaust manifolds, mufflers, exhaust pipes, catalytic
                converters, and other heat generating components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Keep the harness away from pinch points and sharp objects to prevent crushing, cutting, and
                damage to the harness assembly which could result in open or short circuits.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow sufficient bend radii where applicable to prevent sharp bends, kinks, and unnecessary
                strain on the wiring that could result in eventual breakage and open circuits. The conduit manufacturer
                recommends a minimum bend radius of 3-inches.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow sufficient slack in the harness to prevent damage at points of vehicle horizontal
                and/or vertical movement and deflection. This will allow the harness to move with the vehicle and
                prevent unnecessary stress and fatigue resulting in eventual open and/or short circuits.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Caution should be taken as not to leave excessive slack which could cause the harness to become
                    snagged while the vehicle is in motion, especially in off road conditions.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the harness every few inches (typically 6 -12") with nylon straps.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While securing the harness with the nylon straps, care should be taken as not to crush the
                polyethylene flexible split conduit.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the rubber moisture seal is in place on the connectors. This will help to prevent
                moisture from entering the connection and affecting system operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure to apply a good brand moisture displacement lubricant to the connectors prior to
                connecting them to their associated sensor/field device. (A good product for this application is Super
                Lube Silicone Dielectric Grease available through MSC Industrial Supply, P/N 02105658). This will help
                to prevent moisture from entering the connection and affecting system operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When connecting the harness to the vehicle field devices; i.e., sensors, switches, etc. be
                sure the connector is properly orientated by the connector's keying mechanism and that the connectors
                are fully inserted so the latching mechanism is fully engaged. This will help to ensure a positive
                electrical connection, allowing for correct ECU monitoring and control.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure to seal any holes which may have been created for routing and installation of the
                ECU harness connectors, if required with an off the shelf expanding foam. A good product for this
                application is Federal Process Corporation Work Saver Expanding Foam available through MSC Industrial
                Supply, P/N 36913622.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
