<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - New Truck Receiving and Damage Claim Processing - NEW TRUCK RECEIVING AND
        DAMAGE CLAIM PROCESSING - CARRIER'S UNDECKING RESPONSIBILITIES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CARRIER'S UNDECKING RESPONSIBILITIES</title>
        <para>The items listed below are Carrier responsibilities to perform when undecking units at the Receiving
            Location.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Undeck units; remove saddles and wood blocks from the frame and front axle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install wheels if removed, and tighten the mounting hardware.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the exhaust stacks, and tighten per instruction sheet.
                <emph type="italic">(NOTE: Canadian Carriers are not responsible for re-installing exhaust stacks</emph>
                ).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If axles have been removed for transportation purposes,
                <emph type="bold">install new axle gaskets on the rear hubs. (These gaskets are sent with the
                    vehicle.)
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Re-install the axle shafts, special washers, and grade 8 nuts or propeller shaft and
                    tighten. NOTE: Dealer or dealer agent is responsible to torque shaft(s) before driving.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the driveline has been removed for transportation purposes,
                <emph type="bold">re-install pulled drivelines on decked 4X2 if removed (refer to SFN 01-32
                    <exhotlnk document="../sfns/sfn0132.htm" bookname="SFN">
                        https://evalue.internationaldelivers.com/service/sfns/sfn0132.htm</exhotlnk>).
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Remove all grease from the wheels and rims that resulted from axle shaft removal.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unhook the forward tandems when chained up for transportation.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-connect and tighten the air brake lines that were removed for transporting.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If spring brakes were manually released, return them to normal working position and install
                dust caps.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install tail lights in their proper position. Re-connect all wiring, and test it for
                proper operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove temporary mud flaps, lights, wiring and air hoses.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, re-install rear spring rebound pins in the proper position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install all components removed by the Carrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean up the unloading area; place items in the area designated by the Consignee.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>All vehicles should be left in the same condition as when received by the Carrier from the plant.
                    If they are not, or if you have questions, contact ATC Leasing at their Dispatch Hot Line number
                    before co-signing the Delivery Receipt: 1-800/558-3271 (U.S.), or 262/658-4831 (Canada).
                </para>
                <para>The Dealer is responsible to provide equipment for undecking the delivered units (see the
                    <hotlnk document="s10005_X1000503.xml" xrefid="x1000503">Undecking and Storage</hotlnk>
                    section). If a wrecker (tow truck) is used, the wrecker driver is considered to be the Dealer's
                    agent, and any undecking damage to the delivered vehicle(s) must be recovered from the wrecker
                    driver's employer.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
