<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Filing a Loss and Damage Claim</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Filing a Loss and Damage Claim</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Use International System 21 DDEW to submit your claim to International Warranty Claim Center as
                follows:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Be certain any damages or shortages described on the claim is identical to that on the
                        carrier's delivery receipt and/or concealed damage notification.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Complete the claim entry portion of the claim identifying claimant, carrier, vehicle
                        identification number, and damage.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use the CTS-1025, Warranty Coding Manual, for correct group/noun coding in conjunction with
                        failure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The correct warranty code for loss and damage claims is code "38".</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The correct type part, "T/P" for coding can be identified by using the Warranty Coding Manual,
                        CTS-1025.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All damages should be submitted on one DDEW claim utilizing all eight claim sections, one
                        section for each individual repair.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Supporting Documents</title>
            <para>The carrier or International may request any or all of the following documents prior to processing the
                claim:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A copy of the delivery receipt showing all exceptions being claimed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A copy of the work order, accurately reflecting the repair charges, and covering only
                    the noted exceptions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A copy of the invoice, listing replacement parts by name, quantity, and price.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Photographs and/or estimates of the damage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When applicable, a copy of the concealed damage and/or after-hours inspection report.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When applicable, a copy of the carrier's inspection report, indicating when the carrier
                    representative was called and when the inspection was made.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When applicable, a copy of the invoice for sublet materials.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Copies of the above should be retained in the dealer's claim file.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pre-Authorization</title>
            <para>Dealers are required to obtain a prior approval number for loss and damage claims totaling over
                $1000.00 U.S, and $1600.00 Canadian. Pictures or an estimate for repairs will be requested at this time.
                An authorization number may be obtained by calling International at 630-753-5242. Obtaining a
                pre-authorization number for a repair does not insure payment of the claim. Please refer to
                International Service &#38; Warranty Handbook, CTS-1143.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
