<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 - General - Driveline System - General Information</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="x2050062">
        <title>Driveline System - General Information</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Driveline System Description and Operation</title>
            <para>The source of the drivetrain's power is generated by the engine and delivered to the transmission. The
                driveline transfers the engine torque through the driveshaft to the rear axle.
            </para>
            <para>There is one type of axle used:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>S110 Dana&#174; full-float, single reduction axle.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>There are 2 types of driveshafts used:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>2-piece rear driveshaft with 3 U-joints, a front coupling shaft, a center bearing and a rear
                        slip-yoke.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3-piece rear driveshaft with 4 U-joints, 2 center bearings and a rear slip-yoke.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The rear driveshaft is connected to the output shaft of the transmission or transfer case and to the
                rear axle. Universal joints are used at both ends of the driveshaft to allow for angular motions.
                Slip-yokes are used to allow for any changes to the length of the driveshaft. The engine torque enters
                the axle through the drive pinion, which rotates the ring gear. The ring gear is mounted to the
                differential case, which contains the gears that transmit power to the rear axle shafts. These shafts
                rotate the drive wheels.
            </para>
            <para>For additional information on the driveshaft, refer to
                <exhotlnk document="../S06/S06002.htm" bookname="S06002">Driveshaft in S06002</exhotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>For additional information on the rear axle, refer to
                <exhotlnk document="../S14/S14020.htm" bookname="S14020">Rear Drive Axle/Differential in S14020
                </exhotlnk>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The axle identification tag is the official service identifier. Do not damage the tag. Always
                        reinstall the tag after removing it for axle inspection or repair.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
