<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Vehicle Tracking Site</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Vehicle Tracking Site</title>
        <para>Currently Active Transportation offers a vehicle-tracking site for many purposes including tracking in
            transit vehicles and copies of the carrier's freight bill. This is a free system that you may have access to
            at your dealership by filling out the form below. Once you fill out this form, either fax or e-mail it to
            Active, and they will instruct you on how to access the site. Any questions or difficulty with this site
            should be addressed directly to Active Transportation, not International. Below is a letter from Active
            explaining this web site.
        </para>
        <para>Subject: Web Page Truck Status and Tracking</para>
        <para>Dear Customer:</para>
        <para>Your heavy truck carrier Active Transportation (Dallas &#38; Mavis Forwarding) now offers Web Site Truck
            Status and Tracking information available on the Internet. For access, please complete the accompanying form
            and submit per the options noted on the bottom. Your "password "will be emailed back to you within 24 hours
            of receipt, along with instructions for access to this system.
            <emph type="bold">There is no cost to the customer.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>In addition, there are some other items you may find of interest on the ATC Leasing Co. Website. Included
            are a Questions and Comments format, along with the ability to change your password. Please be assured your
            input and data is confidential, and certainly valuable in helping us improve your delivery service.
        </para>
        <para>ATC Leasing Co. provides administrative support to the driveway carrier Active Transp. and others.</para>
        <para>Sincerely,</para>
        <verbatim>
            <line>Chris Fairleigh</line>
            <line>Debbie Minton</line>
            <line>ATC Leasing Co.</line>
            <line>Dealer Quality Assurance</line>
            <line>(800) 527-0491</line>
        </verbatim>
        <figure id="f1010303" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1001303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="562px"/>
            <caption>Figure 3. Vehicle Tracking Site Form</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
