<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Pre-Delivery Inspection Instruction Manual For ProStar Model - ProStar MODEL INSPECTION INSTRUCTIONS (REPORT
        S00125)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ProStar MODEL INSPECTION INSTRUCTIONS (REPORT S00125)</title>
        <para>1.
            <emph type="italic">Prepare vehicle for PDI inspection - wheel chocks etc.</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface, set
                    the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>PDI Inspection should take place in a well-lit location with a smooth level floor (a slight grade
                    for water drainage is acceptable) to assure accurate fluid level checks.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Assure vehicle has 120+ psi air pressure in the brake system per the dash gauges.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Turn OFF key.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Indicate on Pre-Delivery Inspection Report the vehicle Model, Assembly Plant, PDI Facility Name
                    and Location, VIN, R.O. No. (if applicable), Customer Name and Location.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cover seats (if uncovered) and floor mat with protective coverings to protect them from dirt
                    during PDI.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>It is recommended that clean floor mats made of cloth material be placed on the shop floor just
                    outside the vehicle's cab doors to reduce the amount of dirt tracked into the vehicle interior.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>2.
            <emph type="italic">Batteries/Cables/Cover - routing, tight, supported</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Battery cable end connections in box should be tight and secure.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cables in and around box are routed and clipped to avoid rubbing when box moves.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Batteries are securely fastened in box.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Battery view eyes (if equipped) should not be blocked by cables or mounting hardware.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Add or adjust tie-wraps as appropriate during PDI.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>3.
            <emph type="italic">Connect to Midtronics Smart Charger and begin charging - 2 hour minimum</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Carefully connect smart battery charger and charge batteries for a minimum of 2 hours.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Turn charger ON at 12V automatic high rate of charge. Watch for Incorrect Hook-Up warning.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Continue to charge the batteries until the green LED illuminates continuously. Continue charging
                    after Road Test if necessary.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If batteries are cool [less than 60 deg F (16 deg C)], moving vehicle into a heated facility will
                    shorten charging time required. It may take up to 20 hours to achieve a full charge if the batteries
                    are charged in a very cold [0 deg F (-17 deg C)] environment.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>For further details see the Smart Charger operator's manual on ISIS website at:
                    https://evalue.internationaldelivers.com/service/spectools/PowerCharge.pdf
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>4.
            <emph type="italic">Driver Controls with Vehicle Stationary - function properly: Tilt, Dif-lok, PDL, Dump,
                Mirrors, Radio, Wipe/wash, Horns, VID
            </emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Be sure the vehicle has 120 PSI air pressure or some optional equipment may not function.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Features - Verify proper function:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering/ optional Tilt-Telescopic Steering Wheel</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Differential Locks should lock and release properly as denoted by auditory engagement and
                            disengagement.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Power Divider should lock and release properly as denoted by auditory engagement and
                            disengagement.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>In-cab controls for remote 5th wheel jaw release and or remote slider release should
                            function properly.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Rear Air Suspension Dump - rear frame lowers and raises as selected.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Mirror adjustment, manual or motorized</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Radio/CD Player (optional) - Controls: Volume, AM FM, Station Change, CD Player, and
                            Speakers function properly.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                            Remember to remove CD immediately so it will not be left behind.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicle Information Display (VID) turns on and buttons work.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Windshield wipers work in all positions (HI/LO/Intermittent/OFF) and do not contact each
                            other or window frames.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                            If windshield is exceptionally dirty, wipe off windshield with clean cloth prior to wiper
                            test to avoid scratching the windshield.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>All washer fluid nozzles spray in acceptable pattern.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Steering Wheel-mounted Switches - Verify proper function.</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Air horn</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Electric horn</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Radio/Cassette/CD Player (optional) - on/off switches, volume +/- switches</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper function of all other driver controls and accessories that might be present that do
                    not require the vehicle to be moving.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>5.
            <emph type="italic">Cab support block removed - Cab height valve linkage reconnected.</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Vehicles equipped with cab air suspension that have been decked during transport are shipped with
                    a block(s) installed between the cab and the chassis or between cab suspension components. The
                    block(s) is held in position by the weight of the cab and a plastic stay strap. The shipping block
                    is installed in this position to prevent the cab from bouncing during shipping. Before demonstrating
                    or delivering vehicles equipped with cab air suspension, the shipping block MUST BE REMOVED.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Assure there is at least 110 PSI air pressure on both air pressure gages on the dashboard. Start
                    the engine and build up pressure if necessary, or air the truck up by connecting shop air hose to
                    the quick-disconnect fitting found on the air compressor discharge line, air tanks, or elsewhere.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cut the plastic stay strap.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Push up or down, as appropriate, on the cab height control valve arm until its linkage can be
                    aligned with, and fastened to, its mounting location.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                    Resetting ride height is should not be necessary, as only the day cab height valve linkage is
                    adjustable and its adjusting locknut should not have been loosened by the vehicle transportation
                    service.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the day cab height valve linkage locknut has been loosened:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Refer to service manual S16033 for cab air suspension to achieve the correct ride
                            height.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Contact Roger McClatchey at Active Transport via e-mail at:
                            RMcClatchey@activetransport.com and inform him of this procedural error. The height valve
                            linkage should not be disassembled or the locknut loosened. It should be merely disconnected
                            at one of its mounting points thus maintaining its proper length set at the factory.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>Measuring or resetting the cab height is not covered under
                            PDI.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>6.
            <emph type="italic">Install loose components shipped for or with the vehicle</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>These include:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Tailpipes/ Vertical exhaust stacks should be fully inserted into exhaust pipe</para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>Exhaust stacks should be properly aligned if applicable</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Clamps should be tight and secure, and installed in overlapping area between upper
                                    and lower stacks
                                </para>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Torque Specifications:</para>
                                        <randlist type="bullet">
                                            <item>
                                                <para>Aluminized band, bright hardware - 44 to 59 ft-lbs.</para>
                                            </item>
                                            <item>
                                                <para>409 Stainless band, dull gray hardware - 35 to 46 ft-lbs.</para>
                                            </item>
                                            <item>
                                                <para>If in doubt, torque to 46 ft-lbs.</para>
                                            </item>
                                        </randlist>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Correct as needed.</para>
                                        <para>
                                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                                            Vehicle transport personnel frequently install tailpipes. Therefore vehicles
                                            arriving with tailpipes installed should be inspected for proper tailpipe
                                            installation / bolt torques/ etc. Tailpipe installation and alignment labor
                                            is included in the PDI. Any damages to parts should be noted at the time of
                                            the receipt of the vehicle and charged to the vehicle transport service.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Trailer connections</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>CB antennas</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Mud flaps</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Cargo nets</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Any other mounted/installed component shipped with the vehicle and not installed by the
                            plant.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Labor cost for air deflector installation and additional dealer added / installed components is
                    not part of the PDI but is to be charged to the vehicle's cost via the assigned Stock Unit# / VIN /
                    Tag# / Etc.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>7.
            <emph type="italic">2 Keys + 2 Fuel Cap Keys present, RKE functional</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify two ignition keys are present</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Two Fuel Tank Locking Caps (optional) should be attached to vehicle keys. Test keys in fuel
                    caps.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Remote Keyless Entry (RKE) Fobs (optional) are present and functional</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: If RKE Fobs are not initially functional, refer to TSI 07-08-03 for
                        programming instructions.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired/ missing parts on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>8.
            <emph type="italic">Interior panels, trim, moldings and floor coverings - neat, clean, and secure.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify Interior components are neat and fit properly.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify Interior components are clean.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify Interior components are well secured.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>9.
            <emph type="italic">Seats and seat belts - operation and anchorage.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper installation, condition, and operation of Seats and Seat Belts.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>10.
            <emph type="italic">Sleeper Accessories/ Controls - clean/secure/function</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify sleeper controls and accessories are neatly installed and secure.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify sleeper controls and accessories are clean and undamaged.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify sleeper controls and accessories (including, but not limited to the inverter, TV,
                    appliances, etc.) function properly. Plug in a 120 volt light to assure inverter (if present)
                    operation.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>11.
            <emph type="italic">Lights - interior, instrument panel, dome, reading, sleeper, and exterior lights</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check interior lights, dome lights, sleeper lights (ceiling, reading, under bunk) and all exterior
                    lights including steering wheel-mounted Headlight Interrupt Switch and Marker Light Interrupt
                    Switch.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                    Use of mirrors in inspection bay is recommended.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>12.
            <emph type="italic">Paint, Exterior Components - in excellent condition, no body damage</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Remove any protective coatings added for shipping</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>External painted/unpainted and plated surfaces should be free from runs, scratches, scuffs, dents,
                    bumps, holes, or other obvious defects.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Trim pieces should be securely affixed and aligned, and in good condition.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Chrome surfaces should be free from cracks, bubbles, scuffs, or other obvious defects.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Mirrors, Bumper and Chassis Skirts should be securely mounted and in good condition.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected and any other body damage on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>13.
            <emph type="italic">Tires - proper inflation, valve stem caps are tight</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Tires may come from the vendor inflated above the maximum pressure indicated on the sidewall.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Tire pressure should be checked with a pressure gauge that is calibrated at least 4 times per
                    year.
                </para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>An air tire valve chuck with an integral dial pressure gage will speed up this process.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All rear/ drive tires should be inflated to same pressure somewhere between 90 psi. and the
                    maximum "dual tire pressure" listed on the sidewall, and all rear/ drive tires should be within 3
                    psi of each other.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Front tires should be inflated to the max single tire pressure listed on the sidewall + 0 / -3
                    PSI.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Correct tire pressure as needed during PDI</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If one or more tires of a like kind is more than 10 PSI lower in pressure than the other tires of
                    like kind, document tire(s) to be inspected for slow leaks on PDI Report.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Re-install metal (not plastic) valve stem caps tightly.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>14.
            <emph type="italic">Steering Intermediate Shaft Pinch Bolts - both torqued off</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Pinch bolts should be twisted off at each end of steering intermediate shaft.</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>Feel or look to see that the top surface of the head of the pinch bolt is relatively
                            smooth and that the 5/16" (8mm) hex head has been removed during the torquing process. A
                            round raw steel fractured circle can been seen where the hex head fractured off.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Re-torque if required (included in PDI labor).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>15.
            <emph type="italic">Engine compartment routing / clipping - secured, meets specifications, connectors fully
                seated
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check the following items:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Electrical wiring harnesses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Battery cables</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Air hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fuel hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Coolant/heater hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Power steering hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission cooler</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refrigerant hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Add-on hydraulic hosing.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All cables, hoses, and wires should be:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Well supported every 24" or less</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Free from tension</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>5" (125 mm) from any heat source unless shielded</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>3" (75 mm) from any heat source if shielded</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clear from any rub or pinch point</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Free from kinking or pinching</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Should NOT block access to any fluid fill, fluid drain, or inspection points</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Compressor discharge line should be free from any low points, or "water traps"</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Listen for audible air leaks using human ears (and optionally the Ultrasonic Leak Detector if
                    desired).
                    <emph type="bold">Spray a liquid soap solution on all air connections.</emph>
                    Bubbles indicate a leak.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Correct minor routing and clipping problems using tie wraps as needed during PDI.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>16.
            <emph type="italic">Power Steering Fluid Level - between COLD MIN and COLD MAX marks</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Fluid level should register between COLD MIN and COLD MAX marks on reservoir or dipstick.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Add or drain appropriate fluid as needed to correct fluid level.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To prevent a hot overfill, fluid must be drained from reservoir if fluid is cold and above COLD
                    MAX line.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If fluid level is in acceptable operating range, further fluid additions are not covered by PTD
                    Warranty. Only fluid added, not labor, is covered by PTD Warranty.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>17.
            <emph type="italic">Engine Oil Level - between ADD and FULL marks</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle should be parked on a level surface.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine should be turned OFF for at least 5 minutes before checking level.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Engine oil level in upper half of ADD-FULL range on dipstick is considered
                        acceptable as-is.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Add or drain oil as needed during PDI to put fluid level in acceptable range.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If fluid level is in acceptable operating range, further fluid additions are not covered by PTD
                    Warranty. Only fluid added, not labor, is covered by PTD Warranty.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>18.
            <emph type="italic">Proper Engine Coolant Level/Freeze Protection - between MIN COLD and MAX, good to -32 to
                -42F (-35 to -41C)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>If the coolant level is below the MIN COLD line, fill the surge tank to the MIN COLD line. If the
                    coolant
                    <emph type="bold">level is at or above the MIN COLD</emph>
                    line and the freeze point is correct,
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT adjust the level</emph>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Check coolant Freeze point (-32 F to -42 F; -35 C to -41 C) using a refractometer and adjust
                    concentration as necessary to assure specified freeze point.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>19.
            <emph type="italic">Steering Cotter Keys / lock tabs present, spread</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify cotter pins or lock tabs are present and spread.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document, on PDI Report, missing or damaged cotter keys or lock tabs to be corrected.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>20.
            <emph type="italic">Front Hub Oil Level (if equipped) - between indicators</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Oil level on oil-filled front hubs should be at or above the "OIL LEVEL" / "MINIMUM LEVEL" line on
                    the view window, and be below the vent plug opening. Oil should not pour out if the rubber cap is
                    removed.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Add or remove oil as needed during PDI to bring level to the proper range on the hub.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If fluid level is in acceptable operating range, further fluid additions are not covered by PTD
                    Warranty. Only fluid added, not labor, is covered by PTD Warranty.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>21.
            <emph type="italic">Open all coolant / heater valves before Road Test</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Open all coolant valves on vehicle prior to Road Test so that coolant circulates through all
                    possible systems.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Some installations have two hand valves in the engine compartment.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>22.
            <emph type="italic">Rearmost Axle Flange Gaskets - replace axle flange gaskets only if removed during
                shipping / towing
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Determine if the axle shaft has been removed from the rearmost drive axle during vehicle
                    transport. Indications that an axle shaft has been removed may include:
                </para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>The axle shaft flange and or its fasteners may have scratched or chipped paint.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The axle hub and or wheel rim may have evidence of axle lubricant that has dripped onto
                            them.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                            IF THE REARMOST AXLE SHOWS NO EVIDENCE OF HAVING ITS AXLE SHAFTS REMOVED, DO NOT REPLACE THE
                            AXLE SHAFT GASKETS. ACCEPT AS-IS AND MOVE TO NEXT LINE ITEM.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If an axle shaft has been removed, the dealer is to install a new axle shaft flange gasket using
                    the following specific procedures:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure the Dif-Lock (if present) has been engaged to avoid axle shaft-to-differential
                            misalignment upon axle shaft reinsertion.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the right and left axle shafts on the suspect axle. Be sure not to allow the axle
                            shaft to touch any dirty surfaces.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Wipe clean and inspect the axle shaft flange and wheel hub machined mating surfaces for
                            damage.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>If damage is found, document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If any studs come loose from the hub, be sure to use a thread-locker liquid on the
                            inserted section of the threads before reinstallation.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place the new axle flange gasket over the hub studs and fully seat it against the hub.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Carefully reinstall the axle shaft, and make sure not to nick the new gasket. If damage
                            occurs, install a new gasket.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Snug the axle flange fasteners with a hand operated wrench. DO NOT USE AN IMPACT WRENCH AS
                            IT CAN DAMAGE THE GASKET AND CAUSE A LEAK!
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Tighten the nuts in steps in a star pattern with a torque wrench to the specified torque.
                            Refer to the Table below.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Wipe off any visible axle lubricant.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <table id="t1000405a" frame="all">
            <title>Axle Flange Nut and Bolt Torque Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="4" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC3" colwidth="1.54in"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.24in"/>
                <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <spanspec namest="COLSPEC2" nameend="col4" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <spanspec namest="col3" nameend="col4" spanname="3to4"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Size</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC3" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Grade/Type</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Torque: Ft-Lbs.</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col4" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Torque: Nm</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5/8-18</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>8/Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>145-175</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>197-237</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                            <para>5/8-18</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5/Nylok</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>106-125</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>143-170</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>9/16-18</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>8/Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>105-125</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>143-170</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                            <para>9/16-18</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC3" align="center">
                            <para>5/Nylok</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                            <para>96-116</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="col4" align="center">
                            <para>129-156</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3/4-16</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>8/Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>250-300</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>340-410</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                            <para>3/4-16</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5/Nylok</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>219-240</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>294-325</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3/4-10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>8/Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>250-300</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>340-410</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC2" align="center">
                            <para>3/4-10</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5/Nylok</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>219-240</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>294-325</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>23.
            <emph type="italic">Transmission fluid level full / cooler hose connectors fully engaged</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify vehicle is on level ground.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that oil level in transmission is at the bottom of the fill plug opening.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Allow an overfilled transmission to drain excess fluid.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fluid level is acceptable if fluid level is not more than 1/8 inch (3 mm) below the bottom of the
                    fill hole opening, further fluid additions are not covered by PTD Warranty.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the fluid is more than 1/8 inch (3 mm) below the bottom of the fill plug opening add more fluid
                    (Labor covered within PDI. Fluid covered under PTD Warranty.).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that transmission drain plug is snug and leak-free after installation.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that all (up to four) Snap-To-Connect (STC) fittings on each end of the two Transmission
                    Oil Cooler hose sections are fully latched by grasping the tubing on each side of the connections
                    and forcefully pushing the connectors together. Then pull forcefully on each side of the connection
                    and attempt to pull the connectors apart to assure that the connection will not detach during use.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Failure to fully latch the STC fittings can allow the fittings to come apart during use resulting
                    in transmission failure due to oil loss.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Be sure to top-off with the correct fluid type (synthetic/ conventional mineral oil) per Lineset
                    Ticket, Job Information Sheet, or label on plug.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>24.
            <emph type="italic">Drive Axle Oil Level full / adjust (all drive axles)</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify vehicle is on level ground. If not, move vehicle to level ground.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that oil level in Drive Axle is at the bottom of the fill plug opening.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Allow an overfilled Drive Axle to drain excess fluid.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fluid level is acceptable if fluid level is not more than 1/8 inch (3 mm) below the bottom of the
                    fill hole opening, further fluid additions are not covered by PTD Warranty.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the fluid is more than 1/8 inch (3 mm) below the bottom of the fill plug opening, add more
                    fluid (Labor covered within PDI. Fluid covered under PTD Warranty.).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that Drive Axle drain plug is snug and leak-free after installation.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Be sure to top-off with the correct fluid type (synthetic/ conventional mineral oil) per Lineset
                    Ticket, Job Information Sheet, or label on plug.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>25.
            <emph type="italic">Routing/clipping under vehicle - secure/ meets specs</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check the following items:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Electrical wiring harnesses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Battery cables</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Air hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fuel hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Coolant/heater hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Power steering hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission cooler</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refrigerant hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Add-on hydraulic hosing.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All cables, hoses, and wires should be:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Well supported every 24" or less</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Free from tension</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>5" (125 mm) from any heat source unless shielded</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>3" (75 mm) from any heat source if shielded</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clear from any rub or pinch point</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Free from kinking or pinching</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Should NOT block access to any fluid fill, fluid drain, or inspection points</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Compressor discharge line should be free from any low points, or "water traps"</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Listen for audible air leaks using human ears (and optionally the Ultrasonic Leak Detector if
                    desired).
                    <emph type="bold">Spray a liquid soap solution on all air connections.</emph>
                    Bubbles indicate a leak.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Correct minor routing and clipping problems using tie wraps as needed during PDI.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>26.
            <emph type="italic">Lubricate Vehicle - zerks, door hinges, hood supports</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Lubricate all grease zerks (typically a quantity of 33 total zerks) including:</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>King Pins (4 zerks) and King Pin Thrust Bearings (2) with vehicle weight on tires</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Tie Rod Ends (2)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drag Link Ends (2)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering Intermediate Shaft (2) U-Joints and (1) Slip Joint</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering Gear Dust Seal (1) (Not present on some steering gears.)</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">CAUTION: Only use a hand-operated grease gun on Steering Gear Dust Seal
                                grease zerk (if present)! Using a power grease gun will blow out the seal!
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Brake Cam Shafts (6) on 6x4, (4) on 4x2</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Brake Slack Adjusters (6) on 6x4, (4) on 4x2</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drive Shaft U-Joints (2 to 5) (10-Series Drive Shafts Only!)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drive Shaft Slip Joints (2) on 6x4, (1) on 4x2 (10-Series Drive Shafts Only!)</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>DO NOT add grease to SPL XL Drive Shaft (easily identified by
                            having a plastic bellows covering the slip joints). It has synthetic lube from the factory.
                            The zerks are covered with plastic caps which should be left in place. Only grease
                            "10-Series" Drive Shafts.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission Clutch Cross Shaft Bushings (2)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission Clutch Throw-out Bearing (1)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>5th Wheel Pivot Pins (0 to 4)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>5th Wheel Slider Mechanism (0 to 4)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>5th Wheel Top Plate and Locking Jaw (additional details covered in separate 5th Wheel line
                            item)
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Grease Door Hinges and Door Check-Links with spray white Lithium grease.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Grease Bumper hinges with spray white Lithium grease.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>27.
            <emph type="italic">Fifth Wheel - lubed, functions, secured</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Refer to the correct operator's manual for proper lubrication procedures.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Lubricate 5th Wheel Top Plate and Locking Jaw, if applicable. On Fontaine 5th wheels, close the
                    jaw by pushing forward on the lower section of the jaw with a long shaft and then separate the
                    locking jaw from the wedge with a screwdriver and install grease into the gap so that the contact
                    surface between the two parts is well lubricated. This will keep the two parts from sticking
                    together and locking-up the jaw mechanism later.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fifth wheel should lock / unlock smoothly and fully.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Activate hand-operated Jaw Release (and electrically operated feature if present).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sliding fifth wheel should be secure and tight in locked position.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document major component defects to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>28.
            <emph type="italic">Clutch pedal free play - 1-1/4 to 1-3/4" (32 - 44mm)</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Measure the clutch pedal distance traveled while depressing the pedal until resistance is felt.
                    Measure at the midpoint (not lower or upper edge) of the side of the pedal pad.
                </para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>Free play should be 1-1/4 to 1-3/4" (32 - 44mm).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Correct as needed by performing an internal clutch (not linkage) adjustment during PDI.</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>Adjust finger to bearing gap to 1/8" (3mm)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Adjust bearing to clutch brake gap to 1/2" (13mm)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Re-measure the clutch pedal distance traveled while depressing the pedal until resistance
                            is felt.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If internal clutch adjustment does not provide proper free play, clutch linkage adjustment is then
                    necessary during PDI.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>29.
            <emph type="italic">Clear inactive Fault Codes</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Observe as-received fault codes.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clear inactive fault codes using in-cab method, or Vehicle Information Display, EZ Tech, or
                    applicable device.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document active fault codes on PDI Report and complete associated repairs prior to Road Test if
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>30.
            <emph type="italic">Starter only activates with clutch depressed - Manual Transmission only</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Manual Transmission:</emph>
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Starter MUST NOT ACTIVATE except when clutch pedal is depressed.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Start Vehicle.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31.
            <emph type="italic">ROAD TEST 20 minutes - Achieve 55 mph (90 kph)</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Pre-Planned Road Test Course should be nominally 6 miles (10km) and should include</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Reverse operation.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Full-lock turns in right and left directions.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Road speed of 55 mph/ 90 kph or higher.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>A section of rough pavement to evaluate squeaks, rattles, ride, etc.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Before starting the Road Test:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Be sure the Battery Charger has been disconnected and the Battery Box Cover and Chassis
                            Skirts have been reinstalled.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Be sure the Bumper, Hood, Luggage Doors, Passenger Door, Trailer connections, etc. are
                            securely fastened/ closed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Be sure the vehicle has enough fuel to complete the test.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Be sure the vehicle is adequately licensed and insured.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Be sure the Driver has a valid Commercial Driver's License.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31a.
            <emph type="italic">Air Brake Test - perform, verify</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Engine OFF, Key OFF, Cycle brake pedal until at least one air system pressure gage registers below
                    55 PSI.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Turn the key switch to the ON position. The buzzer and light must activate when either gage
                    registers below 55 PSI.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Start the engine and let it run. The light and buzzer must turn off when the gage with the lowest
                    reading is at some point between 55 and 75 PSI.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pressure Build - Timed</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Rev engine to max RPM. Pressure in the gauge with the lowest reading should build from 85
                            to 100 PSI in 45 seconds or less.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Governor should cut-out at 125 to 135 PSI.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pressure Bleed - Timed</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn off engine, switch key to Accessory position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Assure vehicle will not roll, and then release Park Brake and Service Brakes.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After gauges stabilize, air pressure should drop no more than 2 PSI in one minute.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fully apply and hold Service Brake Pedal.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After gauges stabilize, pressure in either gauge should drop no more than 3 PSI in one
                            minute.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Low Pressure Alarm</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Cycle service brake pedal to deplete air pressure.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Alarm must sound before either gauge drops to 55 PSI.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Automatic Park Brake Application</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Continue cycling service brake pedal to deplete air pressure</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Park brake must automatically apply when the highest gage reading is somewhere between 20
                            and 40 PSI.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31b.
            <emph type="italic">Park Brake Function - holds and rolls when it should</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>With Park Brake set and engine at idle and transmission in 1st gear attempt to move vehicle.
                    Vehicle must not move.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With area clear, Park Brake released, engine at idle, and transmission in 1st gear, attempt to
                    move vehicle. Vehicle should move.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31c.
            <emph type="italic">Gages, Dash Warning Lights, Secondary Display - functional</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>With engine off and key moved from OFF to RUN position, gauges (except air pressure) will reset by
                    moving counter clockwise against internal stop and then to actual reading position.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If any gauge goes to 6 o'clock position, data is out of range or not available.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of all warning lamps - With engine off and key moved from OFF to RUN position,
                    warning lights will illuminate momentarily.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Observe function of all gages, displays, dash lights and warning lights with vehicle in motion.
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Speedometer</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Tachometer</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Oil Pressure</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Water Temperature</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Voltmeter</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Air Pressure</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fuel Level</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Any optional gauges</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Odometer Display</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document component defects to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31d.
            <emph type="italic">Windshield and Glass - no damage</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Windshield and other glass should be free from cracks, stars, chips, or other obvious defects.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31e.
            <emph type="italic">Driver Controls with vehicle moving - function properly: Engine-brake and Cruise
                switches
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Features - Verify proper function:</para>
                <para>Steering Wheel-mounted Switches</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Engine/Exhaust Brake ON/OFF Switch - Verify proper function.</para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake activates at all 3 power levels</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake deactivates when steering wheel switch or dash mounted switch are turned
                                    off
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Cruise Control Switches [operable over 35 mph (55kph)]: - ON/OFF, SET/CRUISE,
                            RESUME/ACCEL, deactivates after brake apply - Verify proper function.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper function of all other driver controls and accessories that might be present.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31f.
            <emph type="italic">Engine, Transmission, Brakes, Steering - performance</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>The following characteristics should be considered:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Idle quality - smooth</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Acceleration - smooth and powerful; Accelerator Pedal operates smoothly.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Shifts:</para>
                        <para>Manual Trans - Smooth quiet operation of clutch and gear shift lever</para>
                        <para>Automated Manual Trans - Smooth quiet operation of clutch, auto-shifts crisp but not
                            harsh
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>NVH (Noise, Vibration, and Harshness) - smooth and quiet, no shuddering, squeaking,
                            buzzing, hissing, whining.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Braking (Service Brakes and Engine/ Exhaust Brake) - smooth and powerful</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering - Tight and straight, no pull or vibration</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Oil Pressure - 25 - 50 psi, engine warm</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Water Temperature - 225 F max, engine hot</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Volts - 13.0 - 15.0 Volts</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Each parameter should be within an acceptable range per vehicle type and class.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31g.
            <emph type="italic">Gear Selector Function - correct gear in each position; Switches on Steering Wheel and
                Console, or Lever
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Manual Transmission</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that all gears are selected and achieved.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify Range Selector Lever and Splitter Switch operate smoothly.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Automated - Manual Transmission</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify clutch or service brake (as applicable) must be depressed to move from Neutral to Drive or
                    Reverse.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that all gears are selected and achieved.</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify the 3 Steering Wheel-mounted Automated Manual Transmission Shift Switches are
                            functional - MANUAL/AUTO override, Upshift, Downshift, shift switches
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify the Console-mounted Automated Manual Transmission Shift Switches are functional -
                            Neutral, Drive, Reverse, Hold, Upshift, Downshift, MANUAL/AUTO override shift switches
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31h.
            <emph type="italic">Steering Wheel Alignment - straight +/- 3/4" (18mm)</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Determine if the vehicle axles are out of alignment or if the steering wheel just needs to be
                    repositioned using the following instructions:
                </para>
                <para>- When driving straight ahead on a road with very little road crown, such as a limited-access
                    highway, determine if the vehicle tracks straight ahead.
                </para>
                <para>- If the vehicle pulls significantly to the left or right, the axles are out of alignment.</para>
                <para>Do not attempt to reposition an off-center steering wheel until axle alignment is deemed to be
                    proper.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the axle alignment is acceptable and the top center of the steering wheel rim is within 3/4
                    inch (18 mm) of straight ahead do not attempt to improve the steering wheel alignment. Re-indexing
                    the steering wheel on the steering column splines will move the rim of the steering wheel 3/4 inch
                    (18 mm) per spline.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                    The steering wheel mounts to the steering column shaft by a 72 tooth spline. The steering wheel
                    cannot be adjusted in less than 5 degree (3/4 inch, 18mm) increments.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If necessary,
                    <emph type="bold">adjust steering wheel to shaft alignment during PDI</emph>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be repaired (including axle alignment) on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31i.
            <emph type="italic">Wind noise - no leaking body seals</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify there is no unusually excessive wind noise.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>31j.
            <emph type="italic">Heat/AC/Fans - Cab (for Sleeper: @idle-parked) functional</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper operation of:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Heater</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Defroster</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>A/C</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Blower Fans</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Adjustable Vents</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Auxiliary Heaters</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Auxiliary A/C</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                            If sleeper equipped, apply the parking Brake with Engine ON be sure to leave the driver's
                            seat and operate the controls in the sleeper.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>32.
            <emph type="italic">Fluid, Air, or Exhaust Leaks - Cab / Engine Compartment / Chassis - none</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>With Vehicle running inspect exhaust connections for audible or visible leakage.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Return vehicle to a quiet inspection bay where small air leaks can be heard.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Turn OFF key.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Release parking brake. (This pressurizes additional air hoses)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Apply Service Brakes during the inspection using a prop-rod between the driver's seat and the
                    brake pedal.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify there are no visible fluid, exhaust, or audible air leaks anywhere on the vehicle. Items
                    included in check: (HVAC condensate (water) is not included as that is desirable)
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>CAC hosing</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refrigerant hoses - as evidenced by localized oil mist on hose, sender, or fitting</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Air hoses</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                            It is recommended that the appropriate detector (ultrasonic leak detector (required tool) or
                            refrigerant sniffer) is used in addition to the human ear, sprayed-on soap solution, or
                            visual signs of leakage.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fuel hoses, Fuel Tank, Fuel Delivery System</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Radiator</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Coolant / heater/ in-transit heat hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Power steering reservoir and hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission cooler and hoses</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Engine</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drive Axles</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Wheel Seals</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Add-on hydraulic hosing.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify manual operation of air tank drain valves.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Check that muffler / tailpipe assembly is still clamped and positioned correctly.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>33.
            <emph type="italic">Engine Coolant Level - Hot - Engine Off - near MAX line +/- 2 inch (50mm)</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check HOT coolant level after road test. The coolant level should be approximately 2 inches above
                    the MIN COLD line due to expansion.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Add coolant only if outside this range.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid being scalded by hot coolant, wait until engine cools and then slowly unscrew surge tank
                    cap.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>34.
            <emph type="italic">Axle U-bolts and Front Wheels - re-torque</emph>
            <emph type="boldital">after</emph>
            <emph type="italic">Road Test</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Spring clamp group components will settle-in during Road Test and Axle Spring U-bolt re-torque
                    will be more effective when performed after Road Test. DO NOT re-torque prior to Road Test.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Refer to the Torque Chart for specifications.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <table id="t1000904" frame="all">
            <title>U-Bolt Nut Torque Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="2.64in"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.01in"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.01in"/>
                <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col3" spanname="2to3"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">U-Bolt Dia. (Nominal)</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Torque: Ft-lbs.</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Torque: Nm</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>5/8 Inch Flanged Lock Nut</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>130-160</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>176-217</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>3/4 Inch Flanged Lock Nut</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>200-240</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>271-325</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>7/8 Inch Hex Head With Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>260-300</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>350-380</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>1 Inch Hex Head With Washer</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>325-400</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>441-543</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>Front Wheel Lug Nuts - retorque</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Re-torque is required on Front Wheels only since some front wheels are removed during vehicle
                    transport. Re-torque of rear wheels is not included in PDI.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Turn front wheels slightly to the right to provide clearance between the torque wrench handle and
                    the side of the vehicle to reduce the chances of scratching the vehicle bodywork.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Determine nut size, type, and torque specification.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Re-torque all wheel rim nuts following the proper tightening sequence.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Refer to the Wheels, Rims, and Tires section in GROUP 17 of the Master Service Manual for
                    additional information.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <table id="t1096c16" tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple" frame="all">
            <title>Disc Wheel Torque Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="4" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="14.38*"/>
                <colspec colname="colspec2" colwidth="54.07*"/>
                <colspec colname="colspec0" colwidth="18.06*"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="13.50*"/>
                <spanspec namest="colspec0" nameend="col3" spanname="span1"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="1to4"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry morerows="1" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Size</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry morerows="1" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Nut Mounting</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="span1">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Torque</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">lbf - ft</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">N.m</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>22mm</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="colspec2">
                            <para>Flange: Motor Wheel - 37.5mm Across Flats</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                            <para>450-500</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>610-678</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="col1">
                            <para>22mm</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="colspec2">
                            <para>Flange: International/Budd - 33mm Across Flats</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                            <para>450-500</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry align="center">
                            <para>610-678</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="1to4">
                            <note>
                                <para>Do not use lubrication on dry threads.</para>
                            </note>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <para>35.
            <emph type="italic">Fault Codes - check</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check for fault codes using in-cab method, or Vehicle Information Display, EZ Tech, or applicable
                    device.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document on PDI Report, active or inactive fault codes and any associated symptoms that appeared
                    during Road Test.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>36.
            <emph type="italic">All Additional Accessories as equipped - perf., programming</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper function of all other interior controls and accessories that might be present,
                    including but not limited to:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Programming AWARE</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Programming Theft Deterrent System password</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Calibrate optional Compass (readout is in odometer in instrument cluster)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Ambient Temperature Thermometer (must be present with Compass option)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>No-Idle solutions - Heaters, AC, Charging</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Cummins ICON</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Vehicle Information Display (VID)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Etc.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify proper function of all other exterior controls and accessories that might be present,
                    including but not limited to:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Block Heaters</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Shore Power</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Auxiliary Generator Set</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Chassis Auto-Lube Greasing System programming and functionality</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Etc.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>37.
            <emph type="italic">Complete: PDI "COMMENTS" and Repairs, Affix CTS-1122 sticker (optional), Instruction
                Stickers (if applicable)
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Complete PDI Comments Section</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Document details of problems/corrections made during PDI</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Document details of repairs to be made.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Complete needed repairs.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Affix additional Instruction Stickers (if applicable) (possibly found in vehicle
                            Operator's Manual)
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Complete inspector signature box</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Submit PDI Report to applicable technician, secondary inspector, or shop manager for further
                    processing/repairs or sign-off.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Complete any applicable repairs.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Complete technician signature box</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Re-inspect repaired items and complete additional inspector sign-off or send back to repair until
                    successfully inspected and signed-off by inspector.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Submit fully completed PDI Report to service lead person for a final approval sign-off and filing
                    or return to the "Complete any applicable repairs" step.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Affix CTS-1122 sticker (optional)</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>38.
            <emph type="italic">Operator's Manual, required documents are in vehicle</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Documents potentially required by law including:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Truck Chassis Operator's Manual</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine Operator's Manual</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Seat Belt Installation, Usage and Maintenance Guide</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fifth Wheel Instructions Handbook</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Special Equipment/ options Operator's Manuals</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Incomplete vehicle document (only if vehicle is shipped incomplete: No 5th wheel or Body
                    installed)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Etc.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>Other documents that may be present:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Radio Owner's Manual</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Full Features List/Line Setting Ticket</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle Electronics Programming Station Electronics Parameter Report</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ABS Brake Test Sheet</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Etc.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Not all documents on these lists may necessarily be classified as required documents. Check your
                    local laws for details.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>39.
            <emph type="italic">PDI Location Code, Date - add to Veh. Identification. Label</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Using a permanent felt or roller ball style pen with black ink, write the PDI Location Code, and
                    PDI Date on the Vehicle Identification Label.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cover the written PDI Location Code and PDI Date with high-quality transparent tape to preserve
                    the writing.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>40.
            <emph type="italic">Wash, Vacuum, and Dry Vehicle - look for interior leaks</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not wipe dirt off the vehicle when it is dry as that can scratch the finish.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Assure the vehicle is clean inside and out and no dirt is visible.</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Wash vehicle with mild soap solution and cloth or soft clean brush.</para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>Give extra attention to wheels that have had axle oil on them
                            due to the axle being removed during delivery.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Rinse thoroughly with fresh water.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Starting with the windows, dry the vehicle fully with a soft clean towel to prevent water
                            spots and soap etching.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With mild soap, remove any dirt that has entered the cab.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clean inside of windows with glass cleaner.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clean floor mat using a vacuum. Clean floor mat with soap, sponge, brush, and towel if
                            necessary to eliminate all signs of dirt.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove any protective coverings from interior unless the final customer desires them to
                            remain.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify there are no water leaks into the interior.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Document items to be corrected on PDI Report.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>Remember to remove any Dealer-owned, temporary License Plates from the
            vehicle. Check to make sure all tools and supplies have been removed from the vehicle.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10022_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10022.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
