<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>3200 Integrated Mobility Option Service Manual - Hadley Smart Air Management System - SAMS Manifold and
        Valves
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SAMS Manifold and Valves</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This section is written to provide an introduction to the manifold and valves used on the Smart Air
                Management System (SAMS). This discussion will create a basic understanding of the manifold assembly
                functionality. The knowledge gained by understanding the document content will provide service personnel
                with information to diagnose and repair related system problems.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Theory of Operation</title>
            <para>The manifold is an electro-pneumatic device used to control the air flow within the SAMS system. The
                number of valves used is dependant upon system requirements. The valves typically provide two-position
                control and are of a coil actuated design. The Smart Air Management System requires two valves for air
                bag control. One valve serves as a "fill" valve and allows system air to pass through the manifold
                "into" the air bag. This causes the air bag to inflate, thereby increasing the vehicle ride height. The
                second valve serves as an "exhaust" valve and allows air to pass "from" the air bag, through the
                manifold, into the atmosphere. This causes the air bag to deflate, thereby decreasing the vehicle ride
                height.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The below illustration identifies the individual components used on the SAMS manifold
                    assembly.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1001826" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG10/G1001826.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>The valves are controlled by the SAMS electronic control unit (ECU). The ECU provides the brains for
                the Smart Air Management System. The ECU contains the system specific program to control the vehicle
                ride height, as defined by the system operating requirements. The ECU receives signals from the system
                components, i.e. height sensors, operator control switches, and the respective vehicle hardware
                components (switches) to establish the mode of operation and to provide the desired system control and
                sustain the desired vehicle ride height.
            </para>
            <para>With no power applied to the manifold "control" valve coils, they are in a de-energized condition.
                This allows an internal spring to decompress (expand) and pushes a plunger against the associated
                manifold port, thereby sealing off the internal air passage. The stem of the plunger contains
                two-neoprene rings to serve as a guide to provide true and even travel within the body of the valve
                assembly. The face of the plunger also contains a seal that when forced against the seat of the
                manifold, provides a positive seal to prevent air flow through the manifold when the valves are
                de-energized. This mechanical action enables the SAMS system to seal the air within the system and
                maintain the desired ride height.
            </para>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to either raise or lower the vehicle ride height, the ECU will energize the
                respective manifold valve coil(s) by applying 12VDC. With 12VDC applied to the coil, current flows
                through the windings and creates an electro-magnetic field. This magnetic field is stronger than the
                existing spring pressure that holds the valve plunger against the valve seat within the manifold. The
                strength of the magnetic field will cause the plunger to move inside the body of the valve assembly,
                compressing the spring, and opens the respective "fill" or "exhaust" passage within the manifold. This
                will allow system air to either "fill" or "exhaust" the associated airbag. This action will either raise
                or lower the vehicle, depending upon which valve has been energized. When the desired position has been
                reached, the ECU will remove power from the valve coil(s), the internal spring will decompress (expand),
                and the plunger will once again seal off the associated manifold port. This sealing action will sustain
                the desired ride height until system adjustment once again becomes necessary.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ports of the manifold contain a mesh screen to help prevent air contaminants from entering
                        the manifold. However, it is possible for the screen to become damaged and allow contaminants to
                        enter the manifold. Should this occur, it is possible for debris to collect on the plunger face
                        seal or cause the plunger to stick open, thereby affecting system operation and performance.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symptom Summary</title>
            <para>The following symptoms summarize how system performance can be affected by contaminants entering the
                manifold.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 1:</emph>
                Should the
                <emph type="bold">front system fill control valve</emph>
                plunger become contaminated or the plunger stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plunger
                and continuously fill the front air bags. This would cause the front of the vehicle to continuously
                creep "upwards" while the vehicle is in operation, and result in the SAMS system constantly making
                corrections to lower the front of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 2:</emph>
                Should the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve</emph>
                become contaminated or the plunger stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plunger and
                continuously exhaust the front air bags. This would cause the front of the vehicle to continuously creep
                "downwards" and result in the SAMS system constantly making corrections to raise the front of the
                vehicle.
                <emph type="boldital">It should be noted that this condition would be most noticeable after the vehicle
                    has not been in operation for a period of time because the front of the vehicle would sag.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 3:</emph>
                Should the front
                <emph type="bold">rear system fill control valve plunger AND the rear drive air bag control valve</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously fill the air bag on the rear drive side of the vehicle. This would cause the rear drive
                side of the vehicle to continuously creep "upwards" while the vehicle is in operation, and result in the
                SAMS system constantly making corrections to lower this corner of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 4:</emph>
                Should the front
                <emph type="bold">rear system fill control valve plunger AND the rear curb air bag control valve</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously fill the air bag on the rear curb side of the vehicle. This would cause the rear curb side
                of the vehicle to continuously creep "upwards" while the vehicle is in operation, and result in the SAMS
                system constantly making corrections to lower this corner of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 5:</emph>
                Should the front
                <emph type="bold">rear system fill control valve plunger AND BOTH rear air bag control valves</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously fill the air bags on the rear curb side and the rear drive side of the vehicle. This would
                cause the rear curb side and the rear drive side of the vehicle to continuously creep "upwards" while
                the vehicle is in operation, and result in the SAMS system constantly making corrections to lower the
                rear of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 6:</emph>
                Should the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve AND the rear drive air bag control valve</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously exhaust the front air bags and the rear drive air bag. This would cause the front of the
                vehicle and the rear drive of the vehicle to continuously creep "downwards" and result in the SAMS
                system constantly making corrections to raise the front and rear drive side of the vehicle.
                <emph type="boldital">It should be noted that this condition would be most noticeable after the vehicle
                    has not been in operation for a period of time because the front of the vehicle AND the rear drive
                    of the vehicle would sag.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 7:</emph>
                Should the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve AND the rear curb air bag control valve</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously exhaust the front air bags and the rear curb air bag. This would cause the front of the
                vehicle and the rear curb of the vehicle to continuously creep "downwards" and result in the SAMS system
                constantly making corrections to raise the front and rear curb side of the vehicle.
                <emph type="boldital">It should be noted that this condition would be most noticeable after the vehicle
                    has not been in operation for a period of time because the front of the vehicle AND the rear curb of
                    the vehicle would sag.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Symptom 8:</emph>
                Should the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve AND BOTH REAR air bag control valves</emph>
                become contaminated or the plungers stick "open", it is possible for air to leak past the plungers and
                continuously exhaust the front air bags and the rear air bags. This would cause the front and rear of
                the vehicle to continuously creep "downwards" and result in the SAMS system constantly making
                corrections to raise the front and rear of the vehicle.
                <emph type="boldital">It should be noted that this condition would be most noticeable after the vehicle
                    has not been in operation for a period of time because the entire vehicle would sag.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>External leaks, such as loose air fittings, defective air bags, or leaks in the tubing could
                        also cause the vehicle to lean when not in operation for a period of time. External leaks can be
                        detected by squirting a suitable inspection solution; i.e., soap, water, and glycerin mix onto
                        the external system components. If an air leak is present, air bubbles will be created in the
                        applied solution.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If any of these conditions are noticed, the vehicle should be inspected and the cause of the problem
                corrected. These conditions could eventually cause premature compressor failure due to overheating from
                excessive cycling. The compressor would attempt to maintain system pressure that would continuously
                fluctuate due to the ECU trying to compensate for the system problem.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pneumatic Operation</title>
            <para>The System Definition section of this document defines this SAMS system as a 3-point system. This
                definition can be summarized through the utilization of three height sensors for monitoring the vehicle
                ride height: one in the front and two in the rear. The configuration in this manner requires both front
                air bags to work together simultaneously to either raise or lower the entire front of the vehicle, while
                the rear air bags have the ability to work separately from of one another, thereby controlling the rear
                corners of the vehicle independently. To provide the 3-point system control the manifold has been
                designed to provide unique pneumatic control as outlined in the following sections.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pneumatic Control - Front</title>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to raise the front of the vehicle, the ECU will energize the front system
                fill control valve by applying 12VDC to the respective coil (refer to the illustration at the beginning
                of this section for reference). With 12VDC applied to the coil, current flows through the windings and
                creates an electro-magnetic field. This magnetic field is stronger than the existing spring pressure
                that holds the valve plunger against the valve seat within the manifold. The strength of the magnetic
                field will cause the plunger to move inside the body of the valve assembly, compressing the spring, and
                opens the respective "fill" passage within the manifold. This will allow system air to flow from the
                manifold air supply inlet, through the manifold, and out through ports front1 and front2, through the
                associated tubing and into the front air bags, thereby raising the front of the vehicle. When the
                desired position has been reached, the ECU will remove power from the valve coil, the internal spring
                will decompress (expand), and the plunger will seal off the associated manifold port. This sealing
                action will sustain the desired front ride height until system adjustment becomes necessary.
            </para>
            <para>When it becomes necessary lower the front of the vehicle, the ECU will energize the system exhaust
                pilot control valve by applying 12VDC to the respective coil (refer to the illustration at the beginning
                of this section for reference). The same magnetic principles and mechanical factors apply, thereby the
                plunger moves to open the respective "exhaust" passage in the manifold. This passage, when opened,
                allows air to flow from the front air bags, to ports front 1 and front 2, through the manifold, to the
                front air bag quick exhaust port of the manifold. Threaded into this port of the manifold is a pressure
                relief valve, with a spring tension of 10 psi. The pressure within the air bags (typically 95 - 130 psi)
                is stronger than the mechanical spring tension and causes the internal mechanism to unseat. This will
                allow the pressure to exhaust through the relief valve until the front air pressure equalizes with the
                spring tension. At that point, the spring tension will be strong enough to allow the internal mechanism
                of the relief valve to seat. This type of design allows the front air bags to exhaust quickly and to a
                predetermined air pressure, thereby keeping the air bags preloaded for re-inflation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pneumatic Control - Rear</title>
            <para>The raising or lowering of the front of the vehicle requires the ECU to simply energize the coil of
                the respective valve to fill (inflate) or exhaust the front air bags, thereby providing a single point
                of control. However, raising or lowering the rear of the vehicle requires more sophisticated system
                control. The system must provide independent operation of the rear air bags to provide dual-point
                control. The accumulated front and rear system control of this nature provides 3-points of control,
                referred to in this document as a 3-point system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To better understand the sequence of events necessary to raise the rear of the vehicle, this
                        discussion will focus on each side of the vehicle independently. Refer to the illustration at
                        the beginning of this section for reference.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to
                <emph type="bold">raise the rear drive</emph>
                side of the vehicle, a two-valve operation sequence is required. The ECU will energize the
                <emph type="bold">rear system fill control valve and the rear drive air bag control valve</emph>
                by applying 12VDC to the respective coils. With 12VDC applied to the coils, current flows through the
                windings and creates respective electro-magnetic fields. These magnetic fields are stronger than the
                existing spring pressures that hold the valve plungers against their valve seats within the manifold.
                The strength of the magnetic fields will cause the plungers to move inside the body of the valve
                assemblies, compressing the springs, and open the respective passages within the manifold. This will
                allow system air to flow from the manifold air supply inlet, through the manifold, and out through the
                rear drive manifold port, through the associated tubing and into the rear drive air bag, thereby raising
                the rear drive of the vehicle. When the desired position has been reached, the ECU will remove power
                from the valve coils, the internal springs will decompress (expand), and the plungers will seal off the
                associated manifold port. This sealing action will sustain the desired rear drive ride height until
                system adjustment becomes necessary.
            </para>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to
                <emph type="bold">raise the rear curb</emph>
                side of the vehicle, a two-valve operation sequence is required. The ECU will energize the
                <emph type="bold">rear system fill control valve and the rear curb air bag control valve</emph>
                by applying 12VDC to the respective coils. With 12VDC applied to the coils, current flows through the
                windings and creates respective electro-magnetic fields. These magnetic fields are stronger than the
                existing spring pressures that hold the valve plungers against their valve seats within the manifold.
                The strength of the magnetic fields will cause the plungers to move inside the body of the valve
                assemblies, compressing the springs, and open the respective passages within the manifold. This will
                allow system air to flow from the manifold air supply inlet, through the manifold, and out through the
                rear curb manifold port, through the associated tubing and into the rear curb air bag, thereby raising
                the rear curb of the vehicle. When the desired position has been reached, the ECU will remove power from
                the valve coils, the internal springs will decompress (expand), and the plungers will seal off the
                associated manifold port. This sealing action will sustain the desired rear curb ride height until
                system adjustment becomes necessary.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To better understand the sequence of events necessary to lower the rear of the vehicle, this
                        discussion will focus on each side of the vehicle independently. Refer to the illustration at
                        the beginning of this section for reference.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to
                <emph type="bold">lower the rear drive</emph>
                side of the vehicle, a two-valve operation sequence is required. The ECU will energize the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve and the rear drive air bag control valve</emph>
                by applying 12VDC to the respective coils. The same magnetic principles and mechanical factors apply,
                thereby the plungers move to open their respective passages within the manifold. This will allow air to
                flow from the rear drive side air bag, through the associated tubing, into the rear drive air bag
                manifold port, and out the rear air bag exhaust port, thereby lowering the rear drive of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>When the desired position has been reached, the ECU will remove power from the valve coils, the
                internal springs will decompress (expand), and the plungers will seal off the associated manifold port.
                This sealing action will sustain the desired rear drive ride height until system adjustment becomes
                necessary.
            </para>
            <para>When it becomes necessary to
                <emph type="bold">lower the rear curb</emph>
                side of the vehicle, a two-valve operation sequence is required. The ECU will energize the
                <emph type="bold">system exhaust pilot control valve and the rear curb air bag control valve</emph>
                by applying 12VDC to the respective coils. The same magnetic principles and mechanical factors apply,
                thereby the plungers move to open their respective passages within the manifold. This will allow air to
                flow from the rear curb side air bag, through the associated tubing, into the rear curb air bag manifold
                port, and out the rear air bag exhaust port, thereby lowering the rear curb of the vehicle. When the
                desired position has been reached, the ECU will remove power from the valve coils, the internal springs
                will decompress (expand), and the plungers will seal off the associated manifold port. This sealing
                action will sustain the desired rear curb ride height until system adjustment becomes necessary.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Valve Servicing</title>
            <para>The "control" valves (SMC) are secured to the body of the manifold by using four (4), 10-32NF X &#189;"
                socket head cap screws (SHCS) with lock washers and are factory tightened to 30in/lbs. of torque. Care
                must be taken when removing or replacing the valve assembly so as not to lose the mounting hardware or
                the O-ring that is installed in the respective manifold surface machined groove. The O-ring and mounting
                hardware create a positive seal between the valve assembly mounting plate and the valve mounting surface
                of the manifold.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the O-ring is lost or damaged or the valve is not properly attached to the manifold by
                        using all of the previous mentioned hardware, an external leak will occur and a source for
                        contamination to enter the manifold is created.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The valve body and coil are independent assemblies and can be replaced individually, if necessary. The
                coil only can be replaced by the following procedure:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the associated valve wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the power and ground wire (if applicable) from the harness connector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert an appropriately sized flat head screwdriver into the hook section of the clip
                    groove located on the top of the valve assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the screwdriver handle down, so the clip slides out (towards the screwdriver).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clip and slide the coil upward, to clear the housing of the valve body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To re-install, slide the coil over the valve body and re-install the clip.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and crimp new pins on the coil wires.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the wires in the harness connectors and reconnect the harness connectors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>System operating pressures are typically 95-130 psi. Steps should be taken to relieve pressure
                        from the system prior to removing any valve assembly from the manifold.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The system exhaust pilot control valve (KIP) is threaded into its respective manifold location. Care
                must be taken when removing the valve so as not to lose the O-ring that is installed in the body of the
                manifold or the spring loaded plunger located inside the valve assembly. The O-ring creates a positive
                seal between the valve assembly tapered surface and the body of the manifold, thereby preventing air
                leakage around the threaded portion of the valve body.
            </para>
            <para>The valve body and coil assembly are assembled as a single unit. If the coil is ever found to be
                defective, then the replacement of the entire valve assembly will be required.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electrical Testing</title>
            <para>A digital multimeter is a useful tool for troubleshooting and isolating electrical related problems.
                Open circuits are identified by no continuity shown on the display (1OL). Open circuits in the SAMS
                manifold electrical system are typically caused by pins that have pulled loose from the associated
                harness connector, wires that are broken at the pins in the harness connector, breaks in the coil
                windings, or broken wires in the wiring harness due to improper harness routing during the installation
                of the system.
            </para>
            <para>The coil can be tested for an "open" or "short" circuit by checking the resistance value of the
                windings. The coil must first be isolated by disconnecting its associated wiring harness connector.
                Obtain a multimeter as previously suggested and rotate the dial to the OHMS (resistance) setting. In
                most cases, this should turn on the power to the multimeter. If not, turn on the required switch to
                power the multimeter. Connect the red lead of the multimeter to one lead in the wiring harness connector
                of the coil to be tested. Next, connect the black lead of the multimeter to the other lead in the wiring
                harness connector of the coil to be tested. The display on the multimeter should read approximately 8 to
                10 ohms of resistance on the four manifold "control" valves (SMC). The display on the multimeter should
                read approximately 15 to 18 ohms of resistance on the system exhaust pilot control valve (KIP). If the
                display of the multimeter shows zero ohms of resistance, the coil is "shorted" and requires replacement.
                If the display shows an "open" circuit, as indicated by displaying "1OL", the coil requires replacement,
                as well.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prior to disconnecting the manifold wiring harness to perform the continuity check, be sure
                        power has been completely removed from the SAMS system. This is done by turning the power ON/OFF
                        switch to the "OFF" position and turning the ignition to the "OFF" position. This prevents the
                        SAMS system from operating when the engine is not running. The control valves (SMC) typically
                        require 1.2Amps of current and the KIP valve requires 0.6Amps of current, either of which could
                        drain a battery if energized with the engine "OFF" and the charging system not in operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The SAMS system requires 12VDC for proper system operation. The ECU uses the 12VDC supplied by a
                vehicle power source to control the manifold valve coils and also uses the voltage to create an internal
                5VDC reference signal. This lower voltage provides feedback to the ECU from various sensors to detect
                and maintain the vehicle ride height. Therefore, if the supply voltage is either excessively low
                (typically less than 9.7VDC) or excessively high (typically 14.8 VDC or above) system performance can be
                adversely affected. Depending upon system requirements the ground may also be provided via the ECU or a
                separate wiring harness ground wire may be used.
            </para>
            <para>The multimeter, using the DC voltage scale, is also a useful tool in checking and verifying the
                correct supply voltage and that a good system ground is present. Refer to the SAMS wiring diagram to
                determine the power and ground wires associated with the respective system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The vehicle system DC voltage is polarity sensitive. Therefore the digital multimeter red lead
                        needs to be connected to positive (system power: 12VDC) and the black lead connected to negative
                        (system ground). However, the coils used on the SAMS manifold valves are not polarity sensitive.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The below schematic illustrates the SAMS power connections, manifold coil connections,
                    and the connections for the height sensors for the 3-point system control.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1001827" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG10/G1001827.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Comment:</emph>
                Open and short circuits in the wiring harness are often the direct result of improper installation
                procedures. Hadley engineering has created separate documentation to serve as a guide for installation
                of the electrical and pneumatic hardware (see Appendix A and B respectively for additional information).
                However, there is no guarantee these installation procedures and associated document recommendations are
                adhered to by installation personnel. It is often the service personnel who must address and correct
                issues that arise from installation errors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Summary</title>
            <para>This completes the operation and service information regarding the SAMS manifold and valve assemblies.
                The information contained in this document is not intended to be all inclusive but to serve as a
                reference document. Time spent by installation and service personnel to better acquaint themselves with
                this information will provide a greater understanding of system operation and the associated servicing
                procedures.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
