<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Undecking and Storage - UNDECKING AND STORAGE - VEHICLE STORAGE</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>VEHICLE STORAGE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Dealer is responsible for adequate storage and protection of new vehicles, whether they are on
                Dealer premises or elsewhere. Check current procedures against the following recommendations, and
                correct any conditions creating unnecessary expense and/or preventable customer dissatisfaction.
            </para>
            <para>When vehicles are delivered directly to a contracted body manufacturer, the Dealer should arrange with
                the contracted firm for proper vehicle storage and maintenance. We recommend sending a copy of these
                procedures to the body manufacturer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Losses occurring to a unit while it is in storage will not be considered for reimbursement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Storage Duration - Two Months Or Less</title>
            <para>Because you cannot accurately predict how long vehicles will remain in inventory, use at least the
                following minimum precautions on every unit to prevent deterioration:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protective covering from exposed bright metal components (e.g., polished fuel
                    tanks).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash vehicles as necessary. ALWAYS wash vehicles delivered during winter months because
                    of exposure to road salt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para id="x1000501">Washing Instructions - Wash the vehicle with warm water and mild soap, then wipe
                        wet surfaces with a chamois or soft cloth. DO NOT use hot water or strong soaps or detergents.
                        DO NOT wash the vehicle in direct sun, or when the sheet metal is hot to the touch, because this
                        will streak the finish. DO NOT wipe dirt off dry surfaces, because this will scratch the finish.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect painted surfaces; touch up all exposed primed or raw metal areas to prevent
                    rust.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a thick coat of wax to prevent discoloration from the elements; wax all chrome and
                    stainless steel metal parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the radiator coolant for proper level and adequate freeze protection (-20&#176;F
                    is standard for medium duty models and bus chassis, -40&#176;F is standard for heavy duty models).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cover open ends of vertical exhaust stack(s).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check state of charge eye in batteries. If any one of the batteries has a dark state of
                    charge indication, charge all batteries. If the eyes of all batteries are green, batteries are
                    charged. If batteries do not have an indicator eye, re-charge if open circuit voltage is below 12.6
                    volts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The majority of batteries now provided in International vehicles are equipped with a "charge
                        indicator eye." If the eye is green, the battery is charged and is in satisfactory condition to
                        deliver to the customer. If the eye is dark, the battery is discharged and must be charged prior
                        to delivery to the customer. If the eye is clear, it means that the electrolyte level is low and
                        the battery must be replaced. A low electrolyte level is normally the result of a broken case or
                        years of usage; it will not be normally seen on new vehicles.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On 3000 Models and Stripped Chassis, ensure the protective shipping cover (e.g., horn
                    button cover, shift lever cover, instrument cluster cover, etc.) is properly in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Storage Duration - Over Two Months</title>
            <para>Units in storage two months or longer require the following procedures:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually check that tires are inflated and remove vertical exhaust stack covers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start and run the vehicle at fast idle until it attains operating temperature. To remove
                    surface charge from the battery, built up from previous start-ups and short idle periods, operate
                    the heater and/or air conditioner and other accessories for a few minutes, and turn on the
                    headlights.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check state of charge eye in batteries. If any one of the batteries has a dark state of
                    charge indication, charge all batteries. If the eyes of all batteries are green, batteries are
                    charged. If batteries do not have an indicator eye, re-charge if open circuit voltage is below 12.6
                    volts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drive the vehicle a short distance. Shift the transmission in various ranges; engage and
                    disengage the clutch and parking brake; apply and release the service and parking brake systems.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually check tire inflation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off the heater and/or air conditioner and any other accessories; shut off the
                    headlights. Park the vehicle and shut off the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery ground cables to prevent accidental starting, or parasitic electrical
                    loads from discharging the battery; re-cover the vertical exhaust stack(s).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain air brake reservoirs and close the drain cocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After every 30 additional days of storage, perform Items 1 through 8.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Perform the following procedures as required to maintain stored vehicles in prime condition:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash vehicles as necessary (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x1000501">Washing Instructions</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect painted surfaces; touch up all exposed primed or raw metal areas to prevent
                    rust.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a thick coat of wax to prevent discoloration from the elements; wax all chrome and
                    stainless steel metal parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When vehicles are stored outside, particularly in coastal areas (salt water and high humidity
                        atmosphere), or other areas of corrosive environment, paint and bright metal may require
                        frequent washing and waxing to prevent deterioration. Determining washing frequency is the
                        Dealer's responsibility.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For vehicles exposed to ultraviolet rays of the sun, apply a coating of Bon-Ami, or similar
                        product, to the inside surfaces of the windshield and windows, to shade the interior and prevent
                        fading the interior trim.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check state of charge eye in batteries. If any one of the batteries has a dark state of
                    charge indication, charge all batteries. If batteries do not have an indicator eye, re-charge if
                    open circuit voltage is below 12.6 volts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the radiator coolant for proper level and adequate freeze protection.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate all exposed transmission, auxiliary transmission and PTO shift rails.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>On Models 3000 and Stripped Chassis, ensure the protective shipping cover; e.g., horn button
                        cover, shift lever cover, instrument cluster cover, etc. is properly in place.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Storage Facilities</title>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Whenever possible, store vehicles indoors, protected from sunlight, in a dry, well ventilated
                        area. If indoor storage is not available, select storage lots to eliminate conditions that cause
                        deterioration.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park away from transformers and/or electrical motors, because when the protective wax in tire
                        compound cracks, ozone in the air attacks the exposed areas.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park away from trees, high weeds and/or grass to prevent damage from tree or weed sap, and to
                        minimize bird and insect stains.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park away from railroad tracks, paint shops, smoky industrial areas, and locations of possible
                        road splash contact.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a vehicle is parked on an incline, block the wheels.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_S10005_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
