<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400 MODELS - 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400 Model INSPECTION INSTRUCTIONS (REPORT S00021) - ROAD TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ROAD TEST</title>
        <para>33.
            <emph type="italic">Engine ECM and Truck ESC, clear inactive fault codes.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>To clear International engine ECM fault codes, turn key switch to ON, depress cruise control ON
                    and SET switches simultaneously for 3 seconds, then pump accelerator pedal 3 times. Refer to the
                    applicable Service or Owners Manual for additional information.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>To clear truck ESC fault codes, turn the key switch to ACC, apply left turn signal, and hold the
                    cruise control ON and SET switches simultaneously for 3 seconds. Refer to the applicable Service or
                    Owners Manual for additional information.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify satisfactory operation of...</emph>
        </para>
        <para>34.
            <emph type="italic">Service brakes, clutch, steering, and accelerator systems.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of brakes. Be aware of unusual sounds, pulling or darting.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that clutch releases and engages smoothly without slipping. Insure that free play and
                    clutch brake adjustments (if equipped) are within specifications. Refer to the Service Manual
                    section for clutch listed on line set ticket for proper specification.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Steering system performance. Be aware of unusual sounds, excessive wheel play, pulling or darting
                    sideways. Operate tilt/telescoping column if equipped, WHILE VEHICLE IS STOPPED.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of accelerator. Check freedom of movement and full throttle travel. There should
                    be no interference with other components.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>35.
            <emph type="italic">Speedometer/Tachometer and all gauges.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of speedometer and tachometer.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of additional gauges.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>36.
            <emph type="italic">Heater/defroster, A/C, and ventilation system.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify operation of heater/defroster/air conditioning and ventilation in all modes. System should
                    operate as outlined in the Owners Manual.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>37.
            <emph type="italic">Engine performance.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Overall engine performance. Note any unsatisfactory performance such as hard starting, rough idle,
                    stumble or hesitation during acceleration, or poor acceleration, unusual noises or excessive smoke.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>38.
            <emph type="italic">Transmission operation.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that all gears/speeds are identified correctly on decal or selector.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that transmission shifts correctly in all gears.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>39.
            <emph type="italic">Two speed axle if equipped.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that two speed axle shifts per Owners Manual instructions.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Never attempt to shift a two-speed axle when descending a hill as it could cause a loss of vehicle
                    control and result in an accident.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>40.
            <emph type="italic">All accessories as equipped.</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When auxiliary transmissions are used in combination with automatic transmissions, a loaded
                    vehicle should not be started with the auxiliary in the OD (overdrive) position.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Auxiliary transmission.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Tandem axle power divider lock.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Driver controlled differential lock.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Hand throttle/cruise control operation.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>41.
            <emph type="italic">Parking brake, holding properly.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify park brake operation, apply park brake, start engine and place transmission in low gear.
                    Verify that brake holds when attempting to move the vehicle without use of the accelerator.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Make sure nothing is in the path of the vehicle when performing this operation. Property damage or
                    personal injury could result.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
