<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Pre-Delivery Inspection Master Instruction Manual - General instructions</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>General instructions</title>
        <para>Listed at the top of the Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form is the title and the revision date of the
            form being viewed. Be sure that the title matches the model of vehicle on which a PDI is to be performed. If
            the form was not directly printed from ISIS on the day of the inspection, check on ISIS to verify the latest
            revision of the form is being used. Print out an updated form if necessary and destroy all previously
            printed out-of-date Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Forms and Pre-Delivery Inspection Instruction Manuals.
        </para>
        <para>Boxes are provided at the top of the Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form to link the form with the vehicle
            and provide specific details for future reference and documentation. The various boxes to be completed on
            the Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form include:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle Model [found on the VIN (Vehicle Identification Number) Label]</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle Build Date (found on the VIN Label)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>PDI Facility Name and Location</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The last 8 digits of the VIN</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The Miles on the Vehicle at the time of PDI</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>R.O. No. (Dealer's related Repair Order Number) (if applicable)</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Customer (End user) Name and Location</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A signature line for the Service Lead Person and the signature Date. This signature certifies that
                    all inspections, PTD (Prior To Delivery) warranty repairs, and inspection/technician signatures are
                    completed satisfactorily and that the form has been filled out completely and correctly. This is the
                    last step to be performed on the Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form prior to filing it at the
                    dealer unless there is a special request noted (such as faxing a copy of the completed form to
                    corporate personnel). The Service Lead Person approving the Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form is
                    the final person protecting the end user from quality issues in the vehicle. This responsibility
                    cannot be taken lightly.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Inspection Line items and procedures</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Read the Line Item. Perform the inspection/ task as instructed in this Manual. If the Line Item has been
            successfully completed or the inspected components are in an acceptable condition/working order, place a
            mark in the corresponding box in the ACCEPT AS RECEIVED column. If the line item CANNOT be successfully
            completed or the inspected components are in an unacceptable condition/working order, place a mark in the
            corresponding box in the REWORK REQUIRED column. Also describe what the problem is in writing in the
            COMMENTS section at the bottom of the PDI Report Form. After the item has been adjusted/repaired by the PDI
            Inspector (in the case of a fluid level adjustment, for example) or a technician (in the event of a PTD
            warranty repair), the item may be reinspected and the corresponding box in the ACCEPT AS RECEIVED column may
            be marked.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Comments Section</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This space is used to write details pertaining to problems found during the PDI. Be sure to place the
            applicable task reference number to the left of the comments as a helpful reference. Comments may also
            include R.O.'s opened to perform PTD warranty work. Other notes may be added as desired.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Initials/ Clock Number boxes</emph>
        </para>
        <para>These boxes are used to document who inspected the vehicle. Four boxes are required since one or more
            inspectors may be inspecting the vehicle prior to any necessary repairs. Inspectors must also affix their
            initials and clock number (if applicable) after re-inspecting the vehicle after repairs have been performed.
            The form/ vehicle may go back and forth between the Inspectors and the Repair Technicians if the repairs are
            not found acceptable after the first attempt. Placing a date next to any initials may be helpful as well.
        </para>
        <para>A box at the bottom of the form provides additional instructive details regarding signatures, inspection
            standards, and PDI Report Form filing.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10023_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10023_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
